<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="ghu" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-4-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Secretary shall implement a comprehensive plan to recruit, train, and retain child welfare casew...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary shall implement a comprehensive plan to recruit, train, and retain child welfare caseworkers and casework supervisors who meet the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall hire as caseworkers only human services professionals, such as:<section prefix="(i)">social workers licensed in accordance with Title 19 of the Health Occupations Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">psychologists licensed in accordance with Title 18 of the Health Occupations Article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">professional counselors certified in accordance with Title 17 of the Health Occupations Article;</section><section prefix="(iv)">nurses licensed in accordance with Title 8 of the Health Occupations Article;</section><section prefix="(v)">school psychologists certified in accordance with regulations adopted under Title 6, Subtitle 7 of the Education Article; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">human service workers who:<section prefix="1.">have a degree in an appropriate behavioral science;</section><section prefix="2.">have completed the mandatory preservice training and competency test; and</section><section prefix="3.">are supervised by licensed social workers.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary may retain permanent employees employed on or before December 31, 1998 who do not have the qualifications specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection if the Secretary finds that the employees are performing their duties satisfactorily.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary shall:<section prefix="(1)">implement a preservice training program and competency test for newly employed caseworkers;</section><section prefix="(2)">require that all new casework staff:<section prefix="(i)">be hired provisionally;</section><section prefix="(ii)">except for staff described in item (4) of this subsection, complete a 40-hour preservice training program; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">pass a competency test before being granted permanent employment status;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">implement mandatory standards for continuing education for all caseworkers and casework supervisors that require that employees who fail to obtain the required continuing education credits be subject to disciplinary action, including demotion, suspension, and dismissal;</section><section prefix="(4)">develop and implement mandatory standards that exempt newly hired individuals who have documented and verified casework experience or hold appropriate State licensure from the 40-hour preservice training program specified in item (2)(ii) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(5)">require caseworkers who are exempt from the preservice training program specified in item (2)(ii) of this subsection and fail the competency test to participate in the preservice training program and to take and pass the competency test before being granted permanent employment status.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary may not employ human services professionals on a contractual basis as caseworkers or casework supervisors, except as required to meet an unanticipated need resulting from:<section prefix="(i)">a significant and unexpected increase in reports of child abuse or neglect, or both; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a significant and unexpected increase in the foster care or kinship care caseload, or both.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A caseworker or casework supervisor contractual position may not exist longer than 1 year.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Whenever the Secretary contracts with an outside entity for casework services, the Secretary shall require the contractor to comply with the employment qualifications, training curriculum, preservice and in-service training, and competency testing required under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
