<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="ghu" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-5-319</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "demonstration site" means a site that the Secretary selects in consultation with t...</catch_line>
  <order_by>319</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "demonstration site" means a site that the Secretary selects in consultation with the local director.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Secretary may establish a FIP demonstration site in not more than six jurisdictions.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding any other law, the local director shall appoint a director of the FIP established in a demonstration site who shall report directly to the local director.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding any other law, the Secretary has sole authority to approve demonstration site plans that will govern FIP functions in a demonstration site, including the authority to approve demonstration site plans that will:<section prefix="(1)">assist families that have an employable parent toward a lasting exit from temporary cash assistance;</section><section prefix="(2)">ensure that individuals and families receive appropriate benefits;</section><section prefix="(3)">reduce errors in the administration of FIP;</section><section prefix="(4)">place temporary cash assistance recipients in employment in which their earnings will likely increase; and</section><section prefix="(5)">improve the types of employment and employment retention rates of existing and former recipients.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The local director shall:<section prefix="(1)">develop a demonstration site plan for submittal to the Secretary for approval that will detail its:<section prefix="(i)">programmatic structure, including any programmatic changes;</section><section prefix="(ii)">organizational structure, including any organizational changes;</section><section prefix="(iii)">pay incentive structure and criteria for the award of pay incentives;</section><section prefix="(iv)">measurable performance criteria and how these relate to the incentive structure; and</section><section prefix="(v)">target performance criteria;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">implement the plan as approved; and</section><section prefix="(3)">report to the Department on the progress achieved in the demonstration site.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The proper operation of the demonstration site and the achievement of the target performance criteria shall be an element of the local director's performance evaluation.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Secretary shall establish a performance incentive program to provide pay incentives for employees in a demonstration site.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Secretary's powers under this section shall be construed liberally.</section>
  </text>
</law>
