<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-1004" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-8-1004</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">On or before July 1, 2008, the Office and the cooperating departments shall develop, coordinate, and implement a system for outcomes evaluation.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The system for outcomes evaluation shall be used to:<section prefix="(1)">monitor the care, supervision, education, and treatment provided by State-operated and State-supported programs described in &#xA7; 8-1001(d)(2) of this subtitle so that successful services can be expanded and services that do not produce positive results can be identified;</section><section prefix="(2)">establish an evaluation system for program performance, including measures of safety, quality, and effectiveness; and</section><section prefix="(3)">complete an assessment of the capacity of the programs described in &#xA7; 8-1001(d)(2) of this subtitle in the State that identifies programs in each community to serve the needs of a family that resides in the community.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The system for outcomes evaluation shall use standardized measures of function to evaluate the child's:<section prefix="(1)">protection from harm while in out-of-home placement;</section><section prefix="(2)">stability of living environment;</section><section prefix="(3)">family situation and efforts to treat and counsel the family unit;</section><section prefix="(4)">educational and vocational development;</section><section prefix="(5)">job skills and employment readiness;</section><section prefix="(6)">legal and appropriate use of drugs and alcohol;</section><section prefix="(7)">progress in learning positive, nonaggressive behavioral habits; and</section><section prefix="(8)">delinquency status.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The system for outcomes evaluation shall ensure that collection and use of data in the system maintains confidentiality of information on the children from the cooperating departments.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The system for outcomes evaluation shall ensure that a cooperating department shall:<section prefix="(1)">facilitate the participation of programs described in &#xA7; 8-1001(d)(2) of this subtitle operated by the cooperating department or private agencies with which the cooperating department has a contract for the placement of children in out-of-home care; and</section><section prefix="(2)">include in the cooperating department's contract with a private program provisions requiring the program to collect and report to the cooperating department:<section prefix="(i)">child-specific demographic information; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">data necessary to evaluate changes in functioning of the child as provided in subsection (c) of this section.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">When reporting demographic information and data under subsection (e) of this section, a cooperating department:<section prefix="(1)">may not disclose personal identifiers; and</section><section prefix="(2)">shall ensure the confidentiality of the information about the children under its responsibility.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">On or before October 1 of each year, the Office, in coordination with the cooperating departments, shall submit a report to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly on the progress of implementing the system for outcomes evaluation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
