<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="ghu" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-9-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Secretary shall carry out and enforce this title, the regulations of the Department, and any oth...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary shall carry out and enforce this title, the regulations of the Department, and any other provision of law that relates to the Secretary or the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary may adopt regulations to carry out the provisions of law that are within the jurisdiction of the Secretary.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary shall review and may revise the regulations of:<section prefix="(i)">each unit in the Department that is authorized by law to adopt regulations; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Department.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary is responsible for the budget of the Department and for the budget of each unit in the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary may create any advisory council that the Secretary considers necessary and assign appropriate functions to it.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary is responsible for the coordination and direction of all planning that the office of the Secretary initiates.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary shall keep fully apprised of plans, proposals, and projects of each unit in the Department and, except as expressly provided otherwise, may approve, disapprove, or modify any of them.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall develop a State Comprehensive Juvenile Services 3-Year Plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Plan shall:<section prefix="(i)">include an inventory of all in-day treatment programs and residential care programs and an accounting of the residence of all clients;</section><section prefix="(ii)">include an inventory of nonresidential treatment programs;</section><section prefix="(iii)">specify the needs of the various areas of services for clients, including alcohol and drug abuse rehabilitation services;</section><section prefix="(iv)">specify the needs of clients, including predelinquent diversion services programs;</section><section prefix="(v)">establish priorities for the different services needed;</section><section prefix="(vi)">set standards for the quality of residential services and outreach services;</section><section prefix="(vii)">include a program dedicated to reducing recidivism rates of clients;</section><section prefix="(viii)">include programs dedicated to diverting children from the juvenile justice system; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">include any other matters that the Secretary considers appropriate.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Plan shall be revised for each fiscal year and submitted, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly by February 1 of each year.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary is responsible for the development, implementation, and maintenance of a comprehensive client information system, including an individual current record on each child, that is integrated in and accessible to the various units of the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary shall undertake efforts to link the system to the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene and the Department of Human Resources for the purpose of allowing the exchange of information on clients served by each department.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each employee using the information shall protect the confidentiality of client records.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise expressly provided by law, the Secretary may transfer, by regulation or written directive, any function, staff, or funds from any unit in the Department to the office of the Secretary or another unit in the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any staff transferred to the office of the Secretary shall be provided space, equipment, and services by the unit from which the staff was transferred, unless the Secretary orders removal to another location for the proper and efficient functioning of that office.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before January 1 of each year, the Secretary shall report to the General Assembly, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, on the recidivism rates of children committed to the Department for placement in residential care.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The report shall include:<section prefix="(i)">recidivism rates for all children committed to the Department for placement in residential care;</section><section prefix="(ii)">recidivism rates by region for all children committed to the Department for placement in residential care; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">recidivism rates for each residential care program in which a child committed to the Department is placed.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The report shall include data from the prior 3 fiscal years.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The report shall include recidivism rates that are calculated for 1 year and 3 year time frames.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
