<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-7-114</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>114</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department is the principal unit of State government responsible for developing, maintaining, revising, and enforcing statewide disability policies and standards throughout the units of State government.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In this capacity, the Department shall:<section prefix="(i)">serve as the principal advisor to the Governor on the means and methods available to:<section prefix="1.">implement and fund support to individuals with disabilities in accordance with the State Disabilities Plan;</section><section prefix="2.">modify or consolidate support to individuals with disabilities; and</section><section prefix="3.">collaborate with federal, regional, and local units of government to enhance the effectiveness of the provision and funding of support to individuals with disabilities;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">annually recommend projects to the Department of Budget and Management for inclusion in the capital budget to promote access to State-owned facilities for individuals with disabilities;</section><section prefix="(iii)">assist units of State government to identify federal, State, local, and private funds available to the State for programs and services for individuals with disabilities; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">provide technical assistance to local jurisdictions in planning and implementing collaborative strategies consistent with the State Disabilities Plan.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department shall oversee and administer the following programs and units:<section prefix="(1)">constituent services and ombudsmen programs;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Assistive Technology Guaranteed Loan Program under Subtitle 6 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the Office of Personal Assistance Services, including the Attendant Care Program under Subtitle 4 of this title.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
