<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-113" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-7-113</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary is responsible for the budget of the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as otherwise provided by law, the Secretary shall pay all money collected by the Department under this subtitle into the General Fund of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Before publication in the Maryland Register, the Secretary shall review new or proposed changes to regulations submitted by a unit of State government that relate to the provision of resources and services to individuals with disabilities.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The regulations shall include an assessment that describes the impact of the proposed regulations on individuals with disabilities.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before implementation, the Secretary shall review new or proposed changes to policies, programs, or services submitted by a unit of State government that relate to the provision of resources and services to individuals with disabilities.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall review, coordinate, and concur with any application for federal aid, waivers, or grants that is:<section prefix="(i)">specific to services for individuals with disabilities; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">submitted by or through any unit of State government.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise prohibited by law, the Secretary may apply for, receive, and use grants-in-aid, funds, or services from the federal government or any of its units, or any public or private source made available to the Department for use in carrying out the powers and duties of the Secretary or the Department.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall review the State Disabilities Plan developed by the Board in accordance with &#xA7; 7-132 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary may approve the State Disabilities Plan or amend the Plan if the Secretary determines that the Plan developed by the Board is not in accordance with &#xA7; 7-132 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary shall request that the Board revise the State Disabilities Plan at least once every 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Secretary shall adopt regulations to implement the State Disabilities Plan as approved or as amended in accordance with paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Secretary shall submit an annual analysis of the State's progress in implementing the State Disabilities Plan and related performance objectives to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly on or before October 1 of each year.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Secretary may create citizens' advisory bodies that the Secretary considers necessary for the effective operation of the Department.</section>
  </text>
</law>
