<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-204" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-5-204</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to State and federal laws governing the administration of public assistance, the Executive Director shall:<section prefix="(1)">organize and administer the Administration;</section><section prefix="(2)">supervise the public assistance activities of the local departments; and</section><section prefix="(3)">supervise other agencies and institutions under the supervision of the Administration.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Executive Director may prescribe the number and minimum qualifications of the personnel engaged in the administration of the activities of the Administration and of the local departments that are financed wholly or partly by the Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">As provided in the State budget, the Executive Director may appoint the personnel required to properly perform the duties of the Administration.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Except as otherwise provided, appointment and removal of all paid personnel under this title are subject to the provisions of the State Personnel and Pensions Article.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Executive Director shall submit budget estimates for the Administration to the Secretary.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Executive Director shall:<section prefix="(1)">develop a comprehensive process to:<section prefix="(i)">systematically analyze cash assistance payment errors;</section><section prefix="(ii)">formulate strategies, including improvements in the eligibility determination process, to reduce the errors; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">monitor implementation of the strategies;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">require each local department to submit annual plans that contain measurable objectives, including objectives for participation in work activities, to meet the goals of the Family Investment Program; and</section><section prefix="(3)">monitor the success of the local departments in achieving the objectives of the plans.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
