<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="ghu" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-10-210</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Secretary may impose a civil money penalty against a provider of congregate housing services for...</catch_line>
  <order_by>210</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary may impose a civil money penalty against a provider of congregate housing services for a violation:<section prefix="(1)">that results in conditions presenting an imminent danger or a substantial probability of death or serious physical harm to a resident of congregate housing;</section><section prefix="(2)">of a resident's rights as specified in regulations adopted under this title; or</section><section prefix="(3)">of a State or local fire safety law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Before imposing a penalty under this section, the Department shall send a notice of violation to the provider that states:<section prefix="(1)">when the provider must submit a plan of correction that is acceptable to the Department;</section><section prefix="(2)">when each identified violation must be substantially corrected; and</section><section prefix="(3)">that a civil money penalty may be imposed for failure to:<section prefix="(i)">submit an acceptable plan of correction; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">correct an identified violation.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After the time for correcting a violation has ended, the Department shall reinspect the facility to determine whether the violation has been corrected.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After the reinspection, the Secretary may:<section prefix="(i)">extend the time to correct the violation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">impose a civil money penalty under subsection (d) of this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary may impose a civil money penalty not exceeding $20 per violation per resident for each day that a violation remains uncorrected after the time set for correction under subsection (b)(2) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A penalty imposed under this section may not exceed $1,000 per violation or $5,000 in total.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall provide written notice of a civil money penalty to the provider.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice shall:<section prefix="(i)">be served on the provider by certified mail; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">state:<section prefix="1.">each penalty imposed;</section><section prefix="2.">the regulation or provision violated;</section><section prefix="3.">the amount of the penalty;</section><section prefix="4.">the provider's right to request a reduction of the penalty; and</section><section prefix="5.">how to file an administrative appeal of the penalty.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A provider of congregate housing services may request a reduction of a civil money penalty.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A request for a reduction shall:<section prefix="(i)">be made in writing within 10 days after the provider receives the notice of the civil money penalty; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">state the reasons for the request.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A request for a reduction of a civil money penalty does not affect the accrual of the penalties under subsection (d) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Within 14 days after receiving the request for reduction, the Department shall hold an informal conference with the provider on the issue of whether to reduce the civil money penalty.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In deciding whether to reduce the penalty, the Secretary shall consider:<section prefix="(i)">the provider's history of violations;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the provider's current and past diligence in correcting violations; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">other factors that the Secretary considers appropriate.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Secretary shall issue a written determination granting or denying the request for a reduction of a civil money penalty that states the reasons for the determination.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">As a condition of reducing a penalty, the Secretary shall require correction of all violations.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If a civil money penalty is imposed under this section, the provider has the right to appeal from the order in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Secretary may impose a penalty of three times the amount set forth in subsection (d) of this section on a provider of congregate housing services if a penalty was imposed on the provider for the same violation during the 2 years before the date on which the notice of violation was issued.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An order imposing a civil money penalty is final when the provider has exhausted all opportunities to contest the penalty under subsection (f) or (g) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A provider shall pay all penalties to the Department within 10 days after the provider receives a final order imposing a penalty.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a provider does not comply with this section, the Department may file a civil action to recover the penalty.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
