<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="ghu" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-10-436</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section does not apply to:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>436</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">a transaction undertaken under a contractual obligation in effect on October 1, 1996;</section><section prefix="(2)">a transaction made in the ordinary course of business of operating a facility;</section><section prefix="(3)">a refund under a contract entered into in the ordinary course of business;</section><section prefix="(4)">a transfer of cash, securities, or other investment property in connection with an ordinary investment transaction;</section><section prefix="(5)">a grant of a mortgage, deed of trust, or security interest to an unrelated third party;</section><section prefix="(6)">a transaction involving an easement, right-of-way, road widening, or similar conveyance for the benefit of a public body or a utility;</section><section prefix="(7)">a transaction made for an expansion or renovation; or</section><section prefix="(8)">any other sale, transfer, or other disposition exempted by the Department by regulation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A provider that holds a preliminary, initial, or renewal certificate of registration may not sell, transfer, or otherwise dispose of more than 10% of its total assets in any 12-month period unless the Department approves the sale, transfer, or disposition in accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-437 and 10-438 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A provider may not sell, transfer, or otherwise dispose of assets equal to or less than 10% of its total assets if the sale, transfer, or disposition is likely, according to standards set by regulation, to have an unreasonably adverse effect on:<section prefix="(i)">the financial stability of the provider; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the capacity of the provider to perform its obligations under its continuing care agreements.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Determinations of total assets shall be based on the provider's latest certified financial statements available at the time the sale, transfer, or other disposition is made.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
