<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-10-309</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>309</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Interagency Committee shall:<section prefix="(i)">develop a system to provide services to frail or health-impaired seniors at risk of institutionalization; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">coordinate the system among the agencies represented on the Interagency Committee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall administer the system for the Interagency Committee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The services shall include:<section prefix="(1)">integrated screening and evaluation;</section><section prefix="(2)">development of an individual plan of care;</section><section prefix="(3)">in-home services such as minor home repair, shopping assistance, homemaking, personal care, meal delivery or preparation, supportive services to group or shared living arrangements, transportation services, and health services; and</section><section prefix="(4)">community services such as day care, congregate meals, and other programs to assist seniors or adult caregivers in providing care for seniors.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To be eligible to participate in the system, a county or counties shall establish a community-based plan that:<section prefix="(1)">is developed by a local or regional committee composed of:<section prefix="(i)">the directors of the local health department, local department of social services, and area agency; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">officials of other relevant agencies, such as local housing, transportation, employment, and economic development officials;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">is consistent with the plan developed under &#xA7; 10-306(a) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">specifies administrative arrangements to evaluate and develop care plans for frail or health-impaired seniors;</section><section prefix="(4)">encourages further coordination of service delivery;</section><section prefix="(5)">fosters individual contributions for services provided;</section><section prefix="(6)">fosters the development of innovative service delivery;</section><section prefix="(7)">fosters the development of services in conjunction with the private sector; and</section><section prefix="(8)">fosters community involvement through the use of volunteers.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Interagency Committee, through the Department, shall work with local health departments, local departments of social services, area agencies, and local housing, transportation, economic development, and employment development officials to develop:<section prefix="(1)">a system to designate case managers to secure and manage necessary services for each frail or health-impaired senior in need; and</section><section prefix="(2)">guidelines to establish local or regional committees to coordinate the services system to implement this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
