<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="ghu" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-8-603</section_number>
  <catch_line>At-risk youth prevention and diversion programs shall be coordinated, monitored, and supported by lo...</catch_line>
  <order_by>603</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">At-risk youth prevention and diversion programs shall be coordinated, monitored, and supported by local management boards.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A local management board shall:<section prefix="(1)">develop a request for funds based on the recommendations of the local planning group convened in accordance with &#xA7; 8-605(b) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">award funds to local agencies or organizations to provide direct services;</section><section prefix="(3)">monitor and evaluate at-risk youth prevention and diversion program performance;</section><section prefix="(4)">provide technical assistance to at-risk youth prevention and diversion programs as needed;</section><section prefix="(5)">promote cost-effectiveness strategies;</section><section prefix="(6)">measure at-risk youth prevention and diversion program outcomes; and</section><section prefix="(7)">provide fiscal and program reports to the Office.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">As part of the prevention element of the 3-year plan developed by the Children's Cabinet establishing priorities and strategies for the coordinated delivery of services for children and families, the local management board shall:<section prefix="(1)">assess the adequacy, availability, and accessibility of current community-based services that:<section prefix="(i)">prevent and divert entry and reentry into the juvenile system;</section><section prefix="(ii)">provide alternatives to incarceration and institutionalization;</section><section prefix="(iii)">prevent and divert criminal behavior; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">increase personal responsibility and self-sufficiency;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">identify unserved neighborhoods or communities with critical needs and significant numbers of at-risk or delinquent youth; and</section><section prefix="(3)">recommend programs that can be established or enhanced to address the unmet needs of youth and their families.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
