<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="ghu" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-5-304</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Children of current or former recipients" means minors who:<section prefix="(i)">are at least 14 years old; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">reside with current or former recipients of benefits.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Former recipient" means an individual who received benefits under FIP in the past 5 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Foster youth" means an individual who:<section prefix="(i)">is an adult in out-of-home care under the responsibility of the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">is an adult under the age of 25 years; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">was in out-of-home care under the responsibility of the State on the individual's 18th birthday.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Obligor" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 10-101 of the Family Law Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary of Budget and Management, with the assistance of the Secretary, shall develop and implement a plan for hiring current and former recipients, children of current or former recipients, foster youth, and obligors by the principal departments within the Executive Branch of State government.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For each principal department, the plan shall include:<section prefix="(i)">the units that most easily could hire current and former recipients, children of current or former recipients, foster youth, and obligors;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the positions most suitable for current and former recipients, children of current or former recipients, foster youth, and obligors;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a proposal for recruiting current and former recipients, children of current or former recipients, foster youth, and obligors;</section><section prefix="(iv)">job retention strategies; and</section><section prefix="(v)">a target number of current and former recipients, children of current or former recipients, foster youth, and obligors to be recruited.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In consultation with the Secretary, the Secretary of Budget and Management shall report, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the Senate Finance Committee and the House Appropriations Committee of the General Assembly:<section prefix="(i)">on or before January 1, 2010, on the development of the hiring plan for current and former recipients, children of current or former recipients, foster youth, and obligors; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">on or before November 1 of each year, on the number of recipients, children of current or former recipients, foster youth, and obligors hired and retained by the principal departments within the Executive Branch of State government.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Working with appropriate local government officials, the Secretary and each local director shall develop and implement a local government hiring plan under which local governments may hire current and former recipients, children of current or former recipients, foster youth, and obligors.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For each jurisdiction, the local government hiring plan shall include:<section prefix="(i)">a list of the units that most easily could hire current and former recipients, children of current or former recipients, foster youth, and obligors;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a list of the employment positions most suitable for current and former recipients, children of current or former recipients, foster youth, and obligors;</section><section prefix="(iii)">proposals to recruit current and former recipients, children of current or former recipients, foster youth, and obligors;</section><section prefix="(iv)">employment retention strategies; and</section><section prefix="(v)">a target number of current and former recipients, children of current or former recipients, foster youth, and obligors to be recruited.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each local director shall:<section prefix="(i)">develop and submit the local government hiring plan in accordance with a schedule and format that the Secretary determines;</section><section prefix="(ii)">implement in a timely manner the proposals and strategies in the local government hiring plan;</section><section prefix="(iii)">achieve the target numbers in the local government hiring plan; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">develop and submit reports to the Secretary in accordance with a schedule and format that the Secretary determines.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On or before November 1 of each year and in consultation with the Maryland Association of Counties, the Secretary shall report, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the Senate Finance Committee and the House Appropriations Committee of the General Assembly, on:<section prefix="(i)">the development of the local government hiring plan; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the number of current and former recipients, children of current or former recipients, foster youth, and obligors hired and retained by local governments.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
