<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="ghu" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-3-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "local executive authority" means:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "local executive authority" means:<section prefix="(1)">except as provided in item (2) of this subsection, the county  executive of a county that has a charter form of government;</section><section prefix="(2)">the County Council of Talbot County;</section><section prefix="(3)">the county commissioners of a county that does not have a charter  form of government; or</section><section prefix="(4)">the Mayor of Baltimore City.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In each county, the local director shall be appointed with the concurrence of the Secretary and the appropriate local executive authority or its designee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The local executive authority or its designee shall meet and consult with the local board before the appointment of the local director.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A local director shall have:<section prefix="(1)">a master's degree in social work or a related field;</section><section prefix="(2)">at least 5 years of professional employment in social services administration or supervision; and</section><section prefix="(3)">any other qualifications and training that the Secretary requires by regulation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary, the local executive authority or its designee, and the local board shall:<section prefix="(i)">at least annually, evaluate the local director in writing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">jointly review their respective evaluations with the local director.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In consultation with the local board, the local governing authority of each county shall establish by ordinance or resolution the process for evaluating the local director.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary shall:<section prefix="(i)">establish by regulation the process by which the Secretary will evaluate the local directors; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">notify the local board of any significant deficiencies in the administration of the local department.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A local director may be removed from office with the concurrence of the Secretary and the appropriate local executive authority or its designee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The appropriate local executive authority or its designee shall meet and consult with the local board before the removal of a local director.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A local director shall be in the executive service or management service of the State Personnel Management System.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each deputy director and assistant director of the Baltimore City Department of Social Services shall be in the management service of the State Personnel Management System.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 3-403.1 of this title, the Director of the Department of Social Services in Montgomery County is a member of the Employees' Pension System.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
