<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-427" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-10-427</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a provider has a governing body, at least one of the provider's subscribers shall be a full and regular member of the governing body.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the provider owns or operates more than three facilities in the State, the governing body shall include at least one of the provider's subscribers for every three facilities in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection, a member of the governing body who is selected to meet the requirements of this subsection shall be a subscriber at a facility in the State and be selected according to the same general written standards and criteria used to select other members of the governing body.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The governing body shall confer with the resident association at each of the provider's facilities before the subscriber officially joins the governing body.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Secretary may waive the requirements of this subsection for a provider in the process of decertifying as a provider, if the Secretary determines that there are no subscribers willing and able to serve on the governing body.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a provider does not have a governing body, the provider shall appoint a select committee of its officers or partners to meet at least twice a year with the resident association at each of its facilities to address concerns of the subscribers and to ensure that the opinions of subscribers are relayed to all officers or partners of the provider.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a facility does not have a resident association, the committee shall meet with a reasonable number of representatives, not required to exceed fifteen, that the subscribers elect.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">As determined by the provider's governing body, the provider shall make available to subscribers either the nonconfidential portions of the minutes of each meeting of the governing body or a summary of the nonconfidential portions of the minutes, within 1 month of approval of the minutes.</section>
  </text>
</law>
