<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-10-409</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>409</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A provider may not collect deposits for continuing care or begin construction of a new facility until the Department approves a feasibility study.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person who intends to submit a feasibility study under subsection (c) of this section shall file with the Department a statement of intent to provide continuing care at least 30 days before the person submits the feasibility study to the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A feasibility study shall:<section prefix="(1)">be filed in a form satisfactory to the Department; and</section><section prefix="(2)">include at least the following information:<section prefix="(i)">a statement of the purpose of the proposed construction or conversion;</section><section prefix="(ii)">documentation of the financial resources of the provider;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a statement of the capital expenditures necessary to accomplish the project and the plan for acquiring the necessary capital;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a plan demonstrating the financial feasibility of the proposed project, including future funding sources;</section><section prefix="(v)">a study that demonstrates the market for the project;</section><section prefix="(vi)">an actuarial forecast reviewed by a qualified actuary;</section><section prefix="(vii)">a statement of the planned fee structure, including any proposed escalator or other automatic adjustment provision;</section><section prefix="(viii)">a description of the facility proposed to be used or being used for continuing care;</section><section prefix="(ix)">a copy of the proposed escrow and deposit agreements; and</section><section prefix="(x)">the form and substance of any proposed advertisement, advertising campaign, or promotional material for the facility that is available at the time of filing.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department may approve a feasibility study if the Department determines that:<section prefix="(1)">the number of comprehensive care or assisted living beds in the facility for which licenses are required by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene is not inconsistent with the State health plan;</section><section prefix="(2)">a reasonable financial plan has been submitted for developing and operating the project;</section><section prefix="(3)">a market for the facility appears to exist;</section><section prefix="(4)">a recognized authority prepared the feasibility study;</section><section prefix="(5)">the actuarial forecast supports the projections for the project;</section><section prefix="(6)">the Department has approved the escrow agreement and deposit agreement; and</section><section prefix="(7)">the approved escrow agreement is executed by the provider and the financial institution.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
