<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-5-310</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>310</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For applicants to the FIP, the amount of assistance shall be computed by counting no more than 4 weeks of earned income in any month and disregarding 20% of that earned income.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For eligible recipients who obtain unsubsidized employment, the amount of assistance shall be computed by counting no more than 4 weeks of earned income in any month and disregarding 35% of that earned income.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A recipient who has established eligibility may not lose eligibility solely because one or more wage earners in the family unit works more than 100 hours per month.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Two-parent families shall be exempt from any requirement that the principal wage earner must have worked for a specified time before applying to the FIP.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A child who is living with the child's parent and a stepparent in a household in which the household income exceeds the State eligibility standard for assistance may receive assistance if:<section prefix="(i)">the requirements of &#xA7; 5-308 of this subtitle are met; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the parent and the child would be eligible for assistance, based on the income of the parent and that parent's children.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The amount of assistance to be paid under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be computed with regard to the income of the stepparent if the total income of the stepparent equals or exceeds 50% of the official poverty level, adjusted for family size, established under the federal Community Services Block Grant Act.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A dependent child over the age of 17 years is eligible for inclusion in the FIP grant if:<section prefix="(1)">the child is a full-time student in secondary school or the equivalent; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the education program is expected to be completed in the calendar year that the child attains the age of 19 years.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
