<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="ghu" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-9-240</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>240</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Step-down aftercare" means:<section prefix="(i)">a network of programs that provide education and rehabilitation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">services and treatment to ease the transition of children from the custody of the Department to their homes and communities.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Step-down aftercare plan" means an individualized plan for each child in step-down aftercare that proposes specific assistance, guidance, treatment, services, and supervision that:<section prefix="(i)">prepares the child for reentry into the specific community to which the child will return;</section><section prefix="(ii)">ensures the delivery of prescribed services to the child in the community; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">monitors conduct in the community to ensure public safety.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A child discharged from a committed residential placement shall receive step-down aftercare for the period that the Department determines.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A child in step-down aftercare shall receive:<section prefix="(i)">a step-down aftercare plan;</section><section prefix="(ii)">supervision by step-down aftercare staff in accordance with the step-down aftercare plan;</section><section prefix="(iii)">educational services; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">any other services necessary to implement the step-down aftercare plan.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The step-down aftercare staff shall:<section prefix="(1)">prepare a step-down aftercare plan for each child assigned to the step-down aftercare program and file the plan with the Department;</section><section prefix="(2)">keep regular records concerning the progress of each child;</section><section prefix="(3)">file with the Department a monthly progress report on each child; and</section><section prefix="(4)">file with the Department an annual report on the outcome of step-down aftercare plans for the children in the step-down aftercare program, that includes to the extent possible:<section prefix="(i)">information on the number of children who:<section prefix="1.">are rearrested;</section><section prefix="2.">are rearrested and charged with serious or violent offenses;</section><section prefix="3.">are rearrested and waived to the adult system;</section><section prefix="4.">are re-referred to the Department;</section><section prefix="5.">are readjudicated and recommitted;</section><section prefix="6.">graduate from high school or successfully complete a high school equivalency examination; and</section><section prefix="7.">are employed; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">other relevant information.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
