<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-317" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-5-317</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall establish demonstration projects through grants to:<section prefix="(i)">nonprofit organizations;</section><section prefix="(ii)">local education agencies;</section><section prefix="(iii)">local management boards;</section><section prefix="(iv)">local health departments;</section><section prefix="(v)">religious organizations; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">institutions of higher education.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The entities listed in paragraph (1) of this subsection shall jointly develop proposals for demonstration projects under this section with local departments.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At least one of the demonstration projects under this section shall be located in a county other than the two counties with the largest numbers of FIP recipients.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall award grants for demonstration projects under this section through a competitive bid process that includes:<section prefix="(i)">the issuance of a request for proposals; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the establishment of an evaluation panel to review competing proposals and to make a recommendation to the Secretary concerning which proposals have the greatest programmatic and financial merit.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Not more than 50% of the funds allocated for demonstration projects under this section may be allocated to a single demonstration project.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The funds allocated for demonstration projects under this section are incentive funds over and above any transfer of FIP benefits to a third party payee.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Funds allocable to demonstration projects under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall, if feasible, be used for demonstration projects in the counties that generated the savings reallocated to demonstration projects under &#xA7; 5-316(e) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">When awarding grants under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Secretary shall give priority in funding for at least 20% of the funds allocated to demonstration projects under this section to regional proposals from two or more counties in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Funds allocated to demonstration projects under this section may not be used in the furtherance of sectarian religious instruction or worship.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In the request for proposals issued under subsection (b)(1)(i) of this section, the Secretary shall include requirements that:<section prefix="(1)">applicants specify what goods or services, or both, they will provide to participants; and</section><section prefix="(2)">each demonstration project:<section prefix="(i)">complement the local department FIP Plan; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">address specific, unmet local needs and barriers that prevent families from meeting the requirements of this subtitle.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition to the demonstration projects funded under subsection (b) of this section, the Secretary shall encourage and facilitate demonstration projects that are supported through:<section prefix="(1)">the voluntary transfer of temporary cash assistance and food stamp benefits to the demonstration project;</section><section prefix="(2)">the transfer of administrative costs from the local department; and</section><section prefix="(3)">any nonstate funds available to the project.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
