<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-601" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-5-601</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "resident" means an individual who resides in this State on the date the individual applies for public assistance.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to &#xA7; 5-314 of this title and as authorized under 21 U.S.C. &#xA7; 862a(d)(1), the State removes itself from the application of &#xA7; 115 of the federal Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Act of 1996 to allow the Department to provide temporary cash assistance and food stamps to a resident who has been convicted of a felony involving the possession, use, or distribution of a controlled dangerous substance.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding subsection (b) of this section, if a resident applying for temporary cash assistance or food stamps has been convicted of a felony involving the possession, use, or distribution of a controlled dangerous substance after August 22, 1996, the resident is subject to testing for substance abuse, as provided by the Department, and to treatment as required under &#xA7; 5-314 of this title for 2 years, beginning on the date of application, to the extent authorized under federal law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding subsection (b) of this section, if a resident receiving temporary cash assistance or food stamps is found to be in violation of &#xA7;&#xA7; 5-602 through 5-609, &#xA7; 5-612, or &#xA7; 5-613 of the Criminal Law Article, or 21 U.S.C. &#xA7; 841, the resident is:<section prefix="(i)">ineligible for temporary cash assistance or food stamps for 1 year after the date of the conviction; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">subject to testing for substance abuse, as provided by the Department, and to treatment as required under &#xA7; 5-314 of this title, for 2 years beginning on the later of:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An applicant or recipient who fails to comply with the testing required under this subsection or the treatment required under &#xA7; 5-314 of this title or who tests positive for the abuse of controlled dangerous substances is subject to the sanctions provided under &#xA7; 5-314 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In consultation with the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene, the Secretary shall adopt regulations to establish the testing methods and procedures, consistent with &#xA7; 5-314 of this title, to be required by the Department under this subsection, including the intervals of testing and methods required.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
