<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-6-604</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>604</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission consists of the following 18 members appointed by the Governor:<section prefix="(1)">the Secretary of Budget and Management;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene;</section><section prefix="(3)">the Secretary of Human Resources;</section><section prefix="(4)">the Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation;</section><section prefix="(5)">the State Superintendent of Schools;</section><section prefix="(6)">the Executive Director of the Governor's Office for Children;</section><section prefix="(7)">one judge assigned to the family division of a circuit court nominated by the Chief Judge of the Court of Appeals;</section><section prefix="(8)">one member of the Senate of Maryland nominated by the President of the Senate;</section><section prefix="(9)">one member of the House of Delegates nominated by the Speaker of the House;</section><section prefix="(10)">three individuals with extensive programmatic or academic experience with noncustodial fathers and their children;</section><section prefix="(11)">three individuals with an interest or expertise in matters pertaining to noncustodial fathers and their children, including representatives of community, parent, or religious groups or organizations;</section><section prefix="(12)">two representatives of local government in areas with a significant number of noncustodial fathers; and</section><section prefix="(13)">one noncustodial father.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member appointed under subsection (a)(10), (11), or (12) of this section is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The term of the member appointed under subsection (a)(13) of this section is 2 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The terms of members appointed under subsection (a)(10), (11), (12), and (13) of this section shall be staggered as required by the terms in effect for those members on October 1, 2007.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed to a position with a fixed term after the term has begun shall serve only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A member appointed under subsection (a)(1) through (6) of this section may designate in writing an alternate to represent the member and exercise the member's power to vote.</section>
  </text>
</law>
