<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-1-211</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>211</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A public agency may not disclose information or records under &#xA7; 1-210 of this subtitle if:<section prefix="(i)">disclosure is prohibited by federal law; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the public agency has not obtained written consent if required by &#xA7; 1-212 of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A public agency may disclose only the information and records that are identified specifically in the written request.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A public agency may not disclose child protective services records collected before October 1, 1993, unless the person in interest gives consent after being given an opportunity to review the records and the information to be disclosed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On request, the person in interest may review the entire child protective services record regarding the minor.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A public agency may not disclose to the person in interest or a requesting public agency the identity of:<section prefix="(i)">a reporter of abuse or neglect; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">another person whose life or safety is likely to be endangered by the disclosure.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Information and records disclosed to a public agency under this part shall remain confidential and, except as provided in &#xA7; 1-212(c) of this subtitle, may not be further disclosed.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Information collected by the Children's Cabinet under &#xA7; 1-212 of this subtitle may not be redisclosed in any form that reveals the identity of a recipient of services.</section>
  </text>
</law>
