<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="ghu" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-2-406</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Commission shall:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>406</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">stimulate and encourage study and review of the status of women in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">strengthen home life by directing attention to critical problems confronting women as wives, mothers, homemakers, and workers;</section><section prefix="(iii)">recommend methods of overcoming discrimination against women in public and private employment;</section><section prefix="(iv)">encourage women to become candidates for public office;</section><section prefix="(v)">promote more effective methods for enabling women to develop skills, continue education, and be retrained;</section><section prefix="(vi)">secure appropriate recognition of women's accomplishments and contributions to the State;</section><section prefix="(vii)">work to develop healthy attitudes within the framework of the Commission's responsibilities; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">inform the executive and legislative branches of government on issues concerning women, including offering testimony on these issues before legislative and administrative bodies.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission may:<section prefix="(i)">act as a clearinghouse for activities to avoid duplication of effort; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">make surveys and appoint advisory committees in fields including education, social services, labor laws and employment policies, law enforcement, health and safety, new and expanded services, legal rights, family relations, human relations, and volunteer services.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Through the Secretary, the Commission shall submit an annual report including recommendations based on the Commission's studies to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission may not adopt regulations.</section>
  </text>
</law>
