<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="ghu" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-9-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>As used in this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated, unless the context clearly...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">As used in this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated, unless the context clearly requires a different construction.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Bylaws" means those bylaws established by the Interstate Commission for its governance, or for directing or controlling its actions or conduct.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Compact Administrator" means the individual in each compacting state appointed pursuant to the terms of this Compact responsible for the administration and management of the state's supervision and transfer of juveniles subject to the terms of this Compact, the rules adopted by the Interstate Commission, and policies adopted by the State Council under this Compact.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Compacting state" means any state which has enacted the enabling legislation for this Compact.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Commissioner" means the voting representative of each compacting state appointed pursuant to Article III of this Compact.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Court" means any court having jurisdiction over delinquent, neglected, or dependent children.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Deputy compact administrator" means the individual, if any, in each compacting state appointed to act on behalf of a Compact Administrator pursuant to the terms of this Compact responsible for the administration and management of the state's supervision and transfer of juveniles subject to the terms of this Compact, the rules adopted by the Interstate Commission, and policies adopted by the State Council under this Compact.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Interstate Commission" means the Interstate Commission for Juveniles created by Article III of this Compact.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Juvenile" means any person defined as a juvenile in any member state or by the rules of the Interstate Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Juvenile" includes:<section prefix="(i)">an accused delinquent or person charged with an offense that, if committed by an adult, would be a criminal offense;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an adjudicated delinquent or person found to have committed an offense that, if committed by an adult, would be a criminal offense;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an accused status offender or person charged with an offense that would not be a criminal offense if committed by an adult;</section><section prefix="(iv)">an adjudicated status offender or person found to have committed an offense that would not be a criminal offense if committed by an adult; or</section><section prefix="(v)">a nonoffender or person in need of supervision who has not been accused or adjudicated a status offender or delinquent.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Noncompacting state" means any state which has not enacted the enabling legislation for this Compact.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Probation or parole" means any kind of supervision or conditional release of juveniles authorized under the laws of the compacting states.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Rule" means a written statement by the Interstate Commission promulgated pursuant to Article VI of this Compact that:<section prefix="(i)">is of general applicability;</section><section prefix="(ii)">implements, interprets, or prescribes a policy or provision of the Compact, or an organizational, procedural, or practice requirement of the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">has the force and effect of statutory law in a compacting state.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Rule" includes the amendment, repeal, or suspension of an existing rule.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"State" means  a state of the United States, the District of Columbia or its designee, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the U.S. Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Northern Marianas Islands.</section>
  </text>
</law>
