<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="ghu" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-8-1104</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Office shall administer the Fund as directed by the Executive Committee....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Office shall administer the Fund as directed by the Executive Committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Prior to final action by the Executive Committee, the Advisory Board shall review and make recommendations on:<section prefix="(i)">Program standards;</section><section prefix="(ii)">requests for proposals; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">criteria for awarding grants.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member of the Advisory Board may not vote on or make any recommendation to the Executive Committee if the member has a financial interest that may be substantially affected by that recommendation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before December 15 of each year, the Executive Committee, in consultation with the Advisory Board, shall review and update the comprehensive plan of after-school and summer opportunity programs as described in paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The comprehensive plan shall address at least the following issues:<section prefix="(i)">integration of public and private funding sources;</section><section prefix="(ii)">maximization of federal funding opportunities;</section><section prefix="(iii)">consideration of the special needs of disabled children, including needed services, supports, and appropriate provider training;</section><section prefix="(iv)">promotion of the use of school buildings and local public transportation resources for after-school and summer opportunity programs;</section><section prefix="(v)">where needed, technical assistance for compliance with the Maryland Out of School Time Programs' Quality Standards Framework;</section><section prefix="(vi)">promotion of continued expansion of high quality after-school and summer opportunity programs in the State; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">integration of any plans developed by local jurisdictions.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each fiscal year, in consultation with the Advisory Board and subject to the availability of money in the Fund, the Executive Committee shall issue a request for proposals under the State procurement law soliciting bids for a grant from the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to subsection (b)(2) of this section, the Executive Committee may award a grant from the Fund to an applicant only after consultation with the Advisory Board and upon a favorable vote of a majority of the members of the Executive Committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In any fiscal year, the total grants awarded to applicants operating within a particular county or Baltimore City may not exceed 15% of the total grants awarded in that fiscal year.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Only nonprofit organizations are eligible to receive a grant.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Executive Committee must identify and ensure that a responsible nonprofit organization will administer any grant awarded from the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In selecting a nonprofit organization to administer a grant from the Fund, the Executive Committee shall select the responsive and responsible bidder whose application best incorporates features that will have a positive measurable impact on one or more of the conditions of well-being for Maryland children and youth identified by the Maryland Out of School Time Programs' Quality Standards Framework.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Executive Committee shall ensure funds are granted to nonprofit organizations in all geographic areas of the State as equitably as possible.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Executive Committee may award a planning grant from the Fund to assist nonprofit organizations in a county to prepare an application for a grant for the next fiscal year.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Executive Committee may award a capacity building grant from the Fund to assist nonprofit organizations to increase staff capacity, training, and sustainability of the Programs.</section>
  </text>
</law>
