<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="ghu" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-6-426</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Department shall:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>426</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">contract with nonprofit organizations to operate the Program;</section><section prefix="(2)">seek the recommendations of the Advisory Board about policy determinations, the allocation of funds, and the development of a plan to serve homeless individuals and families;</section><section prefix="(3)">allocate any available federal funds and State funds to establish, administer, and operate shelter, nutrition, and service programs for homeless individuals and families;</section><section prefix="(4)">allocate funds to the areas of the State, considering unmet needs and the number of homeless individuals and families in those areas;</section><section prefix="(5)">establish a housing counselor and aftercare program to assist families and individuals in obtaining and maintaining permanent housing;</section><section prefix="(6)">establish and implement a homelessness prevention program to provide services to families and individuals in a housing crisis, which may include:<section prefix="(i)">case management services;</section><section prefix="(ii)">counseling to detect households at risk of becoming homeless;</section><section prefix="(iii)">training on budgeting and other life skills;</section><section prefix="(iv)">education about tenants' rights and responsibilities; and</section><section prefix="(v)">cash assistance;</section></section><section prefix="(7)">establish uniform reporting criteria for providers of services to homeless individuals and families under this part;</section><section prefix="(8)">collect regional data on the number of homeless individuals and families that receive services under this part; and</section><section prefix="(9)">make recommendations on the resources necessary to provide adequate programs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall report annually to the Governor on the extent of homelessness during the preceding year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall submit a report to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly on the effectiveness of the homelessness prevention program in preventing families and individuals from becoming homeless.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
