<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-5A-06" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-5-5A-06</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Office shall maintain liaison with:<section prefix="(i)">the United States Department of Health and Human Services;</section><section prefix="(ii)">local government units concerned with energy programs;</section><section prefix="(iii)">citizens' groups;</section><section prefix="(iv)">utility vendors and major fuel vendors in the State; and</section><section prefix="(v)">any other state, federal, and local units.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Office shall:<section prefix="(i)">consult with and advise the local entities described in paragraph (1) of this subsection regarding their energy assistance programs;</section><section prefix="(ii)">work at all levels of government to carry out this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">consult with all utility vendors and major fuel vendors in the State when developing and implementing the Program.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Office shall:<section prefix="(1)">collect and assemble information relating to energy assistance available from other units of the State and federal governments;</section><section prefix="(2)">disseminate information to further energy assistance;</section><section prefix="(3)">identify all utility vendors and major fuel vendors in the State and attempt to obtain their voluntary cooperation with the Program;</section><section prefix="(4)">establish and maintain a State information service that utilizes a toll-free telephone number to provide the public with information about the Program and the location of the nearest local energy assistance office; and</section><section prefix="(5)">establish a mechanism for monitoring the effectiveness of the Program to determine whether eligible households are aware of and have access to a local energy assistance office.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Consistent with this subtitle and other applicable laws, the Office may enter into contracts or assume any other function necessary to carry out this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Office may enter into contracts for any study or research activity that is necessary and proper.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
