<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-401" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-4-401</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to:<section prefix="(1)">each insurer that provides professional liability insurance to:<section prefix="(i)">a physician, nurse, dentist, podiatrist, optometrist, or chiropractor licensed under the Health Occupations Article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a hospital licensed under the Health - General Article; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">each self-insured hospital.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An entity subject to this section shall report quarterly any claim or action for damages for personal injury if the claim or action:<section prefix="(1)">is claimed to have been caused by an error, omission, or negligence in the performance of the insured's professional services or is based on a claimed performance of the insured's professional services without consent; and</section><section prefix="(2)">resulted in:<section prefix="(i)">a final judgment in any amount;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a settlement in any amount; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a final disposition that does not result in payment on behalf of the insured.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A report required under this section shall contain the information required under &#xA7; 4-405(b) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A report required under this section shall be filed within 90 days after the end of the quarter during which an event described in subsection (b)(2)(i), (ii), or (iii) of this section occurred.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A report that relates to a physician shall be filed with the State Board of Physicians.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A report that relates to a hospital shall be filed with the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A report that relates to a nurse, dentist, podiatrist, optometrist, or chiropractor shall be filed with the appropriate licensing board for these health care providers.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, a report filed in accordance with this section shall be treated as a personal record under &#xA7; 10-624(e) of the State Government Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each report shall be released to the Maryland Health Care Commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">An insurer that reports under this section or its agents or employees, the State Board of Physicians or its representatives, and any appropriate licensing authority that receives a report under this section shall have the immunity from liability described in &#xA7; 5-701 of the Courts Article for any action taken by them under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Failure to report to a person specified in subsection (e)(1), (2), or (3) of this section may result in the imposition by a circuit court of a civil penalty of up to $5,000.</section>
  </text>
</law>
