<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-19-509</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "uninsured motor vehicle" means a motor vehicle:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>509</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "uninsured motor vehicle" means a motor vehicle:<section prefix="(1)">the ownership, maintenance, or use of which has resulted in the bodily injury or death of an insured; and</section><section prefix="(2)">for which the sum of the limits of liability under all valid and collectible liability insurance policies, bonds, and securities applicable to bodily injury or death:<section prefix="(i)">is less than the amount of coverage provided under this section; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">has been reduced by payment to other persons of claims arising from the same occurrence to an amount less than the amount of coverage provided under this section.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The uninsured motorist coverage required by this section does not apply to a motor vehicle liability insurance policy that insures a motor vehicle that:<section prefix="(1)">is not subject to registration under &#xA7; 13-402 of the Transportation Article because it is not driven on a highway; or</section><section prefix="(2)">is exempt from registration under &#xA7; 13-402(c)(10) of the Transportation Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In addition to any other coverage required by this subtitle, each motor vehicle liability insurance policy issued, sold, or delivered in the State after July 1, 1975, shall contain coverage for damages, subject to the policy limits, that:<section prefix="(1)">the insured is entitled to recover from the owner or operator of an uninsured motor vehicle because of bodily injuries sustained in a motor vehicle accident arising out of the ownership, maintenance, or use of the uninsured motor vehicle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a surviving relative of the insured, who is described in &#xA7; 3-904 of the Courts Article, is entitled to recover from the owner or operator of an uninsured motor vehicle because the insured died as the result of a motor vehicle accident arising out of the ownership, maintenance, or use of the uninsured motor vehicle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The uninsured motorist coverage required by this section shall be in the form and subject to the conditions that the Commissioner approves.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The uninsured motorist coverage contained in a motor vehicle liability insurance policy:<section prefix="(i)">shall at least equal:<section prefix="1.">the amounts required by Title 17 of the Transportation Article; and</section><section prefix="2.">the coverage provided to a qualified person under Title 20, Subtitle 6 of this article; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">may not exceed the amount of liability coverage provided under the policy.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless waived in accordance with &#xA7; 19-510 of this subtitle, the amount of uninsured motorist coverage provided under a private passenger motor vehicle liability insurance policy shall equal the amount of liability coverage provided under the policy.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An insurer may exclude from the uninsured motorist coverage required by this section benefits for:<section prefix="(1)">the named insured or a family member of the named insured who resides in the named insured's household for an injury that occurs when the named insured or family member is occupying or is struck as a pedestrian by an uninsured motor vehicle that is owned by the named insured or an immediate family member of the named insured who resides in the named insured's household; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the named insured, a family member of the named insured who resides in the named insured's household, and any other individual who has other applicable motor vehicle insurance for an injury that occurs when the named insured, family member, or other individual is occupying or is struck as a pedestrian by the insured motor vehicle while the motor vehicle is operated or used by an individual who is excluded from coverage under &#xA7; 27-609 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The limit of liability for an insurer that provides uninsured motorist coverage under this section is the amount of that coverage less the amount paid to the insured, that exhausts any applicable liability insurance policies, bonds, and securities, on behalf of any person that may be held liable for the bodily injuries or death of the insured.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A policy that, as its primary purpose, provides coverage in excess of other valid and collectible insurance or qualified self-insurance may include the uninsured motorist coverage provided for in this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The uninsured motorist coverage required by this section is primary to any right to recovery from the Maryland Automobile Insurance Fund under Title 20, Subtitle 6 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">An endorsement or provision that protects the insured against damages caused by an uninsured motor vehicle that is contained in a policy issued and delivered in the State is deemed to cover damages caused by a motor vehicle insured by a liability insurer that is insolvent or otherwise unable to pay claims to the same extent and in the same manner as if the damages were caused by an uninsured motor vehicle.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">A provision in a motor vehicle liability insurance policy issued after July 1, 1975, about coverage for damages sustained by the insured as a result of the operation of an uninsured motor vehicle that requires a dispute between the insured and the insurer to be submitted to binding arbitration is prohibited and is of no legal effect.</section>
  </text>
</law>
