<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-1216</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Commissioner shall establish the Maryland Small Employer Health Reinsurance Pool....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1216</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commissioner shall establish the Maryland Small Employer Health Reinsurance Pool.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Pool shall be operational and may reinsure claims in accordance with this subtitle on or after July 1, 1994.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The reinsuring carriers shall elect a Board of Directors to be composed of seven members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall include representation from carriers whose principal business in health insurance comprises small employers and, to the extent possible, at least one nonprofit health service plan, at least one commercial carrier, and at least one health maintenance organization.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A carrier, including its affiliates, may not be represented by more than one member on the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The term of a member is 3 years except that the terms of initial members shall be staggered for periods of 1 to 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is elected.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Vacancies shall be filled by an election of the remaining Board members.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">A member who is elected after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is elected.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">A member who serves two consecutive full 3-year terms may not be reelected for 3 years after the completion of those terms.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board shall choose a Chairman.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall appoint an Executive Director, who shall be the chief administrative officer of the Pool.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Executive Director serves at the pleasure of the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Under the direction of the Board, the Executive Director shall perform any duty or function that the Board requires.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Pool may employ a staff in accordance with the budget of the Pool.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall submit to the Commissioner a plan of operation to ensure the fair, reasonable, and financially sound administration of the Pool.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner may amend or rescind a plan of operation if the Commissioner finds that the Pool is not operating in a fair, reasonable, and financially sound manner.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
