<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-10-105</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>105</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To qualify for a license as an insurance producer for life insurance, health insurance, annuities, nonprofit health service plans, dental plan organizations, health maintenance organizations, or fraternal benefit societies an individual applicant must meet the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An applicant must be of good character and trustworthy based on the standards of &#xA7; 10-126 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An applicant must be at least 18 years of age.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An applicant may not have committed any act that the Commissioner finds would warrant denial of a license under &#xA7; 10-126 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">So that the applicant is reasonably familiar with the kind or subdivision of insurance for which the applicant wants to be licensed:<section prefix="(i)">the applicant must complete successfully a program of studies that has been established or approved by the Commissioner;</section><section prefix="(ii)">during the 3 years immediately preceding the date of application, the applicant must have been employed regularly for periods totaling at least 1 year:<section prefix="1.">by the Administration as an employee or by an insurer or insurance producer; and</section><section prefix="2.">in responsible insurance duties in connection with the kind or subdivision of insurance for which the applicant wants to be licensed; or</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">during the 3 years immediately preceding the date of entering or immediately after discharge from the armed forces of the United States, the applicant must have been employed regularly for periods totaling at least 1 year:<section prefix="1.">by an insurer or insurance producer; and</section><section prefix="2.">in connection with the kind or subdivision of insurance for which the applicant wants to be licensed.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the case of an applicant for a limited lines license to act as an insurance producer for credit life insurance or credit health insurance, the applicant shall successfully complete a program of instruction that is:<section prefix="(i)">provided by an insurer that sells, solicits, or negotiates limited line credit insurance; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">approved by the Commissioner.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commissioner may waive the requirement of paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection for life insurance for an applicant who:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">has been conferred the Chartered Life Underwriter (C.L.U.) designation by the American College of Life Underwriters; and</section><section prefix="2.">is a member in good standing of the American Society of Chartered Life Underwriters; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">has been conferred the designation of:<section prefix="1.">Fellow of the Society of Actuaries;</section><section prefix="2.">Certified Employee Benefit Specialist (C.E.B.S.);</section><section prefix="3.">Chartered Financial Consultant (ChFC);</section><section prefix="4.">Certified Insurance Counselor (CIC);</section><section prefix="5.">Certified Financial Planner (CFP);</section><section prefix="6.">Fellow, Life Management Institute (FLMI); or</section><section prefix="7.">Life Underwriter Training Council Fellow (LUTCF).</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Commissioner may waive the requirement of paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection for health insurance for an applicant who has been conferred the designation of:<section prefix="(i)">Registered Health Underwriter (RHU);</section><section prefix="(ii)">Certified Employee Benefit Specialist (C.E.B.S.);</section><section prefix="(iii)">Registered Employee Benefit Consultant (REBC); or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Health Insurance Associate (HIA).</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Before taking a written examination, an applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">demonstrate to the Commissioner that the applicant has completed the requirements set out by the Commissioner, including the requirements of subsection (e) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">pay the application fee required under &#xA7; 2-112(a)(6)(iv) of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the applicant must pass an examination given by the Commissioner under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The following applicants are not required to take an examination:<section prefix="(i)">an applicant for a license to act as an insurance producer only for selling credit life insurance or credit accident and health insurance or both to a borrower of money or buyer of goods in connection with a loan or credit transaction;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an applicant for a license to act as an insurance producer for a dental plan organization if the applicant for compensation solicited, procured, or negotiated contracts for dental plan organizations continuously from July 1, 1988, to June 30, 1989;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an applicant for a license to act as an insurance producer for a nonprofit health service plan if the applicant for compensation solicited, procured, or negotiated contracts for nonprofit health service plans continuously from July 1, 1988, to June 30, 1989; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">an applicant for a license to act as an insurance producer for a health maintenance organization if the applicant for compensation solicited, procured, or negotiated contracts for health maintenance organizations continuously from July 1, 1988, to June 30, 1989.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">An applicant may be licensed as to any particular kind or kinds of insurance.</section>
  </text>
</law>
