<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-20-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Association" means the Industry Automobile Insurance Association.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Association member" means an insurer that is licensed to write motor vehicle liability insurance or motor vehicle physical damage insurance in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Association member" does not include the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Board of Directors" means the Board of Directors of the Association.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Board of Trustees" means the Board of Trustees of the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Executive Director" means the Executive Director of the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Fund" means the Maryland Automobile Insurance Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Motor vehicle liability insurance" means insurance coverage that is reported as private passenger auto no-fault, other private passenger auto liability, commercial auto no-fault, or other commercial auto liability on the exhibit of premiums and losses page of the annual statement that Association members are required to file with the Commissioner.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Motor vehicle physical damage insurance" means insurance coverage that is reported as private passenger auto physical damage or commercial auto physical damage on the exhibit of premiums and losses page of the annual statement that Association members are required to file with the Commissioner.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Person" includes a governmental unit.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Uninsured motor vehicle" means a motor vehicle for which:<section prefix="(1)">the security required under &#xA7; 17-103 of the Transportation Article is not in force; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the security required under &#xA7; 17-103 of the Transportation Article is in force but a receiver or conservator has been appointed by a court for the insurer that issued the security.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
