<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-7-305</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>305</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">At the time a person files the statement required by &#xA7; 7-304 of this subtitle, the person shall:<section prefix="(1)">file with the Commissioner:<section prefix="(i)">all invitations for tenders or advertisements making a tender offer or inviting tenders of voting securities of the domestic insurer or insurance holding company controlling the domestic insurer made by or for the person; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any agreement to:<section prefix="1.">exchange or otherwise acquire securities of the domestic insurer or insurance holding company controlling the domestic insurer; or</section><section prefix="2.">merge with or otherwise acquire control of the domestic insurer or insurance holding company controlling the domestic insurer; and</section></section></section><section prefix="(2)">send to the domestic insurer or insurance holding company controlling the domestic insurer:<section prefix="(i)">copies of the documents specified in item (1) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any information contained in the statement filed under &#xA7; 7-304 of this subtitle that the Commissioner requires by regulation.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By regulation, the Commissioner may set requirements that the Commissioner considers necessary or appropriate in the public interest or for the protection of policyholders for the contents of:<section prefix="(i)">additional materials inviting tender offers after the initial invitations; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">amendments to agreements described in subsection (a)(1)(ii) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The additional materials and amendments shall contain the information that the Commissioner requires.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The person required to file a statement under &#xA7; 7-304 of this subtitle shall file with the Commissioner the additional materials and amendments required by paragraph (1) of this subsection and send copies to the domestic insurer or insurance holding company controlling the domestic insurer no later than the date that:<section prefix="(i)">copies of the material are first published or sent or given to security holders; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the amendment is entered into.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
