<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-7-603</section_number>
  <catch_line>Each insurer subject to registration shall file the registration statement on the form provided by t...</catch_line>
  <order_by>603</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each insurer subject to registration shall file the registration statement on the form provided by the Commissioner, containing the following current information:<section prefix="(1)">the corporate and capital structure, general financial condition, ownership, and management of the insurer and of any person controlling the insurer;</section><section prefix="(2)">the identity and relationship of each member of the insurance holding company system;</section><section prefix="(3)">any pledge of the insurer's stock, including stock of a subsidiary or controlling affiliate, for a loan made to any member of the insurance holding company system;</section><section prefix="(4)">the following agreements in force, and transactions currently outstanding or that have occurred during the previous calendar year between the insurer and the insurer's affiliates:<section prefix="(i)">loans, other investments, purchases, sales, and exchanges of securities of the affiliates by the insurer or of the insurer by its affiliates;</section><section prefix="(ii)">purchases, sales, and exchanges of assets;</section><section prefix="(iii)">transactions not in the ordinary course of business;</section><section prefix="(iv)">except for insurance contracts entered into in the ordinary course of the insurer's business, guarantees or undertakings for the benefit of an affiliate that result in an actual contingent exposure to liability of the insurer's assets;</section><section prefix="(v)">management agreements, service contracts, and cost-sharing arrangements;</section><section prefix="(vi)">reinsurance agreements;</section><section prefix="(vii)">dividends and other distributions to shareholders; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">consolidated tax allocation agreements;</section></section><section prefix="(5)">any other matters about transactions between the insurer and its affiliates that the registration statement form requires; and</section><section prefix="(6)">a summary outlining all items in the current registration statement that represent changes from the prior registration statement.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each affiliate in an insurance holding company system shall give an insurer subject to registration under this subtitle that is in the same insurance holding company system complete and accurate information if that information is reasonably necessary to enable the insurer to comply with this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each insurer required to register under this subtitle shall:<section prefix="(1)">file with the National Association of Insurance Commissioners a copy of the registration statement required by subsection (a) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">on request of the commissioner of any state where the insurer is authorized to do business, file with that commissioner a copy of the registration statement summary required by subsection (a)(6) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commissioner may allow or require affiliated insurers subject to registration under this subtitle to file a consolidated registration statement.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commissioner may require an insurer that is a member of an insurance holding company system and that is not subject to registration under this subtitle to provide to the Commissioner a copy of the registration statement or other information that the insurer files with the commissioner of the insurer's domiciliary jurisdiction.</section>
  </text>
</law>
