<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-1301" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-1301</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE JUNE 30, 2014 PER CHAPTER 734 OF 2010 //<section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section><section prefix="(b)">"Affiliation period" means a period of time beginning on the date of enrollment and not to exceed 2 months, or 3 months in the case of a late enrollee, during which a health maintenance organization does not collect premium, and coverage issued does not become effective.</section><section prefix="(c)">"Association" or "bona fide association" means an association that:<section prefix="(1)">has been actively in existence for at least 5 years;</section><section prefix="(2)">has been formed and maintained in good faith for purposes other than obtaining insurance and does not condition membership on the purchase of association-sponsored insurance;</section><section prefix="(3)">does not condition membership in the association on any health status-related factor relating to an individual, and states so clearly in all membership and application materials;</section><section prefix="(4)">makes health insurance coverage offered through the association available to all members regardless of any health status-related factor relating to the members or individuals eligible for coverage and states so clearly in all membership and application materials;</section><section prefix="(5)">does not make health insurance coverage offered through the association available other than in connection with membership in the association, and states so clearly in all marketing and application materials; and</section><section prefix="(6)">provides and annually updates information necessary for the Commissioner to determine whether or not the association meets the definition of bona fide association before qualifying as an association under this subtitle.</section></section><section prefix="(d)">"Carrier" means a person that is:<section prefix="(1)">an insurer that holds a certificate of authority in the State and provides health insurance in the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">a health maintenance organization that is licensed to operate in the State;</section><section prefix="(3)">a nonprofit health service plan that is licensed to operate in the State; or</section><section prefix="(4)">any other person or organization that provides health benefit plans subject to State insurance regulation.</section></section><section prefix="(e)">"Church plan" means a plan as defined under &#xA7; 3(33) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974.</section><section prefix="(f)"><section prefix="(1)">"Creditable coverage" means coverage of an individual under:<section prefix="(i)">an employer sponsored plan;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a health benefit plan;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Part A or Part B of Title XVIII of the Social Security Act;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Title XIX of the Social Security Act, other than coverage consisting solely of benefits under &#xA7; 1928 of that Act;</section><section prefix="(v)">Chapter 55 of Title 10 of the United States Code;</section><section prefix="(vi)">a medical care program of the Indian Health Service or of a tribal organization;</section><section prefix="(vii)">a State health benefits risk pool;</section><section prefix="(viii)">a health plan offered under the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program (FEHBP), Title 5, Chapter 89 of the United States Code;</section><section prefix="(ix)">a public health plan as defined by federal regulations authorized by the Public Health Service Act, &#xA7; 2701(c)(1)(i), as amended by P.L. 104-191; or</section><section prefix="(x)">a health benefit plan under &#xA7; 5(e) of the Peace Corps Act, 22 U.S.C. 2504(e).</section></section><section prefix="(2)">A period of creditable coverage shall not be counted, with respect to enrollment of an individual under a health benefit plan or an employer sponsored plan, if, after such period and before the enrollment date, there was a 63-day period during all of which the individual was not covered under any creditable coverage.</section></section><section prefix="(g)">"Eligible individual" means an individual:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">for whom, as of the date on which the individual seeks coverage under this subtitle, the aggregate of the periods of creditable coverage is 18 or more months; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">whose most recent prior creditable coverage was under an employer sponsored plan, governmental plan, church plan, or health benefit plan offered in connection with any of these plans;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">who is not eligible for coverage under:<section prefix="(i)">an employer sponsored plan;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Part A or Part B of Title XVIII of the Social Security Act; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a State plan under Title XIX of the Social Security Act;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">who does not have coverage under a health benefit plan;</section><section prefix="(4)">who has not had the most recent prior creditable coverage described in paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection terminated for nonpayment of premiums or fraud by the individual; and</section><section prefix="(5)">who, if the individual has been offered the option of continuation coverage under a State or federal continuation provision:<section prefix="(i)">has elected that coverage; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">has exhausted that coverage.</section></section></section><section prefix="(h)">"Employer sponsored plan" means an employee welfare benefit plan that provides medical care to employees or their dependents, and is not subject to State regulation in accordance with the federal Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974.</section><section prefix="(i)">"Enrollment date" means the date on which:<section prefix="(1)">an individual enrolls in a health benefit plan; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the first day of the waiting period before which the individual may enroll.</section></section><section prefix="(j)">"Governmental plan" means a plan as defined in &#xA7; 3(32) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 and any federal governmental plan.</section><section prefix="(k)"><section prefix="(1)">"Health benefit plan" means a:<section prefix="(i)">hospital or medical policy or certificate, including those issued under multiple employer trusts or associations located in Maryland or any other state covering Maryland residents;</section><section prefix="(ii)">policy, contract, or certificate issued by a nonprofit health service plan that covers Maryland residents; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">health maintenance organization subscriber or group master contract.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">"Health benefit plan" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">one or more, or any combination of the following:</section><section prefix="(ii)">the following benefits if they are provided under a separate policy, certificate, or contract of insurance or are otherwise not an integral part of a plan:</section><section prefix="(iii)">the following benefits if offered as independent, noncoordinated benefits:</section><section prefix="(iv)">the following benefits if offered as a separate insurance policy:</section></section></section><section prefix="(l)">"Health status-related factor" means a factor related to:<section prefix="(1)">health status;</section><section prefix="(2)">medical condition;</section><section prefix="(3)">claims experience;</section><section prefix="(4)">receipt of health care;</section><section prefix="(5)">medical history;</section><section prefix="(6)">genetic information;</section><section prefix="(7)">evidence of insurability including conditions arising out of acts of domestic violence; or</section><section prefix="(8)">disability.</section></section><section prefix="(m)">"High level policy form" means a policy or plan under which the actuarial value of the benefit under the coverage is:<section prefix="(1)">at least 15% greater than the actuarial value of the low level policy form coverage offered by the carrier in this State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">at least 100% but not greater than 120% of the weighted average.</section></section><section prefix="(n)"><section prefix="(1)">"Individual health benefit plan" means:<section prefix="(i)">a health benefit plan other than a converted policy or a professional association plan for eligible individuals and their dependents; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a certificate issued to an eligible individual that evidences coverage under a policy or contract issued to a trust or association or other similar group of individuals, regardless of the situs of delivery of the policy or contract, if the eligible individual pays the premium and is not being covered under the policy or contract under either federal or State continuation of benefits provisions.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">"Individual health benefit plan" does not include short-term limited duration insurance.</section></section><section prefix="(o)">"Low level policy form" means a policy or plan under which the actuarial value of the benefit under the coverage is at least 85% but not greater than 100% of the weighted average.</section><section prefix="(p)">"Preexisting condition" means a condition that was present before the date of enrollment for coverage, whether or not any medical advice, diagnosis, care, or treatment was recommended or received before that date.</section><section prefix="(q)">"Waiting period" means the period of time that must pass before an individual is eligible to be covered for benefits under the terms of a group health benefit plan.</section><section prefix="(r)"><section prefix="(1)">"Weighted average" means the average actuarial value of the benefits provided by:<section prefix="(i)">all the health insurance coverages issued by the carrier in this State in the individual market during the previous calendar year, weighted by enrollment for the different coverages; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">all the health insurance coverages issued by all carriers in this State in the individual market, if the data are available, during the previous calendar year, weighted by enrollment for the different coverages.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">"Weighted average" does not include coverages issued under this subtitle.</section></section></text>
</law>
