<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-20-516</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to &#xA7; 20-517 of this subtitle, the Fund:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>516</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to &#xA7; 20-517 of this subtitle, the Fund:<section prefix="(1)">may reject an application of insurance if the applicant owes to the Fund an unpaid premium on an expired or canceled policy;</section><section prefix="(2)">at any time may cancel a policy for nonpayment of premiums; or</section><section prefix="(3)">may reject an application of insurance or at any time may cancel a policy if it is found that the driver's license of the applicant or policyholder is:<section prefix="(i)">suspended, unless the suspension is for a first offense under &#xA7; 16-205.1 of the Transportation Article for driving with an alcohol concentration of 0.08 or more; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">revoked.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Fund shall notify the applicant or policyholder promptly after the Fund rejects an application or cancels a policy.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a person does not have a valid license or other privilege to drive a covered vehicle in the State, or is otherwise ineligible to be insured by the Fund, the Fund may issue the appropriate policy with an excluded driver endorsement under &#xA7; 27-609 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund may cancel a policy if:<section prefix="(i)">the temporary registration issued for the covered vehicle under &#xA7; 13-405 or &#xA7; 23-107(b) of the Transportation Article has expired; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the covered vehicle is not otherwise validly registered in the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The cancellation may not take effect until the day after the temporary registration of the covered vehicle expires.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
