<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-112.2" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-112.2</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Capitated dental provider panel" means a provider panel for one or more dental plan organizations offering contracts only for dental services reimbursed on a capitated basis for certain services.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Carrier" means:<section prefix="(i)">an insurer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a nonprofit health service plan;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a health maintenance organization; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">a dental plan organization.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Enrollee" means a person entitled to health care benefits from a carrier.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Fee-for-service dental provider panel" means a provider panel for one or more dental plan organizations, insurers, or nonprofit health service plans offering contracts only for dental services reimbursed on a full or discounted fee-for-service basis.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"HMO provider panel" means a provider panel for one or more health maintenance organizations.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Managed care organization" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 15-101 of the Health - General Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Non-HMO provider panel" means a provider panel for one or more nonprofit health service plans or insurers.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">"Provider" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 19-701 of the Health - General Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(10)">"Provider contract" means a contract:<section prefix="(i)">between a provider and a carrier, an affiliate of a carrier, or an entity that contracts with a provider to serve a carrier; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">under which the provider agrees to provide health care services to enrollees.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(11)">"Provider panel" means the providers that contract either directly or through a subcontracting entity with a carrier to provide health care services to enrollees.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A provider contract may not contain a provision that requires a provider:<section prefix="(i)">as a condition of participating in a non-HMO provider panel, to participate in an HMO provider panel; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">as a condition of participating in a fee-for-service dental provider panel, to participate in a capitated dental provider panel.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, a provider contract may contain a provision that requires a provider, as a condition of participating in a non-HMO provider panel, an HMO provider panel, or a dental provider panel, to participate in a managed care organization.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to a provider contract for a dental provider panel.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each provider contract shall disclose the carriers comprising each provider panel.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to a provider contract for a dental provider panel.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a provider contract includes more than one schedule of applicable fees, the provider contract may not contain a provision that requires a provider as a condition of participation to accept each schedule of applicable fees included in the provider contract.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">	If a provider rejects a schedule of applicable fees, the provider contract may not require the provider to treat the enrollees of the carriers that reimburse the provider in accordance with any of the rejected schedules of applicable fees.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">	Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (1) of this subsection, a provider contract may include a provision that requires a provider, as a condition of participation, to accept each schedule of applicable fees for a carrier that is not affiliated through common ownership with the entity arranging the provider panel.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a provider elects to terminate participation on a provider panel, the provider shall:<section prefix="(1)">notify the carrier at least 90 days before the date of termination; and</section><section prefix="(2)">for at least 90 days after the date of the notice of termination, continue to furnish health care services to an enrollee of the carrier for whom the provider was responsible for the delivery of health care services before the notice of termination.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A provider contract may not contain a provision that requires a participating dental provider, as a condition of continued participation in a capitated dental provider panel or a fee-for-service dental provider panel, to accept an added, revised, or amended fee schedule that contains a lower fee.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "covered services" means health care services that are reimbursable under a policy or contract for dental services between an enrollee and a carrier, subject to any contractual limitations on benefits, including deductibles, copayments, or frequency limitations.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A carrier may not include in a dental provider contract a provision that requires a dental provider to provide health care services that are not covered services at a fee set by the carrier.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
