<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-125" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-10-125</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Attorney" means an individual admitted to practice law by the Court of Appeals of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Law firm" means an association of attorneys in a law partnership, professional corporation, sole proprietorship, or other business entity who:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Law firm" includes a sole practitioner.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Law firm" does not include:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Title agency" means a business entity, other than a law firm, formed for the primary purpose of soliciting, procuring, or negotiating title insurance contracts and providing settlement services.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Title agency" includes a sole proprietor, partnership, or corporation.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to this section, the Commissioner may issue a limited lines license to an attorney who solicits, procures, or negotiates title insurance contracts to act as a title insurance producer.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">All licensing provisions of this subtitle apply to:<section prefix="(1)">an attorney who solicits, procures, or negotiates title insurance contracts; and</section><section prefix="(2)">title agencies even if the title agency is established or owned by an attorney or an association of attorneys.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">the licensing, bonding, education, experience, and examination requirements of this subtitle relating to title insurance producers do not apply to law firms; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">except as otherwise provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the bonding, education, experience, and examination requirements of this subtitle relating to title insurance producers do not apply to attorneys.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The bonding requirements of this subtitle are applicable to:<section prefix="(i)">an attorney or an association of attorneys who own, operate, or share an interest in a title agency; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">an attorney who is employed by a title agency as a title insurance producer.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
