<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="19-513" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-19-513</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not prohibit a nonprofit health service plan or an authorized insurer, with the approval of the Commissioner, from providing medical, hospital, and disability benefits in connection with motor vehicle accidents.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, a person may not recover benefits under the coverages described in &#xA7;&#xA7; 19-504, 19-505, 19-509, and 19-512 of this subtitle from more than one motor vehicle liability insurance policy or insurer on a duplicative or supplemental basis.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The insurer of a motor vehicle for which the coverage described in &#xA7; 19-505 of this subtitle is in effect shall pay the benefits described in &#xA7; 19-505 of this subtitle to an individual who is injured in a motor vehicle accident:<section prefix="(i)">while occupying the insured motor vehicle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">by the insured motor vehicle as a pedestrian, while in, on, or alighting from a vehicle powered by animal or muscular power, or while on or alighting from an animal.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An insurer may not pay benefits under paragraph (1) of this subsection to an individual who is in violation of &#xA7; 17-103 of the Transportation Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The insurer under a policy that contains the coverages described in &#xA7;&#xA7; 19-505 and 19-509 of this subtitle shall pay the benefits described in &#xA7;&#xA7; 19-505 and 19-509 to an individual insured under the policy who is injured in a motor vehicle accident:<section prefix="(i)">while occupying a motor vehicle for which the coverages described in &#xA7;&#xA7; 19-505 and 19-509 of this subtitle are not in effect; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">by a motor vehicle for which the coverages described in &#xA7;&#xA7; 19-505 and 19-509 of this subtitle are not in effect as a pedestrian, while in, on, or alighting from a vehicle powered by animal or muscular power, or while on or alighting from an animal.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Benefits payable under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be reduced to the extent of any medical or disability benefits coverage that is:<section prefix="(i)">applicable to the motor vehicle for which the coverages described in &#xA7;&#xA7; 19-505 and 19-509 of this subtitle are not in effect; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">collectible from the insurer of that motor vehicle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Benefits payable under the coverages described in &#xA7;&#xA7; 19-505 and 19-509 of this subtitle shall be reduced to the extent that the recipient has recovered benefits under the workers' compensation laws of a state or the federal government for which the provider of the workers' compensation benefits has not been reimbursed.</section>
  </text>
</law>
