<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-31-119</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>119</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Exchange shall be administered in a manner designed to:<section prefix="(1)">prevent discrimination;</section><section prefix="(2)">streamline enrollment and other processes to minimize expenses and achieve maximum efficiency;</section><section prefix="(3)">prevent waste, fraud, and abuse; and</section><section prefix="(4)">promote financial integrity.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Exchange shall establish a full-scale fraud, waste, and abuse detection and prevention program designed to:<section prefix="(i)">ensure the Exchange's compliance with federal and State laws for the detection and prevention of fraud, waste, and abuse, including whistleblower and confidentiality protections and federal anti-kickback prohibitions; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">promote transparency, credibility, and trust on the part of the public in the integrity of its operations.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The fraud, waste, and abuse detection and prevention program shall:<section prefix="(i)">establish a framework for internal controls;</section><section prefix="(ii)">identify control cycles;</section><section prefix="(iii)">conduct risk assessments;</section><section prefix="(iv)">document processes; and</section><section prefix="(v)">implement controls.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Exchange:<section prefix="(i)">shall, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, submit its plan for the fraud, waste, and abuse detection and prevention program to the Senate Finance Committee and the House Health and Government Operations Committee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall allow the committees 60 days for review and comment before establishing the program.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Exchange shall keep an accurate accounting of all its activities, expenditures, and receipts.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before December 1 of each year, the Board shall forward to the Secretary, the Governor, and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly, a report on the activities, expenditures, and receipts of the Exchange.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The report shall:<section prefix="(i)">be in the standardized format required by the Secretary;</section><section prefix="(ii)">include data regarding:<section prefix="1.">health plan participation, ratings, coverage, price, quality improvement measures, and benefits;</section><section prefix="2.">consumer choice, participation, and satisfaction information to the extent the information is available;</section><section prefix="3.">financial integrity, fee assessments, and status of the Fund; and</section><section prefix="4.">any other appropriate metrics related to the operation of the Exchange that may be used to evaluate Exchange performance, assure transparency, and facilitate research and analysis;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">include data to identify disparities related to gender, race, ethnicity, geographic location, language, disability, or other attributes of special populations; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">include information on its fraud, waste, and abuse detection and prevention program.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board shall cooperate fully with any investigation into the affairs of the Exchange, including making available for examination the records of the Exchange, conducted by:<section prefix="(1)">the Secretary under the Secretary's authority under the Affordable Care Act; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the Commissioner under the Commissioner's authority to regulate the sale and purchase of insurance in the State.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
