<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-10-108</section_number>
  <catch_line>An individual applicant who otherwise qualifies for a license for insurance other than life insuranc...</catch_line>
  <order_by>108</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An individual applicant who otherwise qualifies for a license for insurance other than life insurance, health insurance, or annuities is entitled to be examined as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To determine the competence of an individual applicant as to the kind or subdivision of insurance for which the applicant wants to become licensed, the applicant shall pass a written examination that relates to that kind or subdivision of insurance.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner shall adopt reasonable regulations that specify:<section prefix="(1)">the scope, type, conduct, and grading of the written examinations;</section><section prefix="(2)">the frequency, times, and locations within the State where the written examinations will be held; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the educational requirements for an individual applicant to be eligible to take a written examination.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Before taking a written examination, an individual applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">demonstrate to the Commissioner that the applicant has completed the educational requirements set out by the Commissioner; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">submit to the Commissioner at the time of the examination an affidavit from the employer of the applicant stating facts that show compliance with the applicable requirements of &#xA7; 10-104(e)(2) or (3) of this subtitle, if the applicant qualifies by meeting the experience requirements of &#xA7; 10-104(e)(2) or (3) of this subtitle; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">pay the application fee required under &#xA7; 2-112(a)(6)(iv) of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">All written examinations shall be graded within 30 days following the date of the examination.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An individual applicant who fails an examination may not take another examination until at least 14 days after the date of the last examination that the applicant failed.</section>
  </text>
</law>
