<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-467" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-8-467</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A society doing insurance business in the State may not make or allow unfair discrimination between insured members of the same class and equal life expectancy in:<section prefix="(1)">the premiums charged for certificates of insurance;</section><section prefix="(2)">the dividends or other benefits payable on certificates of insurance; or</section><section prefix="(3)">any other terms and conditions of the contracts the society makes.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to:<section prefix="(i)">a society;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a person acting for the society;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an insurance producer that acts on behalf of a fraternal benefit society; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">a person acting for an insurance producer that acts on behalf of a fraternal benefit society.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not offer, promise, allow, give, set off, or pay, directly or indirectly, any valuable consideration or inducement to or for insurance on any risk authorized to be taken by a society that is not specified in the certificate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A society member may not receive or accept, directly or indirectly:<section prefix="(1)">a rebate of all or part of a premium payable on a certificate;</section><section prefix="(2)">a rebate of a fraternal benefit agent's commission on a premium payable on a certificate;</section><section prefix="(3)">any favor, advantage, or share in the dividends or other benefits to accrue on the insurance contract; or</section><section prefix="(4)">any other valuable consideration or inducement not specified in the insurance contract.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
