<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-1642</section_number>
  <catch_line>If the Commissioner determines that a pharmacy benefits manager has violated any provision of this s...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1642</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If the Commissioner determines that a pharmacy benefits manager has violated any provision of this subtitle or any regulation adopted under this subtitle, the Commissioner may issue an order that requires the pharmacy benefits manager to:<section prefix="(1)">cease and desist from the identified violation and further similar violations;</section><section prefix="(2)">take specific affirmative action to correct the violation; or</section><section prefix="(3)">make restitution of money, property, or other assets to a person that has suffered financial injury because of the violation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An order of the Commissioner issued under this section may be served on a pharmacy benefits manager that is registered under Part II of this subtitle in the manner provided in &#xA7; 2-204 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An order of the Commissioner issued under this section may be served on a pharmacy benefits manager that is not registered under Part II of this subtitle in the manner provided in &#xA7; 4-206 or &#xA7; 4-207 of this article for service on an unauthorized insurer that does an act of insurance business in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A request for a hearing on any order issued under this section does not stay that portion of the order that requires the pharmacy benefits manager to cease and desist from conduct identified in the order.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Commissioner may file a petition in the circuit court of any county to enforce an order issued under this section, whether or not a hearing has been requested or, if requested, whether or not a hearing has been held.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If the Commissioner prevails in an action brought under this section, the Commissioner may recover, for the use of the State, reasonable attorney's fees and the costs of the action.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In addition to any other enforcement action taken by the Commissioner under this section, the Commissioner may impose a civil penalty not exceeding $10,000 for each violation of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section does not limit any other regulatory authority of the Commissioner under this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
