<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-19-210</section_number>
  <catch_line>An insurer shall offer at least one actuarially justified premium discount on a policy of homeowner'...</catch_line>
  <order_by>210</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An insurer shall offer at least one actuarially justified premium discount on a policy of homeowner's insurance to a policyholder who submits proof of improvements made to the insured premises as a means of mitigating loss from a hurricane or other storm.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Means of mitigating loss include:<section prefix="(1)">the installation of one or more of the following:<section prefix="(i)">hurricane shutters;</section><section prefix="(ii)">secondary water barrier;</section><section prefix="(iii)">reinforced roof coverings;</section><section prefix="(iv)">braced gable ends;</section><section prefix="(v)">reinforced roof to wall connections;</section><section prefix="(vi)">tie downs; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">reinforced opening protections;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">repair or replacement of:<section prefix="(i)">exterior doors, including garage doors;</section><section prefix="(ii)">hurricane resistant trusses, studs, and other structural components; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">repair or replacement of manufactured home piers, anchors, and tie down straps; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">any mitigation effort that materially mitigates loss from a hurricane or other storm otherwise covered under the policy.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Improvements made to the insured premises under this section shall be inspected by a contractor licensed by the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An insurer shall be allowed to inspect the improvements that are the basis of a premium discount under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Verification of improvements that are the basis of a premium discount under this section rests with the insurer.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An insurer may accept an inspection certificate issued by a governmental agency as verification of improvements that are the basis of a premium discount under this section.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A premium discount offered under this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">comply with the provisions of Title 11 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">only be offered for improvements identified by the Commissioner as qualified mitigation actions made to the insured premises that may materially mitigate loss from a hurricane or other storm otherwise covered under the policy.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An insurer that offers a premium discount under this section shall provide a policyholder with an annual statement regarding the availability of the discount and the method of applying for the discount.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice required under paragraph (1) of this subsection may be sent with the statement required under &#xA7; 19-205 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Commissioner may adopt regulations to implement the provisions of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
