<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-25-401</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>401</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Association" means the Joint Insurance Association.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Association member" means an insurer that is licensed to write in the State, on a direct basis, essential property insurance or a component of essential property insurance in multi-peril policies.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Essential property insurance" means insurance against direct loss to property from the perils of fire, lightning, removal, explosion, windstorm, hail, smoke, aircraft, vehicles, riot, civil commotion, or vandalism as defined and limited in property insurance forms that the Association files with the Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Essential property insurance" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">automobile insurance;</section><section prefix="(ii)">inland marine insurance; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">insurance on property that:<section prefix="1.">is used for fabrication, processing, or assembly of products or components of products;</section><section prefix="2.">has an insurable value in excess of $250,000; and</section><section prefix="3.">is used in a business that employs at least 25 individuals.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Homeowner's insurance" means insurance for residential property that provides a combination of coverages including:<section prefix="(1)">fire;</section><section prefix="(2)">extended coverage;</section><section prefix="(3)">vandalism and malicious mischief;</section><section prefix="(4)">burglary;</section><section prefix="(5)">theft; and</section><section prefix="(6)">personal liability.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Premiums written" means, as computed by the Association, gross direct premiums charged during the second preceding calendar year with respect to property in the State on all policies of essential property insurance and the essential property insurance components of multi-peril policies, less return premiums, dividends paid or credited to policyholders, or the unused or unabsorbed parts of premium deposits.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Premiums written" does not include premiums or parts of premiums relating to risks ceded to the Association.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
