<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-27-210</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>210</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Sections 27-208 and 27-209 of this subtitle may not be construed to include within the definition of discrimination or rebates any of the practices set forth in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For a contract of life insurance or an annuity contract, it is not discrimination or a rebate to pay bonuses to policyholders or otherwise abate their premiums wholly or partly out of the surplus accumulated from nonparticipating insurance, if the bonuses or abatement of premiums is fair, equitable to, and in the best interest of policyholders.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For policies of life insurance or health insurance issued on the industrial debit, preauthorized check, bank draft, or similar plans, it is not discrimination or a rebate to make an allowance to policyholders who have continuously for a specified period made premium payments directly to an office of the insurer or by preauthorized check, bank draft, or similar plans in an amount that fairly represents the savings in collection expense.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">It is not discrimination or a rebate to readjust the rate of premium for a group policy based on the loss or expense experience under the policy, at the end of any policy year, retroactive only for that policy year.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">It is not discrimination or a rebate to reduce the premium rate for policies of large amount, if the reduction does not exceed savings in issuance and administrative expenses reasonably attributable to policies of large amount as compared with policies of similar plan issued in smaller amounts.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">It is not discrimination or a rebate to issue policies of life insurance or health insurance or annuity contracts on a salary savings or payroll deduction plan or other distribution plan at a reduced rate reasonably commensurate with the savings made by use of the plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">It is not discrimination or a rebate to issue policies of health insurance that provide for increases in benefits to policyholders who maintain their policies continuously in force without lapse for specified periods.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "bona fide wellness program" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 15-509 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">It is not discrimination or a rebate for a carrier to provide reasonable incentives to an individual who is an insured, a subscriber, or a member for participation in a bona fide wellness program offered by the carrier in accordance with &#xA7; 15-509 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">	Any incentive offered for participation in a bona fide wellness program:<section prefix="(i)">shall be reasonably related to the bona fide wellness program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">may not have a value that exceeds any limit established in regulations adopted by the Commissioner.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">	The Commissioner shall adopt regulations to implement the provisions of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
