<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-815</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>815</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Mastectomy" means the surgical removal of all or part of a breast.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Reconstructive breast surgery" means surgery performed as a result of a mastectomy to reestablish symmetry between the two breasts.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Reconstructive breast surgery" includes augmentation mammoplasty, reduction mammoplasty, and mastopexy.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to contracts issued by:<section prefix="(1)">insurers and nonprofit health service plans that provide medical and surgical benefits to individuals or groups on an expense-incurred basis under health insurance contracts that are issued or delivered in the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">health maintenance organizations that provide medical and surgical benefits to individuals or groups under contracts that are issued or delivered in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A contract subject to this section shall provide coverage for:<section prefix="(1)">reconstructive breast surgery, including coverage for all stages of reconstructive breast surgery performed on a nondiseased breast to establish symmetry with the diseased breast when reconstructive breast surgery is performed on the diseased breast; and</section><section prefix="(2)">physical complications of all stages of mastectomy, including lymphedemas, in a manner determined in consultation with the attending physician and the patient.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
