<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-31-115</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>115</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Exchange shall certify:<section prefix="(1)">health benefit plans as qualified health plans;</section><section prefix="(2)">dental plans as qualified dental plans, which may be offered by carriers as:<section prefix="(i)">stand-alone dental plans; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">dental plans sold in conjunction with or as an endorsement to qualified health plans; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">vision plans as qualified vision plans, which may be offered by carriers as:<section prefix="(i)">stand-alone vision plans; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">vision plans sold in conjunction with or as an endorsement to qualified health plans.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To be certified as a qualified health plan, a health benefit plan shall:<section prefix="(1)">except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, provide the essential health benefits required under &#xA7; 1302(a) of the Affordable Care Act and &#xA7; 31-116 of this title;</section><section prefix="(2)">obtain prior approval of premium rates and contract language from the Commissioner;</section><section prefix="(3)">except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, provide at least a bronze level of coverage, as defined in the Affordable Care Act and determined by the Exchange under &#xA7; 31-108(b)(8)(ii) of this title;</section><section prefix="(4)"><section prefix="(i)">ensure that its cost-sharing requirements do not exceed the limits established under &#xA7; 1302(c)(1) of the Affordable Care Act; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the health benefit plan is offered through the SHOP Exchange, ensure that the health benefit plan's deductible does not exceed the limits established under &#xA7; 1302(c)(2) of the Affordable Care Act;</section></section><section prefix="(5)">be offered by a carrier that:<section prefix="(i)">is licensed and in good standing to offer health insurance coverage in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the carrier participates in the Individual Exchange's individual market, offers at least one qualified health plan at the silver level and one at the gold level in the individual market outside the Exchange;</section><section prefix="(iii)">if the carrier participates in the SHOP Exchange, offers at least one qualified health plan at the silver level and one at the gold level in the small group market outside the SHOP Exchange;</section><section prefix="(iv)">charges the same premium rate for each qualified health plan regardless of whether the qualified health plan is offered through the Exchange, through an insurance producer outside the Exchange, or directly from a carrier;</section><section prefix="(v)">does not charge any cancellation fees or penalties in violation of &#xA7; 31-108(c) of this title; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">complies with the regulations adopted by the Secretary under &#xA7; 1311(d) of the Affordable Care Act and by the Exchange under &#xA7; 31-106(c)(1)(iv) of this title;</section></section><section prefix="(6)">meet the requirements for certification established under the regulations adopted by:<section prefix="(i)">the Secretary under &#xA7; 1311(c)(1) of the Affordable Care Act, including minimum standards for marketing practices, network adequacy, essential community providers in underserved areas, accreditation, quality improvement, uniform enrollment forms and descriptions of coverage, and information on quality measures for health plan performance; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Exchange under &#xA7; 31-106(c)(1)(iv) of this title;</section></section><section prefix="(7)">be in the interest of qualified individuals and qualified employers, as determined by the Exchange;</section><section prefix="(8)">provide any other benefits as may be required by the Commissioner under any applicable State law or regulation; and</section><section prefix="(9)">meet any other requirements established by the Exchange under this title, including:<section prefix="(i)">transition of care language in contracts as determined appropriate by the Exchange to ensure care continuity and reduce duplication and costs of care;</section><section prefix="(ii)">criteria that encourage and support qualified plans in facilitating cross-border enrollment; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">demonstrating compliance with the federal Mental Health Parity and Addiction Equity Act of 2008.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A qualified health plan is not required to provide essential benefits that duplicate the minimum benefits of qualified dental plans, as provided in subsection (h) of this section, if:<section prefix="(i)">the Exchange has determined that at least one qualified dental plan is available to supplement the qualified health plan's coverage; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">at the time the carrier offers the qualified health plan, the carrier discloses in a form approved by the Exchange that:<section prefix="1.">the plan does not provide the full range of essential pediatric dental benefits; and</section><section prefix="2.">qualified dental plans providing these and other dental benefits also not provided by the qualified health plan are offered through the Exchange.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Exchange may determine whether a carrier may elect to include nonessential oral and dental benefits in a qualified health plan.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A qualified health plan is not required to provide essential benefits that duplicate the minimum benefits of qualified vision plans, as provided in subsection (i) of this section, if:<section prefix="(i)">the Exchange has determined that at least one qualified vision plan is available to supplement the qualified health plan's coverage; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">at the time the carrier offers the qualified health plan, the carrier discloses in a form approved by the Exchange that:<section prefix="1.">the plan does not provide the full range of essential pediatric vision benefits; and</section><section prefix="2.">qualified vision plans providing these and other vision benefits also not provided by the qualified health plan are offered through the Exchange.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Exchange may determine whether a carrier may elect to include nonessential vision benefits in a qualified health plan.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A qualified health plan is not required to provide at least a bronze level of coverage under subsection (b)(3) of this section if the qualified health plan:<section prefix="(1)">meets the requirements and is certified as a qualified catastrophic plan as provided under the Affordable Care Act; and</section><section prefix="(2)">will be offered only to individuals eligible for catastrophic coverage.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A health benefit plan may not be denied certification:<section prefix="(1)">solely on the grounds that the health benefit plan is a fee-for-service plan;</section><section prefix="(2)">through the imposition of premium price controls by the Exchange; or</section><section prefix="(3)">solely on the grounds that the health benefit plan provides treatments necessary to prevent patients' deaths in circumstances the Exchange determines are inappropriate or too costly.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In addition to other rate filing requirements that may be applicable under this article, each carrier seeking certification of a health benefit plan shall:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">submit to the Exchange notice of any premium increase before implementation of the increase; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">post the increase on the carrier's Web site;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">submit to the Exchange, the Secretary, and the Commissioner, and make available to the public, in plain language as required under &#xA7; 1311(e)(3)(b) of the Affordable Care Act, accurate and timely disclosure of:<section prefix="(i)">claims payment policies and practices;</section><section prefix="(ii)">financial disclosures;</section><section prefix="(iii)">data on enrollment, disenrollment, number of claims denied, and rating practices;</section><section prefix="(iv)">information on cost-sharing and payments with respect to out-of-network coverage;</section><section prefix="(v)">information on enrollee and participant rights under Title I of the Affordable Care Act; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">any other information as determined appropriate by the Secretary and the Exchange; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">make available information about costs an individual would incur under the individual's health benefit plan for services provided by a participating health care provider, including cost-sharing requirements such as deductibles, co-payments, and coinsurance, in a manner determined by the Exchange.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) through (5) of this subsection, the requirements applicable to qualified health plans under this title also shall apply to qualified dental plans to the extent relevant, whether offered in conjunction with or as an endorsement to qualified health plans or as stand-alone dental plans.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A carrier offering a qualified dental plan shall be licensed to offer dental coverage but need not be licensed to offer other health benefits.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A qualified dental plan shall:<section prefix="(i)">be limited to dental and oral health benefits, without substantial duplication of other benefits typically offered by health benefit plans without dental coverage; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">include at a minimum:<section prefix="1.">the essential pediatric dental benefits required by the Secretary under &#xA7; 1302(b)(1)(j) of the Affordable Care Act; and</section><section prefix="2.">other dental benefits required by the Secretary or the Exchange.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Exchange may determine:<section prefix="1.">the manner in which carriers must disclose the price of oral and dental benefits and, to the extent relevant, medical benefits, when offered:</section><section prefix="2.">when a carrier offers a qualified dental plan in conjunction with a qualified health plan, whether the carrier also must make the qualified health plan, the qualified dental plan, or both qualified plans available on a stand-alone basis.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In determining the manner in which carriers must offer and disclose the price of medical, oral, and dental benefits under this paragraph, the Exchange shall balance the objectives of transparency and affordability for consumers.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Exchange may:<section prefix="(i)">exempt qualified dental plans from a requirement applicable to qualified health plans under this title to the extent the Exchange determines the requirement is not relevant to qualified dental plans; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">establish additional requirements for qualified dental plans in conjunction with its establishment of additional requirements for qualified health plans under subsection (b)(9) of this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) through (5) of this subsection, the requirements applicable to qualified health plans under this title also shall apply to qualified vision plans to the extent relevant, whether offered in conjunction with or as an endorsement to qualified health plans or as stand-alone vision plans.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A carrier offering a qualified vision plan shall be licensed to offer vision coverage but need not be licensed to offer other health benefits.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A qualified vision plan shall:<section prefix="(i)">be limited to vision and eye health benefits, without substantial duplication of other benefits typically offered by health benefit plans without vision coverage; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">include at a minimum:<section prefix="1.">the essential pediatric vision benefits required by the Secretary under &#xA7; 1302(b)(1)(j) of the Affordable Care Act; and</section><section prefix="2.">other vision benefits required by the Secretary or the Exchange.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Exchange may determine:<section prefix="1.">the manner in which carriers must disclose the price of vision benefits and, to the extent relevant, medical benefits, when offered:</section><section prefix="2.">when a carrier offers a qualified vision plan in conjunction with a qualified health plan, whether the carrier also must make the qualified health plan, the qualified vision plan, or both qualified plans available on a stand-alone basis.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In determining the manner in which carriers must offer and disclose the price of medical and vision benefits under this paragraph, the Exchange shall balance the objectives of transparency and affordability for consumers.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Exchange may:<section prefix="(i)">exempt qualified vision plans from a requirement applicable to qualified health plans under this title to the extent the Exchange determines the requirement is not relevant to qualified vision plans; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">establish additional requirements for qualified vision plans in conjunction with its establishment of additional requirements for qualified health plans under subsection (b)(9) of this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">A managed care organization may not be required to offer a qualified plan in the Exchange.</section>
  </text>
</law>
