<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-10D-01</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>01</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Appeal" means a protest filed by a member, a member's representative, or a health care provider with a carrier under its internal appeal process regarding a coverage decision concerning a member.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Appeal decision" means a final determination by a carrier that arises from an appeal filed with the carrier under its appeal process regarding a coverage decision concerning a member.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Carrier" means a person that offers a health benefit plan and is:<section prefix="(1)">an authorized insurer that provides health insurance in the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">a nonprofit health service plan;</section><section prefix="(3)">a health maintenance organization;</section><section prefix="(4)">a dental plan organization; or</section><section prefix="(5)">except for a managed care organization, as defined in Title 15, Subtitle 1 of the Health - General Article, any other person that offers a health benefit plan subject to regulation by the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Complaint" means a protest filed with the Commissioner involving a coverage decision other than that which is covered by Subtitle 10A of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Coverage decision" means:<section prefix="(i)">an initial determination by a carrier or a representative of the carrier that results in noncoverage of a health care service;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a determination by a carrier that an individual is not eligible for coverage under the carrier's health benefit plan; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">any determination by a carrier that results in the rescission of an individual's coverage under a health benefit plan.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Coverage decision" includes nonpayment of all or any part of a claim.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Coverage decision" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">an adverse decision as defined in &#xA7; 15-10A-01(b) of this title; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a pharmacy inquiry.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Designee of the Commissioner" means any person to whom the Commissioner has delegated the authority to review and decide complaints filed under this subtitle, including an administrative law judge to whom the authority to conduct a hearing has been delegated for recommended or final decision.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Health benefit plan" means:<section prefix="(i)">a hospital or medical policy or contract, including a policy or contract issued under a multiple employer trust or association;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a hospital or medical policy or contract issued by a nonprofit health service plan;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a health maintenance organization contract; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">a dental plan organization contract.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Health benefit plan" does not include one or more, or any combination of the following:<section prefix="(i)">long-term care insurance;</section><section prefix="(ii)">disability insurance;</section><section prefix="(iii)">accidental travel and accidental death and dismemberment insurance;</section><section prefix="(iv)">credit health insurance;</section><section prefix="(v)">a health benefit plan issued by a managed care organization, as defined in Title 15, Subtitle 1 of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="(vi)">disease-specific insurance; or</section><section prefix="(vii)">fixed indemnity insurance.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Health care provider" means:<section prefix="(1)">an individual who is licensed under the Health Occupations Article to provide health care services in the ordinary course of business or practice of a profession and is a treating provider of the member; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a hospital, as defined in &#xA7; 19-301 of the Health - General Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Health care service" means a health or medical care procedure or service rendered by a health care provider that:<section prefix="(1)">provides testing, diagnosis, or treatment of a human disease or dysfunction; or</section><section prefix="(2)">dispenses drugs, medical devices, medical appliances, or medical goods for the treatment of a human disease or dysfunction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Member" means a person entitled to health care services under a policy, plan, or contract issued or delivered in the State by a carrier.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Member" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a subscriber; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">unless preempted by federal law, a Medicare recipient.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Member" does not include a Medicaid recipient.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Member's representative" means an individual who has been authorized by the member to file an appeal or a complaint on behalf of the member.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Pharmacy benefits manager" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 15-1601 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Pharmacy inquiry" means an inquiry submitted by a pharmacist or pharmacy on behalf of a member to a carrier or a pharmacy benefits manager at the point of sale about the scope of pharmacy coverage, pharmacy benefit design, or formulary under a health benefit plan.</section>
  </text>
</law>
