<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-129" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-129</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Aggregate attachment point" means the percentage of expected claims in a policy year above which the medical stop-loss insurer assumes all or part of the liability for losses incurred by the insured.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Carrier" means:<section prefix="(i)">an insurer; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a nonprofit health service plan.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Expected claims" means the amount of claims that, in the absence of medical stop-loss insurance, are projected to be incurred by the insured using reasonable and accepted actuarial principles.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Medical stop-loss insurance" means insurance, other than reinsurance, that is purchased by a person, other than a carrier or a health care provider, to protect the person against catastrophic, excess, or unexpected losses incurred by that person's obligations to third parties under the terms of a health benefit plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Medical stop-loss insurer" means a carrier that is authorized to sell, issue, and deliver policies of medical stop-loss insurance in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Specific attachment point" means the dollar amount in losses attributable to a single individual in a policy year beyond which the medical stop-loss insurer assumes all or part of the liability for losses incurred by the insured.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to each medical stop-loss insurer and each medical stop-loss insurance policy or contract that is delivered or issued for delivery in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Medical stop-loss insurance may only be sold, issued, or delivered in the State by a carrier that holds a certificate of authority issued by the Commissioner that authorizes the carrier to engage in the business of health insurance or to act as a nonprofit health service plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A medical stop-loss insurer may not issue, deliver, or offer a policy or contract of medical stop-loss insurance, if the policy has:<section prefix="(1)">a specific attachment point of less than $10,000; or</section><section prefix="(2)">an aggregate attachment point of less than 115% of expected claims.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A medical stop-loss insurer who offers or issues a medical stop-loss insurance policy that does not meet the requirements of this section shall be subject to the sanctions set forth in &#xA7; 4-113 of this article for authorized insurers and &#xA7; 4-212 of this article for unauthorized insurers.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Nothing in this section shall be construed as:<section prefix="(1)">imposing any requirement or duty on any person other than a carrier; or</section><section prefix="(2)">treating any medical stop-loss insurance policy as a policy of individual, group, or blanket health insurance covering the participants in the underlying health benefit plan.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
