<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-9-231</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "chief executive officer" means a person charged by the board of directors or trust...</catch_line>
  <order_by>231</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "chief executive officer" means a person charged by the board of directors or trustees of an insurer to administer and implement policies and procedures of the insurer.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The provisions of this section that apply to insurers also apply to:<section prefix="(1)">a corporation that operates a nonprofit health service plan under Title 14, Subtitle 1 of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">a dental plan organization, as defined in &#xA7; 14-401 of this article;</section><section prefix="(3)">a surplus lines insurer; and</section><section prefix="(4)">a health maintenance organization.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A chief executive officer shall immediately provide the Commissioner and all members of the board of directors or the trustees of an insurer with written notice that the insurer is an impaired insurer, if the chief executive officer:<section prefix="(i)">knows that the insurer is an impaired insurer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">for a period of 60 days, has been unable to remedy the impairment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A director, officer, or trustee of an insurer who knows that the insurer is an impaired insurer shall immediately notify the chief executive officer of the impairment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notice provided to the Commissioner under this section has the confidentiality specified in &#xA7; 7-106 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a person knows that the action will result in or contribute to an insurer becoming an impaired insurer, the person may not:<section prefix="(1)">conceal property that belongs to the insurer;</section><section prefix="(2)">transfer or conceal property of the person or property that belongs to the insurer in contemplation of a delinquency proceeding;</section><section prefix="(3)">conceal, destroy, mutilate, alter, or falsify a document that relates to the property of the insurer;</section><section prefix="(4)">withhold a document from a receiver, trustee, or other officer of the court entitled to its possession under this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(5)">give, obtain, or receive anything of value for acting or forbearing to act in a delinquency proceeding.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to any other applicable penalty provided in this article, a person that violates subsection (e) of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $50,000 or imprisonment not exceeding 3 years or both.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to any other applicable penalty provided in this article, a person that violates subsection (c) of this section is subject to a civil penalty not exceeding $50,000.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Commissioner may issue a cease and desist order in accordance with &#xA7; 27-103 of this article against a person that violates subsection (c) or subsection (e) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
