<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-11-308</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>308</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If, after a hearing, the Commissioner finds that a rate is not in compliance with &#xA7; 11-306 of this subtitle or that a rate was set in violation of &#xA7; 11-342 of this subtitle, the Commissioner shall issue an order that requires that use of the rate be discontinued for each policy issued or renewed after a date specified in the order.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The order may provide prospectively for premium adjustment of each policy then in force.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, the Commissioner shall issue the order within 30 days after the conclusion of the hearing or within a reasonable extension of that time set by the Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An order issued under this subsection expires 1 year after its effective date unless it is rescinded earlier by the Commissioner.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Pending a hearing, the Commissioner may issue an order that prospectively suspends a rate filed by an insurer and reimposes the last previous rate in effect if the Commissioner has reasonable cause to believe that:<section prefix="(i)">the rate is in violation of &#xA7; 11-306 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">unless the order of suspension is issued, certain insureds will suffer irreparable harm;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the hardship that insureds will suffer in the absence of the order of suspension outweighs the hardship that the insurer would suffer if the order of suspension were issued; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the order of suspension will not cause substantial harm to the public.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless the insurer waives a hearing, the Commissioner:<section prefix="(i)">shall hold a hearing within 15 working days after issuing the order of suspension; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">within 15 working days after the conclusion of the hearing, shall make a determination and issue an order as to whether the rate should be disapproved.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">At a hearing to determine compliance with &#xA7; 11-306(b)(2) of this subtitle, the Commissioner first shall determine whether a reasonable degree of competition exists within a market and shall issue a ruling to that effect.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">All insurers that operate within a market that is subject to a determination by the Commissioner under this paragraph shall have the burden of establishing that a reasonable degree of competition exists within that market.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">In determining the competitiveness of a market, the Commissioner shall consider all relevant factors including:<section prefix="1.">the number of insurers actively engaged in providing coverage in the market;</section><section prefix="2.">market shares;</section><section prefix="3.">changes in market shares; and</section><section prefix="4.">ease of entry.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the Commissioner determines that a reasonable degree of competition does not exist in a market, each insurer designated by the Commissioner shall have the burden of justifying its rate in that market.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Commissioner may require that an insurer file supporting data as provided under &#xA7; 11-312 of this subtitle.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commissioner shall make each determination on the basis of findings of fact and conclusions of law.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the Commissioner disapproves a rate:<section prefix="(i)">the disapproval may not take effect until at least 15 days after the date of the order of disapproval; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">unless the Commissioner approves a rate under subsection (d) or (e) of this section, the last previous rate in effect for the insurer shall be reimposed for a period of 1 year.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">During the 1-year period after the effective date of an order of disapproval, a rate adopted to replace a rate disapproved under the order may not be used until:<section prefix="(1)">the rate has been filed with the Commissioner; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the Commissioner has not disapproved the rate within 30 days after it was filed.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an insurer does not have any legally effective rates as a result of the Commissioner's disapproval of rates or other act, the Commissioner:<section prefix="(i)">on request of the insurer, shall specify interim rates for the insurer that are high enough to protect the interests of all parties; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">may order that a specified part of the premiums be placed in a special reserve established by the insurer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, when new rates become legally effective, the Commissioner shall order the specially reserved funds or any overcharge in the interim rates to be distributed appropriately.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Commissioner may not require refunds to policyholders if the refunds are minimal.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
