<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-919</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>919</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Under any circumstance stated in this section, a carrier or insurance producer of a carrier shall give to a prospective buyer eligible for Medicare by reason of age a written statement as required, for each circumstance, by this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The written statement shall be given before the carrier or insurance producer accepts an application.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the proposed policy excludes or limits benefits for preexisting conditions, a statement shall be given that describes in plain language the limitations or exclusions.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the proposed policy provides coverage for care in a Medicare-approved skilled nursing facility, but the policy does not provide coverage for care in other nursing home facilities or for custodial or rest home care, a statement shall be given that describes clearly those expenses that the policy does not cover.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the proposed policy does not comply with the requirements of &#xA7;&#xA7; 15-904, 15-906, 15-907, and 15-908 of this subtitle for a Medicare supplement policy, a statement printed in 12-point type shall be given that:</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The statement required by paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be printed on or attached to the first page of:<section prefix="(i)">the policy form or certificate; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an outline of coverage delivered to the individual covered under the policy or certificate.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A carrier or insurance producer of a carrier need not provide the statement required under paragraph (1) of this subsection for:<section prefix="(i)">a policy or certificate that is issued in accordance with a contract under &#xA7; 1876 of the federal Social Security Act, 42 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1395mm;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a disability income policy; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a policy or contract of one or more employers or labor organizations or the trustees of a fund established by one or more employers or labor organizations or a combination of employers or labor organizations, for employees, former employees, a combination of employees or former employees, members, former members, or a combination of members or former members of the labor organization.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Commissioner shall adopt regulations necessary to conform this subsection to the requirements of applicable federal law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the proposed policy provides accident-only benefits, a statement printed in 12-point type shall be given that contains the language in subsection (d) of this section and the following:</section>
  </text>
</law>
