<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-14-608</section_number>
  <catch_line>If membership in a discount medical plan or a discount drug plan is canceled within the first 30 cal...</catch_line>
  <order_by>608</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If membership in a discount medical plan or a discount drug plan is canceled within the first 30 calendar days after the effective date of enrollment, all fees, dues, charges, or other financial consideration, except a nominal fee, not to exceed any fees, dues, charges, or other financial consideration the  member has already paid, associated with enrollment costs that were part of the cost of the discount medical plan card or the discount drug plan card, shall be refunded to the payor on return of the discount medical plan card to the discount medical plan organization or return of the discount drug plan card to the discount drug plan organization.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner, in consultation with the Attorney General, shall adopt regulations that establish standards for determining the nominal fee associated with enrollment costs that may be retained by a discount medical plan organization or a discount drug plan organization under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to paragraph (1) of this subsection, any regulation adopted under this subsection shall include a cap on the nominal fee that may be retained.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a discount medical plan organization or a discount drug plan organization cancels a membership for any reason other than nonpayment, the discount medical plan organization or discount drug plan organization shall make a pro rata refund to the payor of all fees, dues, charges, or other financial consideration within 30 calendar days after the date of cancellation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
