<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-301" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-8-301</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Administrator" means a person that, to the extent that the person acting for an insurer or plan sponsor, has:<section prefix="(i)">control over or custody of premiums, contributions, or any other money with respect to a plan, for any period of time; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">discretionary authority over the adjustment, payment, or settlement of benefit claims under a plan or over the investment of a plan's assets.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Administrator" does not include a person that:<section prefix="(i)">with respect to a particular plan:</section><section prefix="(ii)">is retained by the Life and Health Insurance Guaranty Corporation to administer a plan underwritten by an impaired insurer that is subject to an order of conservation, liquidation, or rehabilitation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">is a participant or beneficiary of a plan that provides for individual accounts and allows a participant or beneficiary to exercise investment control over assets in the participant's or beneficiary's account, and the participant or beneficiary exercises that investment control;</section><section prefix="(iv)">administers only plans that are subject to ERISA and that do not provide benefits through insurance, unless any of the plans administered is a multiple employer welfare arrangement as defined in &#xA7; 514(b)(6)(A)(ii) of ERISA;</section><section prefix="(v)">is, or is an employee of, a bank, savings bank, trust company, savings and loan association, or credit union that is regulated under the laws of this State, another state, or the United States; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">is, or is an employee of, a person that is registered as:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Employee organization" means:<section prefix="(1)">a labor union or other labor organization;</section><section prefix="(2)">an agency or employee representation committee, association, group, or plan:<section prefix="(i)">in which employees participate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">that exists for the purpose, wholly or partly, of dealing with employers about a plan or other matters incidental to employment relationships; or</section></section><section prefix="(3)">an employees' beneficiary association that is organized for the purpose, wholly or partly, to establish a plan.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Employer" means a person that, in relation to a plan, acts directly as an employer or indirectly in the interest of an employer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Employer" includes a group or association of employers acting for an employer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"ERISA" means the federal Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Plan" means a fund or other arrangement that is established, maintained, or contributed to by an employer, employee organization, or both, to the extent that the fund or arrangement was established or is maintained for the purpose of:<section prefix="(i)">providing for participants or beneficiaries, any of whom are residents of the State, through the purchase of insurance or otherwise:</section><section prefix="(ii)">providing retirement income to or allowing the deferral of income by employees, any of whom are residents of the State, until or after the termination of covered employment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Plan" does not include a fund or arrangement established or maintained solely for the purpose of complying with the workers' compensation laws of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Plan sponsor" means:<section prefix="(1)">the employer, for a plan established or maintained by a single employer;</section><section prefix="(2)">the employee organization, for a plan established or maintained by an employee organization; or</section><section prefix="(3)">the association, committee, joint board of trustees, or other similar group of representatives of the parties that establish or maintain the plan, for a plan established or maintained by two or more employers or jointly by one or more employers and one or more employee organizations.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
