<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-10A-01</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>01</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Adverse decision" means:<section prefix="(i)">a utilization review determination by a private review agent, a carrier, or a health care provider acting on behalf of a carrier that:<section prefix="1.">a proposed or delivered health care service covered under the member's contract is or was not medically necessary, appropriate, or efficient; and</section><section prefix="2.">may result in noncoverage of the health care service; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">a denial by a carrier of a request by a member for an alternative standard or a waiver of a standard to satisfy the requirements of a bona fide wellness program under &#xA7; 15-509 of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Adverse decision" does not include a decision concerning a subscriber's status as a member.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Carrier" means a person that offers a health benefit plan and is:<section prefix="(1)">an authorized insurer that provides health insurance in the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">a nonprofit health service plan;</section><section prefix="(3)">a health maintenance organization;</section><section prefix="(4)">a dental plan organization; or</section><section prefix="(5)">except for a managed care organization as defined in Title 15, Subtitle 1 of the Health - General Article, any other person that provides health benefit plans subject to regulation by the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Complaint" means a protest filed with the Commissioner involving an adverse decision or grievance decision concerning the member.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Designee of the Commissioner" means any person to whom the Commissioner has delegated the authority to review and decide complaints filed under this subtitle, including an administrative law judge to whom the authority to conduct a hearing has been delegated for recommended or final decision.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Grievance" means a protest filed by a member, a member's representative, or a health care provider on behalf of a member with a carrier through the carrier's internal grievance process regarding an adverse decision concerning the member.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Grievance decision" means a final determination by a carrier that arises from a grievance filed with the carrier under its internal grievance process regarding an adverse decision concerning a member.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Health Advocacy Unit" means the Health Education and Advocacy Unit in the Division of Consumer Protection of the Office of the Attorney General established under Title 13, Subtitle 4A of the Commercial Law Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Health benefit plan" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 2-112.2(a) of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Health care provider" means:<section prefix="(1)">an individual who is licensed under the Health Occupations Article to provide health care services in the ordinary course of business or practice of a profession and is a treating provider of the member; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a hospital, as defined in &#xA7; 19-301 of the Health - General Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Health care service" means a health or medical care procedure or service rendered by a health care provider that:<section prefix="(1)">provides testing, diagnosis, or treatment of a human disease or dysfunction; or</section><section prefix="(2)">dispenses drugs, medical devices, medical appliances, or medical goods for the treatment of a human disease or dysfunction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Member" means a person entitled to health care benefits under a policy, plan, or certificate issued or delivered in the State by a carrier.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Member" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a subscriber; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">unless preempted by federal law, a Medicare recipient.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Member" does not include a Medicaid recipient.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Member's representative" means an individual who has been authorized by the member to file a grievance or a complaint on the member's behalf.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Private review agent" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 15-10B-01 of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
