<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-27-221</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>221</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Carrier" means a person that is:<section prefix="(i)">an insurer that holds a certificate of authority in the State and provides health insurance in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a health maintenance organization that holds a certificate of authority to operate in the State; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a nonprofit health service plan that holds a certificate of authority to operate in the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Health coverage" means any of the following:<section prefix="(i)">a health insurance contract that is issued or delivered in the State by an insurer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a contract that is issued or delivered in the State by a nonprofit health service plan; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a contract that is issued or delivered in the State by a health maintenance organization.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Health status-related factor" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 15-1301 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Individual contract" means a contract between a carrier and an individual covering:<section prefix="(i)">the individual;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the individual and the individual's family members; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the family members of the individual.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Reunderwrite" means to reevaluate any health status-related factor, occupation, hobby, or activity of an individual for the purpose of:<section prefix="1.">terminating health coverage of the individual; or</section><section prefix="2.">moving the individual from a more favorable rate class to a less favorable rate class.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Reunderwrite" does not include:<section prefix="1.">moving an individual from one rate tier to another rate tier solely due to the addition or deletion of a family member under the health coverage;</section><section prefix="2.">increasing the premium under an attained age rated contract solely due to the increasing age of the individual covered under the health coverage;</section><section prefix="3.">on receipt of an application from an insured to increase the benefits under an existing contract, evaluating the health status-related factors, occupation, hobbies, or activities of the insured for the purpose of increasing the benefits under the contract; or</section><section prefix="4.">during the period in which a carrier has the right to contest a policy, denying a claim, amending the policy, making an adjustment to the premium, or rescinding the policy based on a material misrepresentation or fraud in the application.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A carrier may not reunderwrite an individual for health coverage under an individual contract after the individual contract has been issued.</section>
  </text>
</law>
