<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-2-112.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>112.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Carrier" means a person that offers a health benefit plan and is:<section prefix="(i)">an authorized insurer that provides health insurance in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a nonprofit health service plan;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a health maintenance organization;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a dental plan organization; or</section><section prefix="(v)">except for a managed care organization as defined in Title 15, Subtitle 1 of the Health - General Article, any other person that provides health benefit plans subject to regulation by the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Health benefit plan" means:<section prefix="1.">a hospital or medical policy, contract, or certificate, including those issued under multiple employer trusts or associations;</section><section prefix="2.">a hospital or medical policy, contract, or certificate issued by a nonprofit health service plan;</section><section prefix="3.">a health maintenance organization contract; or</section><section prefix="4.">a dental plan.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Health benefit plan" does not include one or more, or any combination of the following:<section prefix="1.">long-term care insurance;</section><section prefix="2.">disability insurance;</section><section prefix="3.">accidental travel and accidental death and dismemberment insurance;</section><section prefix="4.">credit health insurance;</section><section prefix="5.">any insurance, medical policy, or certificate for which payment of benefits is conditioned on a determination of medical necessity made solely by the treating health care provider not acting on behalf of the carrier;</section><section prefix="6.">any other insurance, medical policy, or certificate for which payment of benefits is not conditioned on a determination of medical necessity; or</section><section prefix="7.">a health benefit plan issued by a managed care organization, as defined in Title 15, Subtitle 1 of the Health - General Article.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Premium" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 1-101 of this article to the extent it is allocable to health insurance policies or contracts issued or delivered in this State.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Premium" includes any amounts paid to a health maintenance organization as compensation for providing to members and subscribers the services specified in Title 19, Subtitle 7 of the Health - General Article to the extent the amounts are allocable to this State.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commissioner shall:<section prefix="(1)">collect a health care regulatory assessment from each carrier for the costs attributable to the implementation of &#xA7; 2-303.1 of this title and Title 15, Subtitles 10A, 10B, and 10C of this article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">deposit the amounts collected under paragraph (1) of this subsection into the Health Care Regulatory Fund established in &#xA7; 2-112.3 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The health care regulatory assessment that is payable by each carrier shall be calculated by taking the total costs under subsection (b)(1) of this section multiplied by the percentage of gross direct health insurance premiums written in the State attributable to that carrier in the prior calendar year.</section>
  </text>
</law>
