<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-3-119</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "equity security" means:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>119</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "equity security" means:<section prefix="(1)">stock or a similar security;</section><section prefix="(2)">a security convertible, with or without consideration, into stock or a similar security;</section><section prefix="(3)">a security carrying a warrant or right to subscribe to or purchase stock or a similar security;</section><section prefix="(4)">any other warrant or right to subscribe to or purchase stock or a similar security; or</section><section prefix="(5)">any other security that the Commissioner considers to be of a similar nature and necessary or appropriate to treat as an equity security, based on regulations adopted by the Commissioner in the public interest or to protect investors.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subsections (d), (e), and (f) of this section do not apply to foreign or domestic arbitrage transactions unless those transactions are made in contravention of regulations adopted by the Commissioner to carry out this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subsections (d), (e), and (f) of this section do not apply to equity securities of a domestic stock insurer if:<section prefix="(i)">the securities are registered or required to be registered under &#xA7; 12 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the domestic stock insurer did not have any class of its equity securities held of record by 100 or more persons on the last business day of the year immediately preceding the year in which equity securities of the insurer otherwise would be subject to subsections (d), (e), and (f) of this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner:<section prefix="(i)">may adopt regulations necessary to carry out this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">for the purpose of adopting regulations, may classify domestic stock insurers, securities, and other persons or matters within the Commissioner's jurisdiction.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The provisions of subsections (d), (e), and (f) of this section that impose liability may not be applied to an act committed or omitted in good faith in conformity with a regulation of the Commissioner, notwithstanding that the regulation is later amended, rescinded, or determined by judicial or other authority to be invalid for any reason.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person shall file with the Commissioner, in the form the Commissioner requires, a statement of the amount of all equity securities of a domestic stock insurer of which the person is the beneficial owner within 10 days after the person becomes:<section prefix="(i)">directly or indirectly the beneficial owner of more than 10% of any class of equity security of the domestic stock insurer; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a director or officer of the domestic stock insurer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 10 days after the end of each calendar month in which there has been a change in ownership of securities that are subject to reporting under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the person whose ownership has changed shall file with the Commissioner, in the form the Commissioner requires, a statement indicating the person's ownership at the end of the calendar month and the changes in ownership that have occurred during that calendar month.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The purpose of this subsection is to prevent the unfair use of information that may have been obtained by a beneficial owner, director, or officer of a domestic stock insurer because of that person's relationship to the domestic stock insurer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, any profit realized by a beneficial owner, director, or officer of a domestic stock insurer from a purchase and sale, or a sale and purchase, of an equity security of the domestic stock insurer within a period of less than 6 months inures to and is recoverable by the domestic stock insurer, regardless of the intention of the beneficial owner, director, or officer in entering into the transaction of holding the equity security purchased or of not repurchasing the security sold for more than 6 months.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An equity security acquired in good faith in connection with a debt contracted prior to the 6-month period is not subject to subparagraph (i) of this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A suit to recover any profit obtained in violation of this subsection may be brought in a court of competent jurisdiction by:<section prefix="1.">the domestic stock insurer; or</section><section prefix="2.">the owner of any security of the domestic stock insurer in the name and on behalf of the domestic stock insurer, if the domestic stock insurer fails or refuses to bring the suit within 60 days after a request to do so or fails to prosecute the suit diligently.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A suit under this subsection may not be brought more than 2 years after the date the profit was realized.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">This subsection may not be construed to apply to:<section prefix="(i)">a transaction in which the beneficial owner was not a beneficial owner both at the time of the purchase and sale, or the sale and purchase, of the security involved; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a transaction that the Commissioner exempts by regulation as not within the purpose of this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A beneficial owner, director, or officer of a domestic stock insurer may not sell, directly or indirectly, an equity security of the domestic stock insurer if the person selling the equity security or the person's principal does not own the equity security sold.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A beneficial owner, director, or officer of a domestic stock insurer may not sell, directly or indirectly, an equity security of the domestic stock insurer owned by the person selling the security or the person's principal if the person or the person's principal:<section prefix="(i)">does not deliver the equity security against the sale within 20 days after the sale; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">within 5 days after the sale does not deposit the equity security in the mail or other usual channels of transportation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A person is not considered to have violated this subsection if the person proves that, notwithstanding the exercise of good faith, the person was unable to make the delivery or deposit within the time allowed or proves that to do so would cause undue inconvenience or expense.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The following provisions do not apply to a dealer acting in the ordinary course of the dealer's business and incident to the establishment or maintenance by that dealer of a primary or secondary market, other than on an exchange as defined in the Securities Exchange Act of 1934, for an equity security, except for equity securities held by the dealer in an investment account:<section prefix="(i)">subsection (e) of this section, for any purchase and sale, or sale and purchase, of an equity security of a domestic stock insurer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">subsection (f) of this section, for any sale of an equity security of a domestic stock insurer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">By regulation as the Commissioner considers necessary or appropriate in the public interest, the Commissioner may define and require terms and conditions for:<section prefix="(i)">securities held in an investment account; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">transactions made in the ordinary course of business and incident to the establishment or maintenance of a primary or secondary market.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
