<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-5-305</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>305</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 5-306 of this subtitle and subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, this section applies to:<section prefix="(i)">all individual annuity contracts and pure endowment contracts issued on or after the operative date of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">all annuities and pure endowments purchased on or after the operative date under group annuity contracts and pure endowment contracts.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not apply to any disability or accidental death benefit in a contract.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The operative date of this section is:<section prefix="(i)">January 1, 1979; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the date or dates before January 1, 1979, specified by the insurer in a written notice filed with the Commissioner before January 1, 1979, of the insurer's election of an earlier date or dates.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For an individual annuity contract or pure endowment contract issued on or before June 30, 1980, the applicable table and interest rate for the minimum standard for the valuation of the contract are:<section prefix="(1)">the 1971 Individual Annuity Mortality Table or a modification of that table approved by the Commissioner; and</section><section prefix="(2)">interest at:<section prefix="(i)">6% per year for a single premium immediate annuity contract; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">4% per year for any other individual annuity contract or pure endowment contract.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For an individual single premium immediate annuity contract issued on or after July 1, 1980, the applicable table and interest rate for the minimum standard for the valuation of the contract are:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">the 1971 Individual Annuity Mortality Table;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an individual annuity mortality table adopted after 1980 by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners and approved by regulation of the Commissioner for use in determining the minimum standard of valuation for the contract; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a modification of a table specified by subitem (i) or (ii) of this item approved by the Commissioner; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">interest at 7.5% per year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For an individual annuity contract or pure endowment contract issued on or after July 1, 1980, other than a single premium immediate annuity contract, the applicable table and interest rate for the minimum standard for the valuation of the contract are:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">the 1971 Individual Annuity Mortality Table;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an individual annuity mortality table adopted after 1980 by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners and approved by regulation of the Commissioner for use in determining the minimum standard of valuation for the contract; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a modification of a table specified in subitem (i) or (ii) of this item approved by the Commissioner; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">interest at:<section prefix="(i)">5.5% per year for a single premium deferred annuity contract or pure endowment contract; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">4.5% per year for any other individual annuity contract or pure endowment contract.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">For an annuity or pure endowment purchased on or before June 30, 1980, under a group annuity contract or pure endowment contract, the applicable table and interest rate for the minimum standard for the valuation of the contract are:<section prefix="(1)">the 1971 Group Annuity Mortality Table or a modification of that table approved by the Commissioner; and</section><section prefix="(2)">interest at 6% per year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">For an annuity or pure endowment purchased on or after July 1, 1980, under a group annuity contract or pure endowment contract, the applicable table and interest rate for the minimum standard for the valuation of the contract are:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">the 1971 Group Annuity Mortality Table;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a group annuity mortality table adopted after 1980 by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners and approved by regulation of the Commissioner for use in determining the minimum standard of valuation for the annuity or pure endowment; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a modification of a table specified in subitem (i) or (ii) of this item approved by the Commissioner; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">interest at 7.5% per year.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
