<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-109" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-13-109</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the individual policy or group certificate of credit life insurance, credit health insurance, or credit involuntary unemployment benefit insurance shall be delivered to the insured debtor when the indebtedness is incurred.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the individual policy or group certificate is not delivered to the debtor when the indebtedness is incurred, a copy of the application for the policy or a notice of proposed insurance shall be delivered to the debtor when the indebtedness is incurred.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The application for the policy or notice of proposed insurance shall:<section prefix="(i)">be signed by the debtor;</section><section prefix="(ii)">include:</section><section prefix="(iii)">refer exclusively to insurance coverage; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">be separate from the loan, sale, or other credit statement of account, instrument, or agreement, unless that document sets forth prominently the information required by this paragraph.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the insurer accepts the insurance, within 30 days after the date the indebtedness is incurred, the insurer shall cause the individual policy or group certificate to be delivered to the debtor.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the named insurer does not accept the risk:<section prefix="(1)">the debtor shall receive an individual policy or group certificate that sets forth the name and home office address of the substituted insurer, if any, and the amount of the premium to be charged; and</section><section prefix="(2)">an appropriate refund shall be made if the amount of the premium charged by the substituted insurer is less than the premium set forth in the notice of proposed insurance.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
