<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="31-106" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-31-106</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to any limitations under this title or other applicable law, the Board shall have all powers necessary or convenient to carry out the functions authorized by the Affordable Care Act and consistent with the purposes of the Exchange.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The enumeration of specific powers in this title is not intended to restrict the Board's power to take any lawful action that the Board determines is necessary or convenient to carry out the functions authorized by the Affordable Care Act and consistent with the purposes of the Exchange.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to the powers set forth elsewhere in this title, the Board may:<section prefix="(i)">adopt and alter an official seal;</section><section prefix="(ii)">sue, be sued, plead, and be impleaded;</section><section prefix="(iii)">adopt bylaws, rules, and policies;</section><section prefix="(iv)">subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, adopt regulations to carry out this title:</section><section prefix="(v)">maintain an office at the place designated by the Board;</section><section prefix="(vi)">enter into any agreements or contracts and execute the instruments necessary or convenient to manage its own affairs and carry out the purposes of this title;</section><section prefix="(vii)">apply for and receive grants, contracts, or other public or private funding; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">do all things necessary or convenient to carry out the powers granted by this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless waived by the chairs of the committees, at least 30 days before submitting any proposed regulation to the Maryland Register for publication, the Board shall submit the proposed regulation to the Senate Finance Committee and the House Health and Government Operations Committee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To carry out the purposes of this title or perform any of its functions under this title, the Board may contract or enter into memoranda of understanding with eligible entities, including:<section prefix="(i)">the Maryland Medical Assistance Program;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the family investment unit of the Department of Human Resources;</section><section prefix="(iii)">insurance producers and third party administrators registered in the State; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">any other entities that have experience in individual and small group public and private health insurance plans or facilitating enrollment in those plans.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The operations of the Exchange are subject to the provisions of this title whether the operations are performed directly by the Exchange or through an entity under a contract with the Exchange.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board shall ensure that any entity under a contract with the Exchange complies with the provisions of this title when performing services that are subject to this title on behalf of the Exchange.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may enter into information-sharing agreements with federal and state agencies, and other state health insurance exchanges, to carry out the provisions of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An information-sharing agreement entered into under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">include adequate protections with respect to the confidentiality of information; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">comply with all State and federal laws and regulations.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board, in accordance with Title 12, Subtitle 4 of the State Finance and Procurement Article, shall adopt written policies and procedures governing all procurements of the Exchange.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To the fullest extent practicable, and in a manner that does not impair the Exchange's ability to carry out the purposes of this title, the Board's procurement policies and procedures shall establish an open and transparent process that:<section prefix="(i)">promotes public confidence in the procurements of the Exchange;</section><section prefix="(ii)">ensures fair and equitable treatment of all persons and entities that participate in the procurement system of the Exchange;</section><section prefix="(iii)">fosters appropriate competition and provides safeguards for maintaining a procurement system of quality and integrity;</section><section prefix="(iv)">promotes increased economic efficiency and responsibility on the part of the Exchange;</section><section prefix="(v)">achieves the maximum benefit from the purchasing power of the Exchange; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">provides clarity and simplicity in the rules and procedures governing the procurements of the Exchange.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">To carry out the purposes of this title, the Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">create and consult with advisory committees;</section><section prefix="(2)">have at least two standing advisory committees whose members, to the extent practicable, reflect the gender, racial, ethnic, and geographic diversity of the State; and</section><section prefix="(3)">appoint to the advisory committees representatives of:<section prefix="(i)">insurers or health maintenance organizations offering health benefit plans in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">nonprofit health service plans offering health benefit plans in the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">licensed health insurance producers and advisers;</section><section prefix="(iv)">third-party administrators;</section><section prefix="(v)">health care providers, including:</section><section prefix="(vi)">managed care organizations;</section><section prefix="(vii)">employers, including large, small, and minority-owned employers;</section><section prefix="(viii)">public employee unions, including public employee union members who are caseworkers in local departments of social services with direct knowledge of information technology systems used for Medicaid eligibility determination;</section><section prefix="(ix)">consumers, including individuals who:</section><section prefix="(x)">individuals with knowledge and expertise in advocacy for consumers described in item (ix) of this item;</section><section prefix="(xi)">public health researchers and other academic experts with knowledge and background relevant to the functions and goals of the Exchange, including knowledge of the health needs and health disparities among the State's diverse communities; and</section><section prefix="(xii)">any other stakeholders identified by the Exchange as having knowledge or representing interests relevant to the functions and duties of the Exchange.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
