<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-11-329</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>329</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each workers' compensation insurer shall:<section prefix="(1)">be a member of a workers' compensation rating organization; and</section><section prefix="(2)">adhere to the policy forms filed by the rating organization.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each workers' compensation insurer shall adhere to a uniform classification system and uniform experience rating plan filed with the Commissioner by a rating organization designated by and subject to disapproval by the Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An insurer may develop subclassifications of the uniform classification system on which a rate may be made.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Any subclassification developed under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph shall be filed with the Commissioner at least 30 days before its use.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If the insurer fails to demonstrate that the data produced under a subclassification can be reported in a manner consistent with the uniform classification system and uniform statistical plan, the Commissioner shall disapprove the subclassification.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each workers' compensation insurer shall record and report its workers' compensation experience to a rating organization as set forth in the uniform statistical plan approved by the Commissioner.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the approval of the Commissioner, each rating organization shall develop and file rules reasonably related to the recording and reporting of data under the uniform classification system, uniform statistical plan, and uniform experience rating plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In writing and reporting its business, each workers' compensation insurer shall adhere to the approved rules and experience rating plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An insurer may not agree with another insurer or rating organization to adhere to rules that are not reasonably related to the recording and reporting of data under the uniform classification system or uniform statistical plan.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The experience rating plan methodology required under &#xA7; 11-330(d)(4) of this subtitle shall be based on:<section prefix="(1)">reasonable eligibility standards;</section><section prefix="(2)">adequate incentives for loss prevention; and</section><section prefix="(3)">sufficient premium differentials so as to encourage safety.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the uniform experience rating plan shall be the exclusive means of providing prospective premium adjustment based on measurement of the loss-producing characteristics of an individual insured.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to any premium adjustment allowed under paragraph (1) of this subsection and pursuant to a filing made by a rating organization and approved by the Commissioner, an insurer may file a rating plan with the Commissioner that provides for prospective premium adjustments up to 25% based upon characteristics of a risk that are not reflected in the uniform experience rating plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An insurer may file a rating plan that provides for retrospective premium adjustments based on an insured's past experience.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
