<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-9-225</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>225</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Within 3 years after the date of the issuance of an order of rehabilitation or liquidation of a domestic mutual insurer or domestic reciprocal insurer, the Commissioner may file with the court:<section prefix="(1)">a petition for assessment; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a report that states:<section prefix="(i)">the reasonable value of the assets of the mutual insurer or reciprocal insurer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the liabilities of the mutual insurer or reciprocal insurer to the extent determined by the Commissioner at the time of the report;</section><section prefix="(iii)">as provided in &#xA7; 3-111 of this article, the aggregate amount of any assessment that the Commissioner considers reasonably necessary to pay in full:<section prefix="1.">all claims;</section><section prefix="2.">the costs and expenses of the collection of assessments; and</section><section prefix="3.">the costs and expenses of the delinquency proceeding; and</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">any other information about the affairs or the property of the mutual insurer or reciprocal insurer that the Commissioner considers material.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On the filing and reading of the report and petition specified in subsection (a) of this section, the court ex parte may order the Commissioner to assess all members or subscribers of the mutual insurer or reciprocal insurer who may be subject to assessment, in an aggregate amount as the court finds reasonably necessary to pay in full:<section prefix="(i)">all valid claims that are timely filed and proved in the delinquency proceeding;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the costs and expenses of imposing and collecting the assessments; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the costs and expenses of the delinquency proceeding.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The order shall require the Commissioner to assess each member or subscriber for the member's or subscriber's proportion of the aggregate assessment in accordance with a reasonable classification of the members or subscribers and a formula made by the Commissioner and approved by the court.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The court may order an additional assessment on all members or subscribers who may be subject to assessment on the filing and reading of an amendment or supplement to the report and petition specified in subsection (a) of this section if the amendment or supplement is filed within 3 years after the date of issuance of the order of rehabilitation or liquidation.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">After issuance of an order under this subsection, the Commissioner shall assess each member or subscriber in accordance with the order.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The total of all assessments against a member or subscriber with respect to a policy, whether imposed under this subtitle or another provision of this article:<section prefix="(i)">may not be more than as specified in the policy of the member or subscriber; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall be as limited under this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An assessment may not be imposed against a member or subscriber with respect to a nonassessable policy that is issued in accordance with this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The assessment of a member or subscriber is presumed correct if made by the Commissioner in accordance with a court order that:<section prefix="(1)">fixes the aggregate amount of the assessment against all members or subscribers; and</section><section prefix="(2)">approves the classification and formula made by the Commissioner under subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner shall mail to each member or subscriber at the last address of record with the insurer a notice that:<section prefix="(i)">states the amount of the assessment to be paid by the member or subscriber;</section><section prefix="(ii)">specifies when the assessment should be paid; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">requires payment not less than 20 days after the Commissioner mails the notice.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In a proceeding to collect an assessment, it is not a defense that a member or subscriber failed to receive the mailed notice or failed to receive the notice within the time specified in the notice for payment of the assessment.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a member or subscriber fails to pay the assessment within the period specified in the notice, the Commissioner may obtain an order in the delinquency proceeding that requires the member or subscriber to show cause at a time and place fixed by the court why judgment for the amount of the assessment and all costs should not be entered against the member or subscriber.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A copy of the order and petition for assessment shall be served on the member or subscriber within the time and in the manner designated in the order.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">After service of a copy of the order and petition is made on the member or subscriber:<section prefix="(i)">if the member or subscriber fails to appear at the time and place specified in the order, the court shall enter judgment against the member or subscriber as requested in the petition; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the member or subscriber appears in the manner and form required by law in response to the order, the court shall hear and determine the matter and enter judgment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Commissioner may collect the assessment through any other lawful means.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
