<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-27-802</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>802</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An authorized insurer, its employees, fund producers, insurance producers, a viatical settlement provider, or a viatical settlement broker who in good faith has cause to believe that insurance fraud has been or is being committed shall report the suspected insurance fraud in writing to the Commissioner, the Fraud Division, or the appropriate federal, State, or local law enforcement authorities.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An independent insurance producer shall meet the reporting requirement of this subsection by reporting the suspected insurance fraud in writing to the Fraud Division.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A registered premium finance company shall meet the requirement of this subsection by reporting suspected insurance fraud in writing to the Fraud Division.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to any protection provided under &#xA7; 10-618 of the State Government Article, any information, documentation, or other evidence provided under this section by an insurer, its employees, fund producers, or insurance producers, a viatical settlement provider, a viatical settlement broker, an independent insurance producer, or a registered premium finance company to the Commissioner, the Fraud Division, or a federal, State, or local law enforcement authority in connection with an investigation of suspected insurance fraud is not subject to public inspection for as long as the Commissioner, Fraud Division, or law enforcement authority considers the withholding to be necessary to complete an investigation of the suspected fraud or to protect the person investigated from unwarranted injury.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person is not subject to civil liability for a cause of action by virtue of reporting suspected insurance fraud, or furnishing or receiving information relating to suspected, anticipated, or completed fraudulent insurance acts, if:<section prefix="(1)">the report was made, or the information was furnished to or received from:<section prefix="(i)">the Commissioner, Fraud Division, or an appropriate federal, State, or local law enforcement authority;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the National Association of Insurance Commissioners or its agent, employee, or designee;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a not-for-profit organization established to detect and prevent fraudulent insurance acts or its agent, employee, or designee;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a person that contracts to provide special investigative unit services to an insurer; or</section><section prefix="(v)">a provider of a recognized comprehensive database system that the Commissioner approves to monitor activities involving insurance fraud or an employee of the provider; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the person that reported the suspected insurance fraud, or furnished or received the information, acted in good faith when making the report or furnishing or receiving the information.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
