<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-14-501</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>501</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Administrator" means:<section prefix="(1)">a person that is registered as an administrator under Title 8, Subtitle 3 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a carrier as defined under subsection (d) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Board" means the Board of Directors for the Maryland Health Insurance Plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Carrier" means:<section prefix="(1)">an authorized insurer that provides health insurance in the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">a nonprofit health service plan that is licensed to operate in the State; or</section><section prefix="(3)">a health maintenance organization that is licensed to operate in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Creditable coverage" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 15-1301 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Eligible individual" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 15-1301 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Fund" means the Maryland Health Insurance Plan Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Medically uninsurable individual" means an individual who is a resident of the State and who:<section prefix="(i)">provides evidence that, for health reasons, a carrier has refused to issue substantially similar coverage to the individual;</section><section prefix="(ii)">provides evidence that, for health reasons, a carrier has refused to issue substantially similar coverage to the individual, except at a rate that exceeds the Plan rate;</section><section prefix="(iii)">satisfies the definition of "eligible individual" under &#xA7; 15-1301 of this article;</section><section prefix="(iv)">has a history of or suffers from a medical or health condition that is included on a list promulgated in regulation by the Board;</section><section prefix="(v)">is eligible for the tax credit for health insurance costs under &#xA7; 35 of the Internal Revenue Code; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">is a dependent of an individual who is eligible for coverage under this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Medically uninsurable individual" does not include an individual who is eligible for coverage under:<section prefix="(i)">the federal Medicare program;</section><section prefix="(ii)">unless the individual is eligible for a subsidy of Plan costs provided by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene under a Medicaid waiver program, the Maryland Medical Assistance Program;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Maryland Children's Health Program; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">an employer-sponsored group health insurance plan that includes benefits comparable to Plan benefits, unless the individual is eligible for the tax credit for health insurance costs under &#xA7; 35 of the Internal Revenue Code.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Medicare Part D coverage gap" means the gap in coverage under Medicare Part D:<section prefix="(1)">above the initial coverage limit and before catastrophic coverage begins; and</section><section prefix="(2)">during which an individual enrolled in Medicare Part D is responsible for 100% coinsurance costs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Plan" means the Maryland Health Insurance Plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Plan of operation" means the articles, bylaws, and operating rules and procedures adopted by the Board in accordance with &#xA7; 14-503 of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
