<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-18-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>A carrier may not advertise, market, or offer a policy, contract, or certificate in the State as lon...</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A carrier may not advertise, market, or offer a policy, contract, or certificate in the State as long-term care insurance or long-term nursing home insurance unless the policy or contract complies with this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before a carrier advertises, on television or radio or in writing, a policy or contract of long-term care insurance or long-term nursing home insurance that is offered for sale in the State, the carrier shall submit a copy of the advertisement to the Commissioner for review.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The carrier shall retain each advertisement for 3 years after the date the advertisement first was used.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commissioner may exempt a carrier or a carrier's advertising form or material from the requirements of this section if in the opinion of the Commissioner the requirements may not reasonably be applied.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A carrier that markets long-term care insurance in the State shall:<section prefix="(1)">establish marketing procedures to ensure that any comparison of policies by insurance producers of the carrier will be fair and accurate;</section><section prefix="(2)">establish marketing procedures to prevent the sale or issuance of excessive insurance;</section><section prefix="(3)">establish procedures for verifying compliance with this subsection;</section><section prefix="(4)">provide, to the extent possible, information on any senior citizen counseling program;</section><section prefix="(5)">display prominently on the first page of the outline of coverage and the policy the following:</section><section prefix="(6)">make every reasonable effort to identify whether a prospective applicant:<section prefix="(i)">already has long-term care insurance and, if so, the types and amounts of the long-term care insurance;</section><section prefix="(ii)">had long-term care insurance in force during the last 12 months;</section><section prefix="(iii)">is covered under the medical assistance program; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">intends to replace any existing medical or health insurance coverage with long-term care insurance.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
