<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-11-307</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, each authorized insurer and each rating organizatio...</catch_line>
  <order_by>307</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, each authorized insurer and each rating organization that has been designated by an insurer for the filing of rates under subsection (b) of this section shall file with the Commissioner all rates and supplementary rate information and all changes and amendments of rates and supplementary information made by it for use in the State on or before the date they become effective.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Rates and supplementary rate information need not be filed for inland marine risks that by general custom are not written according to manual rules or rating plans.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An insurer may itself establish rates and supplementary rate information based on the factors in &#xA7; 11-306 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except for workers' compensation insurance rates, an insurer may use rates and supplementary rate information prepared and filed with the Commissioner by a rating organization of which it is a member or subscriber, with average loss factors or expense factors determined by the rating organization or with modification for its own expense and loss experience as the credibility of that experience allows.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If an insurer uses rates and supplementary rate information prepared by a rating organization:<section prefix="(i)">the insurer shall notify the Commissioner that it uses rates and supplementary rate information prepared and filed with the Commissioner by a designated rating organization of which it is a member or subscriber and shall provide the Commissioner with information about modifications of those rates and supplementary rate information that is necessary to inform the Commissioner fully; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">subject to modifications filed by the insurer, the insurer's rates and supplementary rate information shall be those filed periodically by the rating organization, including any amendments to those filings.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each filing and any supporting information filed under this subtitle shall be open to public inspection as soon as filed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On request and payment of a reasonable charge, a person may obtain copies of a filing and any supporting information.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner may investigate and determine whether or not rates in the State are excessive, inadequate, or unfairly discriminatory.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In an investigation and determination under this subsection, the Commissioner shall give due consideration to the factors specified in &#xA7; 11-306 of this subtitle.  </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
