<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="20-602" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-20-602</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The maximum amount payable from the Fund, exclusive of interest and costs, for claims filed under this subtitle arising from one accident is:<section prefix="(1)">$30,000 on account of injury to or death of one individual;</section><section prefix="(2)">subject to the limit specified in item (1) of this subsection, $60,000 on account of injury to or death of more than one individual; and</section><section prefix="(3)">$15,000 for damages to property.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The following deductions shall be made from the smaller of the applicable maximum amount under subsection (a) of this section and the amount of the judgment:<section prefix="(i)">$250 from a judgment or part of a judgment for damages to property; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the total amount that the claimant has received or is likely to receive:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For the purposes of this subtitle, medical, hospital, funeral, or other benefits paid or payable for the applicant under the Maryland Workers' Compensation Act shall be considered to be received or receivable by the claimant.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Fund may recover any amount paid out of the Fund that exceeds the amount authorized under this subtitle by bringing an action against the person that received the excess payment.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any workers' compensation law or similar law to the contrary, whenever the amount of a payment by the Fund has been reduced by the amount of benefits paid or to be paid in accordance with a workers' compensation law or similar law, the employer of an injured person or decedent and the insurer of that employer is not entitled to a lien on payment from the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Workers' compensation benefits may not be reduced because of the reduced payment from the Fund.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
