<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-306" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-5-306</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Change in fund basis" means a valuation basis under which the interest rate used to determine the minimum valuation standard applicable to each change in a fund held under an annuity or under a guaranteed interest contract is the calendar year statutory valuation interest rate for the year of the change in the fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Guarantee duration" means:<section prefix="(i)">for life insurance, the maximum number of years the life insurance can remain in force on a basis guaranteed in the policy or under options to convert to plans of life insurance with premium rates, nonforfeiture values, or both, that are guaranteed in the original policy; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">for an annuity or for a guaranteed interest contract:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Issue year basis" means a valuation basis under which the interest rate used to determine the minimum valuation standard for the entire duration of the annuity or of the guaranteed interest contract is the calendar year statutory valuation interest rate for the year of issue or year of purchase of the annuity or guaranteed interest contract.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to:<section prefix="(1)">all life insurance policies issued on or after the operative date of &#xA7; 16-309 of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">all individual annuity contracts and pure endowment contracts issued on or after January 1, 1983;</section><section prefix="(3)">all annuities and pure endowments purchased on or after January 1, 1983, under group annuity contracts or pure endowment contracts; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the net increase, on or after January 1, 1983, in amounts held under guaranteed interest contracts.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Instead of the interest rates specified in &#xA7;&#xA7; 5-304 and 5-305 of this subtitle, the interest rates used to determine the minimum standard for the valuation of a policy, contract, annuity, or pure endowment, or net increase described in subsection (b) of this section shall be:<section prefix="(1)">for a life insurance policy or an individual annuity contract or pure endowment contract, the calendar year statutory valuation interest rate as determined under this section for the calendar year in which the policy or contract was issued;</section><section prefix="(2)">for an annuity or pure endowment purchased under a group annuity contract or pure endowment contract, the calendar year statutory valuation interest rate as determined under this section for the calendar year in which the annuity or pure endowment was purchased; or</section><section prefix="(3)">for a net increase in an amount held under a guaranteed interest contract, the calendar year statutory valuation interest rate as determined under this section for the calendar year in which the net increase occurred.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For purposes of the formulas under paragraph (2) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">"I" is the calendar year statutory valuation interest rate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">"R1" is the lesser of R and .09;</section><section prefix="(iii)">"R2" is the greater of R and .09;</section><section prefix="(iv)">"R" is the reference interest rate determined under subsection (f) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(v)">"W" is the weighting factor determined under subsection (e) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, the calendar year statutory valuation interest rates shall be determined as provided in this paragraph, rounding the results to the nearest 1/4 percent.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The calendar year statutory valuation interest rate for life insurance is:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The calendar year statutory valuation interest rate for a single premium immediate annuity or for an annuity benefit involving a life contingency arising from another annuity or guaranteed interest contract that has a cash settlement option is:</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Except as provided in subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph, for an annuity or guaranteed interest contract that has a cash settlement option and is valued on an issue year basis:</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The formula for single premium annuities under subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph applies to any other annuity or guaranteed interest contract that does not have a cash settlement option.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The formula for single premium annuities under subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph applies to any other annuity or guaranteed interest contract that has a cash settlement option and is valued on a change in fund basis.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the calendar year statutory valuation interest rate for a life insurance policy issued in any calendar year determined without reference to this paragraph differs from the corresponding actual rate for a similar policy issued in the immediately preceding calendar year by less than 0.5%, the calendar year statutory valuation interest rate for that life insurance policy shall equal the corresponding actual rate for the immediately preceding calendar year.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For purposes of this paragraph, the calendar year statutory valuation interest rate for a life insurance policy issued in a calendar year shall be:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Plan Type A" means a plan type under which:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Plan Type B" means a plan type under which:</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">"Plan Type C" means a plan type under which a policyholder may withdraw funds before the expiration of the interest rate guarantee in a single sum or in installments over less than 5 years:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For the purposes of this subsection, an insurer:<section prefix="(i)">may elect to value annuities or guaranteed interest contracts that have cash settlement options on an issue year basis or a change in fund basis; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall value annuities or guaranteed interest contracts that do not have cash settlement options on an issue year basis.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The weighting factor in the formulas under subsection (d) of this section shall be determined as provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The weighting factor for life insurance is determined based on the guarantee duration of the life insurance as follows:</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The weighting factor for a single premium immediate annuity or for an annuity benefit involving a life contingency arising from another annuity or guaranteed interest contract that has a cash settlement option is .80.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Except as provided in paragraphs (5) and (8) of this subsection, the weighting factor for an annuity or guaranteed interest contract valued on an issue year basis is determined based on the guarantee duration of the annuity or contract as follows:</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Except as provided in paragraphs (5) and (8) of this subsection, the weighting factor for an annuity or guaranteed interest contract valued on a change in fund basis is the weighting factor as determined under paragraph (6) of this subsection, increased by:<section prefix="(i)">for Plan Type A, .15;</section><section prefix="(ii)">for Plan Type B, .25; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">for Plan Type C, .05.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The weighting factor as determined under paragraph (6) or (7) of this subsection shall be increased by .05 for:<section prefix="(i)">an annuity or guaranteed interest contract that is valued on an issue year basis, has a cash settlement option, and does not guarantee interest rates on amounts received more than 12 months after issue or purchase; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an annuity or guaranteed interest contract that is valued on a change in fund basis and does not guarantee interest rates on amounts received more than 12 months beyond the valuation date.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Moody's corporate bond yield average" means Moody's corporate bond yield average - monthly average corporates, as published by Moody's Investors Service, Inc.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"12-month Moody's corporate bond yield average" means the average of Moody's corporate bond yield average over the 12-month period that ends:</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">"36-month Moody's corporate bond yield average" means the average of Moody's corporate bond yield average over the 36-month period that ends:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The reference interest rate in the formulas under subsection (d) of this section shall be determined as provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For life insurance, the reference interest rate is the lesser of:<section prefix="(i)">the 36-month Moody's corporate bond yield average; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the 12-month Moody's corporate bond yield average.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">For a single premium immediate annuity or for an annuity benefit involving a life contingency arising from another annuity or guaranteed interest contract that has a cash settlement option, the reference interest rate is the 12-month Moody's corporate bond yield average.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, for an annuity or guaranteed interest contract that has a cash settlement option, is valued on an issue year basis, and has a guarantee duration greater than 10 years, the reference interest rate is the lesser of:<section prefix="(i)">the 36-month Moody's corporate bond yield average; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the 12-month Moody's corporate bond yield average.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, the reference interest rate is the 12-month Moody's corporate bond yield average for any other annuity or guaranteed interest contract that:<section prefix="(i)">has a cash settlement option, is valued on an issue year basis, and has a guarantee duration of 10 years or less;</section><section prefix="(ii)">does not have a cash settlement option; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">has a cash settlement option and is valued on a change in fund basis.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">If Moody's corporate bond yield average is no longer published by Moody's Investors Service, Inc. or if the National Association of Insurance Commissioners determines that Moody's corporate bond yield average is no longer appropriate to determine the reference interest rate, the Commissioner shall approve by regulation an alternative method adopted by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners to determine the reference interest rate.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
