<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-1004</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1004</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">For services rendered by a person entitled to reimbursement under &#xA7; 15-701(a) of this title or by a hospital, as defined in &#xA7; 19-301 of the Health - General Article, an insurer, nonprofit health service plan, or health maintenance organization:<section prefix="(1)">shall accept the uniform claims form and any attachments approved or adopted by the Commissioner under &#xA7; 15-1003 of this subtitle:<section prefix="(i)">as a properly filed claim with all necessary documentation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">as the sole instrument for reimbursement; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">may not impose as a condition of reimbursement a requirement to:<section prefix="(i)">modify the uniform claims form or its content; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">submit additional claims forms.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A uniform claims form submitted under this section shall be completed properly and may be submitted by electronic transfer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the health care practitioner rendering the service is a certified registered nurse anesthetist or certified nurse midwife, the uniform claims form shall include identification modifiers for the certified registered nurse anesthetist or certified nurse midwife that indicate whether the service is provided with or without medical direction by a physician.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 15-1003(d)(1)(ii) and 15-1005(c) of this subtitle, if the legitimacy or appropriateness of a health care service is disputed, an insurer, nonprofit health service plan, or health maintenance organization may request additional medical information that describes and summarizes the diagnosis, treatment, and services rendered to the insured.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Insurers, nonprofit health service plans, and health maintenance organizations shall provide and update, as appropriate, all contracting providers and any other provider on request, with a manual or other document that sets forth the claims filing procedures, including:<section prefix="(i)">the address where the claims should be sent for processing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the telephone number at which providers' questions and concerns regarding claims may be addressed;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the name, address, and telephone number of any entity to which the insurer, nonprofit health service plan, or health maintenance organization has delegated the claims payment function, if applicable; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the address and telephone number of any separate claims processing center for specific types of applicable services.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an insurer, nonprofit health service plan, or health maintenance organization has delegated its claims processing function to a third party, the delegation agreement:<section prefix="(i)">shall require the claims processing entity to comply with the requirements of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">may not be construed to limit the responsibility of the insurer, nonprofit health service plan, or health maintenance organization to comply with the requirements of this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If necessary to determine eligibility for benefits or to determine coverage, an insurer, nonprofit health service plan, or health maintenance organization may obtain additional information from its insured, member, or subscriber, the employer of the insured, member or subscriber, or any other nonprovider third party.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If obtaining additional information results in a delay in paying a claim, the insurer, nonprofit health service plan, or health maintenance organization shall pay interest in accordance with the provisions of &#xA7; 15-1005(f) of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commissioner may impose a penalty not exceeding $5,000 on an insurer, nonprofit health service plan, or health maintenance organization that violates this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
