<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-201" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-12-201</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual of competent legal capacity may procure or effect an insurance contract on the individual's own life or body for the benefit of any person.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, a person may not procure or cause to be procured an insurance contract on the life or body of another individual unless the benefits under the insurance contract are payable to:<section prefix="(i)">the individual insured;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the individual insured's personal representative; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a person with an insurable interest in the individual insured at the time the insurance contract was made.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With reference to personal insurance, an insurable interest includes only the interests described in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">For individuals related closely by blood or law, a substantial interest engendered by love and affection is an insurable interest.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For the prospective parent of a prospective adoptive child, an insurable interest exists in the life of the child as of the date of the earlier of:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For persons other than individuals closely related by blood or law, a lawful and substantial economic interest in the continuation of the life, health, or bodily safety of the individual is an insurable interest but an interest that arises only by, or would be enhanced in value by, the death, disablement, or injury of the individual is not an insurable interest.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies only to employees with respect to whom the corporate employer or an employer sponsored trust for the benefits of employees is the beneficiary under an insurance contract, if the employer is:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A lawful and substantial economic interest exists in:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies only to a contract or option for the purchase or sale of:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An individual party to a contract or option described in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph has an insurable interest in the life of each individual party to the contract or option.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The insurable interest specified in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The trustee of a trust has an insurable interest in the life of an individual insured under a life insurance policy owned by the trust or the trustee of a trust if, on the date on which the policy is issued:<section prefix="(i)">the insured is:</section><section prefix="(ii)">the life insurance proceeds are primarily for the benefit of trust beneficiaries having an insurable interest in the life of the insured.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">A partnership, limited partnership, or limited liability company has an insurable interest in the life of an individual insured under a life insurance policy owned by the partnership, limited partnership, or limited liability company if, on the date on which the policy is issued, substantially all of the owners of the partnership, limited partnership, or limited liability company are:<section prefix="(i)">the insured;</section><section prefix="(ii)">individuals related closely by blood or law to the insured; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">persons having an insurable interest in the life of the insured.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only to a charitable, benevolent, educational, governmental, or religious institution that is described in &#xA7; 170(b)(1)(A) or &#xA7; 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code, or a trust for the benefit of that institution that is qualified as a pooled income fund under &#xA7; 642(c)(5) or a charitable remainder trust under &#xA7; 664 of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An institution or trust described in paragraph (1) of this subsection may procure or cause to be procured an insurance policy on the life of an individual if:<section prefix="(i)">the institution or trust is designated irrevocably as the beneficiary of the insurance policy; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the application for the insurance policy is signed by the individual whose life is to be insured or the individual's legal guardian.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This subsection does not prohibit the institution or individual from being the beneficiary or owner of the policy or paying the premiums for the policy.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a beneficiary, assignee, or other payee under an insurance contract made in violation of this section receives from the insurer benefits that accrue on the insured's death, disablement, or injury, the insured or the insured's executor or administrator may bring an action to recover benefits from the payee that receives them.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Notwithstanding subsection (b)(4) of this section, a corporate employer with an insurable interest in employees described in subsection (b)(3) or (4) of this section may not retaliate against an employee who refuses to consent to an insurance contract being purchased in the employee's name.</section>
  </text>
</law>
