<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-19-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>An insurer shall provide a policyholder with an annual statement that summarizes the coverages and e...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An insurer shall provide a policyholder with an annual statement that summarizes the coverages and exclusions under the policy issued by the insurer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The insurer's statement shall be clear and specific.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The insurer's statement shall state whether the coverages under the policy provide for replacement cost, actual cash value, or other method of loss payment for covered structures and contents.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The insurer's statement shall include a disclosure that states:<section prefix="(i)">the policyholder should read the policy for complete information on coverages and exclusions;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the policyholder should refer to the declarations page for a listing of coverages purchased;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the policyholder should communicate with the insurance producer or the insurer for any additional information regarding the scope of coverages in the policy;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the statement does not include additional optional coverage purchased by the policyholder, if any;</section><section prefix="(v)">the statement is not part of the policy or contract of insurance and does not create a private right of action;</section><section prefix="(vi)">all rights, duties, and obligations are controlled by the policy and contract of insurance; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">the standard homeowner's insurance policy does not cover losses from flood.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The statement under subsection (a) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">is not part of the policy or contract of insurance; and</section><section prefix="(2)">does not create a private right of action.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner may adopt regulations to implement the provisions of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
