<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-846" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-846</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "cancer chemotherapy" means medication that is prescribed by a licensed physician to kill or slow the growth of cancer cells.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to:<section prefix="(1)">insurers and nonprofit health service plans that provide coverage for both orally administered cancer chemotherapy and cancer chemotherapy that is administered intravenously or by injection under health insurance policies or contracts that are issued or delivered in the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">health maintenance organizations that provide coverage for both orally administered cancer chemotherapy and cancer chemotherapy that is administered intravenously or by injection under contracts that are issued or delivered in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section does not apply to a policy or contract issued or delivered by an entity subject to this section that provides the essential health benefits required under &#xA7; 1302(a) of the Affordable Care Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An entity subject to this section may not impose dollar limits, copayments, deductibles, or coinsurance requirements on coverage for orally administered cancer chemotherapy that are less favorable to an insured or enrollee than the dollar limits, copayments, deductibles, or coinsurance requirements that apply to coverage for cancer chemotherapy that is administered intravenously or by injection.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An entity subject to this section may not reclassify cancer chemotherapy or increase a copayment, deductible, coinsurance requirement, or other out-of-pocket expense imposed on cancer chemotherapy to achieve compliance with this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
