<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="23-208" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-23-208</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the hearing provisions of Title 2 of this article, the Commissioner may deny a registration to an applicant or suspend, revoke, or refuse to renew the registration of a registrant if the Commissioner finds that the applicant or registrant has:<section prefix="(1)">failed to comply with a lawful requirement of the Commissioner under this title;</section><section prefix="(2)">violated a provision of this title;</section><section prefix="(3)">made a material misstatement in the application for registration;</section><section prefix="(4)">engaged in fraudulent or dishonest practices; or</section><section prefix="(5)">demonstrated incompetency or untrustworthiness to engage in the business of a premium finance company.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Instead of or in addition to suspending, revoking, or refusing to renew a registration, the Commissioner may:<section prefix="(i)">impose on the registrant a penalty of not less than $25 but not exceeding $1,000 for each violation of this article, up to a maximum of $20,000 in the event of multiple violations; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">require that restitution be made by a registrant that violates this title to a person that has suffered financial injury as a result of a violation of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of this subsection, restitution means the sum of money that, if paid to a person that suffers financial injury as a result of violation of this title, will restore the person to the same financial position the person would have been in had the violation not occurred.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A premium finance company that delegates administration of a premium finance agreement to a third party is responsible for a violation of any provision of this title by the third party in the administration of the premium finance agreement, regardless of the delegation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of this subsection, the following acts by an insurance producer in relation to a premium finance agreement are not considered to be the administration of the premium finance agreement:<section prefix="(i)">signing a premium finance agreement;</section><section prefix="(ii)">accepting payments; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">issuing receipts.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
