<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-11-404</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>404</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless the Commissioner finds that a filing does not meet the requirements of this subtitle or is otherwise contrary to law, the Commissioner shall approve the filing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">As soon as reasonably possible after a filing is made, the Commissioner shall approve or disapprove the filing in writing.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the Commissioner disapproves a filing, the Commissioner shall specify the ways that the Commissioner finds that the filing fails to meet the requirements of this subtitle or is otherwise contrary to law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a filing is not disapproved by the Commissioner within 15 days after the date of filing, or within 30 days after the date of filing if the Commissioner extends the waiting period in writing during the initial 15-day period, the filing is deemed approved and the effective date of the filing is the end of the 15-day or 30-day waiting period.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner shall hold a hearing to review the approval or disapproval of a filing under this section if:<section prefix="(i)">after approval of the filing, the Commissioner finds that the filing does not meet the requirements of this subtitle or is otherwise contrary to law;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a person with an interest in the filing makes a complaint to the Commissioner in writing that sets forth specific and reasonable causes for complaint; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a title insurer, on notice of disapproval by the Commissioner under this section, requests a hearing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A hearing under this subsection shall be held within 30 days after the occurrence of an action specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commissioner shall give written notice of the hearing to all interested parties.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Commissioner may confirm, modify, change, or rescind any previous action, if warranted by the facts shown at the hearing.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
