<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-103" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-3-103</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A domestic insurer may be formed for insurance purposes under Title 2 of the Corporations and Associations Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A domestic insurer may be formed either as a mutual insurer or stock insurer, as stated in its articles of incorporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each policyholder of a domestic mutual insurer, other than a holder of a reinsurance contract, is a member of the mutual insurer, with each right and obligation of membership.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each policy shall state the provisions of paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any person, government, governmental unit, state, or political subdivision may be a member of a domestic, foreign, or alien mutual insurer.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An officer, stockholder, trustee, or legal representative of a member:<section prefix="(i)">may be recognized as acting in a representative capacity for or on behalf of the member for the purpose of the membership; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is not personally liable on the insurance contract for acting in that representative capacity.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A Maryland corporation may participate as a member of a mutual insurer incidentally to the purpose for which the corporation is organized.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each member of a domestic mutual insurer is entitled to one vote, or to the number of votes the bylaws provide, based on:<section prefix="(i)">the insurance in force;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the number of policies held; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the amount of premium paid.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Only the policyholder under a group policy is a member of the mutual insurer and is entitled to vote at the meetings of the mutual insurer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The board of directors of a domestic insurer shall have at least nine members.</section>
  </text>
</law>
