<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-117" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-3-117</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, an authorized insurer or its subsidiary may not make, directly or indirectly, a loan to a director or executive officer of the authorized insurer unless the loan:<section prefix="(i)">is a bona fide mortgage loan made on a principal residence of the director or executive officer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is approved or ratified by the board of directors of the authorized insurer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A director or executive officer may not accept, directly or indirectly, a loan prohibited by paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An authorized insurer may not make an advance to a director or executive officer of the authorized insurer for future services to be performed more than 1 year after the date of making the advance.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An authorized insurer or its affiliate or subsidiary may not guarantee, directly or indirectly, the financial obligation of a director or executive officer of the authorized insurer, affiliate, or subsidiary.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A guarantee made in violation of this subsection is void.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This subsection does not prohibit an insurer from making or entering into an insurance contract or surety bond that is authorized by its articles of incorporation for a director or executive officer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section does not prohibit a life insurer from making a policy loan to a director or executive officer of the life insurer on a policy or contract of the life insurer in an amount not exceeding the loan value of the policy or contract.</section>
  </text>
</law>
