<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-19-206</section_number>
  <catch_line>An insurer that sells or negotiates homeowner's insurance in the State shall provide an applicant, a...</catch_line>
  <order_by>206</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An insurer that sells or negotiates homeowner's insurance in the State shall provide an applicant, at the time a policy of homeowner's insurance is initially purchased, with a written notice that states that a standard homeowner's insurance policy does not cover losses from flood.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an application is made by telephone, the insurer is deemed to be in compliance with this section if, within 7 calendar days after the date of application, the insurer sends by certificate of mailing the notice to the applicant or insured.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If an application is made using the Internet, the insurer is deemed to be in compliance with this section if the insurer provides the notice to the applicant prior to the submission of the application.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The notice shall:<section prefix="(1)">state that flood insurance may be available through the National Flood Insurance Program or other sources;</section><section prefix="(2)">provide the applicant with the contact information for the National Flood Insurance Program;</section><section prefix="(3)">advise the applicant to confirm the need for flood insurance with the National Flood Insurance Program or the applicant's mortgage lender;</section><section prefix="(4)">advise the applicant to contact the National Flood Insurance Program, the applicant's insurer, or the applicant's insurance producer for information about flood insurance;</section><section prefix="(5)">advise the applicant that flood insurance may be available for covered structures and their contents;</section><section prefix="(6)">advise the applicant that a claim under a flood insurance policy may be adjusted and paid on a different basis than a claim under a homeowner's insurance policy; and</section><section prefix="(7)">advise the applicant that a separate application must be completed to purchase flood insurance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A notice required to be sent by certificate of mailing under this section may be sent with the statement required under &#xA7; 19-207 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A notice provided under this section does not create a private right of action.</section>
  </text>
</law>
