<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-19-804</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>804</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The order of preference for distribution from the Fund shall be as follows:<section prefix="(1)">disbursements from the Rate Stabilization Account to subsidize health care provider rates under &#xA7; 19-805 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">disbursements from the Medical Assistance Program Account sufficient to:<section prefix="(i)">pay for increased rates to health care providers identified under &#xA7; 19-807(c)(2) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">pay managed care organization health care providers identified under &#xA7; 19-807(c)(2) of this subtitle consistent with the fee-for-service health care provider rate increases;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">disbursements to maintain the increase in health care provider reimbursements under &#xA7; 19-807(c)(2) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(4)">disbursements to increase capitation payments to managed care organizations participating in the Maryland Medical Assistance Program consistent with &#xA7; 15-103(b)(18) of the Health - General Article; and</section><section prefix="(5)">disbursements from the Medical Assistance Program Account to:<section prefix="(i)">increase fee-for-service health care provider rates under &#xA7; 19-807 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">pay managed care organization health care providers consistent with fee-for-service health care provider rates under &#xA7; 19-807(c)(3) of this subtitle.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Disbursements from the Rate Stabilization Account to a medical professional liability insurer may not exceed the amount necessary to provide a rate reduction, credit, or refund to health care providers.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Portions of the Rate Stabilization Account that exceed the amount necessary to pay for health care provider subsidies shall remain in the Rate Stabilization Account to be used:<section prefix="(i)">to pay for health care provider subsidies in calendar years 2006 through 2008; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">after the fiscal year 2009 allocation to the Rate Stabilization Account under &#xA7; 19-803(b) of this subtitle, by the Medical Assistance Program Account for the purposes specified under &#xA7; 19-807(c) of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any disbursements from the Rate Stabilization Account to a medical professional liability insurer that is not used to provide a rate reduction, credit, or refund to a health care provider shall be returned to the State Treasurer for reversion to the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A medical professional liability insurer shall reduce the subsidy paid to each health care provider electing to receive a subsidy if the balance of the Rate Stabilization Account is insufficient to pay health care provider subsidies.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Notwithstanding subsection (c) of this section or any other provision of law, in fiscal year 2009, $83,275,000 of the balance remaining in the Rate Stabilization Account at the end of fiscal year 2008 shall be transferred as follows:<section prefix="(1)">$7,000,000 to the Medical Assistance Program Account, to be used by the Secretary to increase fee-for-service provider rates to dentists in fiscal year 2009;</section><section prefix="(2)">$3,000,000 to the Health Care Coverage Fund established under Title 15, Subtitle 7 of the Health - General Article, to be used for allowable expenses in fiscal year 2009; and</section><section prefix="(3)">$73,275,000 to the Health Care Coverage Fund established under Title 15, Subtitle 7 of the Health - General Article, to be used for allowable expenses in fiscal year 2010 and fiscal year 2011.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
