<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-8-428</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "eligible children" means children under the minimum age for adult membership but n...</catch_line>
  <order_by>428</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "eligible children" means children under the minimum age for adult membership but not more than 18 years old at the time of application.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A society may provide for benefits on the lives of eligible children:<section prefix="(1)">in accordance with &#xA7; 8-427 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">in accordance with the laws or rules of the society; and</section><section prefix="(3)">on application of an adult.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A society may organize and operate branches for eligible children.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A society may not require eligible children to be members of or be initiated in a local lodge.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Eligible children may not participate in the management of the society.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On obtaining the minimum age for adult beneficial membership under the laws of the society, eligible children insured under certificates issued under this section shall be transferred to and become members of the adult branch of the society if the children otherwise meet the eligibility requirements of the society.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a child fails to meet the adult eligibility requirements of the society, the transfer is effective only as to the child's insurance account.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A society may provide for:<section prefix="(1)">the designation and changing of designation of beneficiaries in certificates;</section><section prefix="(2)">the regulation of certificates; and</section><section prefix="(3)">all rights, obligations, and liabilities incident to the certificates.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
