<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-7-703</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "material transaction" includes:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>703</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "material transaction" includes:<section prefix="(1)">an asset change, determined as of the December 31 immediately preceding a transaction involving an insurer, that exceeds in value the lesser of:<section prefix="(i)">5% of the insurer's surplus as regards policyholders; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the net gain from operations of a life insurer, or the net investment income of an insurer other than a life insurer; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">any other transaction specified by regulation to be a material transaction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Before a domestic insurer and another member of the same insurance holding company system enter into any of the transactions specified in subsection (e) of this section, the domestic insurer shall notify the Commissioner in writing of its intention to enter into the transaction.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The insurer shall notify the Commissioner under subsection (b) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">at least 30 days before the transaction is to be entered into; or</section><section prefix="(2)">if the Commissioner allows a shorter notice period, within the time that the Commissioner sets.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A domestic insurer and another member of the same insurance holding company system may enter into a transaction under this section only if, within the notice period under subsection (c) of this section, the Commissioner does not disapprove the transaction.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The following transactions are subject to subsections (b), (c), and (d) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">a sale, purchase, exchange, loan, extension of credit, guarantee, or investment, if, as of the December 31 immediately preceding the transaction, the amount of the transaction equals or exceeds:<section prefix="(i)">with respect to a life insurer, 3% of the insurer's admitted assets; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">with respect to an insurer other than a life insurer, the lesser of 3% of the insurer's admitted assets and 25% of surplus as regards policyholders;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">a loan or extension of credit by an insurer to a person that is not an affiliate if:<section prefix="(i)">the parties have an agreement or understanding that the proceeds of the transaction, as a whole or in substantial part, are to be used to make loans or extensions of credit to purchase assets of or to make investments in an affiliate of the insurer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">as of the December 31 immediately preceding the transaction, the amount of the transaction equals or exceeds:<section prefix="1.">with respect to a life insurer, 3% of the insurer's admitted assets; and</section><section prefix="2.">with respect to an insurer other than a life insurer, the lesser of 3% of the insurer's admitted assets and 25% of surplus as regards policyholders;</section></section></section><section prefix="(3)">a reinsurance agreement, or a modification to a reinsurance agreement, including an agreement that requires as consideration the transfer of assets from an insurer to a person that is not its affiliate, if:<section prefix="(i)">the parties have an agreement or understanding that part of the insurer's assets will be transferred to an affiliate of the insurer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">as of the December 31 immediately preceding the transaction, the amount of the reinsurance premium or change in the insurer's liabilities equals or exceeds 5% of the insurer's surplus as regards policyholders;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">a management agreement, service contract, or cost-sharing arrangement; and</section><section prefix="(5)">a material transaction that the Commissioner determines may adversely affect the interests of the insurer's policyholders.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In reviewing transactions under subsection (e) of this section, the Commissioner shall consider whether a transaction:<section prefix="(1)">complies with the standards stated in &#xA7; 7-702 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">potentially adversely affects the interests of policyholders.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A material transaction that does not conform to this section is a violation of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to the sanctions in &#xA7;&#xA7; 7-802, 7-803, 7-805, and 7-807 of this title, the Commissioner may set aside and rescind a material transaction that the Commissioner finds does not conform to this section at the initiative of the Commissioner or otherwise under applicable law.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Within 90 days after the date that the Commissioner receives information about the material transaction, the Commissioner shall give the insurer notice of the proposed action to set aside or rescind the material transaction and an opportunity for a hearing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A domestic insurer and another member of the same insurance holding company system may not enter into a transaction that is part of a plan or series of like transactions if the purpose of making separate transactions is to avoid exceeding limitations under this section and the review of the transaction that otherwise would occur.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Commissioner determines that separate transactions were entered into during any 12-month period in violation of paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Commissioner may impose any sanction authorized by &#xA7;&#xA7; 7-802, 7-803, 7-805, and 7-807 of this title.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
