<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-1501</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1501</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Commission" means the Maryland Health Care Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Mandated health insurance service" means a legislative proposal or statute that would require a particular health care service to be provided or offered in a health benefit plan, by a carrier or other organization authorized to provide health benefit plans in the State.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Mandated health insurance service", as applicable to all carriers, does not include services enumerated to describe a health maintenance organization under &#xA7; 19-701(g)(2) of the Health - General Article.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This subtitle does not affect the ability of the General Assembly to enact legislation on mandated health insurance services.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall assess the social, medical, and financial impacts of a proposed mandated health insurance service.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In assessing a proposed mandated health insurance service and to the extent that information is available, the Commission shall consider:<section prefix="(i)">social impacts, including:<section prefix="1.">the extent to which the service is generally utilized by a significant portion of the population;</section><section prefix="2.">the extent to which the insurance coverage is already generally available;</section><section prefix="3.">if coverage is not generally available, the extent to which the lack of coverage results in individuals avoiding necessary health care treatments;</section><section prefix="4.">if coverage is not generally available, the extent to which the lack of coverage results in unreasonable financial hardship;</section><section prefix="5.">the level of public demand for the service;</section><section prefix="6.">the level of public demand for insurance coverage of the service;</section><section prefix="7.">the level of interest of collective bargaining agents in negotiating privately for inclusion of this coverage in group contracts; and</section><section prefix="8.">the extent to which the mandated health insurance service is covered by self-funded employer groups of employers in the State who employ at least 500 employees;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">medical impacts, including:<section prefix="1.">the extent to which the service is generally recognized by the medical community as being effective and efficacious in the treatment of patients;</section><section prefix="2.">the extent to which the service is generally recognized by the medical community as demonstrated by a review of scientific and peer review literature; and</section><section prefix="3.">the extent to which the service is generally available and utilized by treating physicians; and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">financial impacts, including:<section prefix="1.">the extent to which the coverage will increase or decrease the cost of the service;</section><section prefix="2.">the extent to which the coverage will increase the appropriate use of the service;</section><section prefix="3.">the extent to which the mandated service will be a substitute for a more expensive service;</section><section prefix="4.">the extent to which the coverage will increase or decrease the administrative expenses of insurers and the premium and administrative expenses of policy holders;</section><section prefix="5.">the impact of this coverage on the total cost of health care; and</section><section prefix="6.">the impact of all mandated health insurance services on employers' ability to purchase health benefits policies meeting their employees' needs.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Subject to the limitations of the State budget, the Commission may contract for actuarial services and other professional services to carry out the provisions of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before December 31, 1998, and each December 31 thereafter, the Commission shall submit a report on its findings, including any recommendations, to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual report prepared by the Commission shall include an evaluation of any mandated health insurance service legislatively proposed or otherwise submitted to the Commission by a member of the General Assembly prior to July 1 of that year.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
