<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-123" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-123</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Carrier" means:<section prefix="(i)">an insurer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a nonprofit health service plan;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a health maintenance organization;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a dental plan organization;</section><section prefix="(v)">any person or entity acting as a third party administrator; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">except for a managed care organization as defined in Title 15, Subtitle 1 of the Health - General Article, any other person that provides health benefit plans subject to regulation by the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Contract" means any written agreement between a provider and a carrier for the provider to render health care services to enrollees of the carrier.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Diagnostic services" means any medical or surgical service or procedure that allows a provider to identify or diagnose a human disease or disorder.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Enrollee" means any person or subscriber entitled to health care benefits from a carrier.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Health care services" means a health or medical care procedure or service rendered by a provider that:<section prefix="(i)">provides testing, diagnosis, or treatment of a human disease or dysfunction; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">dispenses drugs, medical devices, medical appliances, or medical goods for the treatment of a human disease or dysfunction.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Provider" means a person or entity licensed, certified, or otherwise authorized under the Health Occupations Article or the Health - General Article to provide health care services.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Provider" includes:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Therapeutic services" means any medical or surgical service or procedure that a provider can use to treat a human disease or disorder.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to any carrier that provides health care services to enrollees or otherwise makes health care services available to enrollees through contracts with providers.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The section does not:<section prefix="(1)">apply to any cosmetic or medically unnecessary service or procedure that typically would be excluded from coverage by any carrier that issues or delivers contracts or policies of health insurance in the State; or</section><section prefix="(2)">affect the right of an enrollee to appeal any adverse decision by a carrier through the carrier's appeal process.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each carrier shall disclose to providers and enrollees the carrier's definition of "experimental medical care".</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The carrier shall disclose the definition in:<section prefix="(i)">contracts offered to providers that may render direct health care services to the enrollees of the carrier; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">marketing materials and enrollment materials of the carrier that are provided to current enrollees and prospective enrollees, as appropriate.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each carrier shall establish or subscribe or contract to provide a systematic, scientific process to follow for evaluating emerging medical and surgical treatments to ensure that subscribers have access to the latest appropriate treatments.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The process established or subscribed to or contracted for by a carrier under subsection (e) of this section shall include:<section prefix="(1)">a comprehensive review of medical literature and data evaluation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">input from physicians and other recognized experts:<section prefix="(i)">who are not employees of the carrier; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">who:</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A carrier's decision to provide coverage for an emerging medical or surgical treatment shall result from the consensus of opinion from its own analysis and the knowledge provided to the carrier from the process identified by the carrier in subsection (f) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Each carrier, in conjunction with the clinical experts identified by the carrier under subsection (f)(2) of this section, shall decide the patient selection criteria for an emerging medical or surgical treatment for which coverage by the carrier is to be provided.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Each carrier shall provide a description of the process identified by the carrier under subsection (f) of this section to enrollees and contracting providers and all other providers on request.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A carrier's coverage decision on an emerging medical or surgical treatment shall be in compliance with &#xA7; 15-10B-07 of this title, when being appealed by an enrollee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A carrier may reevaluate annually whether scientific advances warrant a change in the carrier's coverage and payment policy for an emerging medical or surgical treatment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each carrier shall file annually with the Commissioner a summary description of the clinical issues and diagnostic and therapeutic services that were evaluated and the conclusion of the evaluation, including the opinions of the clinical experts.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner shall:<section prefix="(i)">make each carrier's filing under paragraph (1) of this subsection available to the public for inspection and review; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">provide a copy of a carrier's filing under paragraph (1) of this subsection to any person upon request in a timely manner and at a reasonable cost to the person.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">After notifying a carrier and providing an opportunity for a hearing, the Commissioner may issue an order under &#xA7; 4-113(d) of this article for a violation of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner may waive the application of subsection (f) of this section for a carrier that has in place a process for evaluating emerging medical and surgical treatments used for the purpose of making coverage decisions, if the Commissioner determines that the carrier's process is substantially equivalent to, or exceeds, the requirements of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A carrier receiving a waiver under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall report any change in its process for evaluating emerging medical and surgical treatments to the Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commissioner may withdraw a waiver granted under paragraph (1) of this subsection whenever the Commissioner determines that the carrier's process for evaluating emerging medical and surgical treatments is not substantially equivalent to the requirements of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">The Commissioner may adopt regulations to carry out this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
