<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-20-404</section_number>
  <catch_line>On or before March 15 of each year, the Fund shall determine and the Board of Trustees shall certify...</catch_line>
  <order_by>404</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">On or before March 15 of each year, the Fund shall determine and the Board of Trustees shall certify to the Board of Directors the information required under subsections (b) and (c) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to subsection (f) of this section, the following information certified to the Board of Directors shall be separately identified by commercial auto and private passenger auto results:<section prefix="(1)">the statutory operating loss for the immediately preceding calendar year;</section><section prefix="(2)">a calculation to yield a private passenger auto assessment limit that is determined by subtracting the year-end total surplus of the Fund for the immediately preceding calendar year from an amount equal to 25% of the average of net direct written private passenger auto premiums of the Fund for each of the three immediately preceding calendar years; and</section><section prefix="(3)">a calculation to yield a commercial auto assessment limit that is determined by subtracting the year-end commercial auto surplus of the Fund for the immediately preceding calendar year from an amount equal to 25% of the average of net direct written commercial auto premiums of the Fund for each of the 3 immediately preceding calendar years.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The assessment certified to the Board of Directors shall be equal to:<section prefix="(1)">subject to subsection (d) of this section, the assessment limit, if the assessment limit is less than or equal to the statutory operating loss; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the statutory operating loss, if the assessment limit is greater than the statutory operating loss.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the calculation under subsection (b)(2) of this section yields a number that is less than or equal to zero, the assessment limit is zero.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The statutory operating loss or assessment certified to the Board of Directors may not include:<section prefix="(1)">assessment moneys received for a prior year; or</section><section prefix="(2)">moneys transferred between the commercial auto and private passenger auto divisions within the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In a calculation made under this section, income or expenses not clearly attributable to either commercial auto or private passenger auto may be allocated pro rata for that year.</section>
  </text>
</law>
