<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-215" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-2-215</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An appeal under this subtitle may be taken only from:<section prefix="(1)">an order resulting from a hearing;</section><section prefix="(2)">a refusal by the Commissioner to grant a hearing; or</section><section prefix="(3)">a decision issued under &#xA7; 15-10A-04 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An appeal under this subtitle may be taken by:<section prefix="(1)">a party to the hearing;</section><section prefix="(2)">an aggrieved person whose financial interests are directly affected by the order resulting from a hearing or refusal to grant a hearing; or</section><section prefix="(3)">a party to the decision issued under &#xA7; 15-10A-04 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, an appeal under this subtitle shall be taken:<section prefix="(i)">to the Circuit Court for Baltimore City; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if a party to an appeal is an individual, to the circuit court of the county where the individual resides.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the appeal is from the suspension or revocation of a certificate of authority of a domestic insurer or license of an insurance producer, adviser, or public adjuster, an appeal may be taken to the circuit court of the county where:<section prefix="(i)">the domestic insurer has its principal place of business; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the licensee or certificate holder resides.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">To take an appeal, a person shall file a petition for judicial review with the appropriate circuit court within 30 days after:<section prefix="(1)">the order resulting from the hearing was served on the persons entitled to receive it;</section><section prefix="(2)">the order of the Commissioner denying rehearing or reargument was served on the persons entitled to receive it;</section><section prefix="(3)">the refusal of the Commissioner to grant a hearing; or</section><section prefix="(4)">the decision issued under &#xA7; 15-10A-04 of this article was served on the persons entitled to receive it.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An appeal under this subtitle shall be captioned in accordance with the Maryland Rules.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On application to the court, any person may be added as a party, as the court directs, if:<section prefix="(i)">the financial interests of the person are or may be directly affected by the matter on appeal; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the person may be aggrieved by the matter on appeal.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">When a petition for judicial review is filed with the appropriate court, the court has jurisdiction over the case and shall determine whether the filing operates as a stay of the order or action from which the appeal is taken.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In an appeal of an order resulting from a hearing, after receiving a copy of the petition for judicial review and within the time specified in the Maryland Rules, the Commissioner shall file in the court in which the appeal is pending:<section prefix="(i)">a copy of the order of the Commissioner from which the appeal is taken;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a complete transcript, certified by the Commissioner, of the record on which the order was issued; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">all exhibits and documentary evidence introduced at the hearing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In an appeal of a refusal by the Commissioner to grant a hearing, within the time specified in the Maryland Rules, the Commissioner shall file in the court in which the appeal is pending certified copies of all documents on file with the Commissioner that directly relate to the matter on appeal.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In an appeal of a decision issued under &#xA7; 15-10A-04 of this article, after receiving a copy of the petition for judicial review and within the time specified in the Maryland Rules, the Commissioner shall file in the court in which the appeal is pending:<section prefix="(i)">a copy of the decision of the Commissioner from which the appeal is taken;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a copy of the report of the independent review organization or medical expert; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">all documentary evidence provided to the Commissioner and the independent review organization or medical expert that directly relates to the matter on appeal.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The court to which an appeal is taken may:<section prefix="(1)">affirm the decision of the Commissioner;</section><section prefix="(2)">remand the case for further proceedings; or</section><section prefix="(3)">reverse or modify the decision of the Commissioner if substantial rights of the petitioners may have been prejudiced because administrative findings, inferences, conclusions, or decisions:<section prefix="(i)">violate constitutional provisions;</section><section prefix="(ii)">exceed the statutory authority or jurisdiction of the Commissioner;</section><section prefix="(iii)">are made by unlawful procedure;</section><section prefix="(iv)">are affected by other error of law;</section><section prefix="(v)">are unsupported by competent, material, and substantial evidence in view of the entire record, as submitted; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">are arbitrary or capricious.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Costs of an appeal shall be awarded as in civil actions.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any party, including the Commissioner, may appeal from the judgment of the circuit court to the Court of Special Appeals as in other civil cases.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The judgment of the circuit court may be stayed only by order of court on the giving of any security that the court considers proper.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
