<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-1209</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section does not apply to any insurance enumerated in &#xA7; 15-1201(f)(3)(i) through (xiii) of thi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1209</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to any insurance enumerated in &#xA7; 15-1201(f)(3)(i) through (xiii) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A carrier shall issue its health benefit plans to each small employer that meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Nothing in this subsection requires a small employer to contribute to the premium payments for coverage of a dependent of an eligible employee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To be covered under a health benefit plan offered by a carrier, a small employer shall:<section prefix="(i)">elect to be covered;</section><section prefix="(ii)">agree to pay the premiums;</section><section prefix="(iii)">agree to offer coverage to any dependent of an eligible employee when coverage is sought by the eligible employee, in accordance with provisions governing late enrollees and any other provisions of this subtitle that apply to coverage;</section><section prefix="(iv)">agree to collect payments for premiums through payroll deductions for coverage of eligible employees and dependents and transmit those payments to the carrier; and</section><section prefix="(v)">satisfy other reasonable provisions of the health benefit plan as approved by the Commissioner.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In determining whether a small employer satisfies the requirements of this section, a carrier shall apply its requirements uniformly among all small employers with the same number of eligible employees who apply for or receive coverage from the carrier, including a requirement that a minimum percentage of eligible employees of the small employer participate in the health benefit plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A carrier may vary application of minimum participation of eligible employees only by the size of the group of the small employer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A carrier may not require a small employer to contribute to payment of premiums for a health benefit plan.</section>
  </text>
</law>
