<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-810</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies to:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>810</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to:<section prefix="(1)">insurers and nonprofit health service plans that provide hospital, medical, or surgical benefits to individuals or groups on an expense-incurred basis under health insurance policies that are issued or delivered in the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">health maintenance organizations that provide hospital, medical, or surgical benefits to individuals or groups under contracts that are issued or delivered in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An entity subject to this section that provides pregnancy-related benefits may not exclude benefits for all outpatient expenses arising from in vitro fertilization procedures performed on the policyholder or subscriber or dependent spouse of the policyholder or subscriber.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The benefits under this subsection shall be provided:<section prefix="(i)">for insurers and nonprofit health service plans, to the same extent as the benefits provided for other pregnancy-related procedures; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">for health maintenance organizations, to the same extent as the benefits provided for other infertility services.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subsection (b) of this section applies if:<section prefix="(1)">the patient is the policyholder or subscriber or a covered dependent of the policyholder or subscriber;</section><section prefix="(2)">the patient's oocytes are fertilized with the patient's spouse's sperm;</section><section prefix="(3)"><section prefix="(i)">the patient and the patient's spouse have a history of infertility of at least 2 years' duration; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the infertility is associated with any of the following medical conditions:<section prefix="1.">endometriosis;</section><section prefix="2.">exposure in utero to diethylstilbestrol, commonly known as DES;</section><section prefix="3.">blockage of, or surgical removal of, one or both fallopian tubes (lateral or bilateral salpingectomy); or</section><section prefix="4.">abnormal male factors, including oligospermia, contributing to the infertility;</section></section></section><section prefix="(4)">the patient has been unable to attain a successful pregnancy through a less costly infertility treatment for which coverage is available under the policy or contract; and</section><section prefix="(5)">the in vitro fertilization procedures are performed at medical facilities that conform to the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists guidelines for in vitro fertilization clinics or to the American Fertility Society minimal standards for programs of in vitro fertilization.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An entity subject to this section may limit coverage of the benefits required under this section to three in vitro fertilization attempts per live birth, not to exceed a maximum lifetime benefit of $100,000.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, if the coverage required under this section conflicts with the bona fide religious beliefs and practices of a religious organization, on request of the religious organization, an entity subject to this section shall exclude the coverage otherwise required under this section in a policy or contract with the religious organization.</section>
  </text>
</law>
