<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-105</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>105</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Breast implant" means a pocket or envelope that is surgically inserted under the skin and contains soft silicone gel, saline solution, or a combination of soft silicone gel and saline solution.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Breast implant-related condition" means a condition that the federal Food and Drug Administration recognizes as possibly linked to breast implants.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to:<section prefix="(1)">insurers and nonprofit health service plans that provide hospital, medical, or surgical benefits to individuals or groups on an expense-incurred basis under health insurance policies that are issued or delivered in the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">health maintenance organizations that provide hospital, medical, or surgical benefits to individuals or groups under contracts that are issued or delivered in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An entity subject to this section shall provide information to the Commissioner about the entity's:<section prefix="(1)">coverage for breast implant removals and breast implant-related conditions; and</section><section prefix="(2)">preexisting condition provisions in policies for individuals with breast implants.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On request, the Commissioner shall make available to consumers and licensed physicians the information collected under subsection (c) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When providing the information, the Commissioner may include a statement that the Commissioner does not guarantee the accuracy of the information.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commissioner may set a fee to cover the cost of providing the information under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A licensed physician may make available to a patient the information obtained from the Commissioner under subsection (d) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commissioner shall adopt regulations to carry out this section, including regulations that determine the extent and format of the information required under subsection (c) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
