<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-10-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Business entity" means a corporation, professional association, partnership, limited liability company, limited liability partnership, or other legal entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Home state" means any state in which an insurance producer:<section prefix="(1)">maintains the insurance producer's principal place of residence or principal place of business; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is licensed to act as a resident insurance producer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"License" means a document issued by the Commissioner to act as an insurance producer for the kind or subdivision of insurance or combination of kinds or subdivisions of insurance specified in the document.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"License" includes a limited lines license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Limited line credit insurance" includes:<section prefix="(1)">credit life insurance;</section><section prefix="(2)">credit health insurance;</section><section prefix="(3)">credit property insurance;</section><section prefix="(4)">credit unemployment insurance;</section><section prefix="(5)">credit involuntary unemployment benefit insurance;</section><section prefix="(6)">mortgage life insurance;</section><section prefix="(7)">mortgage guaranty insurance;</section><section prefix="(8)">mortgage disability insurance;</section><section prefix="(9)">guaranteed automobile protection (GAP) insurance; and</section><section prefix="(10)">any other form of insurance that:<section prefix="(i)">is offered in connection with an extension of credit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is limited to partially or wholly extinguishing that credit obligation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Commissioner determines should be designated a form of limited line credit insurance.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Limited line credit insurance producer" means a person who sells, solicits, or negotiates one or more forms of limited line credit insurance coverage to individuals through a master, corporate, group, or individual policy.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Limited lines insurance" means:<section prefix="(1)">limited line credit insurance;</section><section prefix="(2)">the lines of insurance described in &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-122 through 10-125 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">insurance sold in connection with, and incidental to, the rental of a motor vehicle under Subtitle 6 of this title; or</section><section prefix="(4)">any other line of insurance that the Commissioner considers necessary to recognize for the purpose of complying with &#xA7; 10-119(d) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Limited lines insurance producer" means a person authorized by the Commissioner to sell, solicit, or negotiate limited lines insurance.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Title insurance producer" means a person that, for compensation, solicits, procures, or negotiates title insurance contracts.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Title insurance producer" includes a person that provides escrow, closing, or settlement services that may result in the issuance of a title insurance contract.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Title insurance producer" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">individuals employed and used by title insurance producers for the performance of clerical and similar office duties;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a financial institution as defined in &#xA7; 1-101(i) of the Financial Institutions Article that does not solicit, procure, or negotiate title insurance contracts for compensation; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a title insurance insurer that is licensed under this article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Title insurance producer independent contractor" means a person that:<section prefix="(1)">is licensed to act as a title insurance producer;</section><section prefix="(2)">provides escrow, closing, or settlement services that may result in the issuance of a title insurance contract as an independent contractor for, or on behalf of, a licensed and appointed title insurance producer; and</section><section prefix="(3)">is not an employee of the licensed and appointed title insurance producer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Trade name" means a name, symbol, or word, or combination of two or more of these that a person uses to:<section prefix="(1)">identify its business, occupation, or self in a business capacity; and</section><section prefix="(2)">be distinguished from another business, occupation, or person.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Uniform application" means the current version of the NAIC uniform application for resident and nonresident insurance producer licensing.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Uniform business entity application" means the current version of the NAIC uniform business entity application for resident and nonresident business entities.</section>
  </text>
</law>
