<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-5-804</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>804</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A deposit of trusteed assets shall be made under a written trust agreement between the alien insurer and the trustee in accordance with this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The deposit of trusteed assets shall be authenticated in the manner approved by the Commissioner.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Whether or not then authorized to transact insurance business in Maryland, an alien insurer that uses or proposes to use Maryland as a state of entry to transact insurance business in the United States may make and execute the trust agreement required by this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The trust agreement is not effective until filed with and approved in writing by the Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner may not approve a trust agreement if the Commissioner finds that the trust agreement:<section prefix="(i)">does not comply with law; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">has terms that do not provide reasonably adequate protection for the alien insurer's policyholders and creditors in the United States.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A trust agreement may be amended.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The amendment is not effective until filed with and approved in writing by the Commissioner as complying with this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner may withdraw approval of a trust agreement or amendment to a trust agreement if the Commissioner finds, after a hearing, that the requirements under this subtitle for approval of the trust agreement or amendment are no longer met.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner shall give notice of the hearing required under paragraph (1) of this subsection to the alien insurer and the trustee of the trust agreement.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
