<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-14-205.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL SEPTEMBER 30, 2015 PER CHAPTER 537 OF 2010 //...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205.2</order_by>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL SEPTEMBER 30, 2015 PER CHAPTER 537 OF 2010 //<section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided, this section applies to both on-call physicians and hospital-based physicians who:<section prefix="(1)">are nonpreferred providers;</section><section prefix="(2)">obtain an assignment of benefits from an insured; and</section><section prefix="(3)">notify the insurer of an insured in a manner specified by the Commissioner that the on-call physician or hospital-based physician has obtained and accepted the assignment of benefits from the insured.</section></section><section prefix="(b)"><section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, an insured may not be liable to an on-call physician or a hospital-based physician subject to this section for covered services rendered by the on-call physician or hospital-based physician.</section><section prefix="(2)">An on-call physician or hospital-based physician subject to this section or a representative of an on-call physician or hospital-based physician subject to this section may not:<section prefix="(i)">collect or attempt to collect from an insured of an insurer any money owed to the on-call physician or hospital-based physician by the insurer for covered services rendered to the insured by the on-call physician or hospital-based physician; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">maintain any action against an insured of an insurer to collect or attempt to collect any money owed to the on-call physician or hospital-based physician by the insurer for covered services rendered to the insured by the on-call physician or hospital-based physician.</section></section><section prefix="(3)">An on-call physician or hospital-based physician subject to this section or a representative of an on-call physician or hospital-based physician subject to this section may collect or attempt to collect from an insured of an insurer:<section prefix="(i)">any deductible, copayment, or coinsurance amount owed by the insured for covered services rendered to the insured by the on-call physician or hospital-based physician;</section><section prefix="(ii)">if Medicare is the primary insurer and the insurer is the secondary insurer, any amount up to the Medicare approved or limiting amount, as specified under the federal Social Security Act, that is not owed to the on-call physician or hospital-based physician by Medicare or the insurer after coordination of benefits has been completed, for Medicare covered services rendered to the insured by the on-call physician or hospital-based physician; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">any payment or charges for services that are not covered services.</section></section></section><section prefix="(c)"><section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only to on-call physicians subject to this section.</section><section prefix="(2)">For a covered service rendered to an insured of an insurer by an on-call physician subject to this section, the insurer or its agent:<section prefix="(i)">shall pay the on-call physician within 30 days after the receipt of a claim in accordance with the applicable provisions of this title; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall pay a claim submitted by the on-call physician for a covered service rendered to an insured in a hospital, no less than the greater of:<section prefix="1.">140% of the average rate the insurer paid for the 12-month period that ends on January 1 of the previous calendar year in the same geographic area, as defined by the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services, for the same covered service, to similarly licensed providers under written contract with the insurer; or</section><section prefix="2.">the average rate the insurer paid for the 12-month period that ended on January 1, 2010, in the same geographic area, as defined by the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services, for the same covered service to a similarly licensed provider not under written contract with the insurer, inflated by the change in the Medicare Economic Index from 2010 to the current year.</section></section></section></section><section prefix="(d)"><section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only to hospital-based physicians subject to this section.</section><section prefix="(2)">For a covered service rendered to an insured of an insurer by a hospital-based physician subject to this section, the insurer or its agent:<section prefix="(i)">shall pay the hospital-based physician within 30 days after the receipt of the claim in accordance with the applicable provisions of this title; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall pay a claim submitted by the hospital-based physician for a covered service rendered to an insured no less than the greater of:<section prefix="1.">140% of the average rate the insurer paid for the 12-month period that ends on January 1 of the previous calendar year in the same geographic area, as defined by the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services, for the same covered service, to similarly licensed providers, who are hospital-based physicians, under written contract with the insurer; or</section><section prefix="2.">the final allowed amount of the insurer for the same covered service for the 12-month period that ended on January 1, 2010, inflated by the change in the Medicare Economic Index to the current year, to the hospital-based physician billing under the same federal tax identification number the hospital-based physician used in calendar year 2009.</section></section></section></section><section prefix="(e)"><section prefix="(1)">For the purposes of subsections (c)(2)(ii)1 and (d)(2)(ii)1 of this section, an insurer shall calculate the average rate paid to similarly licensed providers under written contract with the insurer for the same covered service by summing the contracted rate for all occurrences of the Current Procedural Terminology Code for that covered service and then dividing by the total number of occurrences of the Current Procedural Terminology Code.</section><section prefix="(2)">For the purposes of subsection (c)(2)(ii)2 of this section, an insurer shall calculate the average rate paid to similarly licensed providers not under written contract with the insurer for the same covered service by summing the rates paid to similarly licensed providers not under written contract with the insurer for all occurrences of the Current Procedural Terminology Code for that covered service and then dividing by the total number of occurrences of the Current Procedural Terminology Code.</section></section><section prefix="(f)">An insurer shall disclose, on request of an on-call physician or hospital-based physician subject to this section, the reimbursement rate required under subsection (c)(2)(ii) or (d)(2)(ii) of this section.</section><section prefix="(g)"><section prefix="(1)">An insurer may seek reimbursement from an insured for any payment under subsection (c)(2)(ii) or (d)(2)(ii) of this section for a claim or portion of a claim submitted by an on-call physician or hospital-based physician subject to this section and paid by the insurer that the insurer determines is the responsibility of the insured based on the insurance contract.</section><section prefix="(2)">The insurer may request and the on-call physician or hospital-based physician shall provide adjunct claims documentation to assist in making the determination under paragraph (1) of this subsection or under subsection (c) of this section.</section></section><section prefix="(h)"><section prefix="(1)">An on-call physician or hospital-based physician subject to this section may enforce the provisions of this section by filing a complaint against an insurer with the Administration or by filing a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction under &#xA7; 1-501 or &#xA7; 4-201 of the Courts Article.</section><section prefix="(2)">The Administration or a court shall award reasonable attorney's fees if the Administration or court finds that:<section prefix="(i)">the insurer's conduct in maintaining or defending the proceeding was in bad faith; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the insurer acted willfully in the absence of a bona fide dispute.</section></section></section><section prefix="(i)">The Administration may take any action authorized under this article, including conducting an examination under Title 2, Subtitle 2 of this article, to investigate and enforce a violation of the provisions of this section.</section><section prefix="(j)">In addition to any other penalties under this article, the Commissioner may impose a penalty not to exceed $5,000 on an insurer for each violation of this section.</section><section prefix="(k)">The Administration, in consultation with the Maryland Health Care Commission, shall adopt regulations to implement this section.</section></text>
</law>
