<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-211" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-10-211</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A license expires at the end of every other June 30 unless it is renewed for a 2-year term as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">At least 1 month before a license expires, the Commissioner shall mail to the holder of the license, at the last known address of the holder:<section prefix="(1)">a renewal application form; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a notice that states:<section prefix="(i)">the date by which the Commissioner must receive the renewal application for the renewal to be issued and mailed before the license expires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the amount of the renewal fee.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before a license expires, the holder of the license periodically may renew it for an additional 2-year term, if the holder:<section prefix="(1)">otherwise is entitled to a license;</section><section prefix="(2)">files with the Commissioner a renewal application on the form that the Commissioner provides;</section><section prefix="(3)">pays to the Commissioner the renewal fee required by &#xA7; 2-112 of this article;</section><section prefix="(4)">is in compliance with the bond requirement of &#xA7; 10-206 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(5)">if the Commissioner determines that an examination is advisable to determine the trustworthiness or competence of a holder, passes an examination given by the Commissioner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An application for renewal of a license shall be considered made in a timely manner if it is postmarked on or before June 30 of the year of renewal.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner shall renew the license of each holder who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the holder of a license files an application for renewal before the license expires, the license shall remain in effect until:<section prefix="(i)">the Commissioner issues a renewal license; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">5 days after the Commissioner refuses to renew the license and gives notice of the refusal to the holder.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
