<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-19-510</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only when the liability coverage under a policy or binder of private passenger ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>510</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only when the liability coverage under a policy or binder of private passenger motor vehicle liability insurance exceeds the amount required under &#xA7; 17-103 of the Transportation Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the first named insured under a policy or binder of private passenger motor vehicle liability insurance does not wish to obtain uninsured motorist coverage in the same amount as the liability coverage provided under the policy or binder, the first named insured shall make an affirmative written waiver of having uninsured motorist coverage in the same amount as the liability coverage.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the first named insured does not make an affirmative written waiver under this section, the insurer shall provide uninsured motorist coverage in an amount equal to the amount of the liability coverage provided under the policy or binder.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A waiver made under this section is not effective unless, prior to the waiver, the insurer gives the first named insured written notice of the nature, extent, benefit, and cost of the level of the uninsured motorist coverage being waived.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A waiver made under this section shall be made on the form that the Commissioner requires.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The form may be part of the insurance contract.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The form shall clearly and concisely explain in 10 point boldface type:<section prefix="(i)">the nature, extent, benefit, and cost of the level of the uninsured motorist coverage that would be provided under the policy if not waived by the first named insured;</section><section prefix="(ii)">that a failure of the first named insured to make a waiver requires an insurer to provide uninsured motorist coverage in an amount equal to the amount of the liability coverage provided under the policy or binder of private passenger motor vehicle liability insurance;</section><section prefix="(iii)">that an insurer may not refuse to underwrite a person because the person refuses to waive the excess uninsured motorist coverage under this section; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">that a waiver made under this section must be an affirmative written waiver.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Subject to the Commissioner's approval, a waiver made under this section may be made on the same form as the waiver made under &#xA7; 19-506 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A waiver made under this section by a person that is insured continuously by an insurer or by the Maryland Automobile Insurance Fund is effective until the waiver is withdrawn in writing.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An insurer may not refuse to underwrite a person because the person refuses to waive the excess uninsured motorist coverage under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An insurer that violates this subsection is subject to the penalties provided by &#xA7;&#xA7; 4-113 and 4-114 of this article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
