<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-1205</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to a carrier with respect to any health benefit plan that is a grandfathered health plan, as defined in &#xA7; 1251 of the Affordable Care Act.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In establishing a community rate for a health benefit plan, a carrier shall use a rating methodology that is based on the experience of all risks covered by that health benefit plan without regard to any factor not specifically authorized under this subsection or subsection (g) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A carrier may adjust the community rate only for:<section prefix="(i)">age;</section><section prefix="(ii)">geography based on the following contiguous areas of the State:<section prefix="1.">the Baltimore metropolitan area;</section><section prefix="2.">the District of Columbia metropolitan area;</section><section prefix="3.">Western Maryland; and</section><section prefix="4.">Eastern and Southern Maryland; and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">health status, as provided in subsection (g) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Rates for a health benefit plan may vary based on family composition as approved by the Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, after applying the risk adjustment factors under paragraph (3) of this subsection, a carrier may offer a discount not to exceed 20% to a small employer for participation in a wellness program.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A discount offered under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph shall be:<section prefix="1.">applied to reduce the rate otherwise payable by the small employer;</section><section prefix="2.">actuarially justified;</section><section prefix="3.">offered uniformly to all small employers; and</section><section prefix="4.">approved by the Commissioner.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to a carrier with respect to any health benefit plan that:<section prefix="(i)">is not a grandfathered health plan, as defined in &#xA7; 1251 of the Affordable Care Act; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is issued, delivered, or renewed in the State on or after January 1, 2014.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In establishing a premium rate for a health benefit plan, a carrier shall use a rating methodology that is based on the experience of all risks covered by that health benefit plan without regard to any factor not specifically authorized under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In accordance with &#xA7; 2701(a) of the Affordable Care Act, a premium rate may vary only by:<section prefix="(i)">whether the health benefit plan covers an individual or a family;</section><section prefix="(ii)">rating area;</section><section prefix="(iii)">age, except that a rate may not vary by more than 3 to 1 for adults; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">tobacco use, except that a rate may not vary by more than 1.5 to 1.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A rate may not vary by any factor that is not specified in paragraph (3) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A carrier shall apply all risk adjustment factors under subsections (a) and (g) of this section consistently with respect to all health benefit plans that are:<section prefix="(i)">issued, delivered, or renewed in the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">grandfathered health plans, as defined in &#xA7; 1251 of the Affordable Care Act.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A carrier shall apply all risk adjustment factors under subsection (b) of this section consistently with respect to all health benefit plans that are:<section prefix="(i)">issued, delivered, or renewed in the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">not grandfathered health plans, as defined in &#xA7; 1251 of the Affordable Care Act.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to a carrier with respect to any health benefit plan that is a grandfathered health plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Based on the adjustments allowed under subsection (a)(3)(i) and (ii) of this section, a carrier may charge a rate that is 50% above or 50% below the community rate.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">On or before October 1, 2007, the Commission shall adopt regulations that require carriers to collect and report to the Commission data on participation, by rate band, in health benefit plans issued, delivered, or renewed under this subtitle.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">On or before January 1, 2013, the Commission shall report to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the Senate Finance Committee and the House Health and Government Operations Committee regarding the effect of the 50% rate adjustments authorized under paragraph (1) of this subsection and the effect of the adjustment to the community rate for health status authorized under subsection (g) of this section on participation in health benefit plans issued, delivered, or renewed under this subtitle.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A carrier shall base its rating methods and practices on commonly accepted actuarial assumptions and sound actuarial principles.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A carrier that is a health maintenance organization and that includes a subrogation provision in its contract as authorized under &#xA7; 19-713.1(d) of the Health - General Article shall:<section prefix="(i)">use in its rating methodology an adjustment that reflects the subrogation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">identify in its rate filing with the Administration, and annually in a form approved by the Commissioner, all amounts recovered through subrogation.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to a carrier with respect to any health benefit plan that is a grandfathered health plan, as defined in &#xA7; 1251 of the Affordable Care Act.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A carrier may offer an administrative discount to a small employer if the small employer elects to purchase, for its employees, an annuity, dental insurance, disability insurance, life insurance, long-term care insurance, vision insurance, or, with the approval of the Commissioner, any other insurance sold by the carrier.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The administrative discount shall be offered under the same terms and conditions for all qualifying small employers.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A carrier may adjust the community rate for a health benefit plan that is a grandfathered health plan, as defined in &#xA7; 1251 of the Affordable Care Act, for health status only if a small employer has not offered a health benefit plan issued under this subtitle to its employees in the 12 months prior to the initial enrollment of the small employer in the health benefit plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Based on the adjustment allowed under paragraph (1) of this subsection, in addition to the adjustments allowed under subsection (d)(1) of this section, a carrier may charge:<section prefix="1.">in the first year of enrollment, a rate that is 10% above or below the community rate;</section><section prefix="2.">in the second year of enrollment, a rate that is 5% above or below the community rate; and</section><section prefix="3.">in the third year of enrollment, a rate that is 2% above or below the community rate.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A carrier may not make any adjustment for health status in the community rate of a health benefit plan issued under this subtitle after the third year of enrollment of a small employer in the health benefit plan.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For a health benefit plan that is a grandfathered health plan, as defined in &#xA7; 1251 of the Affordable Care Act, a carrier may use health statements, in a form approved by the Commissioner, and health screenings to establish an adjustment to the community rate for health status as provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A carrier may not limit coverage offered by the carrier, or refuse to issue a health benefit plan to any small employer that meets the requirements of this subtitle, based on a health status-related factor.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">It is an unfair trade practice for a carrier knowingly to provide coverage to a small employer that discriminates against an employee or applicant for employment, based on the health status of the employee or applicant or a dependent of the employee or applicant, with respect to participation in a health benefit plan sponsored by the small employer.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
