<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-10-115</section_number>
  <catch_line>Licenses expire every other year on the date stated on the license unless renewed as provided in thi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>115</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Licenses expire every other year on the date stated on the license unless renewed as provided in this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a license expires under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the appointments held by the insurance producer shall be terminated as of the day of the expiration of the license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">At least 1 month before a license expires, the Commissioner shall mail to the holder of the license, at the last known address of the holder:<section prefix="(1)">a renewal application form; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a notice that states:<section prefix="(i)">the date by which the Commissioner must receive the renewal application for the renewal to be issued and mailed before the license expires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the amount of the renewal fee.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subject to subsection (g) of this section, before a license expires, the holder of the license may renew it for an additional 2-year term, if the holder:<section prefix="(1)">otherwise is entitled to a license;</section><section prefix="(2)">files with the Commissioner a renewal application:<section prefix="(i)">on the form that the Commissioner provides; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">in an electronic format that the Commissioner approves;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">completes the continuing education requirements established under &#xA7; 10-116 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(4)">pays to the Commissioner the renewal fee required by &#xA7; 2-112 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A license renewed under this section shall have an expiration date that is the last day of the month in which the holder of the license was born.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If mailed, an application for renewal of a license shall be considered made in a timely manner if it is postmarked on or before the expiration date of the license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If submitted electronically, an application for renewal shall be considered made in a timely manner if, on or before the expiration date of the license, the application:<section prefix="(i)">is addressed properly or otherwise directed properly to an information processing system that the Administration has designated or uses for the purpose of receiving electronic applications and from which the Administration is able to retrieve the application;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is in a form capable of being processed by that system; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">enters an information processing system outside the control of the sender or of a person that sent the electronic application on behalf of the sender or enters a region of the information processing system designated or used by the Administration that is under the control of the Administration or an agent of the Administration.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner shall renew the license of each holder who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the holder of a license complies with subsections (b) and (c) of this section before the license expires, the license remains in effect until the decision of the Commissioner regarding the application for renewal is final.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A license is considered renewed for purposes of this subsection if the license is issued to a person for the period immediately following a period for which the person previously possessed the same or a substantially similar license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before a license may be renewed under this section, the Commissioner shall verify through the Office of the Comptroller that the applicant has paid all undisputed taxes and unemployment insurance contributions payable to the Comptroller or the Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation or that the applicant has provided for payment in a manner satisfactory to the unit responsible for collection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Commissioner may adopt regulations to:<section prefix="(1)">carry out this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">develop a staggered system of renewals for licenses of insurance producers.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
