<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-25-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Joint Insurance Association.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Association is an unincorporated association.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Association consists of all insurers that are licensed to write in the State, on a direct basis, essential property insurance or a component of essential property insurance in multi-peril policies.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">As a condition of its authority to transact essential property insurance business in the State, an insurer must be and remain an Association member.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Association may:<section prefix="(1)">establish a program of operation, subject to the approval of the Commissioner; and</section><section prefix="(2)">cause policies to be issued and assume and cede reinsurance on risks written in conformity with the program of operation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each Association member shall participate in the Association's expenses, profits, and losses in the proportion that the Association member's premiums written bear to the aggregate premiums written by all Association members.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A Governing Committee shall administer the Association.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Governing Committee consists of nine Association members.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">All Association members annually shall elect the members of the Governing Committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Votes shall be weighted in accordance with the premiums written by each Association member.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An Association member, the Association or its agents or employees, the Board of Directors, and the Commissioner or the Commissioner's representatives shall have the immunity from liability described in &#xA7; 5-411(a) of the Courts Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An Association member, the Association, the Governing Committee, their agents or employees, the Commissioner, and the Commissioner's authorized representatives shall have the immunity from liability described in &#xA7; 5-411(b) of the Courts Article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
