<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-121.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-3-121.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Mutual insurance holding company" means a nonstock corporation that:<section prefix="(i)">is incorporated in the State in accordance with a plan of reorganization adopted and approved under this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is the parent of a reorganized stock insurer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Reorganized stock insurer" means the stock corporation into which a mutual insurer is reorganized in accordance with a plan of reorganization adopted and approved under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to the provisions of this section and in accordance with a plan of reorganization approved by the Commissioner, a mutual insurer may:<section prefix="(1)">reorganize as a stock insurer; and</section><section prefix="(2)">establish a mutual insurance holding company.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A plan of reorganization shall provide that:<section prefix="(1)">all of the initial shares of capital stock of the reorganized stock insurer shall be issued to the mutual insurance holding company.</section><section prefix="(2)">the mutual insurance holding company shall own a majority of:<section prefix="(i)">the voting shares of the capital stock of the reorganized stock insurer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the total market value of all outstanding shares of the capital stock of the reorganized stock insurer.</section></section><section prefix="(3)">the class of capital stock owned by the mutual insurance holding company shall have dividend rights no less favorable than the dividend rights of any other class of stock of the reorganized stock insurer, unless:<section prefix="(i)">at least two-thirds of the board of directors of the mutual insurance holding company determines that such a requirement is not in the best interests of the members; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the determination of the board of directors is approved by the Commissioner.</section></section><section prefix="(4)">in an initial public offering or initial private equity placement of stock, each eligible member of the mutual insurance holding company shall receive, without payment, nontransferable subscription rights to purchase stock, unless:<section prefix="(i)">at least two-thirds of the board of directors of the mutual insurance holding company determines that a subscription rights offering is not in the best interests of the members; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the determination of the board of directors is approved by the Commissioner.</section></section><section prefix="(5)"><section prefix="(i)">the following individuals may not acquire, by stock option or any other manner, the legal or beneficial ownership of any class of stock of the reorganized stock insurer for 6 months from the date of an initial public offering or initial private equity placement:</section><section prefix="(ii)">Notwithstanding subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, any individual who is a policyholder of the reorganized stock insurer may exercise subscription rights in accordance with paragraph (4) of this subsection.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each policyholder of the reorganized stock insurer shall be a member of the mutual insurance holding company.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On the effective date of the reorganization, the membership interests of a policyholder in the mutual insurer shall become nontransferable membership interests in the mutual insurance holding company.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The plan of reorganization shall provide the terms and conditions under which future policyholders of the reorganized stock insurer shall become members of the mutual insurance holding company.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">At least two-thirds of those members of the board of directors of the mutual insurance holding company who are eligible or qualified to purchase a policy from the reorganized stock insurer, shall be members of the mutual insurance holding company.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, each policy of the mutual insurer in effect on the effective date of the reorganization shall remain in effect in accordance with its terms and conditions.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The following rights and obligations under the policy of the mutual insurer shall be void as of the effective date of the reorganization:<section prefix="(i)">voting rights of policyholders;</section><section prefix="(ii)">except as to the holder of a participating policy, a right of a policyholder to share in the surplus or profits of the insurer; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">assessment provisions.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A reorganized stock insurer shall continue to pay dividends to the holder of a participating policy that was in force on the effective date of the reorganization, in accordance with the methodology or formula used by the mutual insurer before the reorganization.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The reorganized stock insurer shall have:<section prefix="(1)">paid-in capital stock not less than the minimum paid-in capital required of a domestic stock insurer that:<section prefix="(i)">transacts like kinds of insurance business; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">started business in the State on the date the mutual insurer received its original certificate of authority in the State; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">surplus funds not less than 100% of the required capital.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The plan of reorganization shall be:<section prefix="(i)">approved by the vote of a majority of the board of directors of the mutual insurer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">submitted to a meeting of members and approved by the vote of at least three-fourths of the members who vote on the plan of reorganization in person, by proxy, or by mail.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notice of the time, place, and purpose of the meeting of members shall be provided in the manner approved by the Commissioner.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The plan of reorganization shall be submitted to the Commissioner for approval at least 60 days before the effective date of the reorganization, together with:<section prefix="(1)">the proposed articles of incorporation and bylaws of the mutual insurance holding company;</section><section prefix="(2)">the amendments to the articles of incorporation and bylaws of the mutual insurer to reorganize as a stock insurer;</section><section prefix="(3)">a 5-year plan of operation for the mutual insurance holding company and the reorganized stock insurer, including any plans for:<section prefix="(i)">an initial public offering of stock in the reorganized stock insurer; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the transfer of assets or liabilities from the reorganized stock insurer or any subsidiaries of the reorganized stock insurer to the mutual insurance holding company;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">a list of the officers and directors of the mutual insurance holding company and the reorganized stock insurer;</section><section prefix="(5)">a biography of each officer and director of the mutual insurance holding company and the reorganized stock insurer; and</section><section prefix="(6)">any other documents or information requested by the Commissioner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless disapproved by the Commissioner, a plan of reorganization is approved:<section prefix="(i)">on written notice from the Commissioner; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">60 days after the plan and all information required under this section and under any regulations adopted in accordance with this section are submitted to the Commissioner.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the Commissioner shall approve the plan of reorganization if the plan of reorganization:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In approving a plan of reorganization, the Commissioner may impose additional conditions and requirements that the Commissioner determines are necessary to achieve the purposes of this section.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the expense of the mutual insurer, the Commissioner may retain a qualified expert who is not a part of the staff of the Commissioner to assist in reviewing the plan of reorganization.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">After written notice to the mutual insurer, the Commissioner may hold a hearing on whether the plan of reorganization:<section prefix="(i)">complies with this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is equitable to the mutual insurer's members.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A mutual insurance holding company is subject to Title 7 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner may require the mutual insurance holding company to file annual statements with the Commissioner in the same manner as an insurer.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The articles of incorporation and any amendments to such articles of the mutual insurance holding company are subject to the approval of the Commissioner in the same manner as those of an insurer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">Compliance with the requirements for a plan of reorganization under this section exempts a mutual insurance holding company from the requirements of Title 7, Subtitle 3 of this article for the purpose of acquiring control of the reorganized stock insurer.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A mutual insurance holding company:<section prefix="(i)">may not dissolve or liquidate except through proceedings under Title 9 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall be a party to any proceeding under Title 9 of this article involving a reorganized stock insurer that is a subsidiary of the mutual insurance holding company.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In any proceeding under Title 9 involving a reorganized stock insurer that is a subsidiary of a mutual insurance holding company, the assets of the mutual insurance holding company shall be deemed to be assets of the estate of the reorganized stock insurer for purposes of satisfying the claims of the reorganized stock insurer's policyholders.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">A mutual insurance holding company may become a stock insurer in accordance with &#xA7; 3-121 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">The Commissioner may adopt regulations to enforce this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
