<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="31-104" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-31-104</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Board of Trustees of the Exchange.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board consists of the following members:<section prefix="(1)">the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Commissioner;</section><section prefix="(3)">the Executive Director of the Maryland Health Care Commission; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the following members appointed by the Governor, with the advice and consent of the Senate:<section prefix="(i)">three members who:</section><section prefix="(ii)">three members who have demonstrated knowledge and expertise in at least two of the following areas:</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In making appointments of members under subsection (b)(4) of this section, the Governor shall assure that:<section prefix="(1)">the Board's composition reflects a diversity of expertise;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Board's composition reflects the gender, racial, and ethnic diversity of the State; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the geographic areas of the State are represented.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For purposes of this subsection, "affiliation" means:<section prefix="(i)">a financial interest, as defined in &#xA7; 15-102 of the State Government Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a position of governance, including membership on a board of directors, regardless of compensation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a relationship through which compensation, as defined in &#xA7; 15-102 of the State Government Article, is received; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">a relationship for the provision of services as a regulated lobbyist, as defined in &#xA7; 15-102 of the State Government Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member of the Board or of the staff of the Exchange, while serving on the Board or the staff, may not have an affiliation with:<section prefix="(i)">a carrier, an insurance producer, a third-party administrator, a managed care organization, or any other person contracting directly with the Exchange;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a trade association of carriers, insurance producers, third-party administrators, or managed care organizations; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">any other association of entities in a position to contract directly with the Exchange.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member appointed by the Governor is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of members appointed by the Governor are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Board on June 1, 2011.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An appointed member of the Board may not serve more than two consecutive full terms.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Governor shall designate a chair of the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall determine the times, places, and frequency of its meetings.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Five members of the Board constitute a quorum.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Action by the Board requires the affirmative vote of at least five members.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A member of the Board is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">A member shall:<section prefix="(1)">meet the requirements of this title, the Affordable Care Act, and all applicable State and federal laws and regulations;</section><section prefix="(2)">serve the public interest of the individuals and qualified employers seeking health care coverage through the Exchange; and</section><section prefix="(3)">ensure the sound operation and fiscal solvency of the Exchange.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">A member of the Board shall perform the member's duties:<section prefix="(1)">in good faith;</section><section prefix="(2)">in the manner the member reasonably believes to be in the best interests of the Exchange; and</section><section prefix="(3)">without intentional or reckless disregard of the care an ordinarily prudent person in a like position would use under similar circumstances.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">A member of the Board who performs the member's duties in accordance with the standard provided in subsection (k) of this section may not be liable personally for actions taken as a member.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">A member of the Board may be removed for incompetence, misconduct, or failure to perform the duties of the position.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A member of the Board shall be subject to the State Ethics Law, Title 15, Subtitles 1 through 7 of the State Government Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In addition to the disclosure required under Title 15, Subtitle 6 of the State Government Article, a member of the Board shall disclose to the Board and to the public any relationship not addressed in the required financial disclosure that the member has with a carrier, insurance producer, third-party administrator, managed care organization, or other entity in an industry involved in matters likely to come before the Board.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On all matters that come before the Board, the member shall:<section prefix="(i)">adhere strictly to the conflict of interest provisions under Title 15, Subtitle 5 of the State Government Article relating to restrictions on participation, employment, and financial interests; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">provide full disclosure to the Board and the public on:</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
