<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-120" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-10-120</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Without regard to the education, experience, or examination requirements of this subtitle, the Commissioner may issue a temporary license to act as an insurance producer to an individual if the individual:<section prefix="(1)">is otherwise qualified; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is:<section prefix="(i)">the surviving spouse, next of kin, personal representative, or appointee of the personal representative, of a deceased insurance producer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the spouse, next of kin, employee, or legal guardian of a mentally or physically disabled insurance producer; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">an employee of a firm, or an officer or employee of a corporation, of a deceased or disabled insurance producer.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Before a person acts as a temporary insurance producer in the State, the person must obtain:<section prefix="(1)">a temporary license in the kind or subdivision of insurance for which the person intends to act as an insurance producer; and</section><section prefix="(2)">if applicable, an appointment from an insurer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An applicant for a temporary license shall:<section prefix="(1)">file with the Commissioner an application on the form that the Commissioner provides; and</section><section prefix="(2)">pay to the Commissioner the applicable fee required by &#xA7; 2-112 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Within 30 days after the date an application is received, the Commissioner shall:<section prefix="(1)">issue a temporary license to the applicant; or</section><section prefix="(2)">refuse in writing to issue a temporary license, stating the reasons for the refusal.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A temporary license issued under subsection (a) of this section expires 15 months after its effective date.</section>
  </text>
</law>
