<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-25-407</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>407</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Association may inspect the property of an applicant for essential property insurance or homeowner's insurance coverage.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Association shall inspect the property without cost to the owner.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Association is unable to complete an inspection of the property due to the fault of the owner or applicant, the Association may require the applicant to pay in advance the reasonable cost of subsequent efforts to inspect the property.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The applicant or representative of the applicant shall be afforded the opportunity to be present during the inspection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The inspector does not have authority to advise whether the Association will provide coverage to the property being inspected.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The inspector may take photographs of the property during the inspection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The inspection report shall:<section prefix="(1)">cover pertinent structural and occupancy features and the general condition of the building and surrounding structures;</section><section prefix="(2)">indicate the pertinent features of building, construction, maintenance, occupancy, and surrounding property; and</section><section prefix="(3)">include a rate makeup statement that covers any condition charges or surcharges imposed:<section prefix="(i)">as a result of the inspection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">under the program of operation; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">under a substandard rating plan approved by the Commissioner.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">On request, the Association shall make available a copy of the inspection report to the applicant or the applicant's licensed insurance producer.</section>
  </text>
</law>
