<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-1001</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1001</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to entities that propose to issue or deliver individual, group, or blanket health insurance policies or contracts in the State or to administer health benefit programs that provide for the coverage of health care services and the utilization review of those services, including:<section prefix="(1)">an authorized insurer that provides health insurance in the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">a nonprofit health service plan;</section><section prefix="(3)">a health maintenance organization;</section><section prefix="(4)">a dental plan organization; or</section><section prefix="(5)">except for a managed care organization as defined in Title 15, Subtitle 1 of the Health - General Article, any other person that provides health benefit plans subject to regulation by the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, each entity subject to this section shall:<section prefix="(i)">have a certificate issued under Subtitle 10B of this title; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">contract with a private review agent that has a certificate issued under Subtitle 10B of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For hospital services, each entity subject to this section may contract with or delegate utilization review to a hospital utilization review program approved under &#xA7; 19-319(d) of the Health - General Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this article, if the medical necessity of providing a covered benefit is disputed, an entity subject to this section that does not meet the requirements of subsection (b) of this section shall pay any person entitled to reimbursement under the policy or contract in accordance with the determination of medical necessity by:<section prefix="(1)">the treating provider; or</section><section prefix="(2)">when hospital services are provided, the hospital utilization review program approved under &#xA7; 19-319(d) of the Health - General Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An entity subject to this section may not:<section prefix="(1)">act as a private review agent without holding a certificate issued under Subtitle 10B of this title; or</section><section prefix="(2)">use a private review agent that does not hold a certificate issued under Subtitle 10B of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An entity that violates any provision of this section is subject to the penalties provided under &#xA7; 15-10B-12 of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
