<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-418</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>418</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the  meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Carrier" means:<section prefix="(i)">an insurer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a nonprofit health service plan; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a health maintenance organization.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Child dependent" means an individual who:<section prefix="(i)">is:<section prefix="1.">the natural child, stepchild, adopted  child, or grandchild of the insured;</section><section prefix="2.">a child placed with the insured for legal  adoption; or</section><section prefix="3.">a child who is entitled to dependent  coverage under &#xA7; 15-403.1 of this subtitle;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">is a dependent of the insured as that term is  used in 26 U.S.C. &#xA7;&#xA7; 104, 105, and 106, and any regulations adopted  under those sections;</section><section prefix="(iii)">is unmarried; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">is under the age of 25 years.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section applies to:<section prefix="(i)">each policy of individual or group health  insurance that is issued in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">each contract that is issued in the State by a  nonprofit health service plan; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">each contract that is issued in the State by a  health maintenance organization.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection,  this section does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">a contract covering one or more, or any  combination of the following:<section prefix="1.">coverage only for loss caused by an  accident;</section><section prefix="2.">disability coverage;</section><section prefix="3.">credit-only insurance; or</section><section prefix="4.">long-term care coverage; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">the following benefits if they are provided  under a separate contract:<section prefix="1.">dental coverage;</section><section prefix="2.">vision coverage;</section><section prefix="3.">Medicare supplement insurance;</section><section prefix="4.">coverage limited to benefits for a  specified disease or diseases;</section><section prefix="5.">travel accident or sickness coverage; and</section><section prefix="6.">fixed indemnity limited benefit insurance that does not provide benefits on an expense incurred basis.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each policy or contract subject to this section that  provides coverage for dependents shall:<section prefix="(1)">include coverage for a child dependent;</section><section prefix="(2)">provide the same health insurance benefits to a  child dependent that are available to any other covered  dependent; and</section><section prefix="(3)">provide health insurance benefits to a child  dependent at the same rate or premium applicable to any other  covered dependent.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section does not limit or alter any right to  dependent coverage or to the continuation of coverage that is  otherwise provided for in this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
