<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-427" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-8-427</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A society authorized to do insurance business in the State may provide for the payment of:<section prefix="(1)">life insurance benefits;</section><section prefix="(2)">annuity benefits;</section><section prefix="(3)">health insurance benefits;</section><section prefix="(4)">monument or tombstone benefits to the memory of a deceased member of the society; and</section><section prefix="(5)">such other benefits as authorized for life insurers and which are not inconsistent with this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A society shall specify in its laws those persons who may receive benefits through the society.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">For all coverages, the member shall be the applicant or the insured.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the member is the applicant, there shall be a bona fide familial or other dependent relationship between the member and the insured or beneficiary.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Every society, by its laws, may limit the scope of beneficiaries only to the extent required by federal law governing fraternal benefit societies.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The society may specify the terms and conditions on which benefits certificates may be assigned.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A society may not provide benefits through group insurance coverages.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A member who applies for additional benefits more than 6 months after becoming a benefit member shall provide additional evidence of insurability acceptable to the society.</section>
  </text>
</law>
