<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-1204" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-1204</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to a carrier with respect to any health benefit plan that is a grandfathered health plan, as defined in &#xA7; 1251 of the Affordable Care Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to any other requirement under this article, a carrier shall:<section prefix="(1)">have demonstrated the capacity to administer the health benefit plan, including adequate numbers and types of administrative personnel;</section><section prefix="(2)">have a satisfactory grievance procedure and ability to respond to enrollees' calls, questions, and complaints;</section><section prefix="(3)">provide, in the case of individuals covered under more than one health benefit plan, for coordination of coverage under all of those health benefit plans in an equitable manner; and</section><section prefix="(4)">design policies to help ensure adequate access to providers of health care.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not offer a health benefit plan in the State unless the person offers at least the Standard Plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A carrier may not offer a health benefit plan that has fewer benefits than those in the Standard Plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A carrier may offer benefits in addition to those in the Standard Plan if:<section prefix="(1)">the additional benefits:<section prefix="(i)">are offered and priced separately from benefits specified in accordance with &#xA7; 15-1207 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">do not have the effect of duplicating any of those benefits; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the carrier:<section prefix="(i)">clearly distinguishes the Standard Plan from other offerings of the carrier;</section><section prefix="(ii)">indicates the Standard Plan is the only plan required by State law; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">specifies that all enhancements to the Standard Plan are not required by State law.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Notwithstanding subsection (c) of this section, a health maintenance organization may provide a point of service delivery system as an additional benefit through another carrier regardless of whether the other carrier also offers the Standard Plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A carrier may offer coverage for dental care and services as an additional benefit.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "prominent carrier" means a carrier that insures at least 10% of the total lives insured in the small group market.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A prominent carrier shall offer a wellness benefit for a health benefit plan offered under this subtitle.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A carrier that is not a prominent carrier may offer a wellness benefit for a health benefit plan offered under this subtitle.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A carrier may not condition the sale of a wellness benefit to a small employer on participation of the eligible employees of the small employer in wellness programs or activities.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
