<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-16-118</section_number>
  <catch_line>** TAKES EFFECT OCTOBER 1, 2013 PER CHAPTER 171 OF 2012 **...</catch_line>
  <order_by>118</order_by>
  <text>** TAKES EFFECT OCTOBER 1, 2013 PER CHAPTER 171 OF 2012 **<section prefix="(a)"><section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section><section prefix="(2)">"Credit life insurance" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 13-101 of this article.</section><section prefix="(3)">"Death master file" means:<section prefix="(i)">the Social Security Administration's Death Master File; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">any other database or service that is at least as comprehensive as the Social Security Administration's Death Master File for determining that an individual reportedly has died.</section></section><section prefix="(4)">"Death master file match" means a match, resulting from a search of a death master file, of a Social Security number or a name and date of birth of an individual on the death master file with the Social Security number or the name and date of birth of an insured, annuitant, or retained asset account holder.</section><section prefix="(5)">"Pre-need insurance contract" means a life insurance policy or certificate, annuity contract, or other insurance contract that, by assignment or otherwise, has as a purpose the funding of an agreement relating to the purchase or provision of specific funeral or cemetery merchandise or services to be provided at the time of death of an individual.</section><section prefix="(6)">"Retained asset account" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 16-117(a) of this article.</section></section><section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">an annuity contract that:<section prefix="(i)">is used to fund an employment-based retirement plan or program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">does not require the insurer under the annuity contract to pay death benefits to the beneficiaries of specific plan or program participants;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">a policy or certificate of life insurance that provides a death benefit under:<section prefix="(i)">an employee benefit plan subject to the federal Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">any federal employee benefit program;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">a pre-need insurance contract;</section><section prefix="(4)">a policy or certificate of credit life insurance; or</section><section prefix="(5)">a policy or certificate of accidental death and dismemberment insurance.</section></section><section prefix="(c)"><section prefix="(1)">An insurer that issues, delivers, or renews a policy of life insurance or an annuity contract in the State shall perform a comparison of the insurer's in-force life insurance policies, annuity contracts, and retained asset accounts against the latest version of a death master file to identify any death benefit payments that may be due under the policies, contracts, or retained asset accounts as a result of the death of an insured, annuitant, or retained asset account holder.</section><section prefix="(2)">An insurer shall perform the comparison required under paragraph (1) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">at regular intervals, on at least a semiannual basis; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">in good faith, using criteria reasonably designed to identify individuals whose death would require the payment of benefits by the insurer under a life insurance policy, annuity contract, or retained asset account.</section></section><section prefix="(3)">For a group life insurance policy, an insurer is not required to perform the comparison required under paragraph (1) of this subsection unless the insurer provides full record-keeping services to the group life insurance policy holder.</section></section><section prefix="(d)"><section prefix="(1)">If a comparison performed by an insurer under subsection (c) of this section results in a death master file match with an insured, annuitant, or retained asset account holder, the insurer, within 90 days after the comparison was performed, shall:<section prefix="(i)">conduct a good faith effort to confirm the death of the insured, annuitant, or retained asset account holder using other available records and information;</section><section prefix="(ii)">determine whether benefits are due under the applicable life insurance policy, annuity contract, or retained asset account; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">if benefits are due under the policy, contract, or retained asset account:<section prefix="1.">use good faith efforts to locate the beneficiary; and</section><section prefix="2.">provide to the beneficiary the appropriate claims forms and instructions necessary to make a claim.</section></section></section><section prefix="(2)">An insurer shall document the good faith efforts made to:<section prefix="(i)">confirm the death of an insured, annuitant, or retained asset account holder under paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">locate a beneficiary under paragraph (1)(iii)1 of this subsection.</section></section><section prefix="(3)">To the extent permitted by law, an insurer may disclose the minimum necessary personal information about an insured, an annuitant, a retained asset account holder, or a beneficiary to a person that the insurer reasonably believes may be able to assist the insurer in locating a beneficiary as required under paragraph (1)(iii)1 of this subsection.</section></section><section prefix="(e)">An insurer may not charge an insured, an annuitant, a retained asset account holder, a beneficiary, or any other person for any fees or costs incurred by the insurer in connection with complying with subsections (c) and (d) of this section.</section><section prefix="(f)">The Commissioner may adopt regulations to implement this section.</section></text>
</law>
