<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-2-112.3</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "Fund" means the Health Care Regulatory Fund....</catch_line>
  <order_by>112.3</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Fund" means the Health Care Regulatory Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Health Care Regulatory Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The purpose of the Fund is to pay all costs and expenses incurred by the Administration related to the implementation of &#xA7; 2-303.1 of this title and Title 15, Subtitles 10A, 10B, and 10C of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Fund shall consist of:<section prefix="(1)">all revenue deposited into the Fund that is received through the imposition and collection of the health care regulatory assessment under &#xA7; 2-112.2 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">income from investments that the State Treasurer makes for the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Expenditures from the Fund to cover the costs and expenses for the implementation of &#xA7; 2-303.1 of this title and Title 15, Subtitles 10A, 10B, and 10C of this article may only be made:<section prefix="(i)">with an appropriation from the Fund approved by the General Assembly in the annual State budget; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">by the budget amendment procedure provided for in &#xA7; 7-209 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If, in any given fiscal year, the amount of the health care regulatory assessment revenue collected by the Commissioner and deposited into the Fund exceeds the actual expenditures incurred by the Administration for the implementation of &#xA7; 2-303.1 of this title and Title 15, Subtitles 10A, 10B, and 10C of this article, the excess amount shall be carried forward within the Fund for the purpose of reducing the assessment imposed by the Administration for the following fiscal year.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If, in any given fiscal year, the amount of the health care regulatory assessment revenue collected by the Commissioner and deposited into the Fund is insufficient to cover the actual expenditures incurred by the Administration to implement &#xA7; 2-303.1 of this title and Title 15, Subtitles 10A, 10B, and 10C of this article because of an unforeseen emergency and expenditures are made in accordance with the budget amendment procedure provided for in &#xA7; 7-209 of the State Finance and Procurement Article, an additional health care regulatory assessment may be made.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Treasurer is the custodian of the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Fund shall be invested and reinvested in the same manner as State funds.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The State Treasurer shall deposit payments received from the Commissioner into the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund is a continuing, nonlapsing fund and is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article, and may not be deemed a part of the General Fund of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">No part of the Fund may revert or be credited to:<section prefix="(i)">the General Fund of the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a special fund of the State, unless otherwise provided by law.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
