<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-14-133</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>133</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Affiliate" means a person that directly or indirectly, through one or more intermediaries, controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with a corporation subject to this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Control" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 7-101(c) of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Subsidiary" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 7-101(f) of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A nonprofit health service plan may not invest in or otherwise acquire an affiliate or subsidiary unless:<section prefix="(1)">the affiliate or subsidiary is licensed by the Commissioner; or</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">the affiliate or subsidiary is majority owned by the nonprofit health service plan; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the business of the affiliate or subsidiary is directly related to the operation of the nonprofit health service plan or the administration of a health benefits program.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A nonprofit health service plan shall submit a statement of proposed action to the Commissioner before the plan may:<section prefix="(i)">create, acquire, or invest in an affiliate or subsidiary in order to control the affiliate or subsidiary;</section><section prefix="(ii)">alter the structure, organization, purpose, or ownership of the plan or an affiliate or subsidiary of the corporation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">make an investment exceeding $500,000; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">make an investment in an affiliate or subsidiary.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The nonprofit health service plan shall file the statement of proposed action required under this subsection at least 60 days before the effective date of the proposed action.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The nonprofit health service plan may not engage in a proposed action described under paragraph (1)(i) through (iii) of this subsection unless the Commissioner approves the action in writing.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Commissioner shall either approve or disapprove the proposed action within 60 days after the Commissioner receives the statement of proposed action.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Commissioner shall approve a statement of proposed action under this section unless the Commissioner determines the proposed action is contrary to the public interest.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commissioner may authorize a corporation to comply with the law of its domiciliary jurisdiction if the corporation is domiciled in a jurisdiction that has adopted by statute or regulation provisions that limit the ownership and operation of an affiliate or subsidiary in substantially the same manner as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an affiliate or subsidiary of a corporation regulated under this subtitle does not comply with this section, the Commissioner shall require the corporation to file a plan of divestiture or liquidation of the affiliate or subsidiary.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The plan of divestiture or liquidation:<section prefix="(i)">shall state the reasons for noncompliance clearly;</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall provide the Commissioner with the information that the Commissioner considers necessary to approve the divestiture or liquidation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">is proprietary and confidential commercial information under &#xA7; 10-617(d) of the State Government Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Before a divestiture or liquidation under this section, the plan of divestiture or liquidation must be approved by the Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Any action by the Commissioner under this section may be appealed in accordance with Title 2 of this article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
