<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-831</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>831</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Authorized prescriber" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 12-101 of the Health Occupations Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Formulary" means a list of prescription drugs or devices that are covered by an entity subject to this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Member" means an individual entitled to health care benefits for prescription drugs or devices under a policy issued or delivered in the State by an entity subject to this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Member" includes a subscriber.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section applies to:<section prefix="(i)">insurers and nonprofit health service plans that provide coverage for prescription drugs and devices under health insurance policies or contracts that are issued or delivered in the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">health maintenance organizations that provide coverage for prescription drugs and devices under contracts that are issued or delivered in the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An insurer, nonprofit health service plan, or health maintenance organization that provides coverage for prescription drugs and devices through a pharmacy benefit manager is subject to the requirements of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This section does not apply to a managed care organization as defined in &#xA7; 15-101 of the Health - General Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each entity subject to this section that limits its coverage of prescription drugs or devices to those in a formulary shall establish and implement a procedure by which a member may receive a prescription drug or device that is not in the entity's formulary in accordance with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The procedure shall provide for coverage for a prescription drug or device that is not in the formulary if, in the judgment of the authorized prescriber:<section prefix="(1)">there is no equivalent prescription drug or device in the entity's formulary; or</section><section prefix="(2)">an equivalent prescription drug or device in the entity's formulary:<section prefix="(i)">has been ineffective in treating the disease or condition of the member; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">has caused or is likely to cause an adverse reaction or other harm to the member.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A decision by an entity subject to this section not to provide access to or coverage of a prescription drug or device in accordance with this section constitutes an adverse decision as defined under Subtitle 10A of this title if the decision is based on a finding that the proposed drug or device is not medically necessary, appropriate, or efficient.</section>
  </text>
</law>
