<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-709" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-709</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "nurse midwife" means a licensed registered nurse who is certified as a nurse midwife by the American College of Nurse-Midwives.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each insurer that proposes to issue, renew, amend, or reissue an individual, group, or blanket health insurance policy in the State that is written on an expense-incurred basis shall offer the option of providing benefits for expenses that arise from services rendered by a nurse midwife.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each nonprofit health service plan that proposes to issue, renew, amend, or reissue a health insurance policy in the State shall offer the option of providing benefits for expenses that arise from services rendered by a nurse midwife.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to each individual, group, or blanket health insurance policy, contract, or certificate of an insurer or nonprofit health service plan that:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">is issued, renewed, amended, or reissued on or after July 1, 1979; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">if issued by an insurer, is written on an expense-incurred basis.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding any other provision of a policy, contract, or certificate subject to this subsection, if the policy, contract, or certificate provides for reimbursement for a service that is within the lawful scope of practice of a nurse midwife, the insured or any other person covered by the policy, contract, or certificate is entitled to reimbursement for the service regardless of whether the service is performed by a physician or nurse midwife.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A policy that provides benefits under this section for services rendered by a nurse midwife may not require, as a condition for the payment of benefits, that the nurse midwife be employed by a physician or act under a physician's orders.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The utilization of health insurance benefits provided under this section for services rendered by a nurse midwife is subject to review by a peer review committee appointed by the State Board of Nursing.</section>
  </text>
</law>
