<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="23-405" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-23-405</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this article, when an insurance contract is canceled, whether by a premium finance company, an insurer, or an insured, the insurer shall return any gross unearned premiums that are due under the insurance contract, computed pro rata, and excluding any expense constant, administrative fee, or any nonrefundable charge filed with and approved by the Commissioner, to the premium finance company for the account of the insured within a reasonable time not exceeding 45 days after:<section prefix="(i)">receipt by the insurer of a notice of cancellation from the premium finance company or the insured;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the date the insurer cancels the insurance contract; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">completion of any payroll audit necessary to determine the amount of premium earned while the insurance contract was in force.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An audit under paragraph (1)(iii) of this subsection shall be performed within 45 days after the insurer receives the notice of cancellation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After the insurer returns to the premium finance company any gross unearned premiums that are due under the insurance contract, the premium finance company shall refund to the insured the amount of unearned premium that exceeds any amount due under the premium finance agreement.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A premium finance company need not make a refund to the insured if the amount of the refund would be less than $5.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Whenever an insurer, after receiving notice of the existence of a premium finance agreement, returns any unearned premiums to a person other than the premium finance company named in the premium finance agreement, the insurer shall be directly responsible to the premium finance company for all unearned premiums arising from the cancellation of the premium finance agreement.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An insurer that fails to return any premium required under this section shall pay interest of 1% per month on the unearned premium that has not been returned until the unearned premium is returned.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any payment under this subsection to the premium finance company shall be credited to the account of the insured.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An insurer may not deduct from any return premium any amount owed to the insurer by the insured under any other insurance contract.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An insurance producer shall return any gross unearned commissions, calculated as provided in subsection (a)(1) of this section, to an insurer within a reasonable period of time as required by the insurer.</section>
  </text>
</law>
