<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-119" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-10-119</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the Commissioner shall waive any license application requirements for an applicant who is not a resident of this State if:<section prefix="(1)">the applicant has a valid license from the home state of the applicant; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the home state of the applicant awards nonresident licenses to residents of this State on the same basis.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection and unless denied a license pursuant to &#xA7; 10-126 of this subtitle, a person that is not a resident of this State may obtain a nonresident license to act as an insurance producer if:<section prefix="(i)">the person currently is licensed as a resident insurance producer and in good standing in the person's home state;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the person has submitted or transmitted to the Commissioner the application for licensure that the person submitted to the person's home state or a completed uniform application;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the person has paid the applicable fee pursuant to &#xA7; 2-112 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the person's home state awards nonresident insurance producer licenses to residents of this State on the same basis.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual who applies for an insurance producer license in this State who was previously licensed for the same lines of authority in another state need not comply with the education, experience, and examination requirements of &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-104, 10-105, and 10-107 through 10-109 of this subtitle if:<section prefix="(i)">the person currently is licensed as an insurance producer in the home state of the person;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the application is received by the Commissioner within 90 days after the cancellation of the applicant's previous license and the prior state issues a certification that, at the time of cancellation, the applicant was in good standing in that state; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the state's producer database records, maintained by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, its affiliates or subsidiaries, indicate that the producer is or was licensed in good standing for the line of authority requested.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner may verify the licensing status of a nonresident insurance producer through the producer database maintained by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, its affiliates or subsidiaries.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, a person licensed as a limited line credit insurance producer or other type of limited lines insurance producer in the person's home state is entitled to receive a nonresident limited lines insurance producer license, pursuant to subsection (b) of this section, granting the same scope of authority as granted under the license issued by the person's home state.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, a person licensed as a surplus lines broker in the person's home state is entitled to receive a nonresident certificate of qualification as a surplus lines broker under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except for subsection (b) of this section, nothing in this section supersedes any provision of Title 3, Subtitle 3 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A nonresident insurance producer who moves from one state to another state or a resident producer who moves from this State to another state shall:<section prefix="(i)">file with the Commissioner a change of address; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">provide to the Commissioner certification from the new resident state within 30 days after the change of legal residence.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner may not charge a fee or require a license application following a change of legal residence.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person licensed as an insurance producer in another state who moves to this State shall apply to become licensed as a resident insurance producer under &#xA7; 10-111 of this subtitle within 90 days of establishing legal residence in this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the person applies to become licensed as a resident insurance producer within 90 days of establishing legal residence in the State, the person need not comply with the education, experience, and examination requirements of &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-104, 10-105, and 10-107 through 10-109 of this subtitle to obtain a license for any line of authority that the person previously held in the prior state, except where the Commissioner determines otherwise by regulation.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
