<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-501" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-2-501</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Assessment" means an assessment that, subject to &#xA7; 2-505(c)(3) of this subtitle, equals 60% of the Administration's approved annual budget appropriation under this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Fund" means the Insurance Regulation Fund established under &#xA7; 2-505 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Health insurer" means an insurer that holds a certificate of authority issued by the Commissioner to engage in the business of health insurance.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Health insurer" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a health maintenance organization operating under a certificate of authority issued by the Commissioner under Title 19, Subtitle 7 of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a nonprofit health service plan operating under Title 14, Subtitle 1 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">a dental plan operating under Title 14, Subtitle 4 of this article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Health insurer assessment portion" means 40% of the assessment.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Insurer" means an insurer or other entity authorized to engage in the insurance business in the State under a certificate of authority issued by the Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Insurer" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a health maintenance organization operating under a certificate of authority issued by the Commissioner under Title 19, Subtitle 7 of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a nonprofit health service plan operating under Title 14, Subtitle 1 of this article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a dental plan operating under Title 14, Subtitle 4 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Maryland Automobile Insurance Fund.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Life insurer" means an insurer that holds a certificate of authority issued by the Commissioner to engage in the business of life insurance.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Life insurer assessment portion" means 26% of the assessment.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Multiple type insurer" means an insurer that engages in more than one of the following types of insurance:<section prefix="(1)">life;</section><section prefix="(2)">health; or</section><section prefix="(3)">property and casualty.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Premium" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 1-101 of this article to the extent it is allocable to this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Premium" includes any amounts paid to a health maintenance organization as compensation on a predetermined basis for providing services to members and subscribers as specified in Title 19, Subtitle 7 of the Health - General Article to the extent it is allocable to this State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Property and casualty insurer" means an insurer that holds a certificate of authority issued by the Commissioner to engage in the business of property and casualty insurance.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Property and casualty insurer" includes the Maryland Automobile Insurance Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Property and casualty insurer assessment portion" means 34% of the assessment.</section>
  </text>
</law>
