<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-4-112</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>112</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A certificate of authority expires on the first June 30 after its effective date unless it is renewed as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">At least 2 months before a certificate of authority expires, the Commissioner shall mail to the holder of the certificate of authority, at the last known address of the holder:<section prefix="(1)">a renewal application form; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a notice that states:<section prefix="(i)">the date on which the current certificate of authority expires;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the date by which the Commissioner must receive the renewal application for the renewal to be issued and mailed before the certificate of authority expires; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the amount of the renewal fee.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before a certificate of authority expires, the holder of the certificate of authority may renew it for an additional 1-year term, if the holder:<section prefix="(1)">otherwise is entitled to a certificate of authority;</section><section prefix="(2)">files with the Commissioner a renewal application on the form that the Commissioner provides; and</section><section prefix="(3)">pays to the Commissioner the appropriate renewal fee required by &#xA7; 2-112 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner shall renew the certificate of authority of each holder who meets the requirements of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a certificate holder pays the applicable renewal fee before the certificate of authority expires, the certificate of authority remains in effect until the Commissioner renews or refuses to renew the certificate of authority.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An insurer shall mail a renewal application and the applicable renewal fee on or before June 30. An insurer that fails to renew its certificate of authority on or before June 30 may forfeit:<section prefix="(i)">$500 for each day from July 1 through July 10;</section><section prefix="(ii)">$1,000 for each day from July 11 through July 31; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">$5,000 for each day after July 31.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to the provisions imposed under paragraph (1) of this subsection, an insurer that fails to renew its certificate of authority on or before June 30 in the previous year shall:<section prefix="(i)">renew its certificate of authority on or before June 1 of the current year; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">forfeit $3,000 if the insurer fails to renew its certificate of authority on or before June 30 in the current year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In addition to the monetary penalties imposed under this subsection, on July 1 of each year, for each insurer that fails to file its renewal application and continuation fee on or before June 30, the Commissioner may:<section prefix="(i)">order that the insurer cease and desist from engaging further from the writing of insurance in this State in accordance with &#xA7; 4-114 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">issue an order to require the insurer to show cause why it should be allowed to continue to engage in the insurance business in the State.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In determining the amount of any financial penalty or forfeiture to be imposed under this section, the Commissioner:<section prefix="(1)">shall consider the following factors:<section prefix="(i)">the seriousness of the violation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the good faith of the violator;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the violator's history of previous violations;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the deleterious effect of the violation on the public and the insurance industry; and</section><section prefix="(v)">the assets of the violator; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">may determine the appropriate amount of the penalty or forfeiture.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
