<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-27-505</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>505</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Commissioner finds that an insurer has violated &#xA7; 27-501, &#xA7; 27-503, &#xA7; 27-504, or &#xA7; 27-504.1 of this subtitle, the Commissioner, in addition to any other power granted by this article, may order the insurer to accept the risk, or accept the business, as appropriate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">With respect to medical professional liability insurance, the Commissioner shall issue a finding within 90 days after receiving a request to review the cancellation or refusal to renew a policy under &#xA7; 27-501(f) of this subtitle.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A medical professional liability insurer may terminate the policy if:<section prefix="1.">the Commissioner fails to issue a finding within 90 days after receiving a request to review the cancellation or refusal to renew; or</section><section prefix="2.">the Commissioner finds that the policy may be canceled or not renewed and issued the finding within 90 days after receiving a request to review the cancellation or refusal to renew.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If a medical professional liability insurer terminates the policy under subparagraph (ii)1 of this paragraph and the Commissioner subsequently issues a finding that the insurer may not cancel or refuse to renew the policy:<section prefix="1.">the insurer immediately shall reinstate the policy; and</section><section prefix="2.">the reinstatement shall be retroactive to the date that the policy was terminated.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A party to a hearing or proceeding under this subtitle may appeal from the hearing, proceeding, or a decision of the Commissioner in accordance with &#xA7; 2-215 of this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
