<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-601" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-11-601</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Carrier" means a person that:<section prefix="(1)">offers a health benefit plan in the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is:<section prefix="(i)">an insurer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a nonprofit health service plan; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a health maintenance organization.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Contract holder" means a person to which a carrier has issued a health benefit plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Health benefit plan" means:<section prefix="(i)">a health insurance contract, a nonprofit health service plan contract, or a health maintenance organization contract that includes benefits for medical care; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a certificate of health insurance issued or delivered to a Maryland resident under a contract issued to an association located in the State or any other state.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Health benefit plan" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">one or more, or any combination of the following:</section><section prefix="(ii)">the following benefits if they are provided under a separate policy, certificate, or contract of insurance or are otherwise not an integral part of a health benefit plan:</section><section prefix="(iii)">the following benefits if offered as independent, noncoordinated benefits:</section><section prefix="(iv)">the following benefits if offered as a separate policy, certificate, or contract of insurance:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Medical care" means:<section prefix="(1)">items or services for the diagnosis, cure, mitigation, treatment, or prevention of a disease, injury, or condition affecting any structure or function of the body; and</section><section prefix="(2)">transportation primarily for and essential to medical care described in item (1) of this subsection.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
