<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-301" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-4-301</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Adjusted RBC report" means an RBC report that has been adjusted by the Commissioner in accordance with &#xA7; 4-303(b) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Corrective order" means an order issued by the Commissioner that specifies corrective actions that the Commissioner has determined are required.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Domestic insurer" means an insurer:<section prefix="(i)">as defined in subsection (h) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">that is formed under the laws of this State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Domestic insurer" does not include the Maryland Automobile Insurance Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Filing date" means March 1 of any given year.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Foreign insurer" means an insurer:<section prefix="(1)">as defined in subsection (h) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">that is formed under the laws of a jurisdiction other than this State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Health insurer" means an insurer that:<section prefix="(i)">is authorized to write health insurance in the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">receives the majority of its premium from the sale of health insurance.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Health insurer" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a health maintenance organization operating under a certificate of authority issued by the Commissioner under Title 19, Subtitle 7 of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a nonprofit health service plan operating under Title 14, Subtitle 1 of this article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a dental plan operating under Title 14, Subtitle 4 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">a provider-sponsored organization operating under Title 19, Subtitle 7A of the Health - General Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Health insurer" does not include a managed care organization operating under Title 15, Subtitle 1 of the Health - General Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Insurer" means an insurer or other entity authorized to engage in the insurance business in the State under a certificate of authority issued by the Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Insurer" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a health maintenance organization operating under a certificate of authority issued by the Commissioner under Title 19, Subtitle 7 of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a nonprofit health service plan operating under Title 14, Subtitle 1 of this article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a dental plan operating under Title 14, Subtitle 4 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">a provider-sponsored organization operating under Title 19, Subtitle 7A of the Health - General Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Insurer" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">monoline:</section><section prefix="(ii)">managed care organizations operating under Title 15, Subtitle 1 of the Health - General Article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Life insurer" means an insurer that:<section prefix="(1)">is authorized to write life insurance in the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">receives the majority of its premium from the sale of life insurance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"NAIC" means the National Association of Insurance Commissioners.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Negative trend" means, with respect to a life insurer or health insurer, negative trend over a period of time, as determined in accordance with the "trend test calculation" included in the RBC instructions.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Property and casualty insurer" means an insurer that:<section prefix="(i)">is authorized to write property insurance or casualty insurance in the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">receives the majority of its premium from the sale of property insurance or casualty insurance.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Property and casualty insurer" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">a health maintenance organization operating under a certificate of authority issued by the Commissioner under Title 19, Subtitle 7 of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a nonprofit health service plan operating under Title 14, Subtitle 1 of this article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a dental plan operating under Title 14, Subtitle 4 of this article;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a provider-sponsored organization operating under Title 19, Subtitle 7A of the Health - General Article; or</section><section prefix="(v)">a managed care organization operating under Title 15, Subtitle 1 of the Health - General Article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"RBC instructions" means the risk based capital instructions developed and adopted by the NAIC.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"RBC level" means an insurer's company action level RBC, regulatory action level RBC, authorized control level RBC, or mandatory control level RBC if:<section prefix="(1)">"company action level RBC" means the product of 2.0 and the authorized control level RBC;</section><section prefix="(2)">"regulatory action level RBC" means the product of 1.5 and the authorized control level RBC;</section><section prefix="(3)">"authorized control level RBC" means the number determined under the risk based capital formula in accordance with the RBC instructions; or</section><section prefix="(4)">"mandatory control level RBC" means the product of .70 and the authorized control level RBC.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"RBC plan" means a comprehensive financial plan that contains the elements specified in &#xA7; 4-305(b) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"RBC report" means a report prepared by a domestic insurer and submitted to the Commissioner that details the domestic insurer's RBC levels as of the end of the immediately preceding calendar year.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Revised RBC plan" means an RBC plan that has been:<section prefix="(1)">rejected by the Commissioner; and</section><section prefix="(2)">subsequently revised by the insurer, with or without the Commissioner's recommendation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Total adjusted capital" means the sum of:<section prefix="(1)">an insurer's statutory capital and surplus as determined in accordance with the statutory accounting principles applicable to the annual financial statements required to be filed under State law and regulations; and</section><section prefix="(2)">any other items provided for in the RBC instructions.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
