<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-14-139</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>139</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An officer, director, or employee of a corporation operating under this subtitle may not:<section prefix="(1)">willfully violate a provision of this article or a regulation adopted under this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">willfully misrepresent or conceal a material fact in a statement, report, record, or communication provided to the Commissioner;</section><section prefix="(3)">willfully misrepresent or conceal a material fact to the board of directors;</section><section prefix="(4)">misappropriate or fail to account properly for money that belongs to the corporation, an insurer, insurance producer, subscriber, or certificate holder;</section><section prefix="(5)">engage in fraudulent or dishonest practices in connection with the provision or administration of a health service plan;</section><section prefix="(6)">willfully fail to produce records or allow an examination under &#xA7; 14-125 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(7)">willfully fail to comply with a lawful order of the Commissioner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An officer, director, or trustee of a corporation operating under this subtitle may not receive any immediate or future remuneration as the result of an acquisition or proposed acquisition, as defined under &#xA7; 6.5-101 of the State Government Article, except in the form of compensation paid for continued employment with the company or acquiring entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A director, trustee, officer, executive, or employee of a corporation operating under this subtitle may only approve or receive from the assets of the corporation fair and reasonable compensation in the form of salary, bonuses, or perquisites for work actually performed for the benefit of the corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The compensation committee of the board shall:<section prefix="(i)">identify nonprofit health service plans in the United States that are similar in size and scope to the nonprofit health service plan managed by the board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">develop proposed guidelines, for approval by the board:<section prefix="1.">for compensation, including salary, bonuses, and perquisites, of all officers and executives that is reasonable in comparison to compensation for officers and executives of similar nonprofit health service plans; and</section><section prefix="2.">for compensation for board members that is reasonable in comparison to compensation for board members of similar nonprofit health service plans.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The board shall review the proposed guidelines at least annually.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The board shall:<section prefix="(i)">provide a copy of the approved guidelines:<section prefix="1.">to each officer and executive of the nonprofit health service plan;</section><section prefix="2.">to each candidate for an officer or executive position with the nonprofit health service plan;</section><section prefix="3.">to each board member of the nonprofit health service plan; and</section><section prefix="4.">on or before September 1, 2004, and annually thereafter, to the Commissioner; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">adhere to the approved guidelines in compensating the officers, executives, and board members of the nonprofit health service plan.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On an annual basis, the Commissioner shall review:<section prefix="(i)">the compensation paid by the nonprofit health service plan to each officer and executive; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the base compensation and compensation for attendance at meetings paid by the nonprofit health service plan to board members.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If the Commissioner finds that the compensation exceeds the amount authorized under the approved guidelines, the Commissioner shall issue an order prohibiting payment of the excess amount.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The approval or receipt of remuneration in violation of an order issued under subsection (d)(5) of this section is a violation of &#xA7; 14-115(c) of this subtitle and shall be considered an unsound or unsafe business practice under &#xA7; 14-116 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for an employee under subsection (c) of this section, a person that violates subsection (a) or (c) of this section is subject to a civil penalty not exceeding $10,000 for each violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Instead of or in addition to imposing a civil penalty, the Commissioner may require the violator to make restitution to any person that has suffered financial injury as a result of the violation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In determining the amount of financial penalty to be imposed, the Commissioner shall consider:<section prefix="(1)">the seriousness of the violation;</section><section prefix="(2)">the good faith of the violator;</section><section prefix="(3)">the violator's history of previous violations;</section><section prefix="(4)">the deleterious effect of the violation on the public and the nonprofit health service industry; and</section><section prefix="(5)">the assets of the violator.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before assessing a civil penalty or restitution, the Commissioner shall serve by certified mail, return receipt requested, on the person to be charged a notice that contains:<section prefix="(i)">the specifications of the charge; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the time and place of a hearing to be held on the charges.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner shall hold a hearing on the charges at least 20 days after the date of mailing the notice.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commissioner or designee of the Commissioner shall conduct a hearing on the charges in accordance with Title 2, Subtitle 2 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Subject to Title 2, Subtitle 2 of this article, an appeal may be taken from a final order of the Commissioner to the Circuit Court for Baltimore City.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">In addition to any other penalty or remedy under this section, a person that is found to have gained financially from a violation of a provision of this article or a regulation adopted by the Commissioner shall forfeit the gain.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">This section does not prevent a person damaged by a director, officer, manager, employee, or agent of a corporation subject to this subtitle from bringing a separate action in a court of competent jurisdiction.</section>
  </text>
</law>
