<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-20-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Board of Trustees of the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of Trustees consists of 13 members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 13 members:<section prefix="(i)">seven shall be appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">five shall be appointed by the Board of Directors; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">one shall be the Executive Director.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 20-203(a)(3) of this subtitle, the Executive Director may vote on all matters before the Board of Trustees.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A member appointed by the Governor may not be actively affiliated with an insurance agency, insurance producer, insurer, or premium finance company that does business with the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">At least three of the five members appointed by the Board of Directors shall be residents of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A member appointed by the Governor serves at the pleasure of the Governor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The term of a member appointed by the Board of Directors is 4 years and begins on September 1.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member appointed by the Board of Directors continues to serve until a successor is chosen and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If a member appointed by the Board of Directors ceases to be a member of the Board of Trustees, the Board of Directors shall appoint a successor for the unexpired term.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A member appointed by the Board of Directors is deemed to have resigned, causing a vacancy on the Board of Trustees, if:<section prefix="(i)">the member was employed by an Association member or insurance trade association when the member's term on the Board of Trustees began; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">for any reason, the member's employment with the Association member or insurance trade association ends during the member's term on the Board of Trustees.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of Trustees shall choose a chairman from among its members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For each successive term, the position of chairman shall alternate between a gubernatorial appointee and an Association appointee.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Executive Director may not be the chairman of the Board of Trustees.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Each member of the Board of Trustees is entitled to:<section prefix="(1)">per diem compensation set by the Board of Public Works for each day actually engaged in the discharge of official duties, if the member is not otherwise an officer or employee of the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the budget of the Board of Trustees.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Board of Trustees shall formulate policy for the Fund.</section>
  </text>
</law>
