<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-2-213</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>213</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, all hearings shall be open to the public in accordance with Article 41, &#xA7; 1-205 of the Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A hearing held by the Commissioner that relates to a filing under Title 11 of this article is not required to be open to the public.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A hearing held by the Commissioner to determine whether an insurer is being operated in a hazardous manner that could result in its impairment is not required to be open to the public if:<section prefix="(i)">the insurer requests that the hearing not be a public hearing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Commissioner determines that it is not in the interest of the public to hold a public hearing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A hearing held by the Commissioner to evaluate the financial condition of an insurer under the risk based capital standards set out in Title 4, Subtitle 3 of this article is not required to be open to the public.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner shall allow any party to a hearing to:<section prefix="(i)">appear in person;</section><section prefix="(ii)">be represented:<section prefix="1.">by counsel; or</section><section prefix="2.">in the case of an insurer, by a designee of the insurer who:</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">be present while evidence is given;</section><section prefix="(iv)">have a reasonable opportunity to inspect all documentary evidence and to examine witnesses; and</section><section prefix="(v)">present evidence.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On request of a party, the Commissioner shall issue subpoenas to compel attendance of witnesses or production of evidence on behalf of the party.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner shall allow any person that was not an original party to a hearing to become a party by intervention if:<section prefix="(1)">the intervention is timely; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the financial interests of the person will be directly and immediately affected by an order of the Commissioner resulting from the hearing.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Formal rules of pleading or evidence need not be observed at a hearing.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On timely written request by a party to a hearing, the Commissioner shall have a full stenographic record of the proceedings made by a competent reporter at the expense of that party.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the stenographic record is transcribed, a copy shall be given on request to any other party to the hearing at the expense of that party.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the stenographic record is not made or transcribed, the Commissioner shall prepare an adequate record of the evidence and proceedings.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
