<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-3-318</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>318</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commissioner may not approve an insurer as a surplus lines insurer unless the insurer:<section prefix="(1)">is authorized in its domiciliary jurisdiction to write the type of insurance it seeks to write;</section><section prefix="(2)">has capital and surplus, or their equivalent under the laws of its domiciliary jurisdiction, equal to the greater of:<section prefix="(i)">the minimum capital and surplus required under the laws of its domiciliary jurisdiction; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">$15,000,000; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">files with the Commissioner the information required under subsection (c) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For a foreign insurer, the requirements of subsection (a)(2) of this section may be satisfied by the insurer's possessing less than the minimum capital and surplus if the Commissioner makes an affirmative finding of acceptability.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The finding shall be based on the following or similar factors:<section prefix="(i)">quality of management;</section><section prefix="(ii)">capital and surplus of any parent company;</section><section prefix="(iii)">company underwriting profit and investment income trends;</section><section prefix="(iv)">market availability; and</section><section prefix="(v)">company record and reputation of the foreign insurer in the industry.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commissioner may not make an affirmative finding of acceptability if the foreign insurer's capital and surplus is less than $4,500,000.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An insurer that seeks approval under subsection (a) of this section shall file each year with the Commissioner:<section prefix="(1)">a written request for approval as a surplus lines insurer to write the type of insurance it seeks to write;</section><section prefix="(2)">a certified copy of its annual statement, on convention form, that shows the amount by line of surplus lines business written on risks located in the State during the period covered by the annual statement; and</section><section prefix="(3)">a certificate of compliance issued by the insurance department of the insurer's state of domicile.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An unauthorized insurer shall appoint in writing the Commissioner as agent for the acceptance of service of process.</section>
  </text>
</law>
