<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-901</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>901</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Applicant" means:<section prefix="(1)">for an individual Medicare supplement policy or subscriber contract, the individual who seeks to contract for insurance benefits; or</section><section prefix="(2)">for a group Medicare supplement policy or subscriber contract, the proposed certificate holder.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Carrier" means an insurer, nonprofit health service plan, or fraternal benefit society that is authorized to issue health insurance policies under this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Certificate" means a certificate that is delivered or issued for delivery in the State under a group Medicare supplement policy.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Certificate form" means the form on which the certificate is delivered or issued for delivery in the State by the carrier.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"CMS" means the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services of the United States Department of Health and Human Services.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Medicaid" means the Health Insurance for the Aged Act, Title XIX of the Social Security Amendments of 1965, as amended.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Medicare" means the Health Insurance for the Aged Act, Title XVIII of the Social Security Amendments of 1965, as amended.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Medicare benefit period" means the unit of time used in the Medicare Program to measure use of services and availability of benefits under Medicare Part A.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Medicare eligible expense" means a health care expense of the kind covered by Medicare to the extent the service for which the expense was incurred is considered reasonable under Medicare rules and regulations.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Medicare supplement policy" or "Medigap policy" means an individual or group policy of health insurance or subscriber contract that is advertised, marketed, or designed primarily as a supplement to reimbursements under Medicare for the hospital, medical, or surgical expenses of individuals eligible for Medicare.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Medicare supplement policy" or "Medigap policy" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">a policy that is issued pursuant to a contract under &#xA7; 1876 of the federal Social Security Act, 42 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1395mm; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a policy that is issued under a demonstration project authorized pursuant to amendments to the federal Social Security Act.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Policy" includes:<section prefix="(1)">a policy that is issued to an individual;</section><section prefix="(2)">a certificate, as that term is used in Title 14, Subtitle 1 of this article, that is issued to an individual subscriber;</section><section prefix="(3)">a certificate, as that term is used in Title 8, Subtitle 4 of this article, that is issued to a member of a fraternal benefit society; and</section><section prefix="(4)">a group policy authorized to be issued under this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Policy form" means the form on which the policy is delivered or issued for delivery in the State by the carrier.</section>
  </text>
</law>
