<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-503" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-11-503</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An order or decision of the Commissioner under this title is subject to judicial review by appeal to the Circuit Court for Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 30 days after the issuance of an order or decision of the Commissioner, an appeal may be commenced by filing a notice of appeal with the Circuit Court for Baltimore City and a copy of the notice of appeal with the Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an appeal is not commenced under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the right to appeal no longer exists.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commissioner shall be made a party to each appeal under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After a copy of the notice of appeal is filed with the Commissioner, the Commissioner shall prepare or cause to be prepared an official record.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The official record:<section prefix="(i)">shall be certified by the Commissioner;</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall include a copy of:</section><section prefix="(iii)">may be in typewritten form.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a hearing was not held by the Commissioner on the matter that is the subject of the appeal, the Commissioner shall prepare and certify a transcript of the files in the office of the Commissioner relating to the matter.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Within 30 days after a copy of the notice of appeal is filed with the Commissioner, the Commissioner shall file the official record with the Circuit Court for Baltimore City.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the filing of the notice of appeal acts as a stay of a ruling, order, or decision of the Commissioner pending the final determination of the issue if the ruling, order, or decision relates to an increase or decrease of premiums or rate or to a change in a rating system.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Paragraph (1) does not apply if the ruling, order, or decision approves or allows a filing of an insurer or rating organization.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 60 days after the date of the filing of a notice of appeal, the Circuit Court for Baltimore City shall:<section prefix="(i)">hear and decide the appeal; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">affirm, reverse, or modify the order or decision of the Commissioner from which the appeal is taken.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Circuit Court for Baltimore City shall reverse or modify the order or decision of the Commissioner wholly or partly if the court finds that the order or decision:<section prefix="(i)">is not supported by the preponderance of the evidence on consideration of the record as a whole; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">is not in accordance with law.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An appeal to the Court of Special Appeals may be taken from the decision of the Circuit Court for Baltimore City as in other civil cases.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner shall be made a party to each appeal to the Court of Special Appeals under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
