<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-19-807</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "health care provider" includes a health care practitioner licensed under Title 4 o...</catch_line>
  <order_by>807</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "health care provider" includes a health care practitioner licensed under Title 4 of the Health Occupations Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner shall disburse money from the Medical Assistance Program Account to the Secretary.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary shall transfer to the Community Health Resources Commission Fund established under &#xA7; 19-2201 of the Health - General Article, within 30 days following the end of each quarter during fiscal year 2008 and each fiscal year thereafter, the money collected from a nonprofit health maintenance organization in accordance with &#xA7; 6-121(b)(3) of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In fiscal year 2005, disbursements from the Medical Assistance Program Account shall be used by the Secretary to increase capitation rates paid to managed care organizations.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Beginning in fiscal year 2006 and annually thereafter, to maintain the rate increases provided under this paragraph, disbursements from the Medical Assistance Program Account of $15,000,000 shall be used by the Secretary to increase fee-for-service health care provider rates and to pay managed care organization health care providers consistent with fee-for-service health care provider rates for procedures commonly performed by:<section prefix="(i)">obstetricians;</section><section prefix="(ii)">neurosurgeons;</section><section prefix="(iii)">orthopedic surgeons; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">emergency medicine physicians.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Portions of the Medical Assistance Program Account that exceed the amount provided under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be used by the Secretary only to:<section prefix="(i)">increase capitation payments to managed care organizations consistent with &#xA7; 15-103(b)(18) of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">increase fee-for-service health care provider rates;</section><section prefix="(iii)">pay managed care organization health care providers consistent with the fee-for-service health care provider rates; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">after fiscal year 2008:<section prefix="1.">maintain increased capitation payments to managed care organizations;</section><section prefix="2.">maintain increased rates for health care providers;</section><section prefix="3.">in accordance with &#xA7; 6-121(b)(3) of this article, support the provision of office-based specialty care, diagnostic testing, and laboratory tests for individuals with family income that does not exceed 200% of the federal poverty level; and</section><section prefix="4.">support generally the operations of the Maryland Medical Assistance Program.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Health care provider rate increases under subsection (b)(2) and (3)(ii), (iii), and (iv)2 of this section shall be determined by the Secretary in consultation with managed care organizations, the Maryland Hospital Association, the Maryland State Medical Society, the American Academy of Pediatrics, Maryland Chapter, the American College of Emergency Room Physicians, Maryland Chapter, the Maryland State Dental Association, and the Maryland Dental Society.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary shall submit the plan for Medicaid health care provider rate increases under paragraph (1) of this subsection to the Senate Budget and Taxation Committee, Senate Finance Committee, House Appropriations Committee, and House Health and Government Operations Committee prior to adopting the regulations implementing the increase.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
