<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-11-603</section_number>
  <catch_line>A carrier subject to this subtitle may not charge a premium to a contract holder or to an individual...</catch_line>
  <order_by>603</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A carrier subject to this subtitle may not charge a premium to a contract holder or to an individual covered under a health benefit plan before the applicable premium rate is filed with and approved by the Commissioner.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A carrier subject to this subtitle may not change the premium charged to a contract holder or to an individual covered under a health benefit plan until the applicable premium rate change has been filed with and approved by the Commissioner.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any applicable premium rate or premium rate change of a carrier subject to this subtitle shall be filed with the Commissioner:<section prefix="(i)">for insurers, in accordance with &#xA7; 12-203 of this article and regulations adopted under Title 31, Subtitle 10 of the Code of Maryland Regulations;</section><section prefix="(ii)">for nonprofit health service plans, in accordance with &#xA7; 14-126 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">for health maintenance organizations, in accordance with &#xA7; 19-713 of the Health - General Article and regulations adopted under Title 31, Subtitle 12 of the Code of Maryland Regulations.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Commissioner shall disapprove or modify a proposed premium rate filing if the proposed premium rates appear, based on statistical analysis and reasonable assumptions, to be inadequate, unfairly discriminatory, or excessive in relation to benefits.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In determining whether to disapprove or modify a premium rate filing of a carrier, the Commissioner shall consider, to the extent appropriate:<section prefix="1.">past and prospective loss experience in and outside the State;</section><section prefix="2.">underwriting practice and judgment;</section><section prefix="3.">a reasonable margin for reserve needs;</section><section prefix="4.">past and prospective expenses, both countrywide and those specifically applicable to the State; and</section><section prefix="5.">any other relevant factors in and outside the State.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each premium rate filing and any supporting information filed under this subtitle shall be open to public inspection as soon as filed.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A carrier may request a finding by the Commissioner that certain information filed with the Commissioner be considered confidential commercial information under &#xA7; 10-617(d) of the State Government Article and not subject to public inspection.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">On request and payment of a reasonable fee, a person may obtain copies of a premium rate filing and any supporting information.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding the Commissioner's previous approval of a premium rate filing of a carrier subject to this section, the Commissioner, at any time, may require the carrier to demonstrate that, based on statistical analysis and reasonable assumptions and considering the factors listed in subsection (c)(2) of this section, its premium rates for a health benefit plan are not inadequate, unfairly discriminatory, or excessive in relation to benefits.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If, after the applicable review period, the Commissioner finds that the premium rates in a premium rate filing of a carrier subject to this section are inadequate, unfairly discriminatory, or excessive, as determined under subsection (c)(2) of this section, the Commissioner shall issue to the carrier an order that:<section prefix="(i)">specifies the reasons why the premium rate filing is inadequate, unfairly discriminatory, or excessive in relation to benefits under subsection (c)(2) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">states when, within a reasonable period after the order, the premium rate filing will no longer be effective.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Commissioner shall hold a hearing before issuing an order under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Commissioner shall give written notice of the hearing to the carrier at least 10 days before the hearing.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The written notice shall specify the matters to be considered at the hearing.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An order issued under paragraph (1) of this subsection does not affect a health benefit plan issued or delivered before the expiration of the period stated in the order.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Each decision or finding of the Commissioner about premium rates made under this subtitle is subject to judicial review in accordance with Subtitle 5 of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
