<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-26-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>An applicant for an initial license shall:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An applicant for an initial license shall:<section prefix="(1)">file with the Commissioner an application on the form that the Commissioner provides; and</section><section prefix="(2)">pay to the Commissioner an application fee of $200.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant for a license shall submit to the Commissioner the information that the Commissioner considers reasonably necessary to determine, in accordance with this title, whether to issue a license to the applicant.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The application shall be executed under oath by the applicant or, if the applicant is not an individual, by an authorized officer of the applicant.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The application shall include:<section prefix="(1)">if the applicant is a corporation:<section prefix="(i)">a certificate of good standing from the Department of Assessments and Taxation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the names and addresses of the officers and directors of the corporation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the names and addresses of each owner of more than 10% of the capital stock of the corporation issued and outstanding;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">if the applicant is not a corporation:<section prefix="(i)">a list of all the owners of interests in the applicant;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a list of the officers of the applicant; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">a list of the parties to any operating or management agreement that affects the applicant, together with a copy of the agreement;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">a financial statement certified by a certified public accountant within the previous 6 months, that presents fairly, in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles, the financial position of the applicant and contains the information that the Commissioner requires;</section><section prefix="(4)">a copy of the applicant's service contract, as described in &#xA7; 26-402 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(5)">evidence of security in accordance with &#xA7; 26-204 of this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
