<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-308" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-9-308</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commissioner:<section prefix="(1)">shall notify the Corporation of the existence of an insolvent insurer not later than 3 days after the Commissioner receives notice of the determination of insolvency; and</section><section prefix="(2)">on request of the Board of Directors, shall provide the Corporation with a statement of the net direct written premiums of each member insurer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Commissioner may require that the Corporation notify each insured, or each principal and specific obligee named in a surety bond, of each insolvent insurer and any other known interested party of the determination of insolvency and of their rights under this subtitle.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The notification required under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph may be by mail at the last known address of the interested party, but if sufficient information for notification by mail is not available, notification by publication in a newspaper of general circulation is sufficient.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner:<section prefix="(i)">after notice and hearing, may suspend or revoke the certificate of authority of a member insurer that fails to pay an assessment when due or fails to comply with the plan of operation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, may impose a penalty on a member insurer that fails to pay an assessment when due.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A penalty imposed under paragraph (2)(ii) of this subsection may not exceed 5% of the unpaid assessment per month and may not be less than $100 per month.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the Commissioner determines that claims are being handled unsatisfactorily, the Commissioner may revoke the designation of a person as a servicing facility.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A final action or order of the Commissioner under this subtitle is subject to judicial review.</section>
  </text>
</law>
