<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-424" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-8-424</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A foreign or alien society may not transact insurance business in the State unless the society has a certificate of authority issued by the Commissioner.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A foreign or alien society that desires to transact insurance business in the State must have the qualifications required of domestic societies organized under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A foreign or alien society may be authorized to transact insurance business in the State if the society:<section prefix="(1)">shows that its assets are invested in accordance with this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">files with the Commissioner:<section prefix="(i)">a certified copy of its charter or articles of incorporation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a copy of its constitution and laws, certified by its secretary or equivalent officer;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a power of attorney as required by &#xA7; 8-407 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a statement of the society's insurance business that is:</section><section prefix="(v)">a certificate of compliance from the proper official of its home state, territory, province, or country that the society is legally incorporated and authorized to transact insurance business in that state, territory, province, or country;</section><section prefix="(vi)">copies of its forms of certificates; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">any additional information that the Commissioner considers necessary.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each foreign or alien society authorized to do insurance business in the State shall file with the Commissioner, within 90 days after enactment, a certified copy of each amendment of, or addition to, its articles of incorporation, constitution, or laws.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner may deny a certificate of authority to a foreign or alien society applicant or suspend or revoke a certificate of authority of a foreign or alien society if, on investigation, the Commissioner finds that the society:<section prefix="(i)">has exceeded its powers;</section><section prefix="(ii)">has failed to comply with any provision of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(iii)">is not fulfilling its contracts in good faith;</section><section prefix="(iv)">is conducting its insurance business fraudulently; or</section><section prefix="(v)">is conducting its insurance business in a manner hazardous to its members, creditors, or the public.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Commissioner makes a finding under subsection (a) of this section, the Commissioner shall:<section prefix="(i)">notify the society of the finding;</section><section prefix="(ii)">state in writing the reasons for dissatisfaction; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">require the society to show cause on or before a specified date why its certificate of authority should not be denied, suspended, or revoked.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If, on or before the date specified in the notice, the society does not show good and sufficient reason why its certificate of authority should not be denied, suspended, or revoked, the Commissioner may:<section prefix="(i)">deny or suspend the certificate of authority until satisfactory evidence is provided to the Commissioner that the denial or suspension should be withdrawn; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">revoke the certificate of authority.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The provisions of subsection (e) of this section do not prevent a foreign or alien society from continuing in good faith all contracts made in the State during the time the society was legally authorized to transact insurance business in the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
