<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-19-801</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>801</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Fund" means the Maryland Health Care Provider Rate Stabilization Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Health care provider" means a health care practitioner:<section prefix="(i)">licensed under Title 14 of the Health Occupations Article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">certified as a nurse midwife under Title 8 of the Health Occupations Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Health care provider" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">a respiratory care practitioner;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a radiation oncology/therapy technologist;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a medical radiation technologist; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">a nuclear medicine technologist.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Medical injury" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 3-2A-01 of the Courts Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Medical professional liability insurer" means an insurer that:<section prefix="(1)">holds a certificate of authority issued by the Commissioner under &#xA7; 4-109 or &#xA7; 4-112 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">issues or delivers a policy in the State that insures a health care provider against damages due to medical injury.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Secretary" means the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Subsidy factor" means, for medical professional liability insurance policies subject to rates that were approved for an initial effective date on or after January 1, 2006, a percentage of the policyholder's premium for the prior year that equals the quotient, measured as a percentage of the balance of the Rate Stabilization Account for the current calendar year divided by the aggregate amount of premiums for medical professional liability insurance that would have been paid by health care providers at the approved rate during the prior calendar year.</section>
  </text>
</law>
