<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-19-208</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>208</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A policy of homeowner's, fire, farmowner's, or dwelling insurance that provides coverage for additional living expenses incurred by an insured as a result of a covered loss may not be issued, sold, or delivered in the State if the policy contains language that limits coverage for additional living expenses to a period of time that is less than 12 months.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A clause in a policy of homeowner's, fire, farmowner's, or dwelling insurance that purports to limit coverage for additional living expenses incurred by an insured as a result of a covered loss to a period of time that is less than 12 months is void and unenforceable.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, the Commissioner may require an insurer to provide coverage for additional living expenses under a policy of homeowner's, fire, farmowner's, or dwelling insurance for up to 24 months if the Commissioner finds that covered property remains uninhabitable due to delays in repair or replacement caused:<section prefix="(1)">by the insurer; or</section><section prefix="(2)">by factors beyond the control of the insured.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Nothing in this section shall be construed to:<section prefix="(1)">prohibit or prevent the enforcement of a monetary limit of liability for additional living expenses under a policy of homeowner's, fire, farmowner's, or dwelling insurance;</section><section prefix="(2)">prohibit an insurer from denying coverage for additional living expenses if the carrier determines that at the time the additional living expenses were incurred the covered property was not unfit to live in; or</section><section prefix="(3)">prohibit an insurer from denying coverage for additional living expenses on the grounds that the covered property was unfit to live in at the time that the additional living expenses were incurred because of delays in repair or replacement caused by the insured.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
