<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-19-506</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>506</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the first named insured does not wish to obtain the benefits described in &#xA7; 19-505 of this subtitle, the first named insured shall make an affirmative written waiver of those benefits.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the first named insured does not make an affirmative written waiver under this section, the insurer shall provide the coverage described in &#xA7; 19-505 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A waiver made under this section constitutes a waiver of all the benefits described in &#xA7; 19-505 of this subtitle, whether provided under:<section prefix="(i)">the first named insured's policy;</section><section prefix="(ii)">any other motor vehicle liability insurance policy issued in the State; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">another form of security used in place of a motor vehicle liability insurance policy as authorized under &#xA7; 17-103 of the Transportation Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, a waiver made under this section is binding on the following individuals covered by the policy:<section prefix="(i)">each named insured;</section><section prefix="(ii)">each listed driver; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">each member of the first named insured's family residing in the first named insured's household who is at least 16 years old.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An individual listed in paragraph (2)(ii) or (iii) of this subsection may recover the benefits described in &#xA7; 19-505 of this subtitle under another motor vehicle liability insurance policy if that individual:<section prefix="(i)">is the first named insured under the other policy;</section><section prefix="(ii)">has not waived the benefits described in &#xA7; 19-505 of this subtitle under the other policy; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">is not a named insured under any other motor vehicle liability insurance policy under which a waiver of the benefits described in &#xA7; 19-505 of this subtitle is in effect.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A waiver made under this section is not effective unless, prior to the waiver, the insurer gives the first named insured written notice of the nature, extent, and cost of the coverage described in &#xA7; 19-505 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A waiver made under this section shall be made on the form that the Commissioner requires.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The form may be part of the insurance contract.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The form shall clearly and concisely explain in 10 point boldface type:<section prefix="(i)">the nature, extent, and cost of the coverage that would be provided under the policy if not waived by the first named insured;</section><section prefix="(ii)">each effect of a waiver as stated in subsection (b) of this section;</section><section prefix="(iii)">that a failure of the first named insured to make a waiver requires an insurer to provide the coverage described in &#xA7; 19-505 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(iv)">that an insurer may not refuse to underwrite a person because the person refuses to waive the coverage described in &#xA7; 19-505 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(v)">that a waiver made under this section must be an affirmative written waiver.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A waiver made under this section by a person that is insured continuously by the Maryland Automobile Insurance Fund or the insurer is effective until the waiver is withdrawn in writing.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An insurer may not refuse to underwrite a person because the person refuses to waive the coverage described in &#xA7; 19-505 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An insurer that violates this subsection is subject to the penalties provided by &#xA7;&#xA7; 4-113 and 4-114 of this article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
