<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-25-102</section_number>
  <catch_line>A risk retention group that seeks to be chartered in the State:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>102</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A risk retention group that seeks to be chartered in the State:<section prefix="(1)">shall be chartered and licensed as a liability insurance company in conformance with all insurance laws and regulations of the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, shall comply with:<section prefix="(i)">all the laws, regulations, and requirements applicable to insurers chartered and licensed in the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the requirements of &#xA7; 25-103 of this subtitle, to the extent that those requirements are not a limitation on the laws, regulations, or requirements of the State.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before a risk retention group may offer insurance in a state, the risk retention group shall submit a plan of operation or feasibility study to the Commissioner for approval.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 10 days of a change to an item of the plan of operation or feasibility study, the risk retention group shall submit to the Commissioner an appropriate revision of the plan of operation or feasibility study.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A risk retention group may not offer additional lines of liability insurance in this State or in another state until a revision of the plan of operation or feasibility study is approved by the Commissioner.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">When a risk retention group files an application for charter, the risk retention group shall provide to the Commissioner the following information:<section prefix="(1)">the name of the risk retention group;</section><section prefix="(2)">the identity of the initial members of the risk retention group;</section><section prefix="(3)">the identity of the individuals who organized the risk retention group, or who will provide administrative services or otherwise influence or control the activities of the risk retention group;</section><section prefix="(4)">the amount and nature of initial capitalization;</section><section prefix="(5)">the coverages to be afforded; and</section><section prefix="(6)">the states in which the risk retention group intends to operate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On receipt of the information required by subsection (c) of this section, the Commissioner shall forward the information to the National Association of Insurance Commissioners.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Providing notification to the National Association of Insurance Commissioners is in addition to and may not be sufficient to satisfy the other requirements of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
