<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-9-307</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Corporation shall submit to the Commissioner a plan of operation and any amendments to it necess...</catch_line>
  <order_by>307</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Corporation shall submit to the Commissioner a plan of operation and any amendments to it necessary or suitable to ensure the fair, reasonable, and equitable administration of the Corporation.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The plan of operation and any amendments to it take effect when approved in writing by the Commissioner.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the Corporation fails to submit suitable amendment to the plan of operation, the Commissioner, after notice and hearing, shall adopt reasonable regulations as necessary or advisable to carry out this subtitle.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Regulations adopted under this paragraph shall continue in effect until modified by the Commissioner or superseded by an amendment to the plan of operation submitted by the Corporation and approved by the Commissioner.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each member insurer shall comply with the plan of operation.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The plan of operation shall:<section prefix="(1)">establish procedures for the performance of the powers and duties of the Corporation specified in &#xA7; 9-306 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">establish procedures for handling the assets of the Corporation;</section><section prefix="(3)">establish the amounts to be reimbursed and the method of reimbursing members of the Board of Directors under &#xA7; 9-305 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(4)">establish procedures for filing claims with the Corporation;</section><section prefix="(5)">establish acceptable forms of proof of covered claims;</section><section prefix="(6)">establish regular places and times for meetings of the Board of Directors;</section><section prefix="(7)">establish procedures for keeping records of the financial transactions of the Corporation, its agents, and the Board of Directors;</section><section prefix="(8)">provide that a member insurer that is aggrieved by a final action or decision of the Corporation may appeal to the Commissioner within 30 days after the action or decision; and</section><section prefix="(9)">contain any additional provisions necessary or proper to perform the powers and duties of the Corporation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notice of a claim to the receiver or liquidator of an insolvent insurer shall be deemed notice to the Corporation or its agent.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The receiver or liquidator periodically shall submit to the Corporation a list of claims of which the receiver or liquidator has received notice.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The plan of operation may provide that any or all of the powers and duties of the Corporation, except those under &#xA7; 9-306(d) and (f)(2) of this subtitle, may be delegated to a person that performs or will perform functions similar to those of the Corporation or its equivalent.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person to which powers and duties are delegated under the plan of operation shall be:<section prefix="(i)">reimbursed as a servicing facility would be reimbursed; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">paid for its performance of the functions of the Corporation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A delegation under this subsection may:<section prefix="(i)">take effect only with the approval of the Board of Directors and Commissioner; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">be made only to a person that extends protection not substantially less favorable and effective than that provided by this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
