<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-31-107</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>107</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Maryland Health Benefit Exchange Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The purpose of the Fund is to provide funding for the operation and administration of the Exchange in carrying out the purposes of the Exchange under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Exchange shall administer the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Treasurer shall hold the Fund separately, and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">any user fees or other assessments collected by the Exchange;</section><section prefix="(2)">income from investments made on behalf of the Fund;</section><section prefix="(3)">interest on deposits or investments of money in the Fund;</section><section prefix="(4)">money collected by the Board as a result of legal or other actions taken by the Board on behalf of the Exchange or the Fund;</section><section prefix="(5)">money donated to the Fund;</section><section prefix="(6)">money awarded to the Fund through grants; and</section><section prefix="(7)">any other money from any other source accepted for the benefit of the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Fund may be used only to provide funding for the operation and administration of the Exchange in carrying out the purposes authorized under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Treasurer shall invest the money of the Fund in the same manner as other State money may be invested.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any investment earnings of the Fund shall be credited to the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">No part of the Fund may revert or be credited to the General Fund or any special fund of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A debt or an obligation of the Fund is not a debt of the State or a pledge of credit of the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
