<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-326" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-11-326</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any data, documents, or other information filed with the Commissioner under Part IV of this subtitle about a particular insurer or that insurer's market share or plan:<section prefix="(i)">shall be considered confidential commercial information;</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall be kept confidential by the Commissioner; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">may not be made public or be subject to subpoena, other than by the Commissioner for the purpose of enforcement of Part IV of this subtitle by the Commissioner.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner:<section prefix="(i)">may release a list of the names of all insurers designated as major insurers; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">may not release the particular market share of a major insurer in Baltimore City unless authorized by the insurer.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before July 1, 1997, the Commissioner shall submit a report to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly about the availability and affordability of private passenger motor vehicle insurance in Baltimore City.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The report shall provide information on:<section prefix="(i)">the number of insurers actively engaged in providing coverage in Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the market shares of insurers in the market in Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the changes in market shares of insurers in the market in Baltimore City; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">whether insurance is available from insurers other than the Maryland Automobile Insurance Fund.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
