<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-27-705</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>705</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An unauthorized foreign insurer or unauthorized alien insurer is deemed to have appointed the Commissioner to be the attorney of the unauthorized insurer for purposes of service of statements of charges, notices, and process in a proceeding instituted under this title for a misrepresentation set forth in &#xA7; 27-703 of this subtitle or in a proceeding for the recovery of a penalty under this title and to have agreed that service on the Commissioner has the same legal effect as personal service in the State on the unauthorized insurer if the unauthorized insurer in the State, by mail or otherwise:<section prefix="(1)">issues or delivers insurance contracts to residents of the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">solicits applications for insurance contracts;</section><section prefix="(3)">collects premiums, membership fees, assessments, or other consideration for insurance contracts; or</section><section prefix="(4)">transacts any other insurance business.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Service of statements of charges and notices under this title shall be made by a deputy or employee of the Administration by delivering to and leaving with the Commissioner or an individual in apparent charge of the office of the Commissioner two copies of the statement of charges or notice.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Service of process issued by a court in a proceeding to collect a penalty under this title shall be made by delivering to and leaving with the Commissioner or an individual in apparent charge of the office of the Commissioner two copies of the process.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Immediately after receipt of a statement of charges, notice, or process, the Commissioner shall cause one copy of the statement of charges, notice, or process to be sent by certified mail to the unauthorized insurer at its last known principal place of business.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Service of statements of charges, notices, or process under this subsection is sufficient if:<section prefix="(i)">the statement of charges, notice, or process is mailed as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">on or before the date that the unauthorized insurer is required to appear or within any further time that may be allowed, the following items are filed with the Commissioner, in the case of a statement of charges or notice, or with the clerk of the court in which the action is pending, in the case of process:<section prefix="1.">the unauthorized insurer's receipt, or the receipt issued by the United States Postal Service, showing the name of the sender of the letter and the name and address of the addressee; and</section><section prefix="2.">an affidavit of the individual who did the mailing showing compliance with paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Commissioner shall keep a record of all statements of charges, notices, and process served on the Commissioner under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">As an alternative to service under subsection (b) of this section, service of statements of charges, notices, or process is valid if:<section prefix="(1)">service is made on any person in the State that, on behalf of the unauthorized insurer:<section prefix="(i)">solicits insurance in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">makes, issues, or delivers an insurance contract in the State; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">collects or receives in the State a premium for insurance;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">within 10 days after service under item (1) of this subsection, a copy of the statement of charges, notice, or process is sent by certified mail by or on behalf of the Commissioner to the unauthorized insurer at its last known principal place of business; and</section><section prefix="(3)">on or before the date that the unauthorized insurer is required to appear or within any further time that the court allows, the following items are filed with the Commissioner, in the case of a statement of charges or notice, or with the clerk of the court in which the action is pending, in the case of process:<section prefix="(i)">the unauthorized insurer's receipt, or the receipt issued by the United States Postal Service, showing the name of the sender of the letter and the name and address of the addressee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">an affidavit of the individual who did the mailing showing compliance with item (1) of this subsection.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A cease or desist order, judgment by default, or judgment by confession under this section may not be entered until the expiration of 30 days after the date of the filing of the affidavit of compliance.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Service of process and notice under this article is in addition to all other methods of service provided by law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This article does not limit or prohibit the right to serve any statement of charges, notice, or process on an insurer in any other manner authorized by law.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
