<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-209" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-8-209</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A managing general agent may not:<section prefix="(1)">commit the insurer to participate in insurance or reinsurance syndicates;</section><section prefix="(2)">appoint or hire an insurance producer to solicit, procure, or negotiate insurance contracts for the insurer without ensuring that the insurance producer is licensed under Title 10, Subtitle 1 of this article;</section><section prefix="(3)">take an action that would violate &#xA7; 27-503 of this article if taken directly by the insurer;</section><section prefix="(4)">without the insurer's written approval, pay or commit the insurer to pay a claim, net of reinsurance, that exceeds 1% of the insurer's policyholder surplus as of December 31 of the immediately preceding calendar year;</section><section prefix="(5)">without the insurer's prior written approval, collect any payment from a reinsurer;</section><section prefix="(6)">commit the insurer to a claim settlement with a reinsurer;</section><section prefix="(7)">employ an individual who also is employed by the insurer;</section><section prefix="(8)">allow an agent or employee of the managing general agent to serve on the insurer's board of directors; or</section><section prefix="(9)">appoint a submanaging general agent unless:<section prefix="(i)">approval of the appointment is obtained from the Commissioner and from the insurer for whom the managing general agent acts; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the submanaging general agent complies with any requirements imposed by the Commissioner under &#xA7; 8-213 of this subtitle.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a managing general agent may not bind reinsurance or retrocessions for an insurer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A managing general agent may bind facultative reinsurance contracts under obligatory facultative agreements if the contract with the insurer contains reinsurance underwriting guidelines for reinsurance both assumed and ceded, including:<section prefix="(i)">a list of reinsurers with which the automatic agreements are in effect;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the coverages and amounts or percentages that may be reinsured; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">commission schedules.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
