<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-24-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Legal Mutual Liability Insurance Society of Maryland....</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Legal Mutual Liability Insurance Society of Maryland.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Society is a nonstock corporation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, the Society has the powers, privileges, and immunities granted by and is subject to the provisions imposed on mutual insurers by this article and by the applicable provisions of the Corporations and Associations Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Society is not subject to &#xA7; 3-105, &#xA7; 3-106, &#xA7; 3-107, or &#xA7; 3-118 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Society is a member of the Property and Casualty Insurance Guaranty Corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Society is not and may not be deemed a department, unit, agency, or instrumentality of the State for any purpose.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">All debts, claims, obligations, and liabilities of the Society, whenever incurred, shall be the debts, claims, obligations, and liabilities of the Society only and not of the State or the State's agencies, instrumentalities, officers, or employees.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The moneys of the Society are not part of the General Fund of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State may not budget for or provide General Fund appropriations to the Society.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The debts, claims, obligations, and liabilities of the Society are not a debt of the State or a pledge of the credit of the State.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
