<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-220" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-11-220</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A member of or subscriber to a rating organization may appeal to the Commissioner from the action or decision of the rating organization in approving or rejecting a proposed change in or addition to the filings of the rating organization.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner:<section prefix="(i)">shall issue an order that approves the action or decision of the rating organization or directs it to give further consideration to the proposal; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the appeal is from the action or decision of the rating organization in rejecting a proposed addition to its filings and the Commissioner finds that the action or decision was unreasonable, may issue an order that directs the rating organization to make, within a reasonable time after issuance of the order, an addition to its filings on behalf of its members and subscribers in a manner consistent with the Commissioner's findings.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commissioner shall hold a hearing before issuing an order under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Commissioner shall give written notice of the hearing to the appellant and rating organization at least 10 days before the hearing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the appeal is based on the failure of a rating organization to make a filing on behalf of the member or subscriber that is based on a system of expense provisions that differs from the system of expense provisions included in a filing made by the rating organization, as authorized under &#xA7; 11-205(e) of this subtitle, and the Commissioner grants the appeal, the Commissioner shall issue an order that requires the rating organization to make the requested filing for use by the appellant.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In deciding the appeal, the Commissioner shall apply the standards set forth in this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
