<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-19-304</section_number>
  <catch_line>If, after a public hearing, the Commissioner finds that there is an abnormally high incidence of ars...</catch_line>
  <order_by>304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If, after a public hearing, the Commissioner finds that there is an abnormally high incidence of arson in properties that are insured through commercial monoline fire policies, have a certain type of occupancy, or are located in a certain geographic area of the State, the Commissioner shall require that an antiarson application be used to obtain property insurance covering the peril of fire for property that is insured through that type of policy, has that type of occupancy, or is located in that geographic area of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commissioner shall require that an antiarson application be completed when a property insurance policy or contract covering the peril of fire is assigned because of the transfer of a major financial interest in the insured real property, if an antiarson application otherwise would be required under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If, after a public hearing, the Commissioner finds that properties that are insured through a type of policy other than a commercial monoline fire policy have an abnormally high incidence of arson, the Commissioner may extend the application of this subtitle to properties insured through that other type of policy.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner may not require the use of any application for property insurance covering the peril of fire other than an antiarson application.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Paragraph (1) of this subsection does not prohibit the Commissioner from requiring the use of alternative antiarson applications in accordance with &#xA7; 19-306 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
