<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-1303" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-1303</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to any other requirements under this article, a carrier that offers individual health benefit plans in this State shall:<section prefix="(1)">have demonstrated the capacity to administer the individual health benefit plans, including adequate numbers and types of administrative staff;</section><section prefix="(2)">have a satisfactory grievance procedure and ability to respond to calls, questions, and complaints from enrollees or insureds; and</section><section prefix="(3)">design policies to help ensure that enrollees or insureds have adequate access to providers of health care.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in this subsection and &#xA7; 31-110(f) of this article, a carrier may not offer individual health benefit plans in the State unless the carrier also offers qualified health plans, as defined in &#xA7; 31-101 of this article, in the Individual Exchange of the Maryland Health Benefit Exchange in compliance with the requirements of Title 31 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A carrier is exempt from the requirement in paragraph (1) of this subsection if:<section prefix="(i)">the reported total aggregate annual earned premium from all individual health benefit plans in the State for the carrier and any other carriers in the same insurance holding company system, as defined in &#xA7; 7-101 of this article, is less than $10,000,000;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Commissioner determines that the carrier complies with the procedures established under paragraph (3) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">when the carrier ceases to meet the requirements for the exemption, the carrier provides to the Commissioner immediate notice and its plan for complying with the requirement in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commissioner shall establish procedures for a carrier to submit evidence each year that the carrier meets the requirements necessary to qualify for an exemption under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Notwithstanding the exemption provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, any carrier that offers a catastrophic plan, as defined by the Affordable Care Act, in the State also must offer at least one catastrophic plan in the Maryland Health Benefit Exchange.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Notwithstanding the exemption provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Commissioner, in consultation with the Maryland Health Benefit Exchange:<section prefix="(i)">may assess the impact of the exemption provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection and, based on that assessment, alter the limit on the amount of annual premiums that may not be exceeded to qualify for the exemption; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall make any change in the exemption requirement by regulation.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For each calendar quarter, a carrier that offers individual health benefit plans in the State shall submit to the Commissioner a report that includes:<section prefix="(i)">the number of applications submitted to the carrier for individual coverage; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the number of declinations issued by the carrier for individual coverage.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The report required under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be filed with the Commissioner no later than 30 days after the last day of the quarter for which the information is provided.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a carrier denies coverage under a medically underwritten health benefit plan to an individual in the nongroup market, the carrier shall provide:<section prefix="(i)">the individual with specific information regarding the availability of coverage under the Maryland Health Insurance Plan established under Title 14, Subtitle 5 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Maryland Health Insurance Plan with:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The information provided by a carrier under this subsection shall be provided in a manner and form required by the Commissioner.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
