<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-3-126</section_number>
  <catch_line>A foreign insurer authorized to engage in the insurance business in the State may become a domestic ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>126</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A foreign insurer authorized to engage in the insurance business in the State may become a domestic insurer by:<section prefix="(i)">complying with all requirements of the law relating to the formation and organization of a domestic insurer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">designating its principal place of business in the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On becoming a domestic insurer, the insurer:<section prefix="(i)">is entitled to the certificates and licenses to transact insurance business in this State that are issued to domestic insurers;</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall be recognized in all respects as an insurer formed under the laws of this State as of the date of authorization as an insurer in its original domiciliary state; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">is subject to the authority and jurisdiction of the State.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When a foreign insurer authorized to engage in the insurance business in this State transfers its corporate domicile to this State or another state by merger, consolidation, or other lawful method, the certificate of authority, appointments of agents, rates, and other issues that are subject to the Commissioner's approval and that are in existence at the time of the transfer remain in effect after the transfer if the insurer at all times remains qualified to engage in the insurance business in this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">All outstanding policies of a transferring insurer remain in effect and need not be endorsed with the new name of the insurer or the new domiciliary and location of the insurer unless the Commissioner so orders.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A transferring insurer:<section prefix="(i)">may file new policy forms with the Commissioner on or before the effective date of the transfer; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if allowed by and under conditions approved by the Commissioner, may use any existing policy form previously filed with the Commissioner with appropriate endorsements.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A foreign insurer that transfers its domicile to another state shall:<section prefix="(i)">notify the Commissioner of the details of the proposed transfer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">file promptly with the Commissioner any resulting amendments to corporate documents and other items on file with the Commissioner.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
