<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-14-504</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Maryland Health Insurance Plan Fund....</catch_line>
  <order_by>504</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Maryland Health Insurance Plan Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Treasurer shall separately hold and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Fund shall be invested and reinvested at the direction of the Board in a manner that is consistent with the requirements of Title 5, Subtitle 6 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Any investment earnings shall be retained to the credit of the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">On an annual basis, the Fund shall be subject to an independent actuarial review setting forth an opinion relating to reserves and related actuarial items held in support of policies and contracts.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The Fund shall be used only to provide funding for the purposes authorized under this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Fund shall consist of:<section prefix="(1)">premiums for coverage that the Plan issues;</section><section prefix="(2)">money collected in accordance with &#xA7; 19-219 of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="(3)">money deposited by a nonprofit health service plan in accordance with &#xA7; 14-513 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(4)">income from investments that the Board makes or authorizes on behalf of the Fund;</section><section prefix="(5)">interest on deposits or investments of money from the Fund;</section><section prefix="(6)">premium tax revenue collected under &#xA7; 14-107 of this title;</section><section prefix="(7)">money collected by the Board as a result of legal or other actions taken by the Board on behalf of the Fund;</section><section prefix="(8)">money donated to the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(9)">money awarded to the Fund through grants.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may allow the Administrator to use premiums collected by the Administrator from Plan enrollees to pay claims for Plan enrollees.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administrator:<section prefix="(i)">shall deposit all premiums for Plan enrollees in a separate account, titled in the name of the State of Maryland, for the Maryland Health Insurance Plan; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">may use money in the account only to pay claims for Plan enrollees.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Administrator shall keep complete and accurate records of all transactions for the separate account.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">By the 15th of the following month, if monthly premiums collected by the Administrator exceed monthly claims received, the Administrator shall deposit the remaining balance, including interest, for that month in the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall take steps necessary to ensure that Plan enrollment does not exceed the number of enrollees the Plan has the financial capacity to insure.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may adopt regulations to limit the enrollment of otherwise eligible medically uninsurable individuals whose premium is paid for by a pharmaceutical manufacturer or its affiliate if the Board determines that their enrollment would have an adverse financial impact on the Plan.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to the operation and administration of the Plan, the Fund shall be used:<section prefix="(i)">for the operation and administration of the Senior Prescription Drug Assistance Program established under Part II of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">to support the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene for the provision of mental health services to the uninsured under Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the Health - General Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall maintain separate accounts within the Fund for the Senior Prescription Drug Assistance Program and the Maryland Health Insurance Plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Accounts within the Fund shall contain those moneys that are intended to support the operation of the Program for which the account is designated.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A debt or obligation of the Plan is not a debt of the State or a pledge of credit of the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
