<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-19-402</section_number>
  <catch_line>An insurer may not issue a workers' compensation insurance policy unless the State Workers' Compensa...</catch_line>
  <order_by>402</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An insurer may not issue a workers' compensation insurance policy unless the State Workers' Compensation Commission has approved the form of the policy.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each policy of workers' compensation insurance shall include the following provisions:<section prefix="(1)">the State Workers' Compensation Commission, in the name of the State and for the benefit of a person entitled to compensation under the policy, may enforce the liability of the insurer for payment of compensation by:<section prefix="(i)">making the insurer a party to the original claim application; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">filing a separate claim application;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the bankruptcy or insolvency of an employer does not relieve the insurer from payment of compensation for injury or death of a covered employee occurring during the life of the policy;</section><section prefix="(3)">as between the employee and the insurer, if the employer receives notice or has knowledge of the occurrence of an accidental injury, occupational disease, hernia, or hearing loss, the insurer is deemed also to have received the notice or have the knowledge;</section><section prefix="(4)">for the purposes of Titles 9 and 10 of the Labor and Employment Article, the insurer is subject to the same jurisdiction as the employer; and</section><section prefix="(5)">each award, decision, finding, or order against the employer for payment of compensation under Titles 9 and 10 of the Labor and Employment Article also is binding on the insurer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person that violates subsection (a) of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $1,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner may revoke the certificate of authority of a person that is convicted under this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
