<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-1104</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the  meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Employer sponsored health benefit plan" means any  plan, fund, or program that:<section prefix="(i)">is established or maintained by an employer  under the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974;</section><section prefix="(ii)">offers coverage for health benefits; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">is treated by the employer or any eligible employee or dependent as part of a plan, fund, or program under  the United States Internal Revenue Code, 26 U.S.C. &#xA7; 106, &#xA7; 125, or &#xA7;  162.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Group health insurance" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 15-302 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Limited benefit group health insurance contract"  means a group health insurance contract that provides health  insurance benefits, but is not required to provide all the benefits  required under Subtitles 7 and 8 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Special eligible employee" means an employee who:<section prefix="(i)">is eligible for health coverage under the terms of an employer sponsored health benefit plan;</section><section prefix="(ii)">works:<section prefix="1.">on a temporary or substitute basis; or</section><section prefix="2.">less than 30 hours in a normal workweek;  and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">is not eligible for coverage under any group health insurance contract, nonprofit health service plan  contract, or health maintenance organization contract issued to  the employee's employer because the employee meets the criteria of item (ii) of this paragraph.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A limited benefit group health insurance contract may be  issued only by an insurer or nonprofit health service plan to an  employer if the limited group health insurance contract is issued  to provide health coverage only for:<section prefix="(1)">special eligible employees; or</section><section prefix="(2)">special eligible employees and their dependents.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An insurer or nonprofit health service plan that sells a limited benefit group health insurance contract, as a condition of  sale, may require the employer to:<section prefix="(1)">collect payment for premiums due under the limited benefit group health insurance contract through payroll  deduction;</section><section prefix="(2)">contribute to the premium payments applicable to  the coverage of a special eligible employee; and</section><section prefix="(3)">offer coverage to any dependent of a special  eligible employee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A limited benefit group health insurance contract shall  comply with:<section prefix="(1)">this title, except Subtitles 7 and 8 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(2)">notwithstanding item (1) of this subsection, &#xA7;&#xA7; 15-802, 15-812, 15-815, 15-830, 15-831, 15-832, and 15-833 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An insurer or nonprofit health service plan shall  disclose in the group certificate and in enrollment material  provided to each special eligible employee that the limited benefit  group health insurance contract does not provide comprehensive  health coverage.</section>
  </text>
</law>
