<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-12-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to a contract of group life insurance or group or blanket health insurance.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, a life insurance or health insurance contract may not be made or put into effect unless at the time of making the contract the individual to be insured:<section prefix="(i)">is of competent legal capacity to contract; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">applies for or consents in writing to the contract.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A spouse may put into effect life insurance or health insurance on the other spouse.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person with an insurable interest in the life of a minor, or a person on whom the minor is dependent for support and maintenance, may put into effect life insurance on or insurance relating to the minor.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A family policy that insures two or more family members may be issued on an application signed by a parent, stepparent, husband, or wife.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A person with an insurable interest in the life of a person who lacks the legal capacity to consent to life insurance may, on written application, put into effect life insurance on that person.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an agreement in an application for a life insurance or health insurance contract authorizes the insurer to issue a policy other than that applied for or to amend the application, the agreement must contain substantially the following language: "Except that no change in amount, classification, plan of insurance, or benefits may take effect unless agreed to in writing by the applicant".</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Ratification of an amendment under paragraph (1) of this subsection is made by the applicant's acceptance of the amended contract.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
