<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-205" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-2-205</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "analysis" means a process by which the Commissioner collects and analyzes information from filed schedules, surveys, required reports specified in subsection (b) of this section, and other sources in order to:<section prefix="(1)">develop an understanding of the affairs, transactions, accounts, records, assets, and financial condition of the entities specified in subsection (b) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(2)">identify or investigate patterns or practices of the entities specified in subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whenever the Commissioner considers it advisable, the Commissioner shall conduct an analysis or examine the affairs, transactions, accounts, records, assets, and financial condition of each:<section prefix="(i)">authorized insurer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">management company of an authorized insurer;</section><section prefix="(iii)">subsidiary owned or controlled by an authorized insurer;</section><section prefix="(iv)">rating organization; or</section><section prefix="(v)">authorized health maintenance organization.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner shall examine each domestic insurer and health maintenance organization at least once every 5 years.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner shall examine the affairs, transactions, accounts, records, and assets of:<section prefix="(1)">each insurer and each health maintenance organization that applies for an original certificate of authority to do business in the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">each rating organization that applies for a license to do business in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">When examining a reciprocal insurer, the Commissioner may examine the attorney in fact of the reciprocal insurer to the extent that the transactions of the attorney in fact relate to the reciprocal insurer.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commissioner may limit the examination of an alien insurer to its insurance transactions and affairs in the United States.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Instead of conducting an examination, the Commissioner may accept a full report, certified by the insurance supervisory official of another state, of the most recent examination of a foreign insurer or health maintenance organization, alien insurer or health maintenance organization, or an out-of-state rating organization.</section>
  </text>
</law>
