<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-1215</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1215</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each carrier shall elect to become either a risk-assuming carrier or reinsuring carrier.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notification of election to become a risk-assuming carrier shall include an appropriate opinion by an independent qualified actuary that the risk-assuming carrier is able to assume and manage the risk of enrolling groups under this subtitle without the protection of the Pool.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The initial election under this section is binding for 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After the initial 3 years, and every 5 years thereafter, each carrier shall again elect to be either a risk-assuming or reinsuring carrier.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each subsequent election is binding for 5 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Commissioner may allow a new carrier to make an election under conditions established by the Commissioner.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner may allow a carrier to change its election at any time for good cause shown.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In determining whether to approve an application by a carrier to change its election, the Commissioner shall consider:<section prefix="(i)">the applicant's financial condition and the financial condition of any parent or guaranteeing corporation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the applicant's history of assuming and managing risk;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the applicant's commitment to market fairly to all small employers in the State or in the applicant's service area;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the applicant's ability to assume and manage the risk of enrolling groups under this subtitle without the protection of the Pool; and</section><section prefix="(v)">the effect of approval of the application on the financial viability of the Pool.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">While the Commissioner is considering an application under this subsection, the carrier may request a hearing as provided under Title 11, Subtitle 5 of this article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
