<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-14-115</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>115</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Board" means the board of directors of a nonprofit health service plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Immediate family member" means a spouse, child, child's spouse, parent, spouse's parent, sibling, or sibling's spouse.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to a nonprofit health service plan that is:<section prefix="(1)">issued a certificate of authority in the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">organized under the laws of the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The business and affairs of a nonprofit health service plan shall be managed under the direction of a board of directors.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The board and its individual members are fiduciaries and shall act:<section prefix="1.">in good faith;</section><section prefix="2.">in a manner that is reasonably believed to be in the best interests of the corporation and its controlled affiliates or subsidiaries that offer health benefit plans;</section><section prefix="3.">in a manner that is reasonably believed to be in furtherance of the mission of the corporation as a nonprofit health service plan as required under &#xA7; 14-102(c) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="4.">with the care that an ordinarily prudent person in a like position would use under similar circumstances.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The board and its individual members may not use board membership for personal or financial enrichment to the detriment of the nonprofit health service plan or the mission of the nonprofit health service plan.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The principal functions of the board shall include:<section prefix="(i)">ensuring that the corporation effectively carries out the nonprofit mission established under &#xA7; 14-102(c) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">selecting corporate management and evaluating its performance;</section><section prefix="(iii)">ensuring to the extent practicable that human resources and other resources are sufficient to meet corporate objectives;</section><section prefix="(iv)">subject to the provisions of subsection (d) of this section, nominating and selecting suitable candidates for the board;</section><section prefix="(v)">establishing a system of governance at the board level, including an annual evaluation of board performance; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">before considering any bid or offer to acquire the nonprofit health service plan and to convert to a for-profit entity under Title 6.5 of the State Government Article, ensuring that adequate consideration is given to an independent valuation of the nonprofit health service plan.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Each member of the board shall demonstrate a commitment to the mission of the nonprofit health service plan as required by &#xA7; 14-102(c) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">An officer or employee of a nonprofit health service plan or any of its affiliates or subsidiaries may not be appointed or elected to the board.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A nonprofit health service plan is subject to the provisions of &#xA7; 2-419 of the Corporations and Associations Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to a corporation that is:<section prefix="(i)">issued a certificate of authority as a nonprofit health service plan; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the sole member of a corporation issued a certificate of authority as a nonprofit health service plan.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The board shall be composed of no more than 23 members, including:<section prefix="(i)">one nonvoting member, who is not a member of the Maryland General Assembly, appointed by and serving at the pleasure of the President of the Senate of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(ii)">one nonvoting member, who is not a member of the Maryland General Assembly, appointed by and serving at the pleasure of the Speaker of the House of Delegates; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">21 members selected by the board, in accordance with the bylaws of the corporation, including two consumer members, who satisfy the requirements of paragraphs (13), (14), and (15) of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">No more than four members of the board may be:<section prefix="(i)">licensed health care professionals;</section><section prefix="(ii)">hospital administrators; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">employees of health care professionals or hospitals.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">To the extent possible, the board shall include individuals with experience in accounting, information technology, finance, law, large and small businesses, nonprofit businesses, and organized labor.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Except for nonvoting members under paragraph (2)(i) and (ii) of this subsection, the board shall be self-perpetuating.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The board shall have the following standing committees whose duties shall include:<section prefix="(i)">an audit committee responsible for ensuring financial accountability;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a finance committee responsible for reviewing and making recommendations on the annual budget and for developing and recommending long-range financial objectives;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a compensation committee responsible for developing proposed compensation guidelines in accordance with &#xA7; 14-139(d) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a nominating committee responsible for identifying, evaluating, and recommending to the board individuals qualified to become board members, including individuals who represent a corporation for which the nonprofit health service plan is the sole member;</section><section prefix="(v)">a service and quality oversight committee responsible for ensuring that policies and processes are in effect to assess and improve the quality of health insurance products provided to subscribers and certificate holders;</section><section prefix="(vi)">a mission oversight committee responsible for ensuring that the officers of the corporation act in accordance with the mission of the nonprofit health service plan;</section><section prefix="(vii)">a strategic planning committee responsible for examining long-range planning objectives, assessing strategies that may be used to implement the planning objectives, and analyzing the nonprofit health service plan's role in the insurance marketplace; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">any other committee that the board determines is necessary to carry out its duties.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Each standing committee shall have representation from:<section prefix="(i)">the voting members under paragraph (2) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">each corporation for which the nonprofit health service plan is the sole member.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The compensation committee and the nominating committee shall each include either the appointee of the President of the Senate or the appointee of the Speaker of the House of Delegates.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">Each board member shall serve on at least one standing committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(10)">The chairman of the board shall select a chairman for each board committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(11)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The board shall approve in advance any action by the nonprofit health service plan, a corporation for which the plan is the sole member, or any affiliate or subsidiary of the nonprofit health service plan to:<section prefix="1.">materially modify options available in benefit plans marketed in the State;</section><section prefix="2.">materially modify Maryland provider networks or Maryland provider reimbursement levels;</section><section prefix="3.">materially modify underwriting guidelines for products marketed in the State;</section><section prefix="4.">materially modify rates or rating plans that are required to be approved by the Commissioner;</section><section prefix="5.">add a product to or withdraw a product from the Maryland market, withdraw from a line or type of business in the State, or withdraw from a geographic region in the State;</section><section prefix="6.">materially modify marketing goals and objectives in the State; or</section><section prefix="7.">materially impact the availability or affordability of health care in the State.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Commissioner shall adopt regulations that define "material" for purposes of subparagraph (i) of this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A decision by the board to convert to a for-profit entity under Title 6.5 of the State Government Article may be rejected by any three members of the board.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The board may delegate approval for the actions listed in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph to a standing committee of the board.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(12)">The board shall take and retain complete minutes of all board and committee meetings.</section>
      <section prefix="(13)">Of the two consumer members, one shall be a subscriber and one shall be a certificate holder of the nonprofit health service plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(14)">Each consumer member of the board:<section prefix="(i)">shall be a member of the general public;</section><section prefix="(ii)">may not be considered an agent or employee of the State for any purpose; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">is entitled to the same rights, powers, and privileges as the other members of the board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(15)">A consumer member of the board may not:<section prefix="(i)">be a licensee of or otherwise be subject to regulation by the Commissioner;</section><section prefix="(ii)">be employed by or have a financial interest in:<section prefix="1.">a nonprofit health service plan or its affiliates or subsidiaries; or</section><section prefix="2.">a person regulated under this article or the Health - General Article; or</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">within 3 years before appointment, have been employed by, had a financial interest in, or have received compensation from:<section prefix="1.">a nonprofit health service plan or its affiliates or subsidiaries; or</section><section prefix="2.">a person regulated under this article or the Health - General Article.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to a board that has fewer than three authorized members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The term of a member is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The terms of the members of a board shall be staggered over a 3-year period as required by the terms provided for members of the board in the bylaws filed and approved by the Commissioner on or after June 1, 2003.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A member may not serve for more than:<section prefix="(i)">three  full terms; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a total of more than 9 years.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">A person may not be a member of the board if the person:<section prefix="(i)">has defaulted on the payment of a monetary obligation to the nonprofit health service plan;</section><section prefix="(ii)">has been convicted of a criminal offense involving dishonesty or breach of trust or a felony;</section><section prefix="(iii)">habitually has neglected to pay debts; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">has been prohibited under any federal securities law from acting as a director or officer of any corporation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(8)">A member shall meet any other qualifications set forth in the bylaws of the nonprofit health service plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">A member may not be an immediate family member of another board member or an officer or employee of the nonprofit health service plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(10)">The board shall elect a chairman from among its members.</section>
      <section prefix="(11)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The composition of the board shall represent the racial and gender diversity of the State.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The board shall include representation from each geographic region of the State.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The board shall notify the Commissioner of any member who attends less than 65% of the meetings of the board during a period of 12 consecutive months.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Board members may receive the following compensation:<section prefix="(i)">reimbursement for ordinary and necessary expenses; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">an amount of base compensation and compensation for attendance at meetings in accordance with &#xA7; 14-139 of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A board member may not receive more than the amount specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection for serving on more than one board of a corporation subject to this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies to a corporation that is:<section prefix="1.">issued a certificate of authority as a nonprofit health service plan; and</section><section prefix="2.">the sole member of a corporation issued a certificate of authority as a nonprofit health service plan.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">On or before June 30 of each calendar year, a corporation subject to this paragraph shall report to the Commissioner on:<section prefix="1.">the total amount of base compensation, compensation for attendance at meetings, and reimbursement for ordinary and necessary expenses paid to each board member in the preceding calendar year; and</section><section prefix="2.">the proposed annual compensation, together with necessary supporting documentation, to be paid to board members for the next calendar year.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
