<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-18-109</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>109</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, a policy or certificate of long-term care insurance may not be delivered or issued for delivery in the State if the policy or certificate limits or excludes coverage by type of illness, treatment, medical condition, or accident.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A policy or certificate of long-term care insurance may limit or exclude coverage of:<section prefix="(1)">preexisting conditions or diseases;</section><section prefix="(2)">mental or nervous conditions or diseases other than Alzheimer's disease;</section><section prefix="(3)">alcohol or drug addiction;</section><section prefix="(4)">unless otherwise provided by State or federal law, treatment provided in a government facility;</section><section prefix="(5)">services provided by a member of the covered individual's immediate family;</section><section prefix="(6)">services for which a charge normally is not made in the absence of insurance;</section><section prefix="(7)">services for which benefits are available under:<section prefix="(i)">Medicare or other governmental programs except Medicaid; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a State or federal workers' compensation, employer's liability, or occupational disease law; and</section></section><section prefix="(8)">illness, treatment, or medical conditions arising out of:<section prefix="(i)">a declared or undeclared war or act of war;</section><section prefix="(ii)">participation in a felony, riot, or insurrection;</section><section prefix="(iii)">service in the armed forces or auxiliary units;</section><section prefix="(iv)">suicide, attempted suicide, or intentionally self-inflicted injury; or</section><section prefix="(v)">aviation, if the insured is a passenger who does not pay a fare.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section does not prohibit:<section prefix="(1)">exclusions and limitations by type of provider; or</section><section prefix="(2)">limitations by territory.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
