<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-8-464</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>464</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commissioner shall take action under subsection (b) of this section if, on investigation, the Commissioner finds that a domestic society:<section prefix="(1)">has exceeded its powers;</section><section prefix="(2)">has failed to comply with this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">is not fulfilling its contracts in good faith;</section><section prefix="(4)">has a membership of less than 400 after an existence of 1 year or more;</section><section prefix="(5)">is conducting its insurance business fraudulently; or</section><section prefix="(6)">is conducting its insurance business in a manner hazardous to its members, creditors, the public, or the business.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the Commissioner makes a finding under subsection (a) of this section, the Commissioner shall:<section prefix="(1)">notify the society of the finding;</section><section prefix="(2)">state in writing the reasons for dissatisfaction; and</section><section prefix="(3)">require the society to show cause on or before a specified date why:<section prefix="(i)">the society should not be enjoined from conducting any insurance business until the violation has been corrected; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an action seeking a mandatory injunction should not be commenced against the society.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If, on or before the date specified in the notice, the society does not present good and sufficient reason why it should not be enjoined from conducting insurance business or why an action seeking a mandatory injunction should not be commenced, the Commissioner may present the facts relating to the violation to the Attorney General.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On request of the Commissioner, the Attorney General may commence:<section prefix="(i)">an action to enjoin the society from conducting insurance business; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an action seeking a mandatory injunction.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The court shall schedule a hearing and notify the officers of the society of the hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If, after a full hearing, the court finds that a violation has occurred under subsection (a) of this section, the court shall pass an order:<section prefix="(i)">enjoining the society from conducting insurance business;</section><section prefix="(ii)">liquidating the society; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">appointing the Commissioner as receiver of the society.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A society enjoined from conducting insurance business under this section may not conduct insurance business until:<section prefix="(1)">the Commissioner finds that the violation has been corrected;</section><section prefix="(2)">the costs of the action have been paid by the society, if the court finds that the society was in default;</section><section prefix="(3)">the court has dissolved the injunction; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the Commissioner has reinstated the society's certificate of authority.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a court orders a society to be liquidated:<section prefix="(1)">the society may not conduct any further insurance business; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the receiver of the society immediately shall:<section prefix="(i)">take possession of the books, papers, money, and other assets of the society; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">close the affairs of the society and distribute its funds to those entitled to the funds under the direction of the court.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">This section also applies to a society that voluntarily determines to discontinue business.</section>
  </text>
</law>
