<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-10-118</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>118</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "producer register" means a register of appointed insurance producers who are authorized to sell, solicit, or negotiate contracts of insurance on behalf of an insurer.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An insurer authorized to transact the business of insurance in the State shall maintain a producer register.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 30 days of the insurer appointing an insurance producer, the insurer shall include the following information in the insurer's producer register:<section prefix="(i)">the insurance producer's name;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the license number assigned to the insurance producer by the Commissioner;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the date that the insurer appointed the insurance producer; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">any additional information that the Commissioner may require.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An insurer shall send written documentation of the appointment to the insurance producer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A licensed insurance producer that has been appointed by an insurer shall maintain:<section prefix="(1)">documentation of the insurer's appointment; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a list of the insurers that have appointed the producer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The insurer's producer register and the producer's record relating to an appointment:<section prefix="(i)">shall be open to inspection and examination by the Commissioner; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">may be maintained electronically.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, an insurance producer may not act on behalf of an insurer unless the insurance producer has received written documentation of the appointment from the insurer.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An insurer may initially accept an application for life insurance, health insurance, or an annuity from an insurance producer who is not appointed by the insurer and is not on the insurer's producer register if, within 30 days of accepting the application, the insurer:<section prefix="(i)">rejects the application in accordance with &#xA7; 27-501 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">appoints the insurance producer and enters in the insurer's producer register the information required by subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">When there is any termination of the appointment, employment, contract, or other insurance business relationship with an insurance producer, the insurer shall, within 30 days following the effective date of the termination, update the insurer's producer register by entering the effective date of the termination.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An insurer or authorized representative of an insurer shall notify the Commissioner of the termination of an appointment when the termination, in whole or in part, is a result of the belief that the producer has engaged or is engaging in any of the activities set forth in &#xA7; 10-126 of this subtitle, including any finding made by a court, governmental unit, or self-regulatory organization authorized by law that:<section prefix="1.">the insurance producer has violated &#xA7; 10-126 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="2.">the insurance producer has engaged in any activities that are set forth in &#xA7; 10-126 of this subtitle.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">On written request of the Commissioner, the insurer shall provide additional information, documents, records, or other data pertaining to:<section prefix="1.">the termination; or</section><section prefix="2.">the activities of the insurance producer if the insurance producer was terminated for cause due to a reason set forth in &#xA7; 10-126 of this subtitle.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the appointment of an insurance producer is terminated because the insurance producer failed to renew the insurance producer's license and the license is reinstated under &#xA7; 10-116.1(c)(1) of this subtitle, an insurer may reappoint the insurance producer retroactively, with the appointment effective on the date that the license expired.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An insurer or authorized representative of an insurer promptly shall notify the Commissioner, in a format acceptable to the Commissioner, of any additional information that:<section prefix="(1)">the insurer discovers on further review or investigation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">would have been reportable to the Commissioner under subsection (e) of this section if the insurer had then known of its existence.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 15 days after providing notice to the Commissioner that is required by subsection (e) of this section, an insurer shall mail a copy of the notice to the insurance producer:<section prefix="(i)">at the last known address of the insurance producer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">by certified mail, return receipt requested, postage prepaid or by overnight delivery using a nationally recognized carrier.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 30 days after an insurance producer receives original or additional notice, the insurance producer may file with the Commissioner written comments concerning the substance of the notice.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If an insurance producer files comments with the Commissioner, the insurance producer shall, by the same means, simultaneously send a copy of the comments to the reporting insurer.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the Commissioner receives comments from an insurance producer, the Commissioner shall:<section prefix="(i)">make the comments part of the Commissioner's file on the subject; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">include a copy of the comments with every copy of a report about the insurance producer that is distributed or disclosed for any reason permitted by subsection (i) of this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to:<section prefix="(i)">an insurer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an authorized representative of an insurer;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an insurance producer;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Commissioner; and</section><section prefix="(v)">an organization of which the Commissioner is a member that compiles information required under this section and makes it available to other insurance commissioners or regulatory or law enforcement agencies.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the absence of actual malice, a person to whom this subsection applies and the agents and employees of the person are not subject to civil liability of any nature as a result of:<section prefix="(i)">any statement or information required by or provided under this section; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">any information relating to any statement that may be requested in writing by the Commissioner from an insurer or insurance producer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a party brings an action against a person that may have immunity under paragraph (2) of this subsection for making a statement required by or under this section or providing any information relating to any statement that may be requested by the Commissioner, the party bringing the action shall plead specifically in any allegation that paragraph (2) of this subsection does not apply because the person making the statement or providing the information did so with actual malice.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">This subsection does not abrogate or modify any existing statutory or common law privileges or immunities.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only to any document, material, or other information in the control or possession of the Insurance Administration that is:<section prefix="(i)">furnished by an insurer or insurance producer or an employee or agent acting on behalf of the insurer or insurance producer under this section; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">otherwise obtained by the Insurance Commissioner in an investigation under this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any document, material, or other information that is subject to this subsection is:<section prefix="(i)">confidential and privileged;</section><section prefix="(ii)">not subject to Title 10, Subtitle 6 of the State Government Article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">not subject to subpoena; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">not subject to discovery or admissible in evidence in any private civil action.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Commissioner may use any document, material, or other information that is subject to this section to further any regulatory or legal action brought as part of the duties of the Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Commissioner and any person who received any document, material, or other information to which this subsection applies while acting under the authority of the Commissioner may not be allowed or required to testify in any private civil action concerning the document, material, or information.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Provided that the recipient agrees to maintain any confidentiality and privileged status, the Commissioner may share a document, material, or other information, including a document, material, or other information that is confidential and privileged under this subsection, with:<section prefix="1.">other State, federal, or international regulatory agencies;</section><section prefix="2.">the National Association of Insurance Commissioners and its affiliates or subsidiaries; or</section><section prefix="3.">State, federal, or international law enforcement authorities.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the Commissioner determines that a confidential document, material, or other information that has been shared through a database or other electronic filing system is inaccurate or incomplete in any way, the Commissioner shall update the information in the database or other electronic filing system so that the information is accurate and complete.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Commissioner may receive a document, material, or information, including a document, material, or information that is otherwise confidential and privileged, from:<section prefix="1.">the National Association of Insurance Commissioners or its affiliates or subsidiaries; or</section><section prefix="2.">regulatory and law enforcement officials of other foreign or domestic jurisdictions.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Commissioner shall maintain as confidential and privileged any document, material, or information received under this paragraph with notice or the understanding that it is confidential or privileged under the laws of the jurisdiction that is the source of the document, material, or information.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The Commissioner may enter into agreements governing sharing and use of information consistent with this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">There is no waiver of any applicable privilege or claim of confidentiality in a document, material, or information as a result of:<section prefix="(i)">disclosure of the document, material, or information to the Commissioner under this section; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">sharing of the document, material, or information by the Commissioner under paragraph (5) of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(9)">This subtitle does not prohibit the Commissioner from releasing final adjudicated actions, including for-cause terminations, that are open to public inspection under Title 10, Subtitle 6 of the State Government Article, to a database or other clearinghouse service maintained by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners or its affiliates or subsidiaries.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The Commissioner may adopt regulations to carry out this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
