<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-829" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-829</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Chlamydia screening test" means any laboratory test that:<section prefix="(i)">specifically detects for infection by one or more agents of chlamydia trachomatis; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is approved for this purpose by the federal Food and Drug Administration.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Human papillomavirus screening test" means any laboratory test that:<section prefix="(i)">specifically detects for infection by one or more agents of the human papillomavirus; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is approved for this purpose by the federal Food and Drug Administration.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Multiple risk factors" means having a prior history of a sexually transmitted disease, new or multiple sex partners, inconsistent use of barrier contraceptives, or cervical ectopy.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to:<section prefix="(1)">insurers and nonprofit health service plans that provide hospital, medical, or surgical benefits to individuals or groups on an expense-incurred basis under health insurance policies or contracts that are issued or delivered in the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">health maintenance organizations that provide hospital, medical, or surgical benefits to individuals or groups under contracts that are issued or delivered in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An entity subject to this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">provide coverage for an annual routine chlamydia screening test for:<section prefix="(i)">women who are:</section><section prefix="(ii)">men who have multiple risk factors; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">provide coverage for a human papillomavirus screening at the testing intervals outlined in the recommendations for cervical cytology screening developed by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the coverage required under this section may be subject to a copayment or coinsurance requirement or deductible that an entity subject to this section imposes for similar coverages under the same policy or contract.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The copayment or coinsurance requirement or deductible imposed under paragraph (1) of this subsection may not be greater than the copayment or coinsurance requirement or deductible imposed by the entity for similar coverages.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Nothing in this section may be construed to prohibit an entity subject to this section from providing coverages that are greater than or more favorable to an insured or enrollee than the coverage required under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
