<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-118</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>118</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Health care service" means a health or medical care procedure or service rendered by a provider that:<section prefix="(i)">provides testing, diagnosis, or treatment of human disease or dysfunction; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">dispenses drugs, medical devices, medical appliances, or medical goods for the treatment of human disease or dysfunction.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Provider" means a physician, hospital, or other person that is licensed or otherwise authorized to provide health care services.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to insurers and nonprofit health service plans that provide coverage for health care services to individuals or groups on an expense-incurred basis under health insurance policies or contracts that are issued or delivered in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If an entity subject to this section negotiates and enters into a contract with providers to render health care services to insureds at alternative rates of payment, and coinsurance payments are to be based on a percentage of the fee for health care services rendered by a provider, the entity shall calculate the amount of the coinsurance payment to be paid by the insured exclusively from the negotiated alternative rate for the health care service rendered.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An entity subject to this section may not charge or collect from an insured a coinsurance payment amount that is greater than the amount calculated under subsection (c) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
