<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-403.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>403.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "child dependent of the domestic partner" means an  individual who:<section prefix="(1)">is:<section prefix="(i)">the natural child, stepchild, adopted  child, or grandchild of the domestic partner of an insured;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a child placed with the domestic partner  of an insured for legal adoption; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a child who is under testamentary or  court appointed guardianship, other than temporary guardianship  of less than 12 months' duration, of the domestic partner of an  insured;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">is a dependent, as that term is used in 26 U.S.C.  &#xA7;&#xA7; 104, 105, and 106, and any regulations adopted under those  sections, of the domestic partner of an insured;</section><section prefix="(3)">resides with the insured;</section><section prefix="(4)">is unmarried; and</section><section prefix="(5)">is under the age of 25 years.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to each individual or group policy or  contract that:<section prefix="(1)">allows family coverage; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is issued by:<section prefix="(i)">an insurer or nonprofit health service plan  that provides inpatient hospital, medical, or surgical benefits to  individuals or groups on an expense-incurred basis under health  insurance policies or contracts that are issued or delivered in the  State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a health maintenance organization that  provides inpatient hospital, medical, or surgical benefits to  individuals or groups under contracts that are issued or delivered  in the State.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each policy or contract subject to this section shall provide that the same health insurance benefits and eligibility guidelines that apply to any covered dependent are available to a domestic partner of an insured or a child dependent of the domestic partner of an insured at the request of:<section prefix="(1)">an insured under an individual policy or contract  that is subject to this section; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the group policyholder of a group policy or contract that is subject to this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An insurer, nonprofit health service plan, or health maintenance organization may require a group policyholder that requests coverage for a domestic partner or child dependent of the domestic partner of an insured under subsection (c)(2) of this section to provide proof of the eligibility of the domestic partner or child dependent of the domestic partner for coverage under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commissioner shall adopt regulations to implement this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
