<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-708" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-708</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "nurse anesthetist" means a registered nurse who is certified as a nurse anesthetist by:<section prefix="(1)">the Council on Certification of Nurse Anesthetists; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the Council on Recertification of Nurse Anesthetists.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to each individual, group, or blanket health insurance policy, contract, or certificate of an insurer or nonprofit health service plan that:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">is issued or delivered in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is issued to a group that is incorporated or has a main office in the State; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">covers individuals who reside or work in the State;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">is issued, renewed, amended, or reissued on or after July 1, 1984; and</section><section prefix="(3)">if issued by an insurer, is written on an expense-incurred basis.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding any other provision of a policy, contract, or certificate subject to this section, if the policy, contract, or certificate provides for reimbursement for a service that is within the lawful scope of practice of a nurse anesthetist, the insured or any other person covered by the policy, contract, or certificate is entitled to reimbursement for the service regardless of whether the service is performed by a physician or nurse anesthetist.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A policy that provides benefits under this section for services rendered by a nurse anesthetist may not require, as a condition for the payment of benefits, that the nurse anesthetist be employed by a physician.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The utilization of health insurance benefits provided under this section for services rendered by a nurse anesthetist is subject to review by a peer review committee appointed by the State Board of Nursing.</section>
  </text>
</law>
