<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-27-212</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>212</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to life insurance, health insurance, and annuities.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except to the extent provided for in an applicable filing with the Commissioner as provided by law, an insurer, employee or representative of an insurer or insurance producer may not pay, allow, give, or offer to pay, allow, or give directly or indirectly as an inducement to insurance or after insurance has become effective:<section prefix="(1)">a rebate, discount, abatement, credit, or reduction of the premium stated in the policy;</section><section prefix="(2)">a special favor or advantage in the dividends or other benefits to accrue on the policy; or</section><section prefix="(3)">any valuable consideration or other inducement not specified in the policy.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An insured named in a policy or an employee of the insured may not knowingly receive or accept directly or indirectly a rebate, discount, abatement, credit, reduction of premium, special favor, advantage, valuable consideration, or inducement described in subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as otherwise provided by law, a person may not knowingly offer, promise, or give any valuable consideration not specified in the policy, except for educational materials, promotional materials, or articles of merchandise that cost no more than $25, regardless of whether a policy is purchased.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An insurer may not make or allow unfair discrimination between insureds or properties having like insuring or risk characteristics in:<section prefix="(i)">the premium or rates charged for insurance;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the dividends or other benefits payable on the insurance; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">any of the other terms or conditions of the insurance.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, an insurer may not make or allow a differential in ratings, premium payments, or dividends for a reason based on the sex, physical handicap, or disability of an applicant or policyholder unless there is actuarial justification for the differential.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">This section does not prohibit an insurer from:<section prefix="(1)">paying commissions or other compensation to licensed insurance producers; or</section><section prefix="(2)">allowing or returning to its participating policyholders, members, or subscribers lawful dividends, savings, or unabsorbed premium deposits.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
