<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-3-116</section_number>
  <catch_line>A director, officer, or member of a stock insurer or mutual insurer or any other person may lend or ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>116</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A director, officer, or member of a stock insurer or mutual insurer or any other person may lend or advance to the stock insurer or mutual insurer any money necessary to enable it to comply with a surplus requirement or any other requirement of law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The instrument evidencing a loan or advance under this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">be approved as to form and content by the Commissioner; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">contain provisions that specify that:<section prefix="1.">the instrument is subordinate to policyholders, claimant and beneficiary claims, and all other classes of creditors other than surplus note holders; and</section><section prefix="2.">interest payments and principal repayments may not be made without prior approval of the Commissioner.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A loan or advance under this subsection and any interest on it:<section prefix="(i)">is payable only out of the surplus remaining after the stock insurer or mutual insurer provides for all reserves and other liabilities; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is not otherwise a liability or claim against the stock insurer or mutual insurer or any of its assets.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Proceeds of a loan or advance under this section shall be in the form of cash or other admitted assets having readily determinable values and liquidity satisfactory to the Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In each annual statement, a stock insurer or mutual insurer shall report the amount of each loan or advance made under this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
