<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-603" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-14-603</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An entity shall register with the Commissioner as a discount medical plan organization before a discount medical plan established by that entity is sold, marketed, or solicited in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A discount medical plan may not be sold, marketed, or solicited in the State unless the discount medical plan organization that established the discount medical plan is registered with the Commissioner.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An entity shall register with the Commissioner as a discount drug plan organization before a discount drug plan established by that entity is sold, marketed, or solicited in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A discount drug plan may not be sold, marketed, or solicited in the State unless the discount drug plan organization that established the discount drug plan is registered with the Commissioner.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An applicant for registration shall:<section prefix="(1)">file with the Commissioner an application on the form that the Commissioner requires; and</section><section prefix="(2)">pay to the Commissioner  an application fee of $250.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An entity that is required to register with the Commissioner under both subsections (a) and (b) of this section may file one application with the Commissioner and pay one application fee.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An applicant shall file with its application a list of the persons authorized to sell, market, or solicit a discount medical plan or discount drug plan established by the applicant.</section>
  </text>
</law>
