<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-12A-02" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-12A-02</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Small Employer Health Benefit Plan Premium Subsidy Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The purposes of the Program are to:<section prefix="(1)">provide an incentive for small employers to offer and maintain a small employer health benefit plan for their employees;</section><section prefix="(2)">help low and moderate income employees of small employers afford small employer health benefit plan premiums;</section><section prefix="(3)">promote access to health care services, particularly preventive health care services that might reduce the need for emergency room care and other acute care services; and</section><section prefix="(4)">reduce uncompensated care in hospitals and other health care settings.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission, in consultation with the Department, shall administer the Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Program shall consist of subsidies, as provided under &#xA7; 15-12A-03 of this subtitle, for:<section prefix="(1)">small employers that have not previously offered a small employer health benefit plan to their employees; and</section><section prefix="(2)">employees of small employers that have not previously offered a small employer health benefit plan to their employees.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Funding for the Program may be provided from:<section prefix="(1)">general funds; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the Health Care Coverage Fund established under Title 15, Subtitle 7 of the Health - General Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commission shall adopt regulations to establish:<section prefix="(1)">the eligibility requirements for small employers under the Program; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the level of subsidies to be provided under the Program.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
