<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-1010" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-1010</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Disability benefit" means a benefit that is payable based on the disability of a covered individual.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Disability benefit" does not include:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Adverse benefit determination" means:<section prefix="(i)">a denial, reduction, or termination of a disability benefit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a failure to provide or make payment, in whole or in part, for a disability benefit; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">any denial, reduction, termination, or failure to provide or make payment that is based on a determination of an individual's eligibility for coverage of a disability benefit.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner shall adopt regulations that establish standards governing the processing of claims by an insurer that:<section prefix="(i)">issues or delivers individual policies in the State that include a disability benefit; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">issues or delivers group policies in the State that include a disability benefit.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The regulations adopted under this subsection shall establish and maintain reasonable claims procedures governing the filing of disability benefit claims, including:<section prefix="(i)">notification of an adverse benefit determination; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">an appeal by an insured or the insured's authorized representative of an insurer's adverse benefit determination.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The claims procedures established for both individual and group policies under this subsection shall be consistent with the provisions of the Department of Labor's regulation entitled "Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, Rules and Regulations for Administration and Enforcement; Claims Procedure; Final Rule" (29 C.F.R. 2560).</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
