<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-10D-02</section_number>
  <catch_line>Each carrier shall establish an internal appeal process for use by its members, its members' represe...</catch_line>
  <order_by>02</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each carrier shall establish an internal appeal process for use by its members, its members' representatives, and health care providers to dispute coverage decisions made by the carrier.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The carrier may use the internal grievance process established under Subtitle 10A of this title to comply with the requirement of paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A carrier under this section shall render a final decision in writing to a member, a member's representative, and a health care provider acting on behalf of the member within 60 working days after the date on which the appeal is filed.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, the carrier's internal appeal process shall be exhausted prior to filing a complaint with the Commissioner under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A member, a member's representative, or a health care provider filing a complaint on behalf of a member may file a complaint with the Commissioner without first filing an appeal with a carrier only if the coverage decision involves an urgent medical condition, as defined by regulation adopted by the Commissioner, for which care has not been rendered.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 30 calendar days after a coverage decision has been made, a carrier shall send a written notice of the coverage decision to the member and the member's representative, if any, and, in the case of a health maintenance organization, the treating health care provider.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notice of the coverage decision required to be sent under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">state in detail in clear, understandable language, the specific factual bases for the carrier's decision; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">include the following information:<section prefix="1.">that the member, the member's representative, or a health care provider acting on behalf of the member has a right to file an appeal with the carrier;</section><section prefix="2.">that the member, the member's representative, or a health care provider acting on behalf of the member may file a complaint with the Commissioner without first filing an appeal, if the coverage decision involves an urgent medical condition for which care has not been rendered;</section><section prefix="3.">the Commissioner's address, telephone number, and facsimile number;</section><section prefix="4.">that the Health Advocacy Unit is available to assist the member or the member's representative in both mediating and filing an appeal under the carrier's internal appeal process; and</section><section prefix="5.">the address, telephone number, facsimile number, and electronic mail address of the Health Advocacy Unit.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 30 calendar days after the appeal decision has been made, each carrier shall send to the member, the member's representative, and the health care provider acting on behalf of the member a written notice of the appeal decision.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notice of the appeal decision required to be sent under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">state in detail in clear, understandable language the specific factual bases for the carrier's decision; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">include the following information:<section prefix="1.">that the member, the member's representative, or a health care provider acting on behalf of the member has a right to file a complaint with the Commissioner within 4 months after receipt of a carrier's appeal decision;</section><section prefix="2.">the Commissioner's address, telephone number, and facsimile number;</section><section prefix="3.">a statement that the Health Advocacy Unit is available to assist the member in filing a complaint with the Commissioner; and</section><section prefix="4.">the address, telephone number, facsimile number, and electronic mail address of the Health Advocacy Unit.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Commissioner may request the member that filed the complaint or a legally authorized designee of the member to sign a consent form authorizing the release of the member's medical records to the Commissioner or the Commissioner's designee that are needed in order for the Commissioner to make a final decision on the complaint.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A carrier shall have the burden of persuasion that its coverage decision or appeal decision, as applicable, is correct:<section prefix="(i)">during the review of a complaint by the Commissioner or a designee of the Commissioner; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">in any hearing held in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article to contest a final decision of the Commissioner made and issued under this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">As part of the review of a complaint, the Commissioner or a designee of the Commissioner may consider all of the facts of the case and any other evidence that the Commissioner or designee of the Commissioner considers appropriate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Commissioner shall:<section prefix="(1)">make and issue in writing a final decision on all complaints filed with the Commissioner under this subtitle that are within the Commissioner's jurisdiction; and</section><section prefix="(2)">provide notice in writing to all parties to a complaint of the opportunity and time period for requesting a hearing to be held in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article to contest a final decision of the Commissioner made and issued under this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
