<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-206" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-11-206</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, each insurer shall file with the Commissioner all rates, supplementary rate information, policy forms, and endorsements and all modifications of rates, supplementary rate information, policy forms, and endorsements that the insurer proposes to use.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each filing shall state its proposed effective date and shall indicate the character and extent of the coverage contemplated.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If a filing is not accompanied by the information on which the insurer supports the filing and the Commissioner does not have sufficient information to determine whether the filing meets the requirements of this subtitle, the Commissioner shall require the insurer to provide supporting information for the filing within 60 days.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the Commissioner requires the filer to provide supporting information, the waiting period under subsection (g) of this section begins on the date the supporting information is provided.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The information provided in support of a filing may include:<section prefix="(i)">the judgment of the filer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the filer's interpretation of any statistical data relied on;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the experience of other filers; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">any other relevant factors.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each filing shall include the experience of the filer.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A filing and any supporting information shall be open to public inspection as soon as filed.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An insurer may satisfy its obligation to make filings by:<section prefix="(1)">being a member of or subscriber to a licensed rating organization that makes filings; and</section><section prefix="(2)">authorizing the Commissioner to accept filings on its behalf from the rating organization.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commissioner shall review each filing as soon as reasonably possible after it is made to determine whether it meets the requirements of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subsections (h) and (i) of this section, a filing may not take effect until 30 working days after it is filed with the Commissioner.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">By written notice to the filer during the initial 30-day waiting period that the Commissioner needs additional time for consideration of the filing, the Commissioner may extend the waiting period for an additional period not exceeding 30 working days.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On written application by the filer, the Commissioner may authorize a filing that the Commissioner has reviewed to become effective before the expiration of the waiting period or any extension of the waiting period or at a later date.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A filing is deemed approved unless disapproved by the Commissioner during the waiting period or any extension of the waiting period.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A filing may be withdrawn or amended by the filer at any time before approval.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">After approval or disapproval of a filing, the withdrawal or amendment of the filing is subject to the approval of the Commissioner in accordance with this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Inland marine risks that by general custom of the business are not written according to manual rates or rating plans need not be filed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, specific inland marine rates on risks specially rated by a rating organization shall be filed, become effective when filed, and remain effective until the Commissioner finds the filing does not meet the requirements of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A special filing with respect to a surety or guarantee bond required by law, by court, by executive order, or by order, rule, or regulation of a public body, not covered by a previous filing shall become effective when filed and remain effective until the Commissioner finds that the filing does not meet the requirements of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "exempt commercial policyholder" means a person that:<section prefix="(i)">pays annual aggregate property and casualty premiums for commercial insurance policies issued in the State during the current or preceding calendar year of $25,000 or more; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">meets any two of the following criteria:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The filing requirements of this section do not apply to policy forms and endorsements and to modifications of policy forms and endorsements issued to an exempt commercial policyholder.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An exempt commercial policyholder must certify in writing, on a form approved by the Commissioner, to the insurer issuing coverage and the Commissioner that it meets the criteria necessary for exemption from form filing requirements.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The certification must include:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">This subsection does not apply to the filing of workers' compensation insurance policy forms.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Commissioner may require, by regulation, that insurers provide information to the Administration on the number and types of policies written for exempt commercial policyholders under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">On written request of the Commissioner, an insurer shall file with the Commissioner a form or endorsement issued to an exempt commercial policyholder.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Except for the exemption from form filing requirements under this section, a form or endorsement issued to an exempt commercial policyholder is subject to all applicable provisions of this article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
