<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-410" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-10-410</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commissioner may deny a license to an applicant or suspend, revoke, or refuse to renew or reinstate a license after notice and opportunity for a hearing under &#xA7;&#xA7; 2-210 through 2-214 of this article if the applicant or licensee:<section prefix="(1)">has violated this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">has made a material misstatement in the application for the license;</section><section prefix="(3)">has engaged in fraudulent or dishonest practices;</section><section prefix="(4)">has demonstrated incompetency or untrustworthiness to act as a public adjuster;</section><section prefix="(5)">has misappropriated, converted, or unlawfully withheld money that belongs to an insurer, insurance producer, insured, or other person;</section><section prefix="(6)">has willfully and materially misrepresented the provisions of a policy;</section><section prefix="(7)">has been convicted of a felony, a crime of moral turpitude, or any criminal offense involving dishonesty or breach of trust;</section><section prefix="(8)">has willfully failed to comply with or has willfully violated a proper order or regulation of the Commissioner;</section><section prefix="(9)">has failed or refused to pay on demand money that belongs to an insurer, insurance producer, insured, or other person entitled to the money;</section><section prefix="(10)">is not carrying on or does not intend to carry on business in good faith while representing to the public that the person is a public adjuster;</section><section prefix="(11)">has been denied a license or has had a license suspended or revoked in another state; or</section><section prefix="(12)">has knowingly employed or knowingly continued to employ an individual acting in a fiduciary capacity who has been convicted within the preceding 10 years of a felony or crime of moral turpitude.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner may deny a license to a business entity applicant or suspend, revoke, or refuse to renew or reinstate the license of a business entity after notice and opportunity for a hearing under &#xA7;&#xA7; 2-210 through 2-214 of this article, if an individual listed in paragraph (2) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">violates any provision of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is convicted of a felony, a crime of moral turpitude, or any criminal offense involving dishonesty or breach of trust; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">has any professional license suspended or revoked for a fraudulent or dishonest practice.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The sanctions provided for under this subsection may be imposed on a business entity if the violation was committed by an individual who:<section prefix="(i)">is a public adjuster employed by the business entity;</section><section prefix="(ii)"/><section prefix="(iii)">has direct control over the fiscal management of the business entity.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Instead of or in addition to suspending or revoking the license of a public adjuster, the Commissioner may impose on the licensee a penalty of not less than $100 but not exceeding $500 for each violation of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Instead of or in addition to suspending or revoking the license, the Commissioner may require that restitution be made to any citizen who has suffered financial injury because of the violation of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the license is suspended under this section, the Commissioner may require the individual to pass an examination and file a new application before the suspension is lifted.</section>
  </text>
</law>
