<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-8-445</section_number>
  <catch_line>Standards of valuation for certificates issued before January 1, 1998, shall be those provided by th...</catch_line>
  <order_by>445</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Standards of valuation for certificates issued before January 1, 1998, shall be those provided by the laws applicable on December 31, 1997.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The minimum standards of valuation for certificates issued on or after January 1, 1998, shall be based on the following tables:<section prefix="(i)">for certificates of life insurance:<section prefix="1.">the Commissioners 1941 Standard Ordinary Mortality Table;</section><section prefix="2.">the Commissioners 1941 Standard Industrial Mortality Table;</section><section prefix="3.">the Commissioners 1958 Standard Ordinary Mortality Table;</section><section prefix="4.">the Commissioners 1980 Standard Ordinary Mortality Table; or</section><section prefix="5.">any more recent table authorized for use under &#xA7; 5-304(b) of this article; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">for annuity and pure endowment certificates, total and permanent disability benefits, accidental death benefits, and noncancelable accident and health benefits, the tables that are authorized for use by life insurers in the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Valuation of all certificates issued on or after January 1, 1998, shall be under valuation methods and standards, including interest assumptions, in accordance with the laws of the State applicable to life insurers issuing policies containing like benefits.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner may:<section prefix="(1)">accept other standards for valuation if the Commissioner finds that the reserves produced by those other standards will not be less in the aggregate than reserves computed in accordance with the minimum valuation standard prescribed in this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">vary the standards of mortality applicable to all benefit contracts on substandard lives or other extra hazardous lives by any society authorized to do business in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With the consent of the commissioner of insurance of the state of domicile of the society, and subject to any conditions the commissioner may impose, a society may establish and maintain reserves on its certificates that exceed the reserves required under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The contractual rights of any benefit member may not be affected by a society establishing and maintaining reserves under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
