<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-31-105</section_number>
  <catch_line>With the approval of the Governor, the Board shall appoint an Executive Director of the Exchange....</catch_line>
  <order_by>105</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With the approval of the Governor, the Board shall appoint an Executive Director of the Exchange.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Executive Director shall serve at the pleasure of the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board shall determine the appropriate compensation for the Executive Director.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Under the direction of the Board, the Executive Director shall:<section prefix="(1)">be the chief administrative officer of the Exchange;</section><section prefix="(2)">direct, administer, and manage the operations of the Exchange; and</section><section prefix="(3)">perform all duties necessary to comply with and carry out the provisions of this title, other State law and regulations, and the Affordable Care Act.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Executive Director may employ and retain a staff for the Exchange.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraphs (3) and (4) of this subsection, or otherwise by law, the Executive Director's appointment, retention, and removal of staff of the Exchange are not subject to Division I of the State Personnel and Pensions Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In hiring staff for functions that must be performed by State personnel under the Affordable Care Act or other applicable federal or State laws, the Executive Director's appointment, retention, and removal of staff shall be in accordance with Division I of the State Personnel and Pensions Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In hiring staff for functions that have been and currently are performed by State personnel, the Executive Director's appointment, retention, and removal of staff shall be in accordance with Division I of the State Personnel and Pensions Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Except as provided in paragraph (6) of this subsection, staff for all other positions necessary to carry out the purposes of this title shall be positions in the executive service or management service, or special appointments of the skilled service or the professional service in the State Personnel Management System.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Executive Director may retain as independent contractors or employees, and set compensation for, attorneys, financial consultants, and any other professionals or consultants necessary to carry out the planning, development, and operations of the Exchange and the provisions of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Executive Director shall determine the classification, grade, and compensation of staff of the Exchange hired or designated under subsection (c)(3), (4), and (5) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">in consultation with the Secretary of Budget and Management;</section><section prefix="(2)">with the approval of the Board; and</section><section prefix="(3)">when possible, in accordance with the State pay plan.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With respect to staff of the Exchange hired or designated under subsection (c)(3), (4), and (5) of this section, the Executive Director shall submit to the Secretary of Budget and Management, at least 45 days before the effective date of the change, each change to the Exchange's salary plans that involves increases or decreases in salary ranges other than those associated with routine reclassifications and promotions or general salary increases approved by the General Assembly.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Reportable changes include:<section prefix="(i)">the creation or abolition of classes;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the regrading of classes from one established range to another; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the creation of new pay schedules or ranges.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary of Budget and Management shall:<section prefix="(i)">review the proposed change; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">at least 15 days before the effective date of the proposed change:<section prefix="1.">advise the Executive Director whether the change would have an adverse effect on comparable State jobs; and</section><section prefix="2.">if there would be an adverse effect, recommend an alternative change that would not have an adverse effect on comparable State jobs.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Failure of the Secretary of Budget and Management to respond in a timely manner is deemed to be agreement with the change as submitted.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, an employee or independent contractor of the Exchange is not subject to any law, regulation, or executive order governing State compensation, including furloughs, pay cuts, or any other General Fund cost savings measure.</section>
  </text>
</law>
