<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-13-117</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>117</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">After notice and hearing, the Commissioner may adopt regulations to carry out this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the Commissioner finds that an insurer or other person authorized or licensed by the Commissioner has violated this title or a regulation adopted under this title, then after written notice and a hearing, the Commissioner shall:<section prefix="(1)">set forth the details of the findings; and</section><section prefix="(2)">issue an order for compliance by a specified date.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An order issued under subsection (b) of this section binds the insurer or other person authorized or licensed by the Commissioner on the date specified unless:<section prefix="(1)">the Commissioner withdraws the order before the specified date; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a court of competent jurisdiction orders a stay of the order of the Commissioner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A party to a proceeding under this title that is aggrieved by an order of the Commissioner is entitled to judicial review in accordance with &#xA7; 2-215 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The filing of an appeal from the withdrawal of approval of a form or rate previously in use operates as a stay, unless the court determines otherwise.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In addition to any other penalty provided by law, on proof satisfactory to the court, the court may impose on an insurer or other person that violates a final order of the Commissioner while the order is in effect a civil penalty not exceeding $250, or if the violation is willful, a civil penalty not exceeding $1,000.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After notice and a hearing, the Commissioner may suspend or revoke the license, certificate of authority, or certificate of qualification of an insurer or other person that violates a final order of the Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The order for suspension or revocation is subject to judicial review in accordance with &#xA7; 2-215 of this article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
