<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-823</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>823</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Bone mass measurement" means a radiologic or radioisotopic procedure or other scientifically proven technology performed on a qualified individual for the purpose of identifying bone mass or detecting bone loss.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Qualified individual" means:<section prefix="(i)">an estrogen deficient individual at clinical risk for osteoporosis;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an individual with a specific sign suggestive of spinal osteoporosis, including roentgenographic osteopenia or roentgenographic evidence suggestive of collapse, wedging, or ballooning of one or more thoracic or lumbar vertebral bodies, who is a candidate for therapeutic intervention or for an extensive diagnostic evaluation for metabolic bone disease;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an individual receiving long-term glucocorticoid (steroid) therapy;</section><section prefix="(iv)">an individual with primary hyperparathyroidism; or</section><section prefix="(v)">an individual being monitored to assess the response to or efficacy of an approved osteoporosis drug therapy.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to:<section prefix="(1)">each individual hospital or major medical insurance policy of an insurer that is delivered or issued for delivery in the State and is written on an expense-incurred basis;</section><section prefix="(2)">each group or blanket health insurance policy of an insurer that is issued or delivered in the State and is written on an expense-incurred basis; and</section><section prefix="(3)">each individual or group medical or major medical contract or certificate of a nonprofit health service plan that is issued or delivered in the State and is written on an expense-incurred basis.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A policy, contract, or certificate subject to this section shall include coverage for qualified individuals for reimbursement for bone mass measurement for the prevention, diagnosis, and treatment of osteoporosis when the bone mass measurement is requested by a health care provider for the qualified individual.</section>
  </text>
</law>
