<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-11-601</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>601</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Carrier" means a person that:<section prefix="(1)">offers a health benefit plan in the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is:<section prefix="(i)">an insurer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a nonprofit health service plan; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a health maintenance organization.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Contract holder" means a person to which a carrier has issued a health benefit plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Health benefit plan" means:<section prefix="(i)">a health insurance contract, a nonprofit health service plan contract, or a health maintenance organization contract that includes benefits for medical care; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a certificate of health insurance issued or delivered to a Maryland resident under a contract issued to an association located in the State or any other state.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Health benefit plan" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">one or more, or any combination of the following:<section prefix="1.">coverage only for accident or disability income insurance;</section><section prefix="2.">coverage issued as a supplement to liability insurance;</section><section prefix="3.">liability insurance, including general liability insurance and automobile liability insurance;</section><section prefix="4.">workers' compensation or similar insurance;</section><section prefix="5.">automobile medical payment insurance;</section><section prefix="6.">credit-only insurance;</section><section prefix="7.">coverage for on-site medical clinics; and</section><section prefix="8.">other similar insurance coverage, as specified in federal regulations issued pursuant to P.L. 104-191, under which benefits for medical care are secondary or incidental to other insurance benefits;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">the following benefits if they are provided under a separate policy, certificate, or contract of insurance or are otherwise not an integral part of a health benefit plan:<section prefix="1.">limited scope dental or vision benefits;</section><section prefix="2.">benefits for long-term care, nursing home care, home health care, community-based care, or any combination of these benefits; and</section><section prefix="3.">other similar limited benefits as specified in federal regulations issued pursuant to P.L. 104-191;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">the following benefits if offered as independent, noncoordinated benefits:<section prefix="1.">coverage only for a specified disease or illness; and</section><section prefix="2.">hospital indemnity or other fixed indemnity insurance; or</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">the following benefits if offered as a separate policy, certificate, or contract of insurance:<section prefix="1.">Medicare supplemental health insurance, as defined in &#xA7; 1882(g)(1) of the Social Security Act;</section><section prefix="2.">coverage supplemental to the coverage provided under Chapter 55 of Title 10, United States Code; and</section><section prefix="3.">similar supplemental coverage provided to coverage under an employer sponsored plan.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Medical care" means:<section prefix="(1)">items or services for the diagnosis, cure, mitigation, treatment, or prevention of a disease, injury, or condition affecting any structure or function of the body; and</section><section prefix="(2)">transportation primarily for and essential to medical care described in item (1) of this subsection.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
