<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-3-316</section_number>
  <catch_line>Unless a certificate of qualification is renewed for a 2-year term as provided in this section, the ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>316</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Unless a certificate of qualification is renewed for a 2-year term as provided in this section, the certificate of qualification expires on the first June 30 that comes after its effective date.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">At least 1 month before a certificate of qualification expires, the Commissioner shall mail to the holder of the certificate of qualification, at the last known address of the holder:<section prefix="(1)">a renewal application form; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a notice that states:<section prefix="(i)">the date by which the Commissioner must receive the renewal application for the renewal to be issued and mailed before the certificate of qualification expires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the amount of the renewal fee.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before a certificate of qualification expires, the holder periodically may renew it for an additional 2-year term, if the holder:<section prefix="(1)">otherwise is entitled to a certificate of qualification;</section><section prefix="(2)">submits to the Commissioner a renewal application on the form that the Commissioner provides;</section><section prefix="(3)">pays to the Commissioner the renewal fee required by &#xA7; 2-112 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(4)">complies with the bond requirement of &#xA7; 3-313 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An application for renewal of a certificate of qualification shall be considered made in a timely manner if it is postmarked on or before June 30 of the year of renewal.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commissioner shall renew the certificate of qualification of each holder who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
