<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-2-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>With respect to an examination, investigation, or hearing conducted by the Commissioner, the Commiss...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">With respect to an examination, investigation, or hearing conducted by the Commissioner, the Commissioner, deputy commissioner, or an examiner authorized by the Commissioner may:<section prefix="(1)">administer oaths;</section><section prefix="(2)">examine individuals under oath; and</section><section prefix="(3)">issue subpoenas for the attendance of witnesses to testify or the production of evidence.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A subpoena issued under this section shall be served:<section prefix="(i)">in the same manner as a subpoena of a circuit court may be served; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">in the same manner as a service of process in a civil action in a circuit court may be served.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a person fails to comply with a lawfully served subpoena, the Commissioner immediately shall file a complaint and a copy of the subpoena and proof of service with the circuit court for the county where the person was required to appear or produce evidence.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On receipt of a complaint and a copy of the subpoena and proof of service, the circuit court shall:<section prefix="(i)">issue an order directing compliance with the subpoena or compelling testimony; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">impose penalties as if the person had failed to comply with a subpoena of the court.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person is not excused from attending, testifying, or producing evidence in an examination, investigation, or hearing conducted by or under authority of the Commissioner on the ground that the testimony or evidence may:<section prefix="(i)">tend to incriminate the person; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">subject the person to a penalty of forfeiture.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before a person that claims the privilege against self-incrimination is required or allowed to testify or produce evidence, the Commissioner shall consult with the Attorney General and, with the consent of the Attorney General, the person may not be prosecuted or punished in a criminal action because of an act, transaction, matter, or thing about which the person is compelled to produce evidence or testify under oath.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A person that testifies is not exempt from prosecution and punishment for perjury committed while testifying.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A witness is entitled to the fees and mileage reimbursement allowed for testimony in a court.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On submission of an itemized claim, witness fees, mileage, and actual necessary expenses incurred in securing attendance and testimony of a witness shall be paid by:<section prefix="(i)">the person being examined, if the person is found to have violated the law as to the matter about which the witness was subpoenaed; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the person that requested the hearing, if the hearing was requested by a person other than the Commissioner.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not willfully testify falsely under oath about any matter that is material to an examination, investigation, or hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person that violates paragraph (1) of this subsection is guilty of perjury and on conviction shall be punished accordingly.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not willfully fail to:<section prefix="(i)">appear and testify under oath before the Commissioner;</section><section prefix="(ii)">attend, answer, or produce evidence requested by the Commissioner; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">give the Commissioner full and truthful information and answer in writing to any material written inquiry of the Commissioner in relation to the subject of an examination, investigation, or hearing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to or instead of any other applicable penalty, a person that violates paragraph (1) of this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $1,000 or imprisonment not exceeding 6 months or both.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
