<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-409.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-409.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Act" means the federal American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 (P.L. 111-5).</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Carrier" means:<section prefix="(i)">an insurer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a nonprofit health service plan; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a health maintenance organization.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Small employer" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 15-1201 of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to a carrier that issues health benefit plans to small employers in accordance with Subtitle 12 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A carrier shall allow an extended election period for continuation coverage under &#xA7; 15-409 of this subtitle if the individual:<section prefix="(1)">was involuntarily terminated from employment by a small employer between September 1, 2008, and February 16, 2009, inclusive, as described in &#xA7; 3001(a)(3)(C) of the Act;</section><section prefix="(2)">is an assistance eligible individual, as defined in &#xA7; 3001(a)(3) of the Act, or would be an assistance eligible individual if an election of continuation coverage under &#xA7; 15-409 of this subtitle was in effect on the date of enactment of the Act; and</section><section prefix="(3)">was eligible for continuation coverage under &#xA7; 15-409 of this subtitle at the time of the individual's termination of employment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The extended election period provided under this section shall continue until 60 days after provision of the notification required by &#xA7; 3001(a)(7)(C) of the Act if the notification describes the extended election period required under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Any continuation coverage elected by an individual during an extended election period under this section:<section prefix="(1)">shall begin during the first period of coverage beginning on or after the individual's election of continuation coverage; and</section><section prefix="(2)">may not extend beyond the period of continuation coverage that would have been required under &#xA7; 15-409 of this subtitle if the coverage had been elected as required under that section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
