<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-827</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>827</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Cooperative group" means a formal network of facilities that collaborate on research projects and have an established NIH-approved Peer Review Program operating within the group.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Cooperative group" includes:<section prefix="1.">the National Cancer Institute Clinical Cooperative Group;</section><section prefix="2.">the National Cancer Institute Community Clinical Oncology Program;</section><section prefix="3.">the AIDS Clinical Trials Group; and</section><section prefix="4.">the Community Programs for Clinical Research in AIDS.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"FDA" means the federal Food and Drug Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Member" means a policyholder, subscriber, insured, or certificate holder or a covered dependent of a policyholder, subscriber, insured, or certificate holder.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Multiple project assurance contract" means a contract between an institution and the federal Department of Health and Human Services that defines the relationship of the institution to the federal Department of Health and Human Services and sets out the responsibilities of the institution and the procedures that will be used by the institution to protect human subjects.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"NIH" means the National Institutes of Health.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Patient cost" means the cost of a medically necessary health care service that is incurred as a result of the treatment being provided to the member for purposes of the clinical trial.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Patient cost" does not include:<section prefix="1.">the cost of an investigational drug or device;</section><section prefix="2.">the cost of nonhealth care services that a patient may be required to receive as a result of the treatment being provided for purposes of the clinical trial;</section><section prefix="3.">costs associated with managing the research associated with the clinical trial; or</section><section prefix="4.">costs that would not be covered under the patient's policy, plan, or contract for noninvestigational treatments.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to:<section prefix="(1)">insurers and nonprofit health service plans that provide hospital, medical, surgical, or pharmaceutical benefits to individuals or groups on an expense-incurred basis under a health insurance policy or contract issued or delivered in the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">health maintenance organizations that provide hospital, medical, surgical, or pharmaceutical benefits to individuals or groups under contracts that are issued or delivered in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section does not apply to a policy, plan, or contract paid for under Title XVIII or Title XIX of the Social Security Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A policy, plan, or contract subject to this section shall provide coverage for patient cost to a member in a clinical trial, as a result of:<section prefix="(1)">treatment provided for a life-threatening condition; or</section><section prefix="(2)">prevention, early detection, and treatment studies on cancer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The coverage under subsection (d) of this section shall be required if:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">the treatment is being provided or the studies are being conducted in a Phase I, Phase II, Phase III, or Phase IV clinical trial for cancer; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the treatment is being provided in a Phase I, Phase II, Phase III, or Phase IV clinical trial for any other life-threatening condition;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the treatment is being provided in a clinical trial approved by:<section prefix="(i)">one of the National Institutes of Health;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an NIH cooperative group or an NIH center;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the FDA in the form of an investigational new drug application;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the federal Department of Veterans Affairs; or</section><section prefix="(v)">an institutional review board of an institution in the State which has a multiple project assurance contract approved by the Office of Protection from Research Risks of the National Institutes of Health;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">the facility and personnel providing the treatment are capable of doing so by virtue of their experience, training, and volume of patients treated to maintain expertise;</section><section prefix="(4)">there is no clearly superior, noninvestigational treatment alternative; and</section><section prefix="(5)">the available clinical or preclinical data provide a reasonable expectation that the treatment will be at least as effective as the noninvestigational alternative.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In conjunction with the provisions of subsection (d) of this section, a policy, plan, or contract shall provide coverage for patient cost incurred for drugs and devices that have been approved for sale by the FDA whether or not the FDA has approved the drug or device for use in treating the patient's particular condition, to the extent that the drugs or devices are not paid for by the manufacturer, distributor, or provider of that drug or device.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An entity seeking coverage for treatment in a clinical trial approved by an institutional review board under subsection (e)(2)(v) of this section shall post electronically and keep up-to-date a list of the clinical trials meeting the requirements of subsections (d) and (e) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The list shall include, for each clinical trial:<section prefix="(i)">the phase for which the trial is approved;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the entity approving the trial;</section><section prefix="(iii)">whether the trial is for treatment of cancer or another life-threatening disease and, if not cancer, the particular disease; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the estimated number of participants in the trial.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">This section may not be construed to affect compliance with &#xA7; 15-804 of this subtitle regarding coverage for off-label use of drugs.</section>
  </text>
</law>
