<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-8-503</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>503</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to a lawyer admitted to the bar of the State while acting within the scope of the profession of the lawyer.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, before a person acts as a reinsurance manager or reinsurance broker in the State, the person:<section prefix="(i)">in the case of a person that maintains an office in the State:<section prefix="1.">must obtain a license under this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="2.">must qualify as an insurance producer under Title 10, Subtitle 1 of this article; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">in the case of a person that maintains an office in another state:<section prefix="1.">must obtain a license under this subtitle or under a law of another state that is substantially similar to this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="2.">must qualify as an insurance producer under Title 10, Subtitle 1 of this article or under a law of another state that is substantially similar to Title 10, Subtitle 1 of this article.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before a person acts as a reinsurance manager for a reinsurer domiciled in the State, the person must:<section prefix="(i)">obtain a license under this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">qualify as an insurance producer under Title 10, Subtitle 1 of this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This subsection applies to a person that maintains an office in the State either directly or as a member or employee of a firm or association or as an officer, director, or employee of a corporation that maintains an office in the State.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
