<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-210" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-8-210</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An insurer shall maintain independent financial examinations, in a form acceptable to the Commissioner, of each managing general agent with whom the insurer has done business.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The insurer shall keep records for at least 5 years.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If, by contract, an insurer allows a managing general agent to maintain loss reserves, the insurer annually shall get an opinion, attesting to the adequacy of the loss reserves established, from an independent actuary who is a member in good standing of the American Academy of Actuaries.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The insurer shall keep the report of the actuary for at least 5 years.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">At least twice a year, an insurer shall conduct an on-site review of the underwriting and claims processing operations of its managing general agent.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 30 days after entering into or terminating a contract with a managing general agent, an insurer shall notify the Commissioner in writing of doing so.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice of entering into a contract shall include:<section prefix="(i)">a statement of the duties and responsibilities of the managing general agent;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the lines of insurance that the managing general agent is contractually authorized to negotiate, procure, or bind for the insurer;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a copy of the contract; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">any other information or documentation that the Commissioner requests.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Unless the relationship between an insurer and managing general agent is controlled by and disclosed under Title 7, Subtitle 6 or 7 of this article, the insurer may not have on its board of directors an officer, director, employee, agent, or shareholder of its managing general agent.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each insurer shall review its books and records each quarter to determine if any insurance producer has become a managing general agent.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the insurer determines that an insurance producer has become a managing general agent:<section prefix="(i)">the insurer promptly shall notify the insurance producer and the Commissioner of the determination; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the insurer and insurance producer must comply fully with the provisions of this subtitle within 30 days after the determination.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
