<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-10B-09" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-10B-09</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "attending provider" means an obstetrician, pediatrician, or other physician or certified nurse midwife or pediatric nurse practitioner attending the mother or newborn child.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsections (c) and (d) of this section, the criteria and standards used by a private review agent or health maintenance organization in performing utilization review of hospital services related to maternity and newborn care, including length of stay, shall be in accordance with the medical criteria outlined in the most current version of the "Guidelines for Perinatal Care" prepared by the American Academy of Pediatrics and the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subject to the provisions of subsection (d) of this section, a private review agent or health maintenance organization performing utilization review of hospital services related to maternity and newborn care shall authorize a minimum coverage of:<section prefix="(1)">48 hours of inpatient hospitalization care following an uncomplicated vaginal delivery; and</section><section prefix="(2)">96 hours of inpatient hospitalization care following an uncomplicated cesarean section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The private review agent or health maintenance organization may authorize a shorter length of stay than that provided in subsection (c) of this section if the mother, in consultation with her attending provider, decides that less time is needed for recovery.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For a mother and newborn child who have a hospital stay shorter in length than that provided under subsection (c) of this section, the private review agent or health maintenance organization performing utilization review shall authorize:<section prefix="(i)">one home visit scheduled to occur within 24 hours after hospital discharge; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">an additional home visit as may be prescribed by the attending provider.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For a mother and newborn child who remain in the hospital for at least the period of time provided under subsection (c) of this section, the private review agent or health maintenance organization performing utilization review shall authorize a home visit as may be prescribed by the attending provider.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A home visit under paragraph (2) or (3) of this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">be provided in accordance with generally accepted standards of nursing practice for home care of a mother and newborn child;</section><section prefix="(ii)">be provided by a registered nurse with at least 1 year of experience in maternal and child health nursing or in community health nursing with an emphasis on maternal and child health; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">include any services required by the attending provider.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The private review agent or health maintenance organization may not require additional documentation from, require additional utilization review of, or otherwise provide financial disincentives for an attending provider who orders care for which coverage is required to be provided under this section, &#xA7; 19-703 of the Health - General Article, or &#xA7; 15-811 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The private review agent, hospital, or health maintenance organization may not deny, limit, or otherwise impair the participation of an attending provider under a contract or any privilege granted an attending provider who advocates more than 48 hours of inpatient hospital care following a complicated vaginal delivery or more than 96 hours of inpatient hospital care following a complicated cesarean section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
