<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-305</section_number>
  <catch_line>Blanket health insurance is health insurance issued to or in the name of persons specified in this s...</catch_line>
  <order_by>305</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Blanket health insurance is health insurance issued to or in the name of persons specified in this section to cover the groups of individuals described in this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The person to which or in the name of which a policy or contract is issued is deemed the policyholder.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A policy or contract of blanket health insurance may be issued to a common carrier or an operator, owner, or lessee of a means of transportation, to cover all individuals or all individuals of a class who may become passengers on the common carrier or means of transportation.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A policy or contract of blanket health insurance may be issued to an employer, to cover all employees, dependents, or guests who are defined by reference to specific hazards that are incident to the activities or operations of the employer or a class of employees, dependents, or guests similarly defined.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A policy or contract of blanket health insurance may be issued to a school or other institution of learning, a camp or its sponsor, or the head or principal of a school, other institution of learning, or camp, to cover students, campers, supervisors, or employees.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A policy or contract of blanket health insurance may be issued in the name of a religious, charitable, recreational, educational, or civic organization, to cover participants in activities sponsored by the organization.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A policy or contract of blanket health insurance may be issued to a sports team or its sponsors, to cover members, officials, and supervisors.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A policy or contract of blanket health insurance may be issued in the name of a volunteer fire department, first aid group, other similar volunteer group, or agency with jurisdiction over a volunteer fire department, first aid group, or other similar volunteer group, to cover all members of the volunteer fire department or similar volunteer group.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A policy or contract of blanket health insurance may be issued to cover any other risk, class of risks, or both that, in the discretion of the Commissioner, may be eligible for blanket health insurance.</section>
  </text>
</law>
