<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="25-308" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-25-308</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After notice and opportunity for a hearing, the Commissioner may impose a monetary penalty on a person or self-insurance group that the Commissioner finds to be in violation of this subtitle or a regulation adopted under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A monetary penalty imposed under this subsection may not exceed $1,000 for each violation or $10,000 in the aggregate.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A person or self-insurance group that is assessed a monetary penalty under this subsection shall pay the penalty to the Commissioner for the use of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After written notice and opportunity for a hearing, the Commissioner may issue an order that requires a person or self-insurance group to cease and desist from engaging in an act or practice that the Commissioner finds to be in violation of this subtitle or a regulation adopted under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Commissioner finds, after notice and opportunity for a hearing, that a person or self-insurance group has violated an order issued under this subsection, the Commissioner may:<section prefix="(i)">impose a monetary penalty of not more than $10,000 for each violation of the order or $100,000 in the aggregate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">suspend or revoke the authority of the self-insurance group to operate.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, after notice and opportunity for a hearing, the Commissioner may suspend or revoke the authority of a self-insurance group to operate if the Commissioner determines that the self-insurance group:<section prefix="(1)">is insolvent;</section><section prefix="(2)">failed to pay the special fund contribution or regulatory fee imposed on the self-insurance group;</section><section prefix="(3)">failed to comply within the time set with a provision of this subtitle, a regulation adopted under this subtitle, or a lawful order of the Commissioner;</section><section prefix="(4)">obtained its authority to operate by fraud, including making a material misrepresentation in the application for authority to operate as a self-insurance group;</section><section prefix="(5)">misappropriated, converted, illegally withheld, or refused to pay on proper demand moneys that have been entrusted to the self-insurance group or its administrator in its fiduciary capacity and that belong to a member of the self-insurance group, an employee of a member, or a person entitled to payment; or</section><section prefix="(6)">for any other reason, must have its authority to operate suspended or revoked to protect the members or insureds of a self-insurance group or the public.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
