<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-16-113</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to the approval of the Commissioner, an insurer authorized to deliver or issue for delivery ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>113</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the approval of the Commissioner, an insurer authorized to deliver or issue for delivery an annuity contract in the State may deliver or issue for delivery funding agreements.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A funding agreement may be issued to:<section prefix="(1)">a person, or a subsidiary of the person, that is authorized by a state or foreign country to engage in the insurance business; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a person, other than a person or a subsidiary of the person that is authorized to engage in the insurance business, to fund:<section prefix="(i)">benefits directly or indirectly under an employee benefit plan, as defined in the federal Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, that is maintained in the United States, or under a similar plan maintained in a foreign country;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the activities of an organization exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 501(c) of the Internal Revenue Code, or of a similar organization in a foreign country;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a program, or plan as defined in &#xA7; 457 of the Internal Revenue Code, of the federal government, a state or political subdivision of a state, or a foreign country or political subdivision of a foreign country;</section><section prefix="(iv)">an agreement that provides for periodic payments in satisfaction of a claim; or</section><section prefix="(v)">a program of an institution that has assets in excess of $25,000,000.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An amount may not be guaranteed or credited under a funding agreement except on a reasonable assumption as to investment income and expenses and on a basis equitable to all holders of funding agreements of a given class.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A funding agreement may not provide for payment to or by the insurer based on a mortality or morbidity contingency.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Under a funding agreement, an insurer may allocate amounts paid to the insurer and proceeds applied under optional modes of settlement to the insurer's general account or to one or more separate accounts.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Amounts allocated to the insurer's general account and any resulting accumulations shall be invested and reinvested in accordance with the provisions of this article governing investment of the reserves of life insurers.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Amounts allocated to a separate account and any resulting accumulations may be invested and reinvested subject only to &#xA7;&#xA7; 5-506, 5-507, and 5-512(b), (e), (f), (g), (h), and (i) of this article and regulations adopted under subsection (e) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner may adopt regulations governing:<section prefix="(i)">the standards for approval of forms of funding agreements;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the reserves to be maintained by insurers that issue funding agreements;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the accounting and reporting of funds credited under funding agreements;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the disclosure of information to holders and prospective holders of funding agreements; and</section><section prefix="(v)">the qualification and compensation of persons that sell funding agreements on behalf of insurers.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">With respect to separate accounts and any resulting accumulations, the Commissioner shall adopt regulations governing the type and amount of investments that may be made under a funding agreement.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Commissioner has sole authority to regulate:<section prefix="(i)">the issuance and sale of funding agreements; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the persons that sell funding agreements on behalf of insurers.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The issuance or delivery of a funding agreement is not the business of life insurance, annuities, health insurance, property insurance, casualty insurance, surety insurance, marine insurance, wet marine and transportation insurance, title insurance, or reinsurance, but is an insurance business.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Solely for the purpose of application of the Tax - General Article, the funding agreements authorized by this section are deemed to be annuity contracts.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
