<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-9-304</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Property and Casualty Insurance Guaranty Corporation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Corporation is a private, nonprofit, nonstock corporation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">As a condition of its authority to transact insurance business in the State, each member insurer must be and remain a member of the Corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Corporation shall:<section prefix="(1)">perform its functions in accordance with a plan of operation established and approved under &#xA7; 9-307 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">exercise its powers through a Board of Directors established under &#xA7; 9-305 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For administration and assessment purposes, the Corporation shall be divided into the following four separate accounts:<section prefix="(1)">the title insurance account;</section><section prefix="(2)">the motor vehicle insurance account;</section><section prefix="(3)">the workers' compensation account; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the account for all other insurance to which this subtitle applies.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, the Corporation has perpetual existence and the powers, privileges, and immunities granted by the applicable provisions of the Corporations and Associations Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Corporation is not and may not be deemed a department, unit, agency, or instrumentality of the State for any purpose.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">All debts, claims, obligations, and liabilities of the Corporation, whenever incurred, shall be the debts, claims, obligations, and liabilities of the Corporation only and not of the State or the State's agencies, instrumentalities, officers, or employees.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The moneys of the Corporation are not part of the General Fund of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State may not budget for or provide General Fund appropriations to the Corporation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The debts, claims, obligations, and liabilities of the Corporation are not a debt of the State or a pledge of the credit of the State.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
