<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-9-201</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Ancillary state" means a state other than a domiciliary state.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Creditor" means a person with a claim against an impaired insurer.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Delinquency proceeding" means a proceeding under this subtitle to liquidate, rehabilitate, reorganize, or conserve an insurer or other entity subject to this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Domiciliary state" means:<section prefix="(1)">the state in which an insurer is incorporated or organized; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the state of entry of an alien insurer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Foreign country" means territory outside of any state.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"General assets" means:<section prefix="(1)">all property that is not specifically mortgaged, pledged, deposited, or otherwise encumbered for the security or benefit of specified persons or a limited class of persons;</section><section prefix="(2)">to the extent that property of an insurer is specifically encumbered, the amount of the property or its proceeds that exceeds the amount necessary to discharge the encumbrance; and</section><section prefix="(3)">assets held in trust and assets held on deposit for the security or benefit of all policyholders and creditors in the United States.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Impaired insurer" means:<section prefix="(1)">a stock insurer whose assets, less all liabilities and required reserves, do not equal or exceed the capital stock and surplus required for authority to engage in insurance business as a stock insurer;</section><section prefix="(2)">a mutual insurer, reciprocal insurer, dental plan organization, or nonprofit health service plan whose assets, less liabilities and required reserves, do not equal or exceed the minimum surplus required under this article for authority to engage in insurance business as a mutual insurer, reciprocal insurer, dental plan organization, or nonprofit health service plan; or</section><section prefix="(3)">as determined by the Commissioner, an insurer that does not have the financial ability to pay an obligation within 30 days after it becomes due.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Insurance business" includes any of the acts of an insurance business specified in &#xA7; 4-205 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Receiver" includes a conservator, rehabilitator, and liquidator.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Reciprocal state" means a state other than this State in which the substance and effect of the provisions of this subtitle are in force, including the requirement that the Commissioner or equivalent insurance supervisory official be the receiver of an insurer subject to a delinquency proceeding and a provision for avoidance of fraudulent conveyances and preferential transfers.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Secured claim" means a claim that:<section prefix="(i)">is secured by mortgage, trust deed, pledge, deposit as security, escrow, or otherwise; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">has become a lien on specific assets through judicial process.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Secured claim" does not include a special deposit claim or a claim against general assets.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Special deposit claim" means a claim secured by a deposit required by law for the security or benefit of a limited class of persons.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Special deposit claim" does not include a claim against general assets.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"State" means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia, or Puerto Rico.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Transfer" means:<section prefix="(1)">the sale or other direct or indirect disposition of property or an interest in property;</section><section prefix="(2)">the fixing of a lien on property or an interest in property; or</section><section prefix="(3)">the retention of a security title to property delivered to a debtor.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
