<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-27-610</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>610</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section applies only to policies of personal insurance and private passenger motor vehicle liability insurance policies subject to &#xA7; 27-613 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless an insurer has provided notice of its intention not to renew a policy in compliance with this subtitle, the insurer must provide each policyholder with notice of renewal premium due at least 45 days before the due date.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a policyholder is being transferred between admitted insurers within the same insurance holding company system, as defined in &#xA7; 7-101 of this article, the notice required under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall include disclosure of the transfer.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A licensed insurance producer may provide notice under paragraph (2) of this subsection on behalf of the insurer.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The duty to provide notice under paragraph (2) of this subsection is deemed discharged if:<section prefix="(i)">the insurer shows that its established procedures would have resulted in placing the notice of renewal premium due in the United States mail; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">there is no showing that in fact the notice was not placed in the mail.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If an insurer fails to provide notice of renewal premium due under subsection (a) of this section, and subsequently the policyholder fails to make timely payment of the renewal premium, the insurer must:<section prefix="(1)">provide coverage for each claim that:<section prefix="(i)">would have been covered under the policy; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">arises within 45 days after the date the insured discovers or should have discovered that the policy was not renewed; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">renew the policy on tender of payment within 30 days after the policyholder discovers or should have discovered that the policy was not renewed.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
