<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-706</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to subsection (c) of this section, a policy, contract, or certificate described in &#xA7; 15-701...</catch_line>
  <order_by>706</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to subsection (c) of this section, a policy, contract, or certificate described in &#xA7; 15-701(a) of this subtitle may provide for reimbursement under &#xA7; 15-701(a) of this subtitle for usual, customary, and reasonable charges for services rendered by a dietitian or nutritionist licensed under the Health Occupations Article if a licensed physician determines that the services are medically necessary for the treatment of cardiovascular disease, diabetes, malnutrition, cancer, cerebral vascular disease, or kidney disease.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Application of this subsection is limited to six visits with a dietitian or nutritionist during a 12-month period for each condition described in paragraph (1) of this subsection and to services for the treatment of obesity only if provided in conjunction with the treatment of a condition described in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not require a policy, contract, or certificate described in &#xA7; 15-701(a) of this subtitle to provide coverage for services rendered by a nutritionist or dietitian.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a service covered under a policy, contract, or certificate described in &#xA7; 15-701(a) of this subtitle is provided to a hospital patient by a dietitian or nutritionist:<section prefix="(1)">the usual, customary, and reasonable charges of the dietitian or nutritionist shall be included in the patient's hospital charges; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the dietitian or nutritionist may not bill the patient separately for the service.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
