<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-8-501</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>501</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"License" means a license issued by the Commissioner to act as a reinsurance intermediary.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Qualified financial institution" means an institution that:<section prefix="(1)">is organized or, in the case of a United States office of a foreign banking organization, licensed under the laws of the United States or a state;</section><section prefix="(2)">is regulated, supervised, and examined by the United States or any state by authorities with regulatory authority over banks and trust companies; and</section><section prefix="(3)">has been determined by the Commissioner or the securities valuation office of the National Association of Insurance Commissioners to meet the standards of financial condition and standing considered necessary and appropriate to regulate the quality of financial institutions whose letters of credit will be acceptable to the Commissioner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Reinsurance broker" means a person that solicits, negotiates, or places reinsurance cessions or retrocessions for a ceding insurer without the authority to bind reinsurance for the ceding insurer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Reinsurance broker" does not include an officer or employee of the ceding insurer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Reinsurance intermediary" means a reinsurance broker or a reinsurance manager.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Reinsurance manager" means a person that:<section prefix="(i)">acts as an insurance producer for a reinsurer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">has authority to bind the reinsurer; or</section><section prefix="2.">manages all or part of the assumed reinsurance business of the reinsurer, including the management of a separate division, department, or underwriting office.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Reinsurance manager" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">an employee of the reinsurer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a United States manager of the United States branch of an alien reinsurer;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an underwriting manager that, by contract:<section prefix="1.">manages all or part of the reinsurance operations of the reinsurer;</section><section prefix="2.">is under common control with the reinsurer; and</section><section prefix="3.">is not compensated based on the volume of premiums written; or</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">the manager of a group, association, pool, or organization of insurers that:<section prefix="1.">engages in joint underwriting or joint reinsurance; and</section><section prefix="2.">is subject to examination by the insurance regulatory authority of the state where the manager's principal business office is located.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Reinsurer" means a person that engages in the business of reinsurance as:<section prefix="(1)">an authorized insurer; or</section><section prefix="(2)">an accepted reinsurer approved by the Commissioner.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
