<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-2-114</section_number>
  <catch_line>The following moneys shall be considered general funds of the State:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>114</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The following moneys shall be considered general funds of the State:<section prefix="(1)">except as provided under &#xA7; 6-107 of this article, revenue received under Title 6, Subtitle 1 of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">all revenue received under &#xA7;&#xA7; 3-324, 4-209, 6-303, and 6-304 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(3)">all penalties imposed by the Commissioner, including the following penalties imposed under:<section prefix="(i)">&#xA7;&#xA7; 4-113(d), 4-212, 10-126(c), 11-232, 14-140, 23-208, 23-506, 26-502, 27-305, and 27-408 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">&#xA7; 19-730 of the Health - General Article.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The following moneys may not be considered general funds of the State and shall be deposited into the Insurance Regulation Fund established under Subtitle 5 of this title:<section prefix="(1)">all revenue received through the imposition and collection of the assessment fee under Subtitle 5 of this title;</section><section prefix="(2)">all revenue received through the imposition and collection of the fees set forth in &#xA7; 2-112 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">all revenue received through the imposition and collection of the fraud prevention fee under Title 6, Subtitle 2 of this article;</section><section prefix="(4)">all revenue received through the collection of examination expenses under &#xA7; 2-208 of this title;</section><section prefix="(5)">except as provided under subsection (a) of this section, all other fees received through the imposition and collection of fees set forth in this article; and</section><section prefix="(6)">income from investments that the State Treasurer makes for the Insurance Regulation Fund.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
