<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-906" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-906</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A Medicare supplement policy shall provide the minimum benefits required by federal law.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For benefits designed to cover deductibles or coinsurance amounts under Medicare, a Medicare supplement policy shall provide for an automatic change in those benefits to coincide with changes in applicable Medicare deductible and copayment provisions.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to approval by the Commissioner, a carrier may reserve the right in a Medicare supplement policy to change premiums to correspond with changes in benefits under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Payment of a benefit for a Medicare eligible expense under a Medicare supplement policy may be conditioned on the same or less restrictive payment conditions that apply to a Medicare claim, including the determination of medical necessity.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless otherwise expressly authorized under this article or a regulation adopted by the Commissioner under this article, coverage under a Medicare supplement policy may not be subject to any exclusion, limitation, or reduction that is inconsistent with the exclusions, limitations, or reductions under Medicare.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To the extent a benefit is available to the insured under Medicare, a Medicare supplement policy shall provide that coverage for the benefit is not duplicated.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the insured is receiving medical assistance under Medicaid, a Medicare supplement policy shall provide for the suspension of policy benefits and premiums for a maximum of 24 months.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A Medicare supplement policy, contract, or certificate in force in the State may not provide benefits that duplicate benefits provided by Medicare.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless approved by the Commissioner, a Medicare supplement policy may not be offered at an introductory premium rate.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
