<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="19-805" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-19-805</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Participation in the Fund by a medical professional liability insurer shall be voluntary.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A medical professional liability insurer seeking reimbursement from the Rate Stabilization Account shall:<section prefix="(i)">determine the amount of the subsidy for each policyholder; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">send a written notice to each policyholder stating:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to &#xA7; 19-804(d) of this subtitle and subsection (c) of this section, the subsidy provided to each policyholder shall be:<section prefix="(1)">for medical professional liability insurance policies subject to rates that were approved for an initial effective date on or after January 1, 2005, but prior to January 1, 2006, the amount of a premium increase that is greater than 5% of the approved rates in effect 1 year prior to the effective date of the policy; and</section><section prefix="(2)">for medical professional liability insurance policies subject to rates that were approved for an initial effective date on or after January 1, 2006, a percentage of the policyholder's premium for the prior year that equals the quotient, measured as a percentage of the balance of the Rate Stabilization Account for the current calendar year divided by the aggregate amount of premiums for medical professional liability insurance that would have been paid by health care providers at the approved rate during the prior calendar year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The State subsidy calculated under subsection (b) of this section may not include the amount of a rate increase resulting from a premium surcharge or the loss of a discount due to a health care provider's loss experience.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A health care provider may elect not to receive a rate reduction, credit, or refund by:<section prefix="(1)">notifying the medical professional liability insurer within 15 days of receiving the notice under subsection (a) of this section of the health care provider's intent not to accept a rate reduction, credit, or refund; and</section><section prefix="(2)">paying, either in full, or on an installment basis, the amount of premium billed by the medical professional liability insurer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A medical professional liability insurer seeking reimbursement from the Rate Stabilization Account on behalf of health care providers shall apply to the Rate Stabilization Account on or before September 30, 2012, on a form and in a manner approved by the Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner may adopt regulations that specify the information that medical professional liability insurers shall submit to receive money from the Rate Stabilization Account.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The information required shall include:<section prefix="(i)">by health care provider classification and geographic territory, the amount of the base premium rate charged by the insurer at the approved rate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">by health care provider classification and geographic territory, the amount of the base premium rate charged by the insurer reduced by the amount of the subsidy;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the number of health care providers in each classification and geographic territory;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the total amount of reimbursement requested from the Rate Stabilization Account;</section><section prefix="(v)">the name, classification, and geographic territory of each health care provider electing not to receive a rate reduction, credit, or refund; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">any other information the Commissioner considers necessary to disburse money from the Rate Stabilization Account.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Within 60 days of receipt of a request for reimbursement from the Fund, the Commissioner shall disburse money from the Rate Stabilization Account to medical professional liability insurers to be used to provide a rate reduction, credit, or refund to health care providers.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In anticipation of reimbursement or on reimbursement from the Rate Stabilization Account, a medical professional liability insurer shall provide a rate reduction, credit, or refund to a policyholder as follows:<section prefix="(1)">for premiums paid on an installment basis, the rate reduction or credit shall be applied against the base premium rate due on the next installment; and</section><section prefix="(2)">if the amount of the rate reduction or credit is more than the amount due on the next installment, or if a policy is paid in full, the policyholder may elect that either a refund be issued, or that a credit be applied against the base premium rate due on the policyholder's next renewal.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">During the period in which disbursements are made from the Rate Stabilization Account to pay for health care provider rate reductions, credits, or refunds:<section prefix="(1)">a disbursement from the Rate Stabilization Account to a medical professional liability insurer conducting business as a mutual company shall be reduced by the value of a dividend that may be issued by the insurer; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a disbursement may not be made from the Rate Stabilization Account to the Medical Mutual Liability Insurance Society of Maryland during any period for which the Commissioner has determined, under &#xA7; 24-212 of this article, that the surplus of the Society is excessive.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
