<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-112</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>112</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Accredited hospital" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 19-301 of the Health - General Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Ambulatory surgical facility" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 19-3B-01 of the Health - General Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Carrier" means:<section prefix="1.">an insurer;</section><section prefix="2.">a nonprofit health service plan;</section><section prefix="3.">a health maintenance organization;</section><section prefix="4.">a dental plan organization; or</section><section prefix="5.">any other person that provides health benefit plans subject to regulation by the State.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Carrier" includes an entity that arranges a provider panel for a carrier.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Credentialing intermediary" means a person to whom a carrier has delegated credentialing or recredentialing authority and responsibility.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Enrollee" means a person entitled to health care benefits from a carrier.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Hospital" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 19-301 of the Health - General Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Participating provider" means a provider on a carrier's provider panel.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">"Online credentialing system" means the system through which a provider may access an online provider credentialing application that the Commissioner has designated as the uniform credentialing form under &#xA7; 15-112.1(e) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(10)">"Provider" means a health care practitioner or group of health care practitioners licensed, certified, or otherwise authorized by law to provide health care services.</section>
      <section prefix="(11)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Provider panel" means the providers that contract either directly or through a subcontracting entity with a carrier to provide health care services to the carrier's enrollees under the carrier's health benefit plan.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Provider panel" does not include an arrangement in which any provider may participate solely by contracting with the carrier to provide health care services at a discounted fee-for-service rate.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A carrier that uses a provider panel shall:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">if the carrier is an insurer, nonprofit health service plan, or dental plan organization, maintain standards in accordance with regulations adopted by the Commissioner for availability of health care providers to meet the health care needs of enrollees;</section><section prefix="2.">if the carrier is a health maintenance organization, adhere to the standards for accessibility of covered services in accordance with regulations adopted under &#xA7; 19-705.1(b)(1)(i)2 of the Health - General Article; and</section><section prefix="3.">if the carrier is an insurer or nonprofit health service plan that offers a preferred provider insurance  policy that conditions the payment of benefits on the use of  preferred providers, adhere to the standards for accessibility of covered services in accordance with regulations adopted under &#xA7; 19-705.1(b)(1)(i)2 of the Health - General Article and as enforced by  the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">establish procedures to:<section prefix="1.">review applications for participation on the carrier's  provider panel in accordance with this section;</section><section prefix="2.">notify an enrollee of:</section><section prefix="3.">notify primary care providers on the carrier's provider  panel of the termination of a specialty referral services provider;</section><section prefix="4.">verify with each provider on the carrier's provider  panel, at the time of credentialing and recredentialing, whether the provider is  accepting new patients and update the information on participating providers that the  carrier is required to provide under subsection (j) of this section; and</section><section prefix="5.">notify a provider at least 90 days before the date of  the termination of the provider from the carrier's provider panel, if the termination is  for reasons unrelated to fraud, patient abuse, incompetency, or loss of licensure status.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The provisions of paragraph (1)(ii)4 of this subsection may not be construed to require a carrier to allow a provider to refuse to accept new patients covered by the carrier.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A carrier that uses a provider panel:<section prefix="(1)">on request, shall provide an application and information that relates to consideration for participation on the carrier's provider panel to any provider seeking to apply for participation;</section><section prefix="(2)">shall make publicly available its application; and</section><section prefix="(3)">shall make efforts to increase the opportunity for a broad range of minority providers to participate on the carrier's provider panel.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A provider that seeks to participate on a provider panel of a carrier shall submit an application to the carrier.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, the carrier, after reviewing the application, shall accept or reject the provider for participation on the carrier's provider panel.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the carrier rejects the provider for participation on the carrier's provider panel, the carrier shall send to the provider at the address listed in the application written notice of the rejection.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection, within 30 days after the date a carrier receives a completed application, the carrier shall send to the provider at the address listed in the application written notice of:<section prefix="1.">the carrier's intent to continue to process the provider's application to obtain necessary credentialing information; or</section><section prefix="2.">the carrier's rejection of the provider for participation on the carrier's provider panel.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The failure of a carrier to provide the notice required under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph is a violation of this article and the carrier is subject to the penalties provided by &#xA7; 4-113(d) of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Except as provided in subsection (o) of this section, if, under subparagraph (i)1 of this paragraph, a carrier provides notice to the provider of its intent to continue to process the provider's application to obtain necessary credentialing information, the carrier, within 120 days after the date the notice is provided, shall:<section prefix="1.">accept or reject the provider for participation on the carrier's provider panel; and</section><section prefix="2.">send written notice of the acceptance or rejection to the provider at the address listed in the application.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The failure of a carrier to provide the notice required under subparagraph (iii)2 of this paragraph is a violation of this article and the carrier is subject to the provisions of and penalties provided by &#xA7;&#xA7; 4-113 and 4-114 of this article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">
          <section prefix="1.">Except as provided in subsubparagraph 4 of this subparagraph, a carrier that receives a complete application shall notify the provider that the application is complete.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">If a carrier does not accept applications through the online credentialing system, notice shall be given to the provider at the address listed in the application within 10 days after the date the application is received.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">If a carrier accepts applications through the online credentialing system, the notice from the online credentialing system to the provider that the carrier has received the provider's application shall be considered notice that the application is complete.</section>
          <section prefix="4.">This subparagraph does not apply to a carrier that arranges a dental provider panel until the Commissioner certifies that the online credentialing system is capable of accepting the uniform credentialing form designated by the Commissioner for dental provider panels.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">A carrier that receives an incomplete application shall return the application to the provider at the address listed in the application within 10 days after the date the application is received.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The carrier shall indicate to the provider what information is needed to make the application complete.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">The provider may return the completed application to the carrier.</section>
          <section prefix="4.">After the carrier receives the completed application, the carrier is subject to the time periods established in paragraph (3) of this subsection.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A carrier may charge a reasonable fee for an application submitted to the carrier under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A carrier may not deny an application for participation or terminate participation on its provider panel on the basis of:<section prefix="(1)">gender, race, age, religion, national origin, or a protected category under the federal Americans with Disabilities Act;</section><section prefix="(2)">the type or number of appeals that the provider files under Subtitle 10B of this title;</section><section prefix="(3)">the number of grievances or complaints that the provider files on behalf of a patient under Subtitle 10A of this title; or</section><section prefix="(4)">the type or number of complaints or grievances that the provider files or requests for review under the carrier's internal review system established under subsection (h) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A carrier may not deny an application for participation or terminate participation on its provider panel solely on the basis of the license, certification, or other authorization of the provider to provide health care services if the carrier provides health care services within the provider's lawful scope of practice.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, a carrier may reject an application for participation or terminate participation on its provider panel based on the participation on the provider panel of a sufficient number of similarly qualified providers.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A violation of this subsection does not create a new cause of action.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f-1)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of this subsection, a carrier may not require a provider participating on its provider panel to be recredentialed based on:<section prefix="(i)">a change in the federal tax identification number of the provider;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a change in the federal tax identification number of a provider's employer; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a change in the employer of a provider, if the new employer is:<section prefix="1.">a participating provider on the carrier's provider panel; or</section><section prefix="2.">the employer of providers that participate on the carrier's provider panel.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A provider that participates on a carrier's provider panel or the provider's employer shall give written notice to the carrier of a change in the federal tax identification number of the provider or the provider's employer not less than 45 days before the effective date of the change.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The notice required under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall include:<section prefix="(i)">a statement of the intention of the provider or the provider's employer to continue to provide health care services in the same field of specialization, if applicable;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the effective date of the change in the federal tax identification number of the provider or the provider's employer;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the new federal tax identification number of the provider or the provider's employer and a copy of U.S. Treasury Form W-9, or any successor or replacement form; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the following information about a new employer of the provider:<section prefix="1.">the employer's name;</section><section prefix="2.">the name of the employer's contact person for carrier questions about the provider; and</section><section prefix="3.">the address, telephone number, facsimile transmission number, and electronic mail address of the contact person for the employer.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the new federal tax identification number or the form required to be included in the notice under paragraph (3)(iii) of this subsection is not available at the time the notice is given to a carrier, it shall be provided to the carrier promptly after it is received by the provider or the provider's employer.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Within 30 business days after receipt of the notice required under paragraph (2) of this subsection, a carrier:<section prefix="(i)">shall acknowledge receipt of the notice to the provider or the provider's employer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the carrier considers it necessary to issue a new provider number as a result of a change in the federal tax identification number of a provider or a provider's employer or a change in the employer of a provider, shall issue a new provider number, by mail, electronic mail, or facsimile transmission, to:<section prefix="1.">the provider or the provider's employer; or</section><section prefix="2.">the representative of the provider or the provider's employer designated in writing to the carrier.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A carrier may not terminate its existing contract with a provider or a provider's employer based solely on a notice given to the carrier in accordance with this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A carrier may not terminate participation on its provider panel or otherwise penalize a provider for:<section prefix="(1)">advocating the interests of a patient through the carrier's internal review system established under subsection (h) of this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">filing an appeal under Subtitle 10B of this title; or</section><section prefix="(3)">filing a grievance or complaint on behalf of a patient under Subtitle 10A of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Each carrier shall establish an internal review system to resolve grievances initiated by providers that participate on the carrier's provider panel, including grievances involving the termination of a provider from participation on the carrier's provider panel.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For at least 90 days after the date of the notice of termination of a primary care provider from a carrier's provider panel for reasons unrelated to fraud, patient abuse, incompetency, or loss of licensure status, the primary care provider shall furnish health care services to each enrollee:<section prefix="(i)">who was receiving health care services from the primary care provider before the notice of termination; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">who, after receiving notice under subsection (b) of this section of the termination of the primary care provider, requests to continue receiving health care services from the primary care provider.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A carrier shall reimburse a primary care provider that furnishes health care services under this subsection in accordance with the primary care provider's agreement with the carrier.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A carrier shall make available to prospective enrollees on the Internet and, on request of a prospective enrollee, in printed form:<section prefix="(i)">a list of providers on the carrier's provider panel; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">information on providers that are no longer accepting new patients.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A carrier shall notify each enrollee at the time of initial enrollment and renewal about how to obtain the following information on the Internet and in printed form:<section prefix="(i)">a list of providers on the carrier's provider panel; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">information on providers that are no longer accepting new patients.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Information provided in printed form under paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection shall be updated at least once a year.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subject to subsection (m) of this section, information provided on the Internet under paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection shall be updated at least once every 15 days.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A policy, certificate, or other evidence of coverage shall:<section prefix="(i)">indicate clearly the office in the Administration that is responsible for receiving and responding to complaints from enrollees about carriers; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">include the telephone number of the office and the procedure for filing a complaint.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The Commissioner:<section prefix="(1)">shall adopt regulations that relate to the procedures that carriers must use to process applications for participation on a provider panel; and</section><section prefix="(2)">in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene, shall adopt strategies to assist carriers in maximizing the opportunity for a broad range of minority providers to participate in the delivery of health care services.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">A carrier may not include in a contract with a provider, ambulatory surgical facility, or hospital a term or condition that:<section prefix="(1)">prohibits the provider, ambulatory surgical facility, or hospital from offering to provide services to the enrollees of another carrier at a lower rate of reimbursement;</section><section prefix="(2)">requires the provider, ambulatory surgical facility, or hospital to provide the carrier with the same reimbursement arrangement that the provider, ambulatory surgical facility, or hospital has with another carrier if the reimbursement arrangement with the other carrier is for a lower rate of reimbursement; or</section><section prefix="(3)">requires the provider, ambulatory surgical facility, or hospital to certify to the carrier that the reimbursement rate being paid by the carrier to the provider, ambulatory surgical facility, or hospital is not higher than the reimbursement rate being received by the provider, ambulatory surgical facility, or hospital from another carrier.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A carrier shall update its provider information under subsection (j)(3)(ii) of this section within 15 working days after receipt of written notification from the participating provider of a change in the applicable information.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notification is presumed to have been received by a carrier:<section prefix="(i)">3 working days after the date the participating provider placed the notification in the U.S. mail, if the participating provider maintains the stamped certificate of mailing for the notice; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">on the date recorded by the courier, if the notification was delivered by courier.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A carrier may not require a provider that provides health care services through a group practice or health care facility that participates on the carrier's provider panel under a contract with the carrier to be considered a participating provider or accept the reimbursement fee schedule applicable under the contract when:<section prefix="(i)">providing health care services to enrollees of the carrier through an individual or group practice or health care facility that does not have a contract with the carrier; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">billing for health care services provided to enrollees of the carrier using a different federal tax identification number than that used by the group practice or health care facility under a contract with the carrier.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A nonparticipating provider shall notify an enrollee:<section prefix="(i)">that the provider does not participate on the provider panel of the enrollee's carrier; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">of the anticipated total charges for the health care services.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">The provisions of subsection (d)(3)(iii) of this section do not apply to a carrier that uses a credentialing intermediary that:<section prefix="(1)">is a hospital or academic medical center;</section><section prefix="(2)">is a participating provider on the carrier's provider panel; and</section><section prefix="(3)">acts as a credentialing intermediary for that carrier for health care practitioners that:<section prefix="(i)">participate on the carrier's provider panel; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">have privileges at the hospital or academic medical center.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding subsection (n)(1) of this section, a carrier shall reimburse a group practice on the carrier's provider panel at the participating provider rate for covered services provided by a provider who is not a participating provider if:<section prefix="(i)">the provider is employed by or a member of the group practice;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the provider has applied for acceptance on the carrier's provider panel and the carrier has notified the provider of the carrier's intent to continue to process the provider's application to obtain necessary credentialing information;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the provider has a valid license issued by a health occupations board to practice in the State; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the provider:<section prefix="1.">is currently credentialed by an accredited hospital in the State; or</section><section prefix="2.">has professional liability insurance.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A carrier shall reimburse a group practice on the carrier's provider panel in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection from the date the notice required under subsection (d)(3)(i)1 of this section is sent to the provider until the date the notice required under subsection (d)(3)(iii)2 of this section is sent to the provider.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A carrier that sends written notice of rejection of a provider for credentialing under subsection (d)(3)(iii)2 of this section shall reimburse the provider as a nonparticipating provider for covered services provided on or after the date the notice is sent.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A health maintenance organization may not deny payment to a provider under this subsection solely because the provider was not a participating provider at the time the services were provided to an enrollee.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A provider who is not a participating provider of a carrier and whose group practice is eligible for reimbursement under paragraph (1) of this subsection may not hold an enrollee of the carrier liable for the cost of any covered services provided to the enrollee during the time period described in paragraph (2) of this subsection, except for any deductible, copayment, or coinsurance amount owed by the enrollee to the group practice or provider under the terms of the enrollee's contract or certificate.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A group practice shall disclose in writing to an enrollee at the time services are provided that:<section prefix="(i)">the treating provider is not a participating provider;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the treating provider has applied to become a participating provider;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the carrier has not completed its assessment of the qualifications of the treating provider to provide services as a participating provider; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">any covered services received must be reimbursed by the carrier at the participating provider rate.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
