<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-25-405</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>405</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Governing Committee shall adopt a program of operation in accordance with this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The program of operation shall provide for economical, fair, and nondiscriminatory administration and for the prompt and efficient delivery of essential property insurance and homeowner's insurance to promote orderly community development.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With the approval of the Commissioner, the Association may amend the program of operation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Association members shall vote on proposed amendments to the program of operation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Votes shall be cast and counted on a weighted basis in accordance with the premiums written by each Association member.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An amendment to the program of operation is not effective until approved by a majority of the votes cast by Association members.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The program of operation shall provide for:<section prefix="(1)">establishment of adequate service facilities and other necessary facilities;</section><section prefix="(2)">management of the Association;</section><section prefix="(3)">assessment of Association members to defray losses and expenses;</section><section prefix="(4)">commission arrangements;</section><section prefix="(5)">reasonable and objective underwriting standards;</section><section prefix="(6)">acceptance and cession of reinsurance;</section><section prefix="(7)">procedures to determine amounts of insurance to be provided;</section><section prefix="(8)">immediate binding of eligible risks;</section><section prefix="(9)">a premium installment plan; and</section><section prefix="(10)">notwithstanding Title 27, Subtitle 6 of this article, underwriting guidelines and procedures that allow the Association to shorten the cancellation period for policies of essential property insurance and homeowner's insurance for certain conditions that are determined to exist.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The program of operation shall provide that the Association may not appoint insurance producers to act on its behalf and shall do business directly with applicants or with licensed insurance producers that represent applicants.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The program of operation shall establish:<section prefix="(1)">a maximum limit of liability of $1,500,000 on real or personal property composed of or contained in a single building; and</section><section prefix="(2)">appropriate sublimits of liability based on construction, protection, and class of occupancy.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The program of operation shall implement procedures to make homeowner's insurance coverage available through the Association.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The homeowner's insurance policies that the Association issues may be limited to basic market value, repair cost, or actual cash value contracts for owner-occupants of one- to four-family dwellings, as approved by the Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The homeowner's insurance shall be implemented through a program that entitles eligible applicants to immediate binding of coverage through the Association for a reasonable period of time pending underwriting and inspection of the premises to determine whether the premises meet the eligibility standards of the program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The program of operation shall provide a method of recoupment by which Association members may recover losses and expenses that have been incurred by the Association and assessed to Association members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To recoup loss and expense assessments, the program of operation shall provide for:<section prefix="(i)">the calculation of the surcharge or rating factors to be added to direct premiums written for essential property insurance and homeowner's insurance covering property located in the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">an adjustment each year for over or under recoupment of assessment.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The program of operation shall develop a participation credit for dwellings as an offset to Association member assessment for voluntary writings in those areas of the State with a significant proportion of essential property insurance policies or homeowner's insurance policies issued by or for the Association.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After consultation with the Governing Committee, the Commissioner shall determine whether an area has a significant proportion of Association policies.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
