<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-916</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>916</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commissioner shall prepare in clear, plain English the text of a Medicare supplement buyer's guide that carriers must provide to prospective buyers of Medicare supplement policies under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The buyer's guide shall:<section prefix="(1)">contain an outline of Medicare coverage; and</section><section prefix="(2)">include advice and other information about purchasing Medicare supplement policies, including a reference to the right of the buyer to cancel a Medicare supplement policy during the first 30 days after it is delivered, as provided in &#xA7; 15-910 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner shall submit the text of the buyer's guide for publication in the Maryland Register and at the same time send a copy of the text to the Department of Aging.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The carrier or insurance producer of the carrier shall deliver to the prospective buyer a Medicare supplement buyer's guide that is printed in at least 12-point type:<section prefix="(1)">before accepting an application;</section><section prefix="(2)">when an existing policy is converted to a Medicare supplement policy; and</section><section prefix="(3)">at any other time required by the Commissioner by regulation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A carrier shall provide:<section prefix="(1)">a copy of the Medicare supplement buyer's guide to an individual covered under a group health insurance policy when the individual becomes eligible for Medicare by reason of age; and</section><section prefix="(2)">any information required under &#xA7; 15-919 of this subtitle that is applicable to the continuing coverage under the group health insurance policy of the individual eligible for Medicare.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The text of the Medicare supplement buyer's guide shall be as the Commissioner submits for publication under subsection (c) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The form of the Medicare supplement buyer's guide shall be as required by the Commissioner by regulation.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
