<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-20-520</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, an insurer that issues, sells, or delivers pri...</catch_line>
  <order_by>520</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, an insurer that issues, sells, or delivers private passenger motor vehicle insurance in the State may not refuse to issue a policy of private passenger motor vehicle insurance to any person who, for the immediately preceding 3 continuous years:<section prefix="(1)">has been insured by the Fund;</section><section prefix="(2)">has not had a moving traffic violation; and</section><section prefix="(3)">has not had a chargeable traffic accident.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to &#xA7; 27-501 of this article, an insurer may refuse to issue a policy under subsection (a) of this section if the person does not satisfy the insurer's eligibility or underwriting standards.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person who is entitled to insurance under subsection (a) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">shall be rated by the insurer in the same manner as any other policyholder not previously insured by the Fund having the same risk characteristics; and</section><section prefix="(2)">may not be surcharged or rated by the insurer solely because the person was insured by the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 60 days before expiration or renewal of a policy of private passenger motor vehicle insurance, the Fund shall provide written notice to each person entitled to insurance under subsection (a) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice shall:<section prefix="(i)">inform the person of the person's right to insurance under subsection (a) of this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">advise the person to contact the fund producer that bound the person's coverage with the Fund during the most recent coverage period;</section><section prefix="(iii)">include a copy of a sample rate guide produced by the Administration; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">provide the toll-free telephone number established under &#xA7; 2-109 of this article.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
