<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="20-509" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-20-509</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to this section and the regulations that relate to the binding of coverage, a fund producer may bind the minimum required coverage for an applicant in the Fund if the applicant submits an application to the fund producer and pays the appropriate premium.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To effect coverage, the fund producer must receive payment of the appropriate premium required under the regulations that relate to the binding of coverage.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Payment of the appropriate premium does not occur so as to effect coverage if payment of all or part of the premium is made by an instrument that is later dishonored.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of Trustees shall adopt and make available to each fund producer reasonable regulations that relate to the authority of fund producers to bind coverage.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The regulations shall include:<section prefix="(i)">the amount of premium to be collected;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the evidence necessary to establish the qualification of an applicant to be insured by the Fund;</section><section prefix="(iii)">procedures for notifying the Fund of the binding of coverage; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the time within which the fund producer is to give notice.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Fund:<section prefix="(1)">may refuse to grant the authority of a fund producer to an insurance producer that has been previously terminated as a fund producer or that has had its license previously revoked or surrendered; and</section><section prefix="(2)">subject to the hearing provisions of &#xA7; 20-514 of this subtitle, may discipline a fund producer that:<section prefix="(i)">employs or otherwise retains a person described in item (1) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">allows the person to become involved in the fund producer's operations or management contrary to a requirement of this article or order of the Administration.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Subject to subsection (e) of this section, the Fund is liable for coverage from the date that the fund producer binds coverage.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On review of an application, the Fund may cancel coverage and refuse to issue a policy if the Fund finds that:<section prefix="(i)">the applicant is not qualified for insurance issued by the Fund;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the applicant has not paid the appropriate premium; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Fund is authorized to reject the application under &#xA7; 20-516 of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Cancellation of coverage may occur not later than 60 days after coverage is effective.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Whenever coverage is canceled:<section prefix="(1)">the Fund promptly shall notify the applicant, fund producer, and Motor Vehicle Administration of the cancellation;</section><section prefix="(2)">the applicant has the right of appeal under &#xA7; 20-517 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(3)">if the cancellation occurred because an applicant did not pay the appropriate premium, the Fund shall give the applicant a reasonable opportunity to pay the appropriate premium.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
