<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-808</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>808</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "home health care" means the continued care and treatment of a covered individual if:<section prefix="(1)">institutionalization of the individual would have been required if home health care was not provided; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the individual's physician establishes and approves in writing the plan of treatment covering the home health care service.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to each individual, group, or blanket health insurance policy that is issued or delivered in the State by an insurer or nonprofit health service plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A policy subject to this section that provides coverage for inpatient hospital care on an expense-incurred basis shall provide benefits for the expenses of home health care that is provided by a person licensed under the Health Occupations Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Home health care shall be provided by:<section prefix="(1)">a hospital that has a valid operating certificate and is certified to provide home health care services; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a public or private health service or agency that is licensed as a home health agency under Title 19, Subtitle 4 of the Health - General Article to provide coordinated home health care.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A contract may limit the number of home health care visits, but not to fewer than 40 visits in a calendar year or in a continuous 12-month period for each individual covered under the contract.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In determining the benefits for home health care available to a covered individual:<section prefix="(i)">each visit by a member of a home health care team is considered one home health care visit; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">up to 4 hours of home health care service is considered one home health care visit.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
