<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-10-111</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person who applies for a license as a resident insurance producer shall:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>111</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person who applies for a license as a resident insurance producer shall:<section prefix="(1)">in the case of an applicant who is an individual, submit to the Commissioner a uniform application and declare under penalty of refusal, suspension, or revocation of the license that the statements made in the uniform application are true, correct, and complete to the best of the individual's knowledge and belief;</section><section prefix="(2)">in the case of an applicant that is a business entity, submit to the Commissioner a uniform business entity application;</section><section prefix="(3)">pay the applicable fee required by &#xA7; 2-112 of this article for a license;</section><section prefix="(4)">file on the form and in the manner that the Commissioner provides:<section prefix="(i)">any trade name to be used by the applicant;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the business address of the applicant; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the name and residence address of each individual who holds a license and does business under the trade name; and</section></section><section prefix="(5)">submit to the Commissioner any additional information or documentation that the Commissioner requires, including any information or documentation to determine the professional competence, good character, and trustworthiness of the applicant.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An applicant who has experience in the armed forces of the United States and qualifies under &#xA7; 10-104(e)(3) of this subtitle must file an application within 1 year after the date of discharge from the armed forces.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to a motor vehicle rental company that applies for a limited lines license to sell insurance in connection with, and incidental to, the rental of a motor vehicle under Subtitle 6 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to any other information required on the application, an applicant that is a business entity must:<section prefix="(i)">identify the licensed insurance producer who is designated to act as the business entity's principal contact with the Administration; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">provide the name and address of each licensed producer employed by the business entity, each individual who has direct control over its fiscal management, and each owner, member, or manager of the business entity and each director of a business entity that is a corporation.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
