<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-26-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An applicant for a license shall deposit with the Treasurer, who shall maintain in trust:<section prefix="(1)">registered United States government bonds with a market value at all times not less than $100,000 or, in the discretion of the Commissioner, a lower amount not less than $15,000;</section><section prefix="(2)">a corporate surety bond in the form that the Commissioner requires in a penal sum not less than $100,000 or, in the discretion of the Commissioner, a lower amount not less than $15,000; or</section><section prefix="(3)">a letter of credit in the form that the Commissioner requires in an amount not less than $100,000 or, in the discretion of the Commissioner, a lower amount not less than $15,000.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The bond or letter of credit described under subsection (a)(2) or (3) of this section shall be:<section prefix="(i)">in favor of the State for the members of the applicant that reside in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">issued by a surety insurer or bank authorized to do business in the State; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">conditioned on the faithful performance by the applicant of its obligations under this title, including payment of any fines, fees, or penalties imposed on it or restitution ordered under this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The total liability of the surety insurer under the bond may not exceed the penal sum of the bond.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The total liability of the bank under the letter of credit may not exceed the amount of the letter of credit.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The surety insurer or bank may cancel the bond or letter of credit after notifying the Commissioner at least 30 days before the effective date of the cancellation.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Neither the surety insurer nor the bank is liable for any breach of condition that occurs after the effective date of the cancellation.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Commissioner may adopt regulations that specify conditions for surety bonds and letters of credit required by this section and provide methods for their termination.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The security required by subsection (a) of this section shall be maintained as long as the licensee has any outstanding liability or obligation in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to approval by the Commissioner, the licensee may substitute any type of security required by subsection (a) of this section for any other type of security required by subsection (a) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On proof satisfactory to the Commissioner that the licensee has stopped doing business and that all of the licensee's liabilities and obligations have been satisfied, the Commissioner shall authorize the Treasurer to return the security to the licensee.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
