<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-27-214</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>214</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not require another person to buy insurance through a particular insurance producer or insurer as a condition, agreement, or understanding with respect to selling or providing a loan, credit, sale, goods, property, contract, lease, or service to the other person.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An insurance producer or insurer may not participate in a combination plan or transaction prohibited by paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not solicit the combination of insurance and other matters prohibited by subsection (a) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An insurance producer or insurer may not participate in a plan of public solicitation of the combination of insurance and other matters prohibited by subsection (a) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This subsection does not prohibit a person from being an insurance producer and engaging in another business at the same time or place if:<section prefix="(i)">the sales of insurance and other matters are not combined or coerced as prohibited by subsection (a) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the buyer or other person has the free choice of insurance.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Violation of this section does not invalidate any contract or transaction.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding a combination contract, tying agreement, understanding, or condition to the contrary, the person required to buy or pay for insurance or to bid ex-insurance may substitute at any time other insurance from insurance producers or insurers chosen by the person, or may decline further insurance coverage if the insurance is other than to protect the interest of a lender, property owner, or other person.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
