<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-31-102</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Maryland Health Benefit Exchange....</catch_line>
  <order_by>102</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Maryland Health Benefit Exchange.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Exchange is a body politic and corporate and is an instrumentality of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Exchange is a public corporation and a unit of State government.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The exercise by the Exchange of its authority under this title is an essential governmental function.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The purposes of the Exchange are to:<section prefix="(1)">reduce the number of uninsured in the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">facilitate the purchase and sale of qualified health plans in the individual market in the State by providing a transparent marketplace;</section><section prefix="(3)">assist qualified employers in the State in facilitating the enrollment of their employees in qualified health plans in the small group market in the State and in accessing small business tax credits;</section><section prefix="(4)">assist individuals in accessing public programs, premium tax credits, and cost-sharing reductions; and</section><section prefix="(5)">supplement the individual and small group insurance markets outside of the Exchange.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Nothing in this title, and no regulation adopted or other action taken by the Exchange under this title, may be construed to:<section prefix="(1)">preempt or supersede:<section prefix="(i)">the authority of the Commissioner to regulate insurance business in the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the requirements of the Affordable Care Act;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">authorize the Exchange to carry out any function not authorized by the Affordable Care Act; or</section><section prefix="(3)">authorize the Exchange to offer any products or services except qualified health plans qualified dental plans, and qualified vision plans</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
