<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-603" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-603</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene notifies an insurer or nonprofit health service plan that the Department has paid for or provided services to an individual who is covered under an individual, group, or blanket health insurance policy or contract that the insurer or nonprofit health service plan issued, delivered, or renewed in the State, the insurer or nonprofit health service plan shall reimburse the Department for the cost of the services, regardless of any provision in the health insurance policy or contract that requires payment to the policyholder, subscriber, or another payee.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The benefits payable to the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene under this section are limited to those benefits available under the terms and conditions of the health insurance policy or contract for the services paid for or provided by the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An insurer or nonprofit health service plan is not required to make payment to the Department under this section if, before receiving notice from the Department under subsection (a) of this section, the insurer or nonprofit health service plan has paid the benefits available under the health insurance policy or contract in good faith and in accordance with the terms and conditions of the policy or contract.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding any other provision of a health insurance policy, contract, or certificate, an insurer or nonprofit health service plan may not refuse to reimburse the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene because of the manner, form, or date of a claim for reimbursement if, within 2 years after the date of the service for which reimbursement is sought, the Department provides to the insurer or nonprofit health service plan sufficient information to determine the liability of the insurer or nonprofit health service plan.</section>
  </text>
</law>
