<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-1207" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-1207</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In accordance with Title 19, Subtitle 1 of the Health - General Article, the Commission shall adopt regulations that specify:<section prefix="(1)">the Comprehensive Standard Health Benefit Plan to apply under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the requirements for a wellness benefit offered by a carrier to apply under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Commission shall exclude or limit benefits or adjust cost-sharing arrangements in the Standard Plan if the average rate for the Standard Plan exceeds 10% of the average annual wage in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission annually shall determine the average rate for the Standard Plan by using the average rate submitted by each carrier that offers the Standard Plan.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In establishing benefits, the Commission shall judge preventive services, medical treatments, procedures, and related health services based on:<section prefix="(1)">their effectiveness in improving the health status of individuals;</section><section prefix="(2)">their impact on maintaining and improving health and on reducing the unnecessary consumption of health care services; and</section><section prefix="(3)">their impact on the affordability of health care coverage.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commission may exclude:<section prefix="(1)">a health care service, benefit, coverage, or reimbursement for covered health care services that is required under this article or the Health - General Article to be provided or offered in a health benefit plan that is issued or delivered in the State by a carrier; or</section><section prefix="(2)">reimbursement required by statute, by a health benefit plan for a service when that service is performed by a health care provider who is licensed under the Health Occupations Article and whose scope of practice includes that service.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commission shall include mental health and substance abuse benefits required under &#xA7; 15-802 of this title and &#xA7; 19-703.1 of the Health - General Article for employers that meet the large employer definition under &#xA7; 15-802 of this title and &#xA7; 19-703.1 of the Health - General Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commission shall specify the deductibles and cost-sharing associated with the benefits in the Standard Plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In establishing cost-sharing as part of the Standard Plan, the Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">include cost-sharing and other incentives to help prevent consumers from seeking unnecessary services;</section><section prefix="(2)">balance the effect of cost-sharing in reducing premiums and in affecting utilization of appropriate services; and</section><section prefix="(3)">limit the total cost-sharing that may be incurred by an individual in a year.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
