<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-401" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-9-401</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Account" means:<section prefix="(1)">the health insurance account;</section><section prefix="(2)">the life insurance account; or</section><section prefix="(3)">the annuity account.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Association" means the Corporation or any similar organization that has been formed in another state that serves the same purpose as the Corporation for the other state.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Contractual obligation" means an obligation under a policy or contract or certificate under a group policy or contract for which coverage is provided under &#xA7; 9-403 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Corporation" means the Life and Health Insurance Guaranty Corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Covered policy" means a policy or contract to which this subtitle applies.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Impaired insurer" means an insurer that:<section prefix="(1)">after July 1, 1971, is not an insolvent insurer and is placed under an order of rehabilitation or conservation by a court of competent jurisdiction; or</section><section prefix="(2)">is determined by the Commissioner after July 1, 1971, to be unable or potentially unable to fulfill its contractual obligations.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Individual" means a natural person covered under an individual policy or covered as a member under a group policy.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Insolvent insurer" means a member insurer that, after July 1, 1971, is placed under an order of liquidation by a court of competent jurisdiction with a finding of insolvency.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Member insurer" means an authorized insurer that writes a kind of insurance to which this subtitle applies.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Member insurer" includes an insurer whose license or certificate of authority in the State may have been suspended, revoked, not renewed, or voluntarily withdrawn.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Member insurer" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">a health maintenance organization;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a fraternal benefit society;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a mandatory State pooling plan;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a mutual assessment company or other entity that operates on an assessment basis; or</section><section prefix="(v)">an insurance exchange.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Moody's corporate bond yield average" means the monthly average yield on corporate bonds as published by Moody's Investors Service, Inc.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Premiums" means amounts received on covered policies or contracts, less premiums, considerations, and deposits returned, and less dividends and experience credits.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Premiums" does not include amounts for policies or contracts, or for parts of policies or contracts, for which coverage is not provided under &#xA7; 9-403(g) of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Resident" means a person that resides in the State on the date of entry of a court order that determines a member insurer to be an impaired insurer or a court order that determines a member insurer to be an insolvent insurer and to whom a contractual obligation is owed.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Structured settlement annuity" means an annuity purchased in order to fund periodic payments for a plaintiff or any other claimant in payment for or with respect to personal injury suffered by the plaintiff or other claimant.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Supplemental contract" means an agreement entered into for the distribution of policy or contract proceeds.</section>
  </text>
</law>
