<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-106.2" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-14-106.2</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to a corporation that is:<section prefix="(1)">issued a certificate of authority as a nonprofit health service plan; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the sole member of a corporation issued a certificate of authority as a nonprofit health service plan.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided under subsection (c) of this section, beginning with the calendar year that starts on January 1, 2009, and each calendar year thereafter, a corporation subject to this section shall transfer $4,000,000 to the separate account for the Senior Prescription Drug Assistance Program within the Maryland Health Insurance Plan Fund established under &#xA7; 14-504 of this title if the corporation has a surplus that exceeds 800% of the consolidated risk-based capital requirements applicable to the corporation based on the corporation's annual required statutory filing due March 1 of the most recent preceding calendar year for which:<section prefix="(1)">the corporation has filed an annual statement with the Administration; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the filing of the annual statement preceded the start of the calendar year for which payment is to be made.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A corporation is not required to make the transfer under subsection (b) of this section if:<section prefix="(1)">the surplus of the corporation does not exceed 800% of the consolidated risk-based capital requirements applicable to the corporation in the most recent preceding calendar year for which:<section prefix="(i)">the corporation has filed an annual statement with the Administration; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the filing of the annual statement preceded the start of the calendar year for which payment is to be made; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the federal government eliminates the coverage gap in the Medicare Part D prescription drug benefit.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before September 1 of each year, a corporation that is subject to this section shall notify the Senior Prescription Drug Assistance Program whether the corporation will transfer $4,000,000 to the Program under this section during the calendar year that starts on the immediately following January 1.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The corporation's determination on the transfer of funds shall be based on the risk-based capital calculation that is due on March 1 of the same calendar year in which the corporation gives the notice required under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A corporation that is subject to this section shall pay the $4,000,000 to the Senior Prescription Drug Assistance Program in quarterly installments of $1,000,000, beginning not later than October 1 for the calendar year that starts on the immediately following January 1.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The transfer of funds that a corporation is required to make to the Senior Prescription Drug Assistance Program under subsection (b) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">is in addition to the subsidy that a nonprofit health service plan is required to provide to the Senior Prescription Drug Assistance Program under &#xA7; 14-106(d)(1)(iii) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is not subject to the limitation on the amount of the subsidy to the Senior Prescription Drug Assistance Program imposed by &#xA7; 14-106(e) of this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
