<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-103" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-2-103</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor shall appoint the Commissioner with the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner shall serve for a term of 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commissioner is directly responsible to the Governor.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Commissioner shall counsel and advise the Governor on all matters assigned to the Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Commissioner may be removed by the Governor for:<section prefix="(i)">malfeasance;</section><section prefix="(ii)">incompetence; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">failure to carry out the duties of office in a manner consistent with the regulatory purpose and requirements of this article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner is responsible for the operation of the Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner shall:<section prefix="(i)">exercise the powers and perform the duties of the Administration under this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">organize the Administration to function efficiently and to serve the public; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">establish, in the Administration, the units necessary for the exercise of the powers and performance of the duties of the Administration.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner shall devote full time to the duties of office.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commissioner is in the executive service of the State Personnel Management System and is entitled to compensation under the Executive Pay Plan in accordance with the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commissioner shall be covered by a surety bond in the form and amount required by law.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner shall have a seal of office in the form approved by the Governor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The impression and description of the seal shall be filed with the Secretary of State.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
