<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-5-505</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>505</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Board" means the board of directors of a life insurer.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Committee" means a committee authorized by the board of directors of a life insurer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The board shall adopt a written plan for:<section prefix="(i)">acquiring and holding investments; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">engaging in investment practices.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The plan required under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall specify guidelines for the:<section prefix="(i)">quality, maturity, and diversification of investments; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">investment strategies that assure that investments and investment practices are appropriate for:<section prefix="1.">the business conducted by the life insurer;</section><section prefix="2.">the liquidity needs of the life insurer; and</section><section prefix="3.">the capital and surplus requirements of the life insurer.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Before adopting the plan required under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the board shall review and assess the life insurer's technical investment and administrative capabilities and investment expertise.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The board shall supervise and direct any investments acquired and held under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At least annually, the board by formal resolution shall determine whether all investments have been made in accordance with delegations, standards, limitations, and investment objectives prescribed by the board or committee charged with the responsibility of directing the life insurer's investments.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In order to determine whether the investment activity of the life insurer is consistent with the plan required under subsection (b) of this section, on at least a quarterly basis, the board or committee shall:<section prefix="(1)">receive and review a summary report on the life insurer's investment portfolio, investment activities, and investment practices engaged in under delegated authority; and</section><section prefix="(2)">review and revise as needed the plan required under subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In the discharge of duties under this section:<section prefix="(1)">the board shall require that the following be made available on a regular basis to the board:<section prefix="(i)">the records of any authorizations or approvals;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the reports of any action taken under the authority delegated under the plan required under subsection (b) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">any other documentation as the board may require; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">each director shall perform their duties as a director, including any duties as a member of a committee:<section prefix="(i)">in good faith;</section><section prefix="(ii)">in a manner reasonably believed to be in the best interests of the insurer; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">with that degree of care that an ordinarily prudent person in a like position would use under similar circumstances.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If a life insurer does not have a board, all references to the board in this section shall be deemed to be references to the governing body of the life insurer having authority equivalent to that of a board.</section>
  </text>
</law>
