<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-12A-03" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-12A-03</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A small employer and the employees of the small employer shall be eligible for a subsidy of small employer health benefit plan premiums if the small employer:<section prefix="(1)">at the time of initial application for the subsidy:<section prefix="(i)">has not offered a small employer health benefit plan to its employees for at least 12 consecutive months;</section><section prefix="(ii)">has at least two but not more than nine eligible employees; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">meets salary and wage requirements established by the Commission;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">offers a small employer health benefit plan to its employees;</section><section prefix="(3)">establishes a payroll deduction plan under &#xA7; 125 of the Internal Revenue Code;</section><section prefix="(4)">agrees to offer a wellness benefit, as required by the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(5)">meets any other requirements established by the Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A subsidy provided to a small employer under the Program:<section prefix="(1)">shall offset a portion of the small employer health benefit plan premium contributions made by a small employer;</section><section prefix="(2)">may not exceed the lower of:<section prefix="(i)">50% of the small employer contribution; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an amount established by the Commission; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">may be calculated on a sliding scale.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A subsidy provided to an employee of a small employer under the Program:<section prefix="(1)">shall offset a portion of the small employer health benefit plan premium contributions made by an employee;</section><section prefix="(2)">may not exceed the lower of:<section prefix="(i)">50% of the employee contribution; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an amount established by the Commission; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">may be calculated on a sliding scale.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commission may alter the subsidy amounts provided under subsections (b) and (c) of this section according to the number of employees of the small employer.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The total amount of all subsidies provided under this section shall be subject to the limitations of the State budget.</section>
  </text>
</law>
