<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-27-911</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>911</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each authorized insurer doing business in the State shall accept and honor each request by a policyholder for a change of insurance producer of record within 30 working days after receipt of the request unless the policyholder withdraws the request in writing.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The new insurance producer of record must have a current appointment and contract with the authorized insurer before the change of insurance producer of record will be effective.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, the new insurance producer of record shall be paid all commissions payable on the policy effective not later than the next anniversary date of the policy following the effective date of change.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The commissions payable under paragraph (1) of this subsection do not include:<section prefix="(i)">vested life insurance commissions;</section><section prefix="(ii)">supplemental health insurance commissions; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">commissions or other compensation payable under an insurer's retirement or deferred compensation plan with the insurance producer.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A request for a change of insurance producer of record shall:<section prefix="(1)">be in writing; and</section><section prefix="(2)">include:<section prefix="(i)">the policyholder's name and address;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the authorized insurer's name and address;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the policy number;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the name and address of the new insurance producer of record;</section><section prefix="(v)">the date of the request;</section><section prefix="(vi)">the signature of the policyholder; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">the signature of acceptance by the new insurance producer.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This section does not require an authorized insurer to:<section prefix="(1)">appoint and contract with an insurance producer of record;</section><section prefix="(2)">alter an insurer's existing contract with an insurance producer which provides for direct compensation in lieu of commission; and</section><section prefix="(3)">require the payment of full commissions to a new insurance producer where the original writing insurance producer or current insurance producer continues to have responsibility for processing and matters relating to the policyholder.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
