<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-11-226</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>226</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">So that the experience of all insurers may be made available at least annually in the form and detail necessary to help the Commissioner in determining whether rating systems comply with the standards set forth in this subtitle, the Commissioner shall adopt reasonable rules and statistical plans that are reasonably adapted to each of the rating systems on file with the Commissioner for the recording and reporting of loss and expense experience.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Commissioner periodically may modify the rules and plans adopted under this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Each insurer shall use the rules and plans adopted by the Commissioner to record and report its loss and countrywide expense experience.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The rules and plans adopted under this subsection may also provide for the recording and reporting of expense experience items that are specially applicable to the State and are not susceptible of determination by prorating countrywide expense experience.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In adopting the rules and plans, the Commissioner shall give due consideration:<section prefix="(i)">to the rating systems on file with the Commissioner; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">to the rules and to the form of the plans used for the rating systems in other states, so that the rules and plans may be as uniform as is practicable among states.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An insurer may not be required to record or report its loss experience on a classification basis that is inconsistent with the rating system filed by it.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Commissioner may designate one or more rating organizations or other agencies to help in gathering and compiling experience information.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subject to reasonable regulations adopted by the Commissioner, the compilations shall be made available to insurers and rating organizations.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commissioner may adopt reasonable rules and plans for the interchange of data necessary for the application of rating plans.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To further uniform administration of rate regulatory laws, the Commissioner and each insurer and rating organization may:<section prefix="(1)">exchange information and experience data with each other and with insurance supervisory officials, insurers, and rating organizations in other states; and</section><section prefix="(2)">consult with them about rate making and the application of rating systems.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
