<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-319" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-8-319</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person aggrieved by the conduct of a person registered or required to be registered under this subtitle may file a written complaint with the Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On receipt of a complaint, the Commissioner shall investigate the complaint.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commissioner may investigate any person if the Commissioner has reasonable cause to believe that the person has violated any provision of this subtitle or a regulation adopted under it.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Without limitation of the powers granted to the Commissioner under Title 2 of this article, in connection with an investigation under this section, the Commissioner may:<section prefix="(1)">examine the books and records of a person registered under this subtitle or any other person that the Commissioner believes has violated this subtitle or a regulation adopted under it;</section><section prefix="(2)">subpoena documents and other evidence; and</section><section prefix="(3)">summon and examine under oath a person whose testimony the Commissioner requires.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For the purpose of conducting an investigation under this section, the Commissioner may not require an administrator to submit to the Commissioner, more than once in a 12-month period, any books or records of a plan administered by the administrator unless the Commissioner has reasonable cause to believe that a violation of this subtitle or a regulation adopted or order issued under it exists.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Subject to subsection (f) of this section, the Commissioner may make available information about a matter that may be subject to an investigation to:<section prefix="(1)">the National Association of Insurance Commissioners;</section><section prefix="(2)">a unit of state or federal government; and</section><section prefix="(3)">a person that is the subject of the investigation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Unless disclosure is required by a court of competent jurisdiction in a legal proceeding, the Commissioner shall keep confidential and may not disclose a trade secret or commercial information contained in:<section prefix="(1)">an administrator's books, records, or other documents; or</section><section prefix="(2)">data provided by the administrator, including the identity and address of persons covered by a plan.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
