<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-1005</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "clean claim" means a claim for reimbursement, as defined in regulations adopted by...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1005</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "clean claim" means a claim for reimbursement, as defined in regulations adopted by the Commissioner under &#xA7; 15-1003 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To the extent consistent with the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA), 29 U.S.C. 1001 et seq., this section applies to an insurer, nonprofit health service plan, or health maintenance organization that acts as a third party administrator.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Within 30 days after receipt of a claim for reimbursement from a person entitled to reimbursement under &#xA7; 15-701(a) of this title or from a hospital or related institution, as those terms are defined in &#xA7; 19-301 of the Health - General Article, an insurer, nonprofit health service plan, or health maintenance organization shall:<section prefix="(1)">mail or otherwise transmit payment for the claim in accordance with this section; or</section><section prefix="(2)">send a notice of receipt and status of the claim that states:<section prefix="(i)">that the insurer, nonprofit health service plan, or health maintenance organization refuses to reimburse all or part of the claim and the reason for the refusal;</section><section prefix="(ii)">that, in accordance with &#xA7; 15-1003(d)(1)(ii) of this subtitle, the legitimacy of the claim or the appropriate amount of reimbursement is in dispute and additional information is necessary to determine if all or part of the claim will be reimbursed and what specific additional information is necessary; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">that the claim is not clean and the specific additional information necessary for the claim to be considered a clean claim.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An insurer, nonprofit health service plan, or health maintenance organization shall permit a provider a minimum of 180 days from the date a covered service is rendered to submit a claim for reimbursement for the service.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an insurer, nonprofit health service plan, or health maintenance organization wholly or partially denies a claim for reimbursement, the insurer, nonprofit health service plan, or health maintenance organization shall permit a provider a minimum of 90 working days after the date of denial of the claim to appeal the denial.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If an insurer, nonprofit health service plan, or health maintenance organization erroneously denies a provider's claim for reimbursement submitted within the time period specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection because of a claims processing error, and the provider notifies the insurer, nonprofit health service plan, or health maintenance organization of the potential error within 1 year of the claim denial, the insurer, nonprofit health service plan, or health maintenance organization, on discovery of the error, shall reprocess the provider's claim without the necessity for the provider to resubmit the claim, and without regard to timely submission deadlines.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an insurer, nonprofit health service plan, or health maintenance organization provides notice under subsection (c)(2)(i) of this section, the insurer, nonprofit health service plan, or health maintenance organization shall mail or otherwise transmit payment for any undisputed portion of the claim within 30 days of receipt of the claim, in accordance with this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an insurer, nonprofit health service plan, or health maintenance organization provides notice under subsection (c)(2)(ii) of this section, the insurer, nonprofit health service plan, or health maintenance organization shall:<section prefix="(i)">mail or otherwise transmit payment for any undisputed portion of the claim in accordance with this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">comply with subsection (c)(1) or (2)(i) of this section within 30 days after receipt of the requested additional information.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If an insurer, nonprofit health service plan, or health maintenance organization provides notice under subsection (c)(2)(iii) of this section, the insurer, nonprofit health service plan, or health maintenance organization shall comply with subsection (c)(1) or (2)(i) of this section within 30 days after receipt of the requested additional information.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an insurer, nonprofit health service plan, or health maintenance organization fails to pay a clean claim for reimbursement or otherwise violates any provision of this section, the insurer, nonprofit health service plan, or health maintenance organization shall pay interest on the amount of the claim that remains unpaid 30 days after receipt of the initial clean claim for reimbursement at the monthly rate of:<section prefix="(i)">1.5% from the 31st day through the 60th day;</section><section prefix="(ii)">2% from the 61st day through the 120th day; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">2.5% after the 120th day.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The interest paid under this subsection shall be included in any late reimbursement without the necessity for the person that filed the original claim to make an additional claim for that interest.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">An insurer, nonprofit health service plan, or health maintenance organization that violates a provision of this section is subject to:<section prefix="(1)">a fine not exceeding $500 for each violation that is arbitrary and capricious, based on all available information; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the penalties prescribed under &#xA7; 4-113(d) of this article for violations committed with a frequency that indicates a general business practice.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
