<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-130</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>130</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section applies to:<section prefix="(i)">insurers and nonprofit health service plans that provide coverage for prescription drugs on an outpatient basis under health insurance policies or contracts that are issued or delivered in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">health maintenance organizations that provide coverage for prescription drugs on an outpatient basis under contracts that are issued or delivered in the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">managed care organizations, as defined in &#xA7; 15-101 of the Health - General Article, that provide coverage for prescription drugs on an outpatient basis under contracts that are issued or delivered in the State; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">to the extent consistent with State and federal law, third party administrators.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">short-term travel or accident-only policies;</section><section prefix="(ii)">short-term nonrenewable policies of not more than 6 months duration; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">any health maintenance organization that operates or maintains its own pharmacies and dispenses, on an annual basis, over 95% of prescription drugs on an outpatient basis to its enrollees at its own pharmacies.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each entity subject to this section shall provide to its insureds, subscribers, or enrollees a health insurance benefit card, prescription benefit card, or other technology that:<section prefix="(1)">complies with the standards set forth in the National Council for Prescription Drug Programs Pharmacy ID Card Implementation Guide in effect at the time of issuance of the card or other technology; or</section><section prefix="(2)">includes, at a minimum, the following data elements:<section prefix="(i)">the name or identifying trademark of the entity subject to this section or, if another entity administers the prescription benefit, the name or identifying trademark of the benefit administrator;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the name and identification number of the insured, subscriber, or enrollee;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the telephone number that providers may call for pharmacy benefit assistance; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">all electronic transaction routing information and other numbers required by the entity subject to this section or benefit administrator to process a prescription claim electronically.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If an entity subject to this section contracts with or otherwise arranges for the prescription benefit to be administered by another subsidiary or entity, including a pharmacy benefit manager, the entity subject to this section shall require the benefit administrator to comply with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The health insurance benefit card, prescription benefit card, or other technology shall be issued to each insured, subscriber, or enrollee by an entity subject to this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a change occurs in any of the data elements required under subsection (b)(2) of this section, an entity subject to this section shall:<section prefix="(i)">reissue a health insurance benefit card, prescription drug benefit card, or other technology; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">provide the insured, subscriber, or enrollee with the corrective information necessary to electronically process a prescription claim.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An entity subject to this section may comply with this section by issuing to each insured, subscriber, or enrollee a health insurance benefit card that contains data elements related to both prescription and nonprescription health insurance benefits.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department of Health and Mental Hygiene shall adopt regulations to enable managed care organizations to comply with:<section prefix="(1)">the requirements of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">any unique requirements of the HealthChoice Program that relate to the electronic processing of claims.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
