<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-28-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Areas under Nazi influence" means the country of Nazi Germany, areas occupied by Nazi Germany, those European countries allied with Nazi Germany, areas occupied by those European countries allied with Nazi Germany, or any other neutral European country or area in Europe under the influence or threat of invasion by Nazi Germany or by any European country allied with or occupied by Nazi Germany.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Holocaust victim" means an individual, claimant, or the estate, heir, legatee, descendant, survivor, beneficiary, or other successor-in-interest of the individual, who died or lost property as a result of discriminatory laws, policies, or actions targeted against discrete groups of individuals based on race, religion, ethnicity, sexual orientation, or national origin, whether or not the individual was actually a member of any of those groups, or because the individual assisted or allegedly assisted any of those groups, between January 1, 1929, and December 31, 1945, in areas under Nazi influence.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Insurance policy" means a policy of insurance substantially similar to any kind of insurance that was authorized at any time in Maryland between and including the years 1929 and 1945 or authorized by the jurisdiction in which the policy was sold at the time it was sold.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Insurance policy" includes any form of life, accident, health, annuities, property, casualty, education, or dowry insurance.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"International Commission" means the twelve member commission, and any successor organization, established by the September 1998 Memorandum of Understanding executed by the Maryland Insurance Commissioner, insurance regulators from other states, European insurers, and international Jewish organizations.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Nazi Germany" means:<section prefix="(1)">for the period from 1929 to 1933, the Republic of Germany, commonly referred to as the Weimar Republic; and</section><section prefix="(2)">for the period from 1933 through 1945, Deutsche Reich.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Proceeds" means the face or other pay-out value of an insurance policy or annuity plus reasonable interest to date of payment as required by regulations adopted by the Commissioner.</section>
  </text>
</law>
