<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-1601" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-1601</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Agent" means a pharmacy, a pharmacist, a mail order pharmacy, or a nonresident pharmacy acting on behalf or at the direction of a pharmacy benefits manager.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Beneficiary" means an individual who receives prescription drug coverage or benefits from a purchaser.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"ERISA" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 8-301 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Formulary" means a list of prescription drugs used by a purchaser.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Manufacturer payments" means any compensation or remuneration a pharmacy benefits manager receives from or on behalf of a pharmaceutical manufacturer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Manufacturer payments" includes:<section prefix="(i)">payments received in accordance with agreements with pharmaceutical manufacturers for formulary placement and, if applicable, drug utilization;</section><section prefix="(ii)">rebates, regardless of how categorized;</section><section prefix="(iii)">market share incentives;</section><section prefix="(iv)">commissions;</section><section prefix="(v)">fees under products and services agreements;</section><section prefix="(vi)">any fees received for the sale of utilization data to a pharmaceutical manufacturer; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">administrative or management fees.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Manufacturer payments" does not include purchase discounts based on invoiced purchase terms.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Nonprofit health maintenance organization" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 6-121(a) of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Nonresident pharmacy" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 12-403 of the Health Occupations Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Pharmacist" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 12-101 of the Health Occupations Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Pharmacy" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 12-101 of the Health Occupations Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Pharmacy and therapeutics committee" means a committee established by a pharmacy benefits manager to:<section prefix="(1)">objectively appraise and evaluate prescription drugs; and</section><section prefix="(2)">make recommendations to a purchaser regarding the selection of drugs for the purchaser's formulary.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Pharmacy benefits management services" means:<section prefix="(i)">the procurement of prescription drugs at a negotiated rate for dispensation within the State to beneficiaries;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the administration or management of prescription drug coverage provided by a purchaser for beneficiaries; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">any of the following services provided with regard to the administration of prescription drug coverage:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Pharmacy benefits management services" does not include any service provided by a nonprofit health maintenance organization that operates as a group model, provided that the service:<section prefix="(i)">is provided solely to a member of the nonprofit health maintenance organization; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is furnished through the internal pharmacy operations of the nonprofit health maintenance organization.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Pharmacy benefits manager" means a person that performs pharmacy benefits management services.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Proprietary information" means:<section prefix="(1)">a trade secret;</section><section prefix="(2)">confidential commercial information; or</section><section prefix="(3)">confidential financial information.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Purchaser" means the State Employee and Retiree Health and Welfare Benefits Program, an insurer, a nonprofit health service plan, or a health maintenance organization that:<section prefix="(i)">provides prescription drug coverage or benefits in the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">enters into an agreement with a pharmacy benefits manager for the provision of pharmacy benefits management services.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Purchaser" does not include a person that provides prescription drug coverage or benefits through plans subject to ERISA and does not provide prescription drug coverage or benefits through insurance, unless the person is a multiple employer welfare arrangement as defined in &#xA7; 514(b)(6)(a)(ii) of ERISA.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Rebate sharing contract" means a contract between a pharmacy benefits manager and a purchaser under which the pharmacy benefits manager agrees to share manufacturer payments with the purchaser.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Therapeutic interchange" means any change from one prescription drug to another.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Therapeutic interchange" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">a change initiated pursuant to a drug utilization review;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a change initiated for patient safety reasons;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a change required due to market unavailability of the currently prescribed drug;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a change from a brand name drug to a generic drug in accordance with &#xA7; 12-504 of the Health Occupations Article; or</section><section prefix="(v)">a change required for coverage reasons because the originally prescribed drug is not covered by the beneficiary's formulary or plan.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Therapeutic interchange solicitation" means any communication by a pharmacy benefits manager for the purpose of requesting a therapeutic interchange.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Trade secret" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 11-1201 of the Commercial Law Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
