<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="28-105" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-28-105</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If directed to do so by the Commissioner, an insurer authorized to do insurance business in the State shall file or cause its holding company to file with the Commissioner, a report setting forth the insurer's plan for complying with this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each insurer that has determined that it does not have any of the information requested in subsection (b) of this section shall file or cause its holding company to file a report stating that they have no information.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In addition, an insurer may request to be relieved from filing any further reports after providing evidence satisfactory to the Commissioner that the insurer has fulfilled its obligations under this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If directed to do so by the Commissioner, an insurer authorized to do insurance business in the State shall report or cause its holding company to report to the Commissioner the following information:<section prefix="(1)">whether it is a member of a holding company system including any insurer, any other member, subsidiary, or division in each case whether a licensee or not, that could possibly be expected to have issued an insurance policy to a Holocaust victim between January 1, 1920, and December 31, 1945, and a list of each entity;</section><section prefix="(2)">the approximate number and the total value of all insurance policies issued to Holocaust victims between January 1, 1920, and December 31, 1945, by the insurer or by any other member, subsidiary, or division within the reporting insurer's holding company system, that, as of the date of the report, remain unpaid or were paid to, or expropriated by, a government located in areas under Nazi influence, that was not the named beneficiary of the insurance policy;</section><section prefix="(3)">attempts made by the insurer to locate the beneficiaries of any insurance policies issued to Holocaust victims between January 1, 1920, and December 31, 1945, for which no claim of benefits has been made;</section><section prefix="(4)">if requested by the Commissioner and to the extent consistent with applicable laws and confidentiality obligations, with respect to each insurance policy issued to Holocaust victims between January 1, 1920, and December 31, 1945, the name of the owner, the name of the beneficiary, and the face amount or pay-out value;</section><section prefix="(5)">the number of claims filed by individuals who allege or have alleged that they are Holocaust victims and whether each claim has been paid or payment has been denied;</section><section prefix="(6)">if requested by the Commissioner, an explanation of any denial or pending payment of a claim to any individual who alleges or has alleged to be a Holocaust victim;</section><section prefix="(7)">a summary of the length of time for the processing and disposition of a claim to an individual who alleges or has alleged to be a Holocaust victim by the insurer; and</section><section prefix="(8)">if the insurer is unable to provide any of the information required by this section, an explanation of the reasons why and whether the information may, in the future, be ascertainable.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner shall direct an insurer in this State to file a report under this section if:<section prefix="(1)">the Commissioner determines that the International Commission is not moving effectively toward the swift and equitable resolution of insurance claims made by Holocaust victims; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the Commissioner determines that an insurer is not meaningfully participating in the work of the International Commission or cooperating with the International Commission in a manner reasonably calculated to effect the prompt investigation and resolution of claims made by Holocaust victims.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as provided in subsection (a) of this section, the reports required by subsection (b) of this section shall be made within 30 days after the end of the calendar year in which the insurer was directed by the Commissioner to file a report and then annually for each of the succeeding 10 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A report submitted to the Commissioner under this section shall be certified and affirmed under oath as being true and not misleading and as containing the most accurate information available at the time of the submission of the report.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commissioner may waive penalties and fines imposed by this title for those insurers that, through no fault of their own, were unaware that they, or members of a holding company system that includes the insurer, were obligated to file reports under this title and to comply with this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Commissioner is authorized to use any power available to the State to compel holding company systems that include issuers of insurance policies to Holocaust victims to submit reports under this title and to comply with this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An insurer that knowingly or recklessly files a false or misleading certification required by this section is subject to a fine of not less than $100,000 or a greater amount as the Commissioner considers appropriate based on the degree of misrepresentation, the willfulness of the misconduct, and the amount of funds misappropriated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The insurer also may be barred from further sales of insurance in the State for a period of up to 10 years.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
