<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-19-704</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>704</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only to lead hazard coverage for affected properties.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not affect coverage for property damage or any other form of coverage provided in a policy or insurance contract for an affected property.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding subsection (g) of this section, whenever an authorized insurer issues or renews a policy for an affected property, the authorized insurer may include in the policy a lead hazard coverage exclusion.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a policy issued or renewed by an authorized insurer on or after February 24, 1996, for an affected property contains a lead hazard coverage exclusion, the authorized insurer shall waive the exclusion to the extent of a qualified offer made or to be made under Title 6, Subtitle 8, Part V of the Environment Article:<section prefix="(1)">if the owner of the affected property complies with Title 6, Subtitle 8, Part III of the Environment Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">if at the election of the insured, and whether or not a change in occupancy has occurred, the affected property:<section prefix="(i)">passes the test for lead-contaminated dust under &#xA7; 6-816 of the Environment Article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">has undergone the lead hazard reduction treatments and complies with the risk reduction standard under &#xA7; 6-815(a)(2) of the Environment Article; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">if the insured submits to the authorized insurer a current verified report completed by an accredited inspector under &#xA7; 6-818 of the Environment Article certifying that the affected property complies with the standards set forth in item (2) of this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Instead of waiving a lead hazard coverage exclusion as required by subsection (d) of this section, after receiving approval from the Commissioner, an authorized insurer may offer an alternative form of coverage for a qualified offer made or to be made under Title 6, Subtitle 8, Part V of the Environment Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An authorized insurer may exclude lead hazard coverage for an affected property in excess of the amount of a qualified offer made or to be made under Title 6, Subtitle 8, Part V of the Environment Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An authorized insurer may cancel or nonrenew lead hazard coverage or reimpose a lead hazard coverage exclusion in a policy for an affected property only if:<section prefix="(i)">the insured fails to:<section prefix="1.">pay the applicable premium;</section><section prefix="2.">provide the authorized insurer or the authorized insurer's designee reasonable access to the affected property to inspect for the presence or condition of lead;</section><section prefix="3.">comply with the terms or conditions of the policy; or</section><section prefix="4.">perform lead hazard reduction treatments; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">the affected property fails to comply or maintain compliance with the risk reduction standard under &#xA7; 6-815(a)(2) of the Environment Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An authorized insurer may cancel or nonrenew lead hazard coverage or reimpose a lead hazard coverage exclusion under paragraph (1)(i)4 or (ii) of this subsection only if the authorized insurer:<section prefix="1.">mails written notice to the insured that the authorized insurer intends to cancel or nonrenew the coverage or to reimpose the exclusion; and</section><section prefix="2.">provides an opportunity to the insured to correct the violation within 30 days after the notice is mailed.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Coverage is automatically reinstated if the violation is corrected within 30 days after the notice is mailed.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Within 45 days after mailing a notice of cancellation or nonrenewal of coverage or reimposition of an exclusion under this paragraph, the authorized insurer shall send a copy of the notice to the Secretary of the Environment or a designee of the Secretary, and include the results of any inspection of the affected property.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
