<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-13-110</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>110</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each form for a policy, certificate of insurance, notice of proposed insurance, application for insurance, endorsement, or rider delivered or issued for delivery in the State and each related schedule of premium rates shall be filed with the Commissioner for approval.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 60 days after a form or premium rate described in subsection (a) of this section is filed, the Commissioner shall disapprove the filing if:<section prefix="(i)">the table of premium rates appears by reasonable assumptions to be excessive in relation to benefits; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the form contains provisions that:<section prefix="1.">are unjust, unfair, inequitable, misleading, or deceptive;</section><section prefix="2.">encourage misrepresentation of the coverage; or</section><section prefix="3.">are contrary to a provision of this article or a regulation adopted under this article.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In making a determination under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Commissioner shall consider:<section prefix="(i)">past and prospective loss experience within and outside the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">underwriting practice and judgment to the extent appropriate;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a reasonable margin for underwriting profit and contingencies;</section><section prefix="(iv)">past and prospective expenses, whether countrywide or specially applicable to the State; and</section><section prefix="(v)">all other relevant factors within and outside the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the Commissioner disapproves a form or premium rate, the Commissioner shall:<section prefix="(i)">notify the insurer of the disapproval and specify in the notice the reason for disapproval; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">state that a hearing on the disapproval will be held within 20 days after receipt of a written request by the insurer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">After notification of disapproval, an insurer may not issue or use the disapproved form or premium rate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An insurer may not issue or use a form or premium rate filed under this section until the end of the 60-day period unless the Commissioner approves the filing in writing before the end of the period.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner may withdraw approval of a form or premium rate if the Commissioner:<section prefix="(i)">notifies the insurer in writing of the proposed withdrawal;</section><section prefix="(ii)">specifies in the notice the reason for withdrawal;</section><section prefix="(iii)">states that a hearing on the withdrawal will be held not less than 20 days after the date of the notice; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">bases the withdrawal of approval on a ground set forth in subsection (b)(1) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An insurer may not issue or use a form or premium rate after the effective date of withdrawal of approval by the Commissioner.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a group policy of credit life insurance, credit health insurance, or credit involuntary unemployment benefit insurance was delivered in the State before April 28, 1970, or is delivered in another state, the insurer shall file with the Commissioner only the group certificate and notice of proposed insurance that have been delivered or issued for delivery in this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner shall approve the group certificate and notice of proposed insurance if:<section prefix="(i)">the group certificate and notice conform with &#xA7;&#xA7; 13-108(b) and 13-109(b) of this title; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the schedule of premium rates for the group insurance does not exceed the schedule of premium rates that the insurer has filed with the Commissioner.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The purpose of this subsection is to ensure that the credit life insurance, credit health insurance, or credit involuntary unemployment benefit insurance operations of the insurer do not:<section prefix="(i)">result in rates that are excessive in relation to benefits;</section><section prefix="(ii)">endanger the solvency of the insurer so that its transaction of business is hazardous to its policyholders or the public; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">adversely affect another class of business of the insurer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To accomplish this purpose, the Commissioner may establish:<section prefix="(i)">the maximum rates of commission or other compensation that may be paid to insurance producers; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">standards for the maximum amounts of dividends, retrospective rate credits, and any other form of refund or benefit to policyholders.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">An order of the Commissioner under this section is subject to judicial review in accordance with &#xA7; 2-215 of this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
