<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-114" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-16-114</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "community foundation" means a nonprofit organization that is:<section prefix="(1)">formed to receive contributions and distribute money to meet cultural, educational, charitable, environmental, civic, or other similar needs of a community; and</section><section prefix="(2)">governed by a board of private citizens who reside in the community.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An educational or religious organization, hospital, or community foundation may not make or issue in the State agreements for annuity payments with donors until it has obtained from the Commissioner a special permit issued in accordance with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On application, the Commissioner may issue a special permit to make agreements for annuity payments with donors to an educational or religious organization not conducted for profit and engaged in bona fide educational or religious activities, to a hospital in the State, or to a community foundation if the educational or religious organization, hospital, or community foundation:<section prefix="(i)">except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, has been in active operation in the State for at least 10 years before issuance of the special permit; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">has been granted exemption from federal income taxation under &#xA7; 501 of the Internal Revenue Code.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner may issue a special permit to a community foundation that has been in existence for at least 5 years but less than 10 years if the community foundation maintains admitted assets in an amount up to 100% of the contributions made to the community foundation, as determined by the Commissioner.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each special permit holder shall have and maintain admitted assets at least equal to adequate reserves on its outstanding agreements for annuity payments with donors as indicated by its annual report.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In determining the reserves of a special permit holder on outstanding agreements for annuity payments with donors, a deduction shall be made for all or part of an annuity risk that is reinsured by an authorized life insurer.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A special permit holder shall submit an annual report to the Commissioner within 90 days after the end of the special permit holder's fiscal year.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The annual reports shall be treated as confidential by the Commissioner and are not available for public inspection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A special permit issued under this section authorizes the special permit holder to receive gifts of money or other property conditional on, or in consideration of, the special permit holder's agreement to pay an annuity to the donor or the donor's nominee and to make and carry out agreements for annuity payments with donors.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A special permit is in effect only as long as the special permit holder is exempt from federal income taxation under &#xA7; 501 of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Commissioner finds, after notice and hearing, that a special permit holder has failed to comply with the requirements of this section or is not exempt from federal income taxation under &#xA7; 501 of the Internal Revenue Code, the Commissioner may:<section prefix="(i)">revoke or suspend the special permit; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">order the special permit holder to stop making new agreements for annuity payments with donors until the requirements have been satisfied.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In case of revocation or suspension, outstanding agreements for annuity payments with donors shall remain in force.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The action of the Commissioner under this subsection is subject to judicial review under &#xA7; 2-215 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, a special permit holder is exempt from the provisions of this article with respect to issuing annuities.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Special permit holders are not subject to a law enacted after June 1, 1957, unless they are expressly designated in the law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Other than by agreements for annuity payments with donors, an educational or religious organization, hospital, or community foundation may agree to:<section prefix="(i)">accept conditional donations; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">pay to the donor or the donor's nominee a specified return established with reference to the actual net earnings of the particular donation or with reference to the actual or estimated earnings of a specified fund of the donee organization.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An educational or religious organization, hospital, or community foundation that accepts conditional donations and pays a specified return to donors under paragraph (1) of this subsection is exempt from this section and all other provisions of this article with respect to issuing annuities.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Educational or religious organizations, hospitals, or community foundations that accept conditional donations and pay specified returns to donors under this subsection are not subject to any law enacted after June 1, 1957, unless they are expressly designated in the law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">Notwithstanding the absence of express power in the charter of a domestic educational, religious, or hospital corporation or community foundation, the corporation or community foundation may make the agreements for annuity payments with donors or other agreements with respect to conditional donations that are expressly allowed by this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
