<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-1105</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1105</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Carrier" means:<section prefix="(i)">an insurer; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a nonprofit health service plan.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Eligible individual" means a Maryland resident who has membership in an association.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Evidence of individual insurability" means medical or other information that indicates health status, used to determine whether coverage of an individual is to be:<section prefix="(i)">issued or denied; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">issued with or without an exclusionary rider.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Health benefit plan" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 15-1301 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Health status-related factor" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 15-1201 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Individual health insurance contract" means a health benefit plan that is issued or delivered in the State to an individual.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Member" means an eligible individual who purchases coverage under an out-of-state association contract.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">"Out-of-state association contract" means a health benefit plan that is issued or delivered to an association outside the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to a carrier that requires evidence of individual insurability for coverage under an out-of-state association contract.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A carrier shall disclose to a Maryland resident applying for coverage under an out-of-state association contract:<section prefix="(1)">that coverage is conditioned on membership in the association that holds the out-of-state association contract;</section><section prefix="(2)">all costs related to joining and maintaining membership in the association;</section><section prefix="(3)">that membership fees or dues are in addition to the premium for coverage under the out-of-state association contract;</section><section prefix="(4)">that the terms and conditions of coverage under the out-of-state association contract are determined by the association and the carrier;</section><section prefix="(5)">the mandated benefits required under Subtitle 8 of this title that are not included in the out-of-state association contract;</section><section prefix="(6)">that the Maryland resident may purchase an individual health benefit plan that includes the mandated benefits under Subtitle 8 of this title that are not included in the out-of-state association contract from a carrier licensed and authorized to do business in the State;</section><section prefix="(7)">that benefits offered under the out-of-state association contract are not regulated by the Commissioner; and</section><section prefix="(8)">that the terms and conditions of coverage under the out-of-state association contract may be changed by agreement of the association and the carrier without the consent of a member.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner may require a carrier that offers coverage under an out-of-state association contract to report, on or before March 1 of each year, the number of Maryland residents covered in the preceding calendar year under the out-of-state association contract.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The data required under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be reported in a manner determined by the Commissioner.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a carrier collects membership fees or dues on behalf of an association, the carrier shall disclose on the enrollment application for an out-of-state association contract that the carrier bills and collects membership fees and dues on behalf of the association.</section>
  </text>
</law>
