<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-27-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>If the Commissioner finds that a person in the State has engaged or is engaging in an act or practic...</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Commissioner finds that a person in the State has engaged or is engaging in an act or practice that is defined in or prohibited under this title, the Commissioner shall order the person to cease and desist from the act or practice.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner shall hold a hearing before the Commissioner issues a cease and desist order under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commissioner shall give the person notice of the hearing and the charges against the person.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The cease and desist order is final:<section prefix="(1)">if no appeal is taken, when the time allowed for taking an appeal from an order of the Commissioner expires; or</section><section prefix="(2)">if an appeal is taken, when the court issues a final decision that affirms the cease and desist order or dismisses the appeal.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If an appeal is taken, the court shall issue its own order that requires compliance with the terms of the cease and desist order to the extent that the cease and desist order is affirmed.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Violation of a cease and desist order issued under this section is deemed to be and is punishable as a violation of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A cease and desist order issued under this section or an order of court that enforces it does not relieve any person affected by the order from any other liability, penalty, or forfeiture under law.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Regardless of whether a hearing is scheduled or held or a cease and desist order is issued, this section does not affect or prevent the imposition of a penalty provided by this article or other law for violation of another provision of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
