<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-1902</section_number>
  <catch_line>Notwithstanding any other provision of this article or the Health - General Article, a contract betw...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1902</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this article or the Health - General Article, a contract between a carrier and a clinically integrated organization may include a provision to pay:<section prefix="(1)">for services associated with the coordination of covered medical services to qualifying individuals; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a bonus, fee-based incentive, bundled fees, or other incentives to promote the efficient, medically appropriate delivery of covered medical services to qualifying individuals.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commissioner, in consultation with the Maryland Health Care Commission, may adopt regulations specifying the types of payments and incentives permissible under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A carrier shall file a copy of a contract between the carrier and a clinically integrated organization with the Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the contract includes a provision to pay a bonus or other incentive that does not comply with &#xA7; 15-113 of this title, the Commissioner shall provide a copy of the contract to the executive director of the Maryland Health Care Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a copy of a contract filed with the Commissioner or provided by the Commissioner to the executive director of the Maryland Health Care Commission under this subsection, is:<section prefix="(i)">confidential and privileged;</section><section prefix="(ii)">not subject to:<section prefix="1.">Title 10, Subtitle 6 of the State Government Article;</section><section prefix="2.">subpoena; or</section><section prefix="3.">discovery; and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">not admissible in evidence in any private action.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
