<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-601" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-16-601</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A stock insurer or mutual insurer may issue individual and group variable life insurance contracts that provide for payment varying directly with the investment experience of a segregated asset account if the stock insurer or mutual insurer:<section prefix="(i)">is authorized to issue life insurance contracts in the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is authorized by the Commissioner to issue individual and group variable life insurance contracts.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A stock insurer or mutual insurer may issue individual and group variable annuity contracts that provide for payment varying directly with the investment experience of a segregated asset account if the stock insurer or mutual insurer:<section prefix="(i)">is authorized to issue annuity contracts in the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is authorized by the Commissioner to issue individual and group variable annuity contracts.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To be authorized to issue variable contracts, a stock insurer or mutual insurer shall comply with regulations adopted by the Commissioner.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The regulations of the Commissioner may include:<section prefix="(1)">requirements for a minimum capital and surplus in excess of the amount otherwise required for the issuance of life insurance contracts and annuity contracts that are not variable contracts; and</section><section prefix="(2)">other requirements that the Commissioner considers appropriate to safeguard the interests of variable contract holders, other policyholders, insurers, and the public.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
