<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="19-406" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-19-406</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except for a cancellation for nonpayment of premium, an insurer may not cancel or refuse to renew a workers' compensation insurance policy before its expiration unless, at least 30 days before the date of cancellation or nonrenewal, the insurer:<section prefix="(1)">serves on the employer, by personal service or certified mail addressed to the last known address of the employer, a notice of intention to cancel or nonrenew the policy; and</section><section prefix="(2)">files a copy of the notice with the State Workers' Compensation Commission's designee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notice under this section may be given:<section prefix="(1)">if the employer is a corporation, to an agent or officer of the corporation on whom legal process may be served; and</section><section prefix="(2)">if the employer is a partnership, to a partner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notice under this section shall state when the cancellation or nonrenewal takes effect.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Whenever an employer receives a notice under this section, the employer immediately shall secure coverage in accordance with &#xA7; 9-402 of the Labor and Employment Article that will be in effect when the cancellation takes effect.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The notice shall state the insurer's actual reason for proposing the cancellation or nonrenewal of the policy.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner may not disallow a proposed action of an insurer because the statement of actual reason contains:<section prefix="(i)">grammatical, typographical, or other errors, if the errors are not material to the proposed action and are not misleading;</section><section prefix="(ii)">surplus information, if the surplus information is not misleading; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">erroneous information, if in the absence of the erroneous information there is a sufficient basis to support the proposed action.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 10 days before the date of cancellation of a workers' compensation insurance policy for nonpayment of premium, the insurer shall send to the employer, by certificate of mail, a written notice of the intention to cancel for nonpayment of premium.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An insurer shall file a copy of the notice sent under paragraph (1) of this subsection with the State Workers' Compensation Commission's designee.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
