<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-924</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>924</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Solicitation of the sale of a health insurance policy proposed to be issued to an individual eligible for Medicare may be made only in accordance with this section and &#xA7; 15-925 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When soliciting the sale of a health insurance policy to an individual eligible for Medicare, a carrier or insurance producer shall ask the individual whether the individual:<section prefix="(i)">is already covered by an existing Medicare supplement policy; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is entitled to Medicaid benefits.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The carrier or insurance producer shall obtain a written statement from the individual that verifies the individual's information provided under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">When soliciting or advertising the sale of a health insurance policy to an individual eligible for Medicare, a carrier or insurance producer may not:<section prefix="(1)">represent or imply that the carrier or insurance producer represents, works for, or is compensated by a federal, State, or local government agency;</section><section prefix="(2)">falsely represent or imply that the carrier or insurance producer is offering insurance to supplement Medicare that is approved or recommended by a federal, State, or local government agency;</section><section prefix="(3)">use terms such as "Medicare consultant", "Medicare advisor", "Medicare bureau", or "disability insurance consultant" when describing the carrier or insurance producer in a letter, envelope, reply card, or any other writing or advertisement or in any oral representation; or</section><section prefix="(4)">knowingly make a misrepresentation or incomplete or fraudulent comparison by commission or omission of a policy or carrier to induce or attempt to induce the individual to:<section prefix="(i)">purchase, amend, lapse, surrender, forfeit, change, duplicate, or not renew coverage already in force;</section><section prefix="(ii)">replace a policy that is only technically at variance with the policy being offered by the carrier or insurance producer; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">take out a policy with another carrier.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
