<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-707" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-10-707</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commissioner may suspend, revoke, or refuse to renew a limited lines license issued under this subtitle after notice and opportunity for a hearing under Title 2, Subtitle 2 of this article if the vendor or an employee or authorized representative of the vendor has:<section prefix="(1)">willfully violated this article or another law of the State that relates to insurance;</section><section prefix="(2)">operated without a limited lines license as required under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">failed to provide the disclosures required under &#xA7; 10-705 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(4)">offered or sold unapproved insurance products;</section><section prefix="(5)">failed to hold an appointment with an insurer;</section><section prefix="(6)">failed to train employees or authorized representatives as required under &#xA7; 10-705 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(7)">misrepresented pertinent facts or policy provisions concerning a policy of portable electronics insurance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A vendor and the employees and authorized representatives of the vendor may not advertise, represent, or otherwise hold themselves out as an authorized insurer or as an insurance producer for any kind or subdivision of insurance, except as provided in this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Instead of, or in addition to, suspending or revoking a limited lines license issued under this subtitle, the Commissioner may:<section prefix="(1)">impose on the vendor a penalty of not more than $2,500 for each violation of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">require that restitution be made to any person who has suffered financial injury because of a violation of this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
