<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-221" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-11-221</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each advisory organization shall file with the Commissioner:<section prefix="(1)">a copy of its constitution, articles of agreement or association, or certificate of incorporation and its bylaws, rules, and regulations that govern its activities;</section><section prefix="(2)">a list of its members;</section><section prefix="(3)">the name and address of a resident of the State on whom may be served notices or orders of the Commissioner or process issued at the direction of the Commissioner; and</section><section prefix="(4)">an agreement that the Commissioner may examine the advisory organization in accordance with &#xA7; 11-225 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If, after a hearing, the Commissioner finds that the provision of information or help by an advisory organization involves an act or practice that is unfair, unreasonable, or otherwise inconsistent with this subtitle, the Commissioner may issue a written order that specifies the ways in which the act or practice is unfair, unreasonable, or otherwise inconsistent with this subtitle and requires that the act or practice be discontinued.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An insurer that makes its own filings or a rating organization may not support its filings by statistics or adopt rate making recommendations provided to it by an advisory organization that has failed to comply with:<section prefix="(i)">this section; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an order of the Commissioner issued under subsection (b) of this section that involves the statistics or recommendations.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Commissioner finds that an insurer or rating organization has violated this subsection, the Commissioner may issue an order that requires that the violation be discontinued.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
