<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-1404</section_number>
  <catch_line>In determining a period of creditable coverage, any period that an individual is in a waiting period...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1404</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In determining a period of creditable coverage, any period that an individual is in a waiting period for any coverage under a group health benefit plan or an affiliation period may not be taken into account in determining any period of continuous creditable coverage.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, a carrier shall count a period of creditable coverage without regard to the specific benefits covered during the period.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A carrier may elect to reduce the period of any preexisting condition provision based on coverage of benefits within any class or category of benefits specified by the Secretary by regulation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any election made under this section shall be made on a uniform basis for all covered individuals.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A carrier that makes an election under this section shall count a period of creditable coverage with respect to any class or category of benefits if any level of benefits is covered within that class or category.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A carrier that makes an election under subsection (c) of this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">prominently state in any disclosure statements concerning the coverage, and to each employer at the time of the offer or sale of the coverage, that the carrier has made this election; and</section><section prefix="(2)">include in the statement a description of the effect of the election on the member or subscriber.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
