<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-408.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-10-408.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">For up to 1 year after the expiration date, a person whose public adjuster's license has expired may reinstate the expired license by:<section prefix="(1)">filing with the Commissioner the appropriate reinstatement application; and</section><section prefix="(2)">paying to the Commissioner the applicable reinstatement fee required under subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The fee for a reinstatement under this section shall be:<section prefix="(i)">the amount charged for a full renewal period for the type of license held by the person seeking the reinstatement; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a reinstatement fee of $100.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner may limit the reinstatement fee to the amount of the renewal fee in cases where the reinstatement applicant did not make timely renewal because of military service, temporary incapacity, hospitalization, or other hardship.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person whose public adjuster's license has expired is prohibited from acting as a public adjuster until the effective date of reinstatement of the license.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a person applies for reinstatement of an expired license within 60 days after the license expired, the Commissioner shall reinstate the license retroactively, with the reinstatement effective on the date that the person's license expired.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a person applies for reinstatement of an expired license more than 60 days after the license expired, the Commissioner shall reinstate the person's license prospectively, with the reinstatement effective on the date that the license is reinstated.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person who does not comply with subsection (a) of this section on or before 1 year after the expiration date shall apply for a license under &#xA7; 10-405 of this subtitle and meet the requirements specified by the Commissioner in regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commissioner may adopt regulations to carry out this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
