<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-4-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The General Assembly finds that:<section prefix="(1)">many residents of the State hold policies issued by insurers and other persons not authorized to do insurance business in the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">these residents face the often insurmountable obstacle of asserting their legal rights under those policies in forums that are foreign to them and under laws and rules of practice that are unfamiliar to them; and</section><section prefix="(3)">protection from the acts of insurers and other persons not authorized to do insurance business in the State can be achieved by:<section prefix="(i)">maintaining fair and honest insurance markets;</section><section prefix="(ii)">protecting the premium tax revenues of the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">protecting authorized insurers, which are subject to strict regulation, from unfair competition by unauthorized persons and unauthorized insurers; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">protecting against evasion of the insurance regulatory laws of the State.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The General Assembly intends to subject certain insurers and other persons to the jurisdiction of the Commissioner, in proceedings before the Commissioner, and to the courts of the State in suits by or for the State and insureds or beneficiaries under insurance contracts.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To carry out this intent, the General Assembly provides for substituted service of process on certain insurers and other persons in any proceeding in a court and substituted service of any notice, order, pleading, or process on certain insurers and other persons in any proceeding before the Commissioner to enforce or effect full compliance with the insurance and tax laws of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In carrying out the intent of this subtitle, the General Assembly declares that it is exercising:<section prefix="(1)">its power to protect the residents of the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">its power to define what constitutes doing an insurance business in the State; and</section><section prefix="(3)">its powers and privileges under the McCarran-Ferguson Act.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
