<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="27-208" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-27-208</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not make or allow unfair discrimination between individuals of the same class and equal expectation of life in:<section prefix="(i)">the rates charged for a contract of life insurance or an annuity contract;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the dividends or other benefits payable on a contract of life insurance or an annuity contract; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">any of the other terms or conditions of a contract of life insurance or an annuity contract.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, an insurer may not make or allow a differential in ratings, premium payments, or dividends for contracts of life insurance or annuity contracts for a reason based on the blindness or other physical handicap or disability of an applicant or policyholder.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Actuarial justification for the differential may be considered for a physical handicap or disability other than blindness or hearing impairment.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Unless there is actuarial justification, an insurer may not refuse to insure or make or allow a differential in ratings, premium payments, or dividends in connection with life insurance and annuity contracts solely because the applicant or policyholder has the sickle-cell trait, thalassemia-minor trait, hemoglobin C trait, Tay-Sachs trait, or a genetic trait that is harmless in itself.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An insurer may not refuse to insure, refuse to continue to insure, limit the amount or extent or kind of coverage available to an individual, or charge an individual a different rate for the same coverage solely for reasons associated with an applicant's or insured's past lawful travel experiences.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not make or allow unfair discrimination between individuals of the same class and of essentially the same hazard:<section prefix="(i)">in the amount of premium, policy fees, or rates charged for a policy or contract of health insurance;</section><section prefix="(ii)">in the benefits payable under a policy or contract of health insurance;</section><section prefix="(iii)">in any of the terms or conditions of a policy or contract of health insurance; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">in any other manner.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, an insurer may not make or allow a differential in ratings, premium payments, or dividends for a reason based on the sex of an applicant or policyholder unless there is actuarial justification for the differential.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 27-909 of this title and notwithstanding any other provision of this section, an insurer may not make or allow a differential in ratings, premium payments, or dividends for contracts of health insurance for a reason based on the blindness or other physical handicap or disability of an applicant or policyholder.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 27-909 of this title, actuarial justification for the differential may be considered for a physical handicap or disability other than blindness or hearing impairment.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
