<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-1003" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-1003</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Health care practitioner" means a person that is licensed or certified under the Health Occupations Article and reimbursed by a third party payor.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Health care practitioner" does not include a physician or other person licensed or certified under this article when the physician or other person is rendering care to a member or subscriber of a health maintenance organization and is compensated by the health maintenance organization for that care on a salaried or capitated basis.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Hospital" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 19-301 of the Health - General Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commissioner shall adopt by regulation as the uniform claims form for reimbursement of hospital services in the State the uniform claims form adopted by the National Uniform Billing Committee and approved by the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services for Hospital Payments under Title XVIII of the Social Security Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner shall adopt by regulation a uniform claims form for reimbursement of health care practitioners' services.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner shall adopt by regulation:<section prefix="(i)">a definition of a clean claim, including:</section><section prefix="(ii)">permissible categories of disputed claims for which additional information may be requested under &#xA7;&#xA7; 15-1004(c) and 15-1005(c) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">standards for determining when a claim is considered received for reimbursement.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In adopting the regulations required under paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection, the Commissioner shall consider:<section prefix="(i)">standards for attachments required by the federal Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services for the Medicare Program;</section><section prefix="(ii)">standards used by insurance carriers, nonprofit health service plans, and health maintenance organizations in the State; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">federal regulations adopted under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
