<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-701" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-10-701</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Covered customer" means a customer who elects to purchase coverage under a policy of portable electronics insurance issued to a vendor.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Customer" means a person who purchases or leases portable electronics or purchases service related to the use of portable electronics.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Location" means:<section prefix="(1)">a physical location in the State; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a Web site, call center site, or similar location where coverage under a policy of portable electronics insurance is offered or sold to residents of the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Portable electronics" means:<section prefix="(i)">an electronic device, including its accessories, that:</section><section prefix="(ii)">any other electronic device that is portable in nature that the Commissioner approves.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Portable electronics" includes:<section prefix="(i)">cellular or satellite phones;</section><section prefix="(ii)">pagers;</section><section prefix="(iii)">personal global positioning satellite units;</section><section prefix="(iv)">portable computers;</section><section prefix="(v)">portable audio listening, video viewing, or recording devices;</section><section prefix="(vi)">digital cameras;</section><section prefix="(vii)">video camcorders;</section><section prefix="(viii)">portable gaming systems;</section><section prefix="(ix)">docking stations; and</section><section prefix="(x)">automatic answering devices.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Portable electronics" does not include telecommunications switching equipment, transmission wires, cell site transceiver equipment, or other equipment and systems used by telecommunications companies to provide telecommunications service to consumers.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Portable electronics insurance" means insurance that provides coverage for the repair or replacement of portable electronics, including coverage against one or more of the following causes of loss:<section prefix="(i)">loss by disappearance;</section><section prefix="(ii)">theft;</section><section prefix="(iii)">mechanical failure;</section><section prefix="(iv)">malfunction;</section><section prefix="(v)">damage; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">any other applicable peril, as approved by the Commissioner.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Portable electronics insurance" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">a service contract governed by Title 14, Subtitle 4 of the Commercial Law Article that does not include coverage for loss by disappearance or theft;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a policy of insurance covering a seller's or a manufacturer's obligations under a warranty; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a homeowner's, renter's, private passenger automobile, or similar policy that covers loss or theft of portable electronics.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Portable electronics transaction" means:<section prefix="(1)">the sale or lease of portable electronics by a vendor to a customer; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the sale of service related to the use of portable electronics by a vendor to a customer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Supervising entity" means a business entity that is:<section prefix="(1)">an authorized insurer; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a licensed insurance producer that is appointed by an insurer to supervise the administration of a portable electronics insurance program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Vendor" means a person in the business of leasing, selling, or providing portable electronics, or selling or providing service related to the use of portable electronics, to customers in the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
