<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-10A-02</section_number>
  <catch_line>Each carrier shall establish an internal grievance process for its members....</catch_line>
  <order_by>02</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each carrier shall establish an internal grievance process for its members.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An internal grievance process shall meet the same requirements established under Subtitle 10B of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to the requirements of Subtitle 10B of this title, an internal grievance process established by a carrier under this section shall:<section prefix="(i)">include an expedited procedure for use in an emergency case for purposes of rendering a grievance decision within 24 hours of the date a grievance is filed with the carrier;</section><section prefix="(ii)">provide that a carrier render a final decision in writing on a grievance within 30 working days after the date on which the grievance is filed unless:<section prefix="1.">the grievance involves an emergency case under item (i) of this paragraph;</section><section prefix="2.">the member, the member's representative, or a health care provider filing a grievance on behalf of a member agrees in writing to an extension for a period of no longer than 30 working days; or</section><section prefix="3.">the grievance involves a retrospective denial under item (iv) of this paragraph;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">allow a grievance to be filed on behalf of a member by a health care provider or the member's representative;</section><section prefix="(iv)">provide that a carrier render a final decision in writing on a grievance within 45 working days after the date on which the grievance is filed when the grievance involves a retrospective denial; and</section><section prefix="(v)">for a retrospective denial, allow a member, the member's representative, or a health care provider on behalf of a member to file a grievance for at least 180 days after the member receives an adverse decision.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For purposes of using the expedited procedure for an emergency case that a carrier is required to include under paragraph (2)(i) of this subsection, the Commissioner shall define by regulation the standards required for a grievance to be considered an emergency case.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, the carrier's internal grievance process shall be exhausted prior to filing a complaint with the Commissioner under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A member, the member's representative, or a health care provider filing a complaint on behalf of a member may file a complaint with the Commissioner without first filing a grievance with a carrier and receiving a final decision on the grievance if:<section prefix="1.">the carrier waives the requirement that the carrier's internal grievance process be exhausted before filing a complaint with the Commissioner;</section><section prefix="2.">the carrier has failed to comply with any of the requirements of the internal grievance process as described in this section; or</section><section prefix="3.">the member, the member's representative, or the health care provider provides sufficient information and supporting documentation in the complaint that demonstrates a compelling reason to do so.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Commissioner shall define by regulation the standards that the Commissioner shall use to decide what demonstrates a compelling reason under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to subsections (b)(2)(ii) and (h) of this section, a member, a member's representative, or a health care provider may file a complaint with the Commissioner if the member, the member's representative, or the health care provider does not receive a grievance decision from the carrier on or before the 30th working day on which the grievance is filed.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Whenever the Commissioner receives a complaint under paragraph (1) or (2) of this subsection, the Commissioner shall notify the carrier that is the subject of the complaint within 5 working days after the date the complaint is filed with the Commissioner.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each carrier shall:<section prefix="(1)">file for review with the Commissioner and submit to the Health Advocacy Unit a copy of its internal grievance process established under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">file any revision to the internal grievance process with the Commissioner and the Health Advocacy Unit at least 30 days before its intended use.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">For nonemergency cases, when a carrier renders an adverse decision, the carrier shall:<section prefix="(1)">document the adverse decision in writing after the carrier has provided oral communication of the decision to the member, the member's representative, or the health care provider acting on behalf of the member; and</section><section prefix="(2)">send, within 5 working days after the adverse decision has been made, a written notice to the member, the member's representative, and a health care provider acting on behalf of the member that:<section prefix="(i)">states in detail in clear, understandable language the specific factual bases for the carrier's decision;</section><section prefix="(ii)">references the specific criteria and standards, including interpretive guidelines, on which the decision was based, and may not solely use generalized terms such as "experimental procedure not covered", "cosmetic procedure not covered", "service included under another procedure", or "not medically necessary";</section><section prefix="(iii)">states the name, business address, and business telephone number of:<section prefix="1.">the medical director or associate medical director, as appropriate, who made the decision if the carrier is a health maintenance organization; or</section><section prefix="2.">the designated employee or representative of the carrier who has responsibility for the carrier's internal grievance process if the carrier is not a health maintenance organization;</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">gives written details of the carrier's internal grievance process and procedures under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(v)">includes the following information:<section prefix="1.">that the member, the member's representative, or a health care provider on behalf of the member has a right to file a complaint with the Commissioner within 4 months after receipt of a carrier's grievance decision;</section><section prefix="2.">that a complaint may be filed without first filing a grievance if the member, the member's representative, or a health care provider filing a grievance on behalf of the member can demonstrate a compelling reason to do so as determined by the Commissioner;</section><section prefix="3.">the Commissioner's address, telephone number, and facsimile number;</section><section prefix="4.">a statement that the Health Advocacy Unit is available to assist the member or the member's representative in both mediating and filing a grievance under the carrier's internal grievance process; and</section><section prefix="5.">the address, telephone number, facsimile number, and electronic mail address of the Health Advocacy Unit.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If within 5 working days after a member, the member's representative, or a health care provider, who has filed a grievance on behalf of a member, files a grievance with the carrier, and if the carrier does not have sufficient information to complete its internal grievance process, the carrier shall:<section prefix="(1)">notify the member, the member's representative, or the health care provider that it cannot proceed with reviewing the grievance unless additional information is provided; and</section><section prefix="(2)">assist the member, the member's representative, or the health care provider in gathering the necessary information without further delay.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A carrier may extend the 30-day or 45-day period required for making a final grievance decision under subsection (b)(2)(ii) of this section with the written consent of the member, the member's representative, or the health care provider who filed the grievance on behalf of the member.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For nonemergency cases, when a carrier renders a grievance decision, the carrier shall:<section prefix="(i)">document the grievance decision in writing after the carrier has provided oral communication of the decision to the member, the member's representative, or the health care provider acting on behalf of the member; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">send, within 5 working days after the grievance decision has been made, a written notice to the member, the member's representative, and a health care provider acting on behalf of the member that:<section prefix="1.">states in detail in clear, understandable language the specific factual bases for the carrier's decision;</section><section prefix="2.">references the specific criteria and standards, including interpretive guidelines, on which the grievance decision was based;</section><section prefix="3.">states the name, business address, and business telephone number of:</section><section prefix="4.">includes the following information:</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A carrier may not use solely in a notice sent under paragraph (1) of this subsection generalized terms such as "experimental procedure not covered", "cosmetic procedure not covered", "service included under another procedure", or "not medically necessary" to satisfy the requirements of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For an emergency case under subsection (b)(2)(i) of this section, within 1 day after a decision has been orally communicated to the member, the member's representative, or the health care provider, the carrier shall send notice in writing of any adverse decision or grievance decision to:<section prefix="(i)">the member and the member's representative, if any; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the grievance was filed on behalf of the member under subsection (b)(2)(iii) of this section, the health care provider.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A notice required to be sent under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall include the following:<section prefix="(i)">for an adverse decision, the information required under subsection (f) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">for a grievance decision, the information required under subsection (i) of this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each carrier shall include the information required by subsection (f)(2)(iii), (iv), and (v) of this section in the policy, plan, certificate, enrollment materials, or other evidence of coverage that the carrier provides to a member at the time of the member's initial coverage or renewal of coverage.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each carrier shall include as part of the information required by paragraph (1) of this subsection a statement indicating that, when filing a complaint with the Commissioner, the member or the member's representative will be required to authorize the release of any medical records of the member that may be required to be reviewed for the purpose of reaching a decision on the complaint.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Nothing in this subtitle prohibits a carrier from delegating its internal grievance process to a private review agent that has a certificate issued under Subtitle 10B of this title and is acting on behalf of the carrier.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a carrier delegates its internal grievance process to a private review agent, the carrier shall be:<section prefix="(i)">bound by the grievance decision made by the private review agent acting on behalf of the carrier; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">responsible for a violation of any provision of this subtitle regardless of the delegation made by the carrier under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
