<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-126" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-126</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "emergency medical condition" means a medical condition that manifests itself by symptoms of sufficient severity, including severe pain, that the absence of immediate medical attention could reasonably be expected by a prudent layperson, who possesses an average knowledge of health and medicine, to result in:<section prefix="(1)">placing the patient's health in serious jeopardy;</section><section prefix="(2)">serious impairment to bodily functions; or</section><section prefix="(3)">serious dysfunction of any bodily organ or part.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to:<section prefix="(1)">insurers and nonprofit health service plans that provide hospital, medical, or surgical benefits to individuals or groups under health insurance policies that are issued or delivered in the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">health maintenance organizations that provide hospital, medical, or surgical benefits to individuals or groups under contracts that are issued or delivered in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An entity subject to this section may not establish or promote an emergency medical response and transportation system that encourages or directs access by an insured or enrollee in competition with or in substitution of the Maryland Emergency Medical Services System (911) or other State, county, or local government emergency medical services system.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, an entity subject to this section may use transportation outside the 911 or other government emergency medical services system for services that are not in response to an emergency medical condition.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An entity subject to this section may not require an insured or enrollee to obtain prior authorization before accessing the 911 system or other State, county, or local government emergency medical services system for an emergency medical condition.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An entity subject to this section may not use false or misleading language in its enrollment sales materials or in any other materials provided to insureds or enrollees to discourage or prohibit insureds or enrollees from accessing the 911 system for an emergency medical condition.</section>
  </text>
</law>
