<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-311" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-4-311</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The provisions of this subtitle are supplemental to other laws of the State, and may not preclude or limit any other powers or duties of the Commissioner.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner may adopt regulations to carry out this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene, shall adopt regulations that apply appropriate risk based capital standards to managed care organizations as defined under &#xA7; 15-101(e) of the Health - General Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner may exempt from the application of this subtitle any domestic property and casualty insurer that:<section prefix="(1)">writes direct business only in the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">writes direct annual premiums of $2,000,000 or less; and</section><section prefix="(3)">assumes no reinsurance in excess of 5% of direct premiums written.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commissioner may exempt from the application of this Act any domestic health insurer that:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">writes direct business only in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">assumes no reinsurance in excess of 5% of direct premiums written; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">writes direct annual premiums for comprehensive medical business of $2,000,000 or less; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">covers less than 2,000 lives if the health insurer is:<section prefix="(i)">a nonprofit health service plan that provides coverage solely for dental services; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a dental plan organization.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
