<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-10-309</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies to bail bondsmen licensed under this subtitle and to bail bondsmen that provide...</catch_line>
  <order_by>309</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to bail bondsmen licensed under this subtitle and to bail bondsmen that provide bail bondsman services under &#xA7; 5-203 of the Criminal Procedure Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A bail bondsman may arrange to accept payment for the premium charged for a bail bond in installments.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a bail bondsman arranges to accept payment for the premium charged for a bail bond in installments, the installment agreement shall include:<section prefix="(1)">the total amount of the premium owed;</section><section prefix="(2)">the amount of any down payment made;</section><section prefix="(3)">the balance amount owed to the bail bondsman or the bail bondsman's insurer;</section><section prefix="(4)">the amount and due date of each installment payment; and</section><section prefix="(5)">the total number of installment payments required to pay the amount due.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a bail bondsman arranges to accept payment of the premium charged for a bail bond in installments, the bail bondsman shall:<section prefix="(1)">secure a signed affidavit of surety by the defendant or the insurer containing the information required under subsection (c) of this section and provide the affidavit of surety to the court;</section><section prefix="(2)">take all necessary steps to collect the total amount owed by the insured, including seeking remedies provided by law for the collection of debts; and</section><section prefix="(3)">keep and maintain records of all collection attempts, installment agreements, and affidavits of surety.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The bail bondsman shall keep and maintain the records required under this section in an office that is generally accessible to the public during normal business hours.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The bail bondsman shall make the records required under this section available to the Commissioner for inspection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each year, each bail bondsman shall certify to the Commissioner that the records required to be kept and maintained under this section are accurate and true.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If a bail bondsman violates any provision of this section, the Commissioner may take any actions authorized under &#xA7; 10-126 of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
