<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-1403</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A carrier shall provide written certification of creditable coverage in connection with group health benefit plans, including those issued in accordance with Subtitle 12 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The certification of creditable coverage described in subsection (a) of this section shall be provided:<section prefix="(1)">automatically at the time an individual ceases to be covered under the health benefits plan or otherwise becomes covered under a COBRA continuation provision;</section><section prefix="(2)">in the case of an individual who becomes covered under a COBRA continuation provision, at the time the individual ceases to be covered under the provision; and</section><section prefix="(3)">on the request on behalf of an individual made not later than 24 months after the date of cessation of the coverage described in item (1) or (2) of this subsection, whichever is later.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The certification may be provided at a time consistent with notices required under any applicable State or federal continuation provision.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The certification shall contain:<section prefix="(1)">written certification of the period of creditable coverage of the individual under the health benefit plan, and the coverage, if applicable, under the applicable State or federal continuation provision; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the waiting period, if any, imposed with respect to the individual for any coverage under the health benefit plan.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a group health plan enrolls an individual for coverage under the plan and the individual provides a certification of coverage, then:<section prefix="(1)">on request of the group health plan, the entity that issued the certification provided by the individual promptly shall disclose to the requesting group health plan, information regarding coverage of classes and categories of health benefits available under the entity's plan or policy; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the entity may charge the requesting plan for the reasonable cost of disclosing the information.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
