<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-804" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-804</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Medical literature" means scientific studies published in a peer-reviewed national professional medical journal.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Off-label use" means the prescription of a drug for a treatment other than those treatments stated in the labeling approved by the federal Food and Drug Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Standard reference compendia" means any authoritative compendia as recognized periodically by the federal Secretary of Health and Human Services or the Commissioner.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not:<section prefix="(1)">alter any law that limits the coverage of drugs that have not been approved by the federal Food and Drug Administration;</section><section prefix="(2)">require coverage of a drug if the federal Food and Drug Administration has determined use of the drug to be contraindicated; or</section><section prefix="(3)">require coverage of experimental drugs not approved for any indication by the federal Food and Drug Administration.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to each health insurance policy or contract that is delivered or issued for delivery in the State to an employer or individual on a group or individual basis, including a contract issued by a health maintenance organization.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A policy or contract subject to this subsection that provides coverage for drugs may not exclude coverage of a drug for an off-label use of the drug if the drug is recognized for treatment in any of the standard reference compendia or in the medical literature.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Coverage of a drug required by this subsection also includes medically necessary services associated with the administration of the drug.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commissioner may direct a person, including a health maintenance organization, that issues a health insurance policy or contract to make payments required by this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
