<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-23-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To engage in business as a premium finance company in the State, each premium finance company shall elect to:<section prefix="(1)">maintain a net worth of at least $250,000 calculated under generally accepted accounting principles;</section><section prefix="(2)">file with the Commissioner an irrevocable letter of credit in the amount of $50,000 issued by a financial institution;</section><section prefix="(3)">deposit with the State Treasurer cash in the amount of $50,000; or</section><section prefix="(4)">file with the Commissioner a bond that:<section prefix="(i)">is in favor of the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is in the penal sum of $50,000;</section><section prefix="(iii)">is executed by an authorized surety insurer; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">is conditioned that the premium finance company will account for and pay over to the person entitled to receive it all money belonging to the person that comes into the possession of the premium finance company, including unearned premiums due to an insured and unearned commissions due to an insurer.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A bond shall remain in force until the surety insurer is released from liability by the Commissioner or until the bond is canceled by the surety insurer.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The total liability of the surety insurer under a bond may not exceed the penal sum of the bond.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The surety insurer may cancel a bond after filing written notice with the Commissioner at least 30 days before the effective date of the cancellation.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A cancellation under this paragraph does not affect any liability that accrued before the cancellation.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After notification of the cancellation of the bond, the premium finance company shall act promptly to replace the bond.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the premium finance company fails to act promptly to replace the bond, the Commissioner shall deny, suspend, revoke, or refuse to renew the registration of the premium finance company until the required bond is filed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If, at any time, the premium finance company fails to comply with subsection (a) of this section, the Commissioner shall deny, suspend, revoke, or refuse to renew the registration of the premium finance company until the premium finance company complies with subsection (a) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
