<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-512" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-14-512</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Program shall:<section prefix="(1)">provide a prescription drug benefit subsidy, as determined by the Board, that may pay all or some of the deductibles, coinsurance payments, premiums, and copayments under the federal Medicare Part D Pharmaceutical Assistance Program for enrollees of the Program; and</section><section prefix="(2)">provide the subsidy to the maximum number of individuals eligible for enrollment in the Program, subject to the moneys available in the segregated account under &#xA7; 14-504 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Program may limit payment of any subsidy by paying the subsidy only on behalf of eligible individuals enrolled in a Medicare Part D Prescription Drug Plan or Medicare Advantage Plan that coordinates with the Program in accordance with federal requirements.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Program:<section prefix="(1)">may annually provide an additional subsidy, up to the full amount of the Medicare Part D Prescription Drug Plan premium, for individuals who qualify for a partial federal low-income subsidy; and</section><section prefix="(2)">shall annually provide an additional subsidy up to the full amount of the Medicare Part D coverage gap, subject to the availability of:<section prefix="(i)">funds provided under &#xA7; 14-106.2 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any other funds available for this purpose.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Program shall maintain a waiting list of individuals who meet the eligibility requirements for the Program but who are not served by the Program due to funding limitations.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board shall determine annually:<section prefix="(1)">the number of individuals to be enrolled in the Program;</section><section prefix="(2)">the amount of subsidy to be provided under subsections (a) and (c)(2) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the amount of any additional subsidy provided under subsection (c)(1) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">On or before January 1 of each year, the Board, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, shall report to the General Assembly on:<section prefix="(1)">the number of individuals on the waiting list for the Program; and</section><section prefix="(2)">to the extent that the Board is able to collect the information:<section prefix="(i)">the number of enrollees with out-of-pocket prescription drug costs that exceed $2,250, broken down for each fiscal quarter; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the total annual out-of-pocket prescription drug costs for enrollees.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
