<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-8-511</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>511</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the hearing provisions of &#xA7;&#xA7; 2-210 through 2-214 of this article, the Commissioner may deny, refuse to renew, suspend, or revoke a reinsurance intermediary's license, or a reinsurance intermediary's insurance producer license, if the reinsurance intermediary has violated this subtitle or &#xA7; 10-126 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Instead of or in addition to the penalties provided in subsection (a) of this section, the Commissioner:<section prefix="(1)">may impose a penalty not exceeding $5,000 for each violation of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">may bring a civil action for the benefit of an insurer or reinsurer and its policyholders and creditors to recover compensatory damages or may seek other appropriate relief; and</section><section prefix="(3)">may impose any other penalty authorized by this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An order of the Commissioner issued under this section is subject to judicial review in accordance with &#xA7; 2-215 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A receiver appointed under Title 9, Subtitle 2 of this article may bring a civil action to recover damages or for other appropriate sanctions for the benefit of an insurer if the receiver determines that:<section prefix="(1)">a reinsurance intermediary or other person has failed to comply materially with this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the failure has caused an insurer under an order of rehabilitation or liquidation to suffer a loss or damage.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This section is not intended to limit the rights of policyholders or claimants of an insurer or reinsurer.</section>
  </text>
</law>
