<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-4-207</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>207</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An unauthorized insurer or person that does an act of insurance business listed in &#xA7; 4-205(c) of this subtitle is deemed to have appointed irrevocably the Secretary of State to be the attorney of the unauthorized insurer or person in a proceeding in a court by the Commissioner or the State, and on whom may be served any notice, order, pleading, or process in a proceeding before the Commissioner, and which proceeding arises from the unauthorized insurer or person doing an insurance business in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An unauthorized insurer or person that does an act of insurance business listed in &#xA7; 4-205(c) of this subtitle is deemed to have agreed that service on the Secretary of State under this section has the same legal effect as personal service in the State on the unauthorized insurer or person.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The deemed appointment of the Secretary of State binds the unauthorized insurer or person and any executor, administrator, personal representative, or successor in interest if a corporation, of the unauthorized insurer or person.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Service of process on the Secretary of State in a court proceeding or administrative proceeding under this section shall be made by delivering to the Secretary of State or an individual in apparent charge of the office of the Secretary of State two copies of the process in a court proceeding or the notice, order, pleading, or process in an administrative proceeding.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Immediately after receipt of process in a court proceeding or the notice, order, pleading, or process in an administrative proceeding, the Secretary of State shall mail one copy of the process or notice, order, pleading, or process to the defendant in the court proceeding, or to the person to whom the notice, order, pleading, or process is addressed or directed in the administrative proceeding, at its last known principal place of business.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Service of process under this section is sufficient if:<section prefix="(i)">within 10 days after service on the Secretary of State under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the plaintiff or plaintiff's attorney in a court proceeding or the Commissioner in an administrative proceeding sends notice of the service and a copy of the court process, or the notice, order, pleading, or process in the administrative proceeding, by certified mail, return receipt requested, bearing a postmark from the United States Postal Service, to the defendant in a court proceeding or the person to whom the notice, order, pleading, or process is addressed or directed in the administrative proceeding at its last known principal place of business; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">on or before the date that the defendant is required to appear or respond in a court or administrative proceeding or within any further time that the court or Commissioner allows, the plaintiff or plaintiff's attorney in a court proceeding or the Commissioner in an administrative proceeding files with the clerk of the court in which the court proceeding is pending or with the Commissioner in an administrative proceeding:<section prefix="1.">the defendant's receipt, or the receipt issued by the United States Postal Service, showing the name of the sender of the letter and the name and address of the addressee; and</section><section prefix="2.">an affidavit of the plaintiff or plaintiff's attorney in a court proceeding, or the Commissioner in an administrative proceeding, showing compliance with paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A certificate by the Secretary of State that shows service in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection and is attached to the original or third copy of the process is sufficient evidence of service.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Service on the Secretary of State under this section is deemed service on the principal.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Secretary of State shall keep a record of all process served on the Secretary of State under this section that shows the day and time of service.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A judgment or determination, by default, in any court or administrative proceeding in which court process or a notice, order, pleading, or process is served under this section may not be entered until the expiration of 45 days after the date of filing of the affidavit of compliance.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section does not limit the right to serve any process, notice, order, pleading, or demand on an insurer or another person in any other manner authorized by law.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">On request of the Commissioner, the Attorney General may proceed in a court of this State or another state or in a federal court or agency to enforce an order or decision in a court proceeding or in an administrative proceeding before the Commissioner.</section>
  </text>
</law>
