<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="19-802" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-19-802</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Maryland Health Care Provider Rate Stabilization Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The purposes of the Fund are to:<section prefix="(1)">retain health care providers in the State by allowing medical professional liability insurers to collect rates that are less than the rates approved under &#xA7; 11-201 of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">increase fee-for-service rates paid by the Maryland Medical Assistance Program to health care providers identified under &#xA7; 19-807 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">pay managed care organization health care providers identified under &#xA7; 19-807 of this subtitle consistent with fee-for-service health care provider rates;</section><section prefix="(4)">increase capitation payments to managed care organizations participating in the Maryland Medical Assistance Program consistent with &#xA7; 15-103(b)(18) of the Health - General Article; and</section><section prefix="(5)">during the period that an allocation is made to the Rate Stabilization Account, subsidize up to $350,000 annually to provide for the costs incurred by the Commissioner to administer the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Fund shall consist of:<section prefix="(1)">the revenue from the tax imposed on health maintenance organizations and managed care organizations under &#xA7; 6-102 of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">interest or other income earned on the moneys in the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(3)">any other money from any other source accepted for the benefit of the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The State Treasurer shall hold the Fund separately and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The State Treasurer shall invest the money of the Fund in the same manner as other State money may be invested.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Fund comprises:<section prefix="(1)">the Rate Stabilization Account from which disbursements shall be made to pay for health care provider rate subsidies; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the Medical Assistance Program Account from which disbursements shall be made to:<section prefix="(i)">provide an increase in fee-for-service health care provider rates paid by the Maryland Medical Assistance Program;</section><section prefix="(ii)">provide an increase for managed care organization health care providers consistent with fee-for-service health care provider rate increases;</section><section prefix="(iii)">provide an increase in capitation payments to managed care organizations participating in the Maryland Medical Assistance Program consistent with &#xA7; 15-103(b)(18) of the Health - General Article; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">after fiscal year 2009, maintain rates for health care providers and generally to support the operations of the Maryland Medical Assistance Program.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
