<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-2-109</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Commissioner may adopt regulations to:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>109</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commissioner may adopt regulations to:<section prefix="(1)">carry out this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">establish, maintain, and administer reserves under Title 3, Subtitle 2A of the Courts Article; and</section><section prefix="(3)">regulate the solicitation by a domestic stock insurer or other person of proxies, consents, and authorizations with respect to equity securities of the domestic stock insurer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner shall:<section prefix="(i)">compile and keep in the office of the Commissioner a set of current regulations adopted under this article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">make a copy of the regulations for anyone who asks for one.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner may set a fee to cover the cost of making and mailing a copy of the current regulations.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By regulation, the Commissioner shall establish or direct the establishment of a toll-free telephone number to help consumers with and educate consumers about the purchase of private passenger automobile insurance.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner:<section prefix="(i)">may not recommend specific insurers or insurance producers; but</section><section prefix="(ii)">may provide to callers educational material, including a rate guide and a list of insurers and insurance producers.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By regulation, the Commissioner shall establish standards governing the privacy of consumer financial and health information pursuant to Title V of the Federal Financial Services Modernization Act of 1999 (Public Law 106-102).</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The regulations shall be consistent with the provisions of the model regulation adopted by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners entitled "Privacy of Consumer Financial and Health Information Regulation".</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">By regulation, the Commissioner shall establish criteria and a process to allow an individual who is otherwise prohibited from engaging in or participating in the business of insurance under the Federal Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 (Public Law 103-322) to obtain written consent from the Commissioner to engage in or participate in the business of insurance under the federal Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In addition to any other penalty provided, a person that willfully violates a regulation adopted under this article is subject to any applicable penalty under this article for violation of the provision to which the regulation relates.</section>
  </text>
</law>
