<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-839</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>839</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Body mass index" means a practical marker that is used to assess the degree of obesity and is calculated by dividing the weight in kilograms by the height in meters squared.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Morbid obesity" means a body mass index that is:<section prefix="(i)">greater than 40 kilograms per meter squared; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">equal to or greater than 35 kilograms per meter squared with a comorbid medical condition, including hypertension, a cardiopulmonary condition, sleep apnea, or diabetes.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to:<section prefix="(1)">insurers and nonprofit health service plans that provide hospital, medical, or surgical benefits to individuals or groups on an expense-incurred basis under health insurance policies or contracts that are issued or delivered in the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">health maintenance organizations that provide hospital, medical, or surgical benefits to individuals or groups under contracts that are issued or delivered in the State; and</section><section prefix="(3)">managed care organizations, as defined in &#xA7; 15-101 of the Health - General Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An entity subject to this section shall provide coverage for the surgical treatment of morbid obesity that is:<section prefix="(1)">recognized by the National Institutes of Health as effective for the long-term reversal of morbid obesity; and</section><section prefix="(2)">consistent with guidelines approved by the National Institutes of Health.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An entity subject to this section shall provide the benefits required under this section to the same extent as for other medically necessary surgical procedures under the enrollee's or insured's contract or policy with the entity.</section>
  </text>
</law>
