<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-31-118</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>118</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Beginning January 1, 2014, subject to subsections (b) and (c) of this section, the Exchange may:<section prefix="(1)">impose user fees, licensing or other regulatory fees, or other assessments that do not exceed reasonable projections regarding the amount necessary to support the operations of the Exchange under this title; or</section><section prefix="(2)">otherwise generate funding necessary to support its operations under this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Any fees, assessments, or other funding mechanisms shall be imposed or implemented, to the maximum extent possible, in a manner that is transparent and broad-based.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before imposing or altering any fee or assessment established by law, the Exchange shall adopt regulations that specify:<section prefix="(1)">the persons subject to the fee or assessment;</section><section prefix="(2)">the amount of the fee or assessment; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the manner in which the fee or assessment will be collected.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Funds collected through any fees, assessments, or other funding mechanisms:<section prefix="(1)">shall be deposited in the Fund;</section><section prefix="(2)">shall be used only for the purposes authorized under this title; and</section><section prefix="(3)">may not be used for staff retreats, promotional giveaways, excessive executive compensation, or promotion of federal or State legislative and regulatory actions.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Exchange may not impose fees or assessments authorized under this section in a manner that would provide a competitive disadvantage to health benefit plans operating outside of the Exchange.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Exchange shall maintain a Web site on which it shall publish:<section prefix="(1)">the average amounts of any fees, assessments, or other payments required by the Exchange;</section><section prefix="(2)">the administrative costs of the Exchange; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the amount of funds known to be lost through waste, fraud, and abuse.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
