<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-10-405</section_number>
  <catch_line>An applicant for an initial license shall file with the Commissioner an application on the form that...</catch_line>
  <order_by>405</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An applicant for an initial license shall file with the Commissioner an application on the form that the Commissioner provides.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The application form shall require:<section prefix="(1)">the name and address of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(2)">whether any other insurance license or certificate has been issued to the applicant;</section><section prefix="(3)">the business in which the applicant has been engaged for the 5 years immediately preceding the date of application and, if employed by another, the name and address of each employer;</section><section prefix="(4)">for a business entity applicant:<section prefix="(i)">the name of the individual licensed public adjuster employed by the business entity who is designated to act as the business entity's principal contact with the Administration; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the name and address of each licensed public adjuster employed by the business entity, each individual who has direct control over its fiscal management, each owner, partner, member, or manager of the business entity, and each director of a business entity that is a corporation; and</section></section><section prefix="(5)">any other information that the Commissioner requires of applicants to enable the Commissioner to determine the trustworthiness and competence of the applicant to transact business as a public adjuster so as to safeguard the interests of the public.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An application shall be signed under oath:<section prefix="(1)">in the case of an individual applicant, by the applicant; or</section><section prefix="(2)">in the case of an applicant that is a business entity, by an individual who has direct control over its fiscal management, an owner, partner, member, or manager of the business entity, or a director of a business entity that is a corporation.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
