<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-25-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "service company" means a person that provides services that are not provided by the administrator, including:<section prefix="(1)">claims adjustment;</section><section prefix="(2)">safety engineering;</section><section prefix="(3)">compilation of statistics and the preparation of premium, loss, and tax reports;</section><section prefix="(4)">preparation of other required self-insurance reports;</section><section prefix="(5)">development of members' assessments and fees; and</section><section prefix="(6)">administration of a claim fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commissioner shall adopt regulations to carry out this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The regulations shall include:<section prefix="(1)">classifications of businesses and industries, based on the type of activity conducted by the business or industry, within which employers may join together in self-insurance groups;</section><section prefix="(2)">for each classification:<section prefix="(i)">a minimum level of contribution of at least $250,000 in premiums collected from or pledged by members of a self-insurance group to a fund from which workers' compensation claims will be paid;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a minimum level of excess insurance coverage that must be obtained by each self-insurance group;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a requirement that the minimum levels of excess insurance adopted under this subtitle may be satisfied by placing, in a depository that the Commissioner designates, securities in a form and amount that the Commissioner requires; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">a surety bond of at least $100,000 that must be obtained by each self-insurance group;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">conditions under which contributions by members of a self-insurance group may be rebated or temporarily suspended;</section><section prefix="(4)">for each administrator or service company, a bond that the Commissioner may require in addition to any other required bond; and</section><section prefix="(5)">a requirement that the governance of the group be under the control of its members.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
