<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="gin" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-10-128</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section does not apply to:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>128</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">reinsurance;</section><section prefix="(2)">life insurance, health insurance, or annuity contracts;</section><section prefix="(3)">insurance of:<section prefix="(i)">rolling stock, vessels, or aircraft of a common carrier used in interstate or foreign commerce;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a vehicle principally garaged and used outside the State; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">liability or other risks, incident to the ownership, maintenance, or operation of a subject of insurance under item (i) or (ii) of this item;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">insurance of property while transported in interstate or in foreign trade, or any liability or risk incident to the transportation;</section><section prefix="(5)">insurance of wet marine and transportation risks;</section><section prefix="(6)">bid bonds issued in connection with public or private contracts;</section><section prefix="(7)">policies or endorsements issued through:<section prefix="(i)">insurance producers compensated only by salary;</section><section prefix="(ii)">insurers not using insurance producers in the general solicitation of business;</section><section prefix="(iii)">mutual insurers or other insurers not customarily using insurance producers compensated by commission if no commission is payable to an insurance producer on the policy or endorsement; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">insurers or groups of insurers under common management or control that are represented exclusively by insurance producers who represent only the insurers or groups of insurers;</section></section><section prefix="(8)">reciprocal insurers; or</section><section prefix="(9)">insurance written through:<section prefix="(i)">the Maryland Automobile Insurance Fund; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Maryland Property Insurance Availability Program.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not alter the requirements of &#xA7; 10-119 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law of this State or of policy forms, and subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, an insurance producer that is a resident of this State may not be required to sign or countersign a policy covering a subject of insurance resident, located, or to be performed in this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A policy covering a subject of insurance resident, located, or to be performed in this State shall be signed or countersigned by an insurance producer that is a resident of this State if:<section prefix="(i)">the policy is written by an insurance producer that is a resident of another state and is qualified as a nonresident insurance producer in this State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the law of the other state requires a signature or countersignature by an insurance producer that is a resident of that state on a policy written by an insurance producer that is not a resident in that state.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A policy is not invalid because it does not have the required signature or countersignature.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not sign or countersign a policy or endorsement subject to this section unless the person:<section prefix="(i)">is a licensed insurance producer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is a resident of this State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">is compensated by commissions on policies subject to this section; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">is not an employee or officer of the insurer issuing the policy.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not prevent an insurance producer from:<section prefix="(i)">delegating the duty of signing or countersigning to employees of the insurance producer that are not also employees of lending institutions; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">directing the payment of commissions on policies subject to this section to a corporation or partnership insurance agency or otherwise.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An insurance producer may not countersign a policy or endorsement unless the policy or endorsement states, as applicable:<section prefix="(1)">the rates or premiums;</section><section prefix="(2)">a description of the property insured; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the name and address of the insured.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If the law of another state requires an insurance producer that is a resident of that state to keep part of the commission paid on a policy written, countersigned, or delivered by the insurance producer in that state on request of a nonresident insurance producer of that state, an insurance producer that is a resident of this State and that signs or countersigns a policy written by an insurance producer that is a resident of the other state and qualified as a nonresident insurance producer in this State covering a subject of insurance resident, located, or to be performed in this State shall keep an equal pro rata part of any commission on the policy.</section>
  </text>
</law>
