<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-10-606</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>606</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commissioner may suspend, revoke, or refuse to renew a limited lines license to sell insurance in connection with, and incidental to, the rental of a motor vehicle issued under this subtitle after notice and opportunity for a hearing under Title 2, Subtitle 2 of this article if the motor vehicle rental company or an employee of the motor vehicle rental company has:<section prefix="(1)">willfully violated this article or another law of the State that relates to insurance;</section><section prefix="(2)">operated without a limited lines license to sell insurance in connection with, and incidental to, the rental of a motor vehicle as required under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">failed to provide required disclosures;</section><section prefix="(4)">offered or sold unapproved insurance products;</section><section prefix="(5)">failed to hold an appointment with the insurer;</section><section prefix="(6)">failed to train employees selling or soliciting, or negotiating the sale of, insurance products on behalf of the motor vehicle rental company; or</section><section prefix="(7)">misrepresented pertinent facts or policy provisions that relate to the coverage offered or sold pursuant to this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A motor vehicle rental company and its employees may not advertise, represent, or otherwise hold itself out as an authorized insurer, or as an insurance producer, for any kind or subdivision of insurance.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Instead of, or in addition to, suspending or revoking the limited lines license to sell insurance in connection with, and incidental to, the rental of a motor vehicle, the Commissioner may:<section prefix="(1)">impose on the motor vehicle rental company a penalty of not less than $100 but not more than $2,500 for each violation of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">require that restitution be made to any person who has suffered financial injury because of the violation of this article.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
