<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-19-504.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>504.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only when the liability coverage under a policy or binder of private passenger motor vehicle liability insurance exceeds the amount required under &#xA7; 17-103 of the Transportation Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An insurer shall offer to the first named insured under a policy or binder of private passenger motor vehicle liability insurance liability coverage for claims made by a family member in the same amount as the liability coverage for claims made by a nonfamily member under the policy or binder.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An offer made under this section shall be made on the form that the Commissioner requires.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The form may be part of the insurance application, policy, contract, or binder.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The form shall clearly and concisely explain in 10 point boldface type:<section prefix="(i)">the nature, extent, benefit, and cost of the amount of liability coverage for claims made by family members that is available to the first named insured; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">that an insurer may not refuse to underwrite a first named insured because the first named insured requests or elects the liability coverage for claims made by family members in an amount equal to the coverage provided for claims made by nonfamily members.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An insurer may not refuse to underwrite a first named insured because the first named insured requests or elects the liability coverage for claims made by family members in an amount equal to the coverage provided for claims made by nonfamily members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An insurer that violates this subsection is subject to the penalties provided in &#xA7;&#xA7; 4-113 and 4-114 of this article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
