<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-112.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>112.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Carrier" means:<section prefix="1.">an insurer;</section><section prefix="2.">a nonprofit health service plan;</section><section prefix="3.">a health maintenance organization;</section><section prefix="4.">a dental plan organization;</section><section prefix="5.">a managed care organization; or</section><section prefix="6.">any other person that provides health benefit plans subject to regulation by the State.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Carrier" includes an entity that arranges a provider panel for a carrier.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Credentialing intermediary" means a person to whom a carrier has delegated credentialing or recredentialing authority and responsibility.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Health care provider" means an individual who is licensed, certified, or otherwise authorized under the Health Occupations Article to provide health care services.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Provider panel" means the providers that contract with a carrier to provide health care services to the enrollees under a health benefit plan of the carrier.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Uniform credentialing form" means the form designated by the Commissioner for use by a carrier or its credentialing intermediary for credentialing and recredentialing a health care provider for participation on a provider panel.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, a carrier or its credentialing intermediary shall accept the uniform credentialing form as the sole application for a health care provider to become credentialed or recredentialed for a provider panel of the carrier.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A carrier or its credentialing intermediary shall make the uniform credentialing form available to any health care provider that is to be credentialed or recredentialed by that carrier or credentialing intermediary.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The requirements of subsection (b) of this section do not apply to a hospital or academic medical center that:<section prefix="(1)">is a participating provider on the carrier's provider panel; and</section><section prefix="(2)">acts as a credentialing intermediary for that carrier for health care practitioners that:<section prefix="(i)">participate on the carrier's provider panel; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">have privileges at the hospital or academic medical center.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commissioner may impose a penalty not to exceed $500 against any carrier for each violation of this section by the carrier or its credentialing intermediary.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner may adopt regulations to implement the provisions of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner may designate a provider credentialing application developed by a nonprofit alliance of health plans and trade associations for an online credentialing system offered to carriers and providers as the uniform credentialing form if:<section prefix="(i)">the provider credentialing application is available to providers at no charge; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">use of the provider credentialing application is not conditioned on submitting the provider credentialing application to a carrier through the online credentialing system.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
