<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-305" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-4-305</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A company action level event occurs:<section prefix="(1)">when an insurer files an RBC report that indicates that:<section prefix="(i)">the insurer has total adjusted capital that is:</section><section prefix="(ii)">in the case of a life insurer, the life insurer has total adjusted capital that:</section><section prefix="(iii)">in the case of a property and casualty insurer, the property and casualty insurer has total adjusted capital that:</section><section prefix="(iv)">in the case of a health insurer, the health insurer has total adjusted capital that:</section></section><section prefix="(2)">when the Commissioner notifies an insurer of an adjusted RBC report that indicates an event under item (1) of this subsection; or</section><section prefix="(3)">if an insurer requests a hearing to challenge an adjusted RBC report that indicates an event under item (1) of this subsection, when the Commissioner notifies the insurer that the Commissioner, after a hearing, has rejected the insurer's challenge.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In the event of a company action level event, the insurer shall prepare and submit to the Commissioner an RBC plan that shall:<section prefix="(1)">identify the conditions that contribute to the company action level event;</section><section prefix="(2)">contain proposals of corrective actions that the insurer intends to take and that would be expected to result in the elimination of the company action level event;</section><section prefix="(3)">provide projections of the insurer's financial results in the current year and at least the 4 succeeding years that:<section prefix="(i)">project financial results:</section><section prefix="(ii)">include projections of statutory operating income, net income, capital, and surplus; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">for both new and renewal business, include separate projections for each major line of business and separately identify each significant income, expense, and benefit component;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">identify the key assumptions that impact the insurer's projections and the sensitivity of the projections to the assumptions; and</section><section prefix="(5)">identify the quality of and the problems associated with the insurer's business, including its assets, anticipated business growth and associated surplus strain, extraordinary exposure to risk, mix of business, and use of reinsurance, as appropriate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The insurer shall submit the RBC plan to the Commissioner:<section prefix="(1)">within 45 days after the date of the company action level event; or</section><section prefix="(2)">if the insurer requests a hearing to challenge an adjusted RBC report, within 45 days after notification to the insurer that the Commissioner, after a hearing, has rejected the insurer's challenge.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 60 days after an insurer submits an RBC plan to the Commissioner, the Commissioner shall notify the insurer whether the Commissioner has determined that the RBC plan may be implemented or that the RBC plan is unsatisfactory.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Commissioner determines that the RBC plan is unsatisfactory, the notification to the insurer:<section prefix="(i)">shall set forth the reasons for the determination; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">may set forth proposed revisions that will make the RBC plan satisfactory to the Commissioner.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On notification that the RBC plan is unsatisfactory, the insurer shall:<section prefix="(i)">prepare a revised RBC plan, which may incorporate by reference any revisions proposed by the Commissioner; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">submit the revised RBC plan to the Commissioner.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The insurer shall submit the revised RBC plan required by paragraph (3) of this subsection to the Commissioner:<section prefix="(i)">within 45 days after the notification from the Commissioner; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the insurer requests a hearing to challenge the notification from the Commissioner, within 45 days after notification to the insurer that the Commissioner, after a hearing, has rejected the insurer's challenge.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Subject to the right of the insurer to a hearing, when the Commissioner notifies an insurer that the insurer's RBC plan or revised RBC plan is unsatisfactory, the Commissioner may specify in the notification that the notification constitutes a regulatory action level event.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each domestic insurer that files an RBC plan or revised RBC plan with the Commissioner shall file a copy of the RBC plan or revised RBC plan with the insurance commissioner of any state in which the insurer is authorized to do business if:<section prefix="(i)">the state has a confidentiality provision substantially similar to &#xA7; 4-310(a) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the insurance commissioner of that state has notified the insurer in writing of its request for the filing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On request of an insurance commissioner of another state under this subsection, the insurer shall file a copy of the RBC plan or revised RBC plan with that insurance commissioner by the later of:<section prefix="(i)">15 days after receipt of the notification to file a copy of its RBC plan or revised RBC plan with that state; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the date on which the RBC plan or revised RBC plan is filed under subsection (c) or (d) of this section.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
