<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="20-507" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-20-507</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the approval of the Commissioner, the Executive Director shall determine the premiums to be charged on policies issued by the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, the provisions of Title 11, Subtitle 2 of this article apply to the determination of premiums by the Executive Director.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding Title 11, Subtitle 2 of this article or any other provision of this title, the Executive Director may base premiums on one or both of the following items:<section prefix="(i)">the number of points accumulated by an insured or applicant for insurance under the point system provided for in Title 16, Subtitle 4 of the Transportation Article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the prior claims experience of an insured or applicant for insurance.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Premiums for all commercial coverage shall be determined in accordance with this section and &#xA7; 20-508 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, the rating principles under subsection (d) of this section may not be used to determine the premium for commercial coverage.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In reviewing rates filed by the Fund, the Commissioner shall consider not only the rating principles under Title 11, Subtitle 2 of this article but also the statutory purpose of the Fund under &#xA7; 20-301 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Motor Vehicle Administration and Executive Director may arrange for the Motor Vehicle Administration to collect premiums on policies issued by the Fund when the Motor Vehicle Administration issues a driver's license or certificate of registration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A premium collected under this subsection shall be paid to the State Treasurer for the account of the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund may not:<section prefix="(i)">provide directly or indirectly for the financing of premiums; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">accept premiums on an installment basis.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A premium may be financed only by a premium finance company registered with the Commissioner in accordance with &#xA7; 23-201 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a prospective insured's initial payment to the Fund, a fund producer, or premium finance company is not honored, a policy or endorsement issued in reliance on that payment is void.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
