<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-14-413</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>413</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">On or before March 1 of each year, each dental plan organization shall file with the Commissioner a complete statement of its financial condition, transactions, and affairs for the immediately preceding calendar year.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The annual statement shall:<section prefix="(1)">be in the form and have the content approved for current use by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners or its successor organization; and</section><section prefix="(2)">contain any additional information that the Commissioner requires.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Unless the Commissioner extends the time for filing, a dental plan organization that fails to file an annual statement on or before March 10 shall pay a penalty of:<section prefix="(1)">$100 for each day from March 1 to March 10, both inclusive; and</section><section prefix="(2)">$150 for each day from March 11 to the day before the Commissioner receives the report, both inclusive.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">At any time, the Commissioner may require a dental plan organization doing business in the State to file an interim statement containing the information that the Commissioner considers necessary.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (5) of this subsection, on or before June 1 of each year, each dental plan organization shall file with the Commissioner an audited financial report for the immediately preceding calendar year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The dental plan organization shall have the audited financial report prepared by an independent certified public accountant.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commissioner may:<section prefix="(i)">set requirements for the form and content of the audited financial report; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">for good cause, extend the time for filing the audited financial report.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Unless the Commissioner extends the time for filing, a dental plan organization that fails to file an audited financial report on or before June 10 shall pay a penalty of:<section prefix="(i)">$100 for each day from June 1 to June 10, both inclusive; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">$150 for each day from June 11 to the day before the Commissioner receives the report, both inclusive.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">With 90 days' advance notice, the Commissioner may require a dental plan organization to file an audited financial report earlier than the date specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
