<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1">Insurance</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-14-107</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>107</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">By November 1 of each year, the Commissioner shall issue an order notifying each nonprofit health service plan that is required to file a report under &#xA7; 14-106 of this subtitle of whether the plan has satisfied the requirements of &#xA7; 14-106 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the Commissioner determines that a nonprofit health service plan has not satisfied the requirements of &#xA7; 14-106 of this subtitle, the Commissioner shall issue an order requiring the nonprofit health service plan to pay the premium tax under Title 6, Subtitle 1 of this article:<section prefix="(1)">for a period of time beginning with the date the plan was determined to be out of compliance with &#xA7; 14-106 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">in an amount equal to the amount by which the value of the nonprofit health service plan's premium tax exemption under &#xA7; 6-101(b) of this article exceeds the sum of:<section prefix="(i)">the subsidy required under the Senior Prescription Drug Assistance Program established under Subtitle 5, Part II of this title; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">other funds used by the nonprofit health service plan to meet the public service requirement under &#xA7; 14-106 of this subtitle.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A nonprofit health service plan that fails to timely file the report required under &#xA7; 14-106 of this subtitle shall pay the penalties under &#xA7; 14-121 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A party aggrieved by an order of the Commissioner issued under this section has a right to a hearing in accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 2-210 through 2-215 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Premium tax revenue collected by the Administration as the result of an order issued under subsection (b) of this section shall be deposited into the Maryland Health Insurance Plan Fund established under &#xA7; 14-504 of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
