<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-701" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-14-701</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL MAY 31, 2013 PER CHAPTERS 626 AND 627 OF 2008 //<section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section><section prefix="(b)">"Certified nonprofit corporation" means a nonprofit corporation certified under this subtitle to establish and operate a public-private health care program.</section><section prefix="(c)">"Health care provider" means any person, including a physician or hospital, who is licensed or otherwise authorized to provide health care services in the State.</section><section prefix="(d)">"Health care services" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 19-701 of the Health - General Article.</section><section prefix="(e)">"Qualifying individual" means an individual who:<section prefix="(1)">is not eligible for or enrolled in the federal Medicare program, the Maryland Primary Adult Care Program, or the Maryland Children's Health Program;</section><section prefix="(2)">is not covered under a health benefit plan issued under Title 15, Subtitle 12 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(3)">meets any other eligibility requirements established by a public-private health care program.</section></section><section prefix="(f)">"Participants" means qualifying individuals enrolled in a public-private health care program.</section><section prefix="(g)">"Public-private health care program" means a program that:<section prefix="(1)">is established and operated by a nonprofit corporation that:<section prefix="(i)">has been certified by the Commissioner under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">has entered into a written agreement with each county in which the program proposes to operate; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">for a membership fee, provides or arranges for the provision of health care services for participants.</section></section></text>
</law>
