<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-1201" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-15-1201</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the Board of Directors of the Pool established under &#xA7; 15-1216 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Carrier" means a person that:<section prefix="(1)">offers health benefit plans in the State covering eligible employees of small employers; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is:<section prefix="(i)">an authorized insurer that provides health insurance in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a nonprofit health service plan that is licensed to operate in the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a health maintenance organization that is licensed to operate in the State; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">any other person or organization that provides health benefit plans subject to State insurance regulation.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Commission" means the Maryland Health Care Commission established under Title 19, Subtitle 1 of the Health - General Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Eligible employee" means:<section prefix="(i)">an individual who:</section><section prefix="(ii)">a sole employee of a nonprofit organization that has been determined by the Internal Revenue Service to be exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 501(c)(3), (4), or (6) of the Internal Revenue Code who:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Eligible employee" does not include an individual who works:<section prefix="(i)">on a temporary or substitute basis; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">except for an individual described in paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection, for less than 30 hours in a normal workweek.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Health benefit plan" means:<section prefix="(i)">a policy or certificate for hospital or medical benefits;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a nonprofit health service plan; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a health maintenance organization subscriber or group master contract.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Health benefit plan" includes a policy or certificate for hospital or medical benefits that covers residents of this State who are eligible employees and that is issued through:<section prefix="(i)">a multiple employer trust or association located in this State or another state; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a professional employer organization, coemployer, or other organization located in this State or another state that engages in employee leasing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Health benefit plan" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">accident-only insurance;</section><section prefix="(ii)">fixed indemnity insurance;</section><section prefix="(iii)">credit health insurance;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Medicare supplement policies;</section><section prefix="(v)">Civilian Health and Medical Program of the Uniformed Services (CHAMPUS) supplement policies;</section><section prefix="(vi)">long-term care insurance;</section><section prefix="(vii)">disability income insurance;</section><section prefix="(viii)">coverage issued as a supplement to liability insurance;</section><section prefix="(ix)">workers' compensation or similar insurance;</section><section prefix="(x)">disease-specific insurance;</section><section prefix="(xi)">automobile medical payment insurance;</section><section prefix="(xii)">dental insurance; or</section><section prefix="(xiii)">vision insurance.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Health status-related factor" means a factor related to:<section prefix="(1)">health status;</section><section prefix="(2)">medical condition;</section><section prefix="(3)">claims experience;</section><section prefix="(4)">receipt of health care;</section><section prefix="(5)">medical history;</section><section prefix="(6)">genetic information;</section><section prefix="(7)">evidence of insurability including conditions arising out of acts of domestic violence; or</section><section prefix="(8)">disability.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Late enrollee" means:<section prefix="(1)">an eligible employee or dependent who requests enrollment in a health benefit plan after the initial enrollment period provided under the health benefit plan; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a self-employed individual described in &#xA7; 15-1203(c) or (d) of this subtitle or dependent who requests enrollment in a health benefit plan after an annual open enrollment period for self-employed individuals established by the carrier in accordance with regulations adopted by the Commissioner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Pool" means the Maryland Small Employer Health Reinsurance Pool established under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Preexisting condition" means:<section prefix="(1)">a condition existing during a specified period immediately preceding the effective date of coverage, that would have caused an ordinarily prudent person to seek medical advice, diagnosis, care, or treatment; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a condition for which medical advice, diagnosis, care, or treatment was recommended or received during a specified period immediately preceding the effective date of coverage.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Preexisting condition provision" means a provision in a health benefit plan that denies, excludes, or limits benefits for an enrollee for expenses or services related to a preexisting condition.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Reinsuring carrier" means a carrier that participates in the Pool.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Risk-assuming carrier" means a carrier that does not participate in the Pool.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Small employer" means:<section prefix="(1)">an employer described in &#xA7; 15-1203 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">an entity that leases employees from a professional employer organization, coemployer, or other organization engaged in employee leasing and that otherwise meets the description of &#xA7; 15-1203 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Special enrollment period" means a period during which a group health plan shall permit certain individuals who are eligible for coverage, but not enrolled, to enroll for coverage under the terms of the group health benefit plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Standard Plan" means the Comprehensive Standard Health Benefit Plan adopted by the Commission in accordance with &#xA7; 15-1207 of this subtitle and Title 19, Subtitle 1 of the Health - General Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Wellness program" means a program or activity that:<section prefix="(i)">is designed to improve health status and reduce health care costs; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">complies with guidelines developed by the Commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Wellness program" includes programs and activities for:<section prefix="(i)">smoking cessation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">reduction of alcohol misuse;</section><section prefix="(iii)">weight reduction;</section><section prefix="(iv)">nutrition education; and</section><section prefix="(v)">automobile and motorcycle safety.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Wellness benefit" means a benefit that:<section prefix="(1)">includes a bona fide wellness program as defined in &#xA7; 15-509 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(2)">complies with regulations adopted by the Commission.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
