<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gin" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-419" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gin-8-419</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A society may amend, in accordance with their provisions, its laws by:<section prefix="(1)">action of its supreme legislative or governing body at a regular or special meeting of the body; or</section><section prefix="(2)">referendum.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An amendment by referendum may be approved in accordance with the laws of a society, by the vote of:<section prefix="(i)">the society's voting members;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the delegates or representatives of the society's voting members; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the society's local lodges or branches.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An amendment may not be adopted by referendum unless, within 6 months after it is submitted for adoption, a majority of all the voting members of the society have consented to the amendment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An amendment to the laws of a society may not take effect unless the Commissioner approves.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner shall approve an amendment if the Commissioner finds that the amendment was adopted properly and is not inconsistent with the laws of the State or the society.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commissioner's approval or disapproval shall be in writing and mailed to the secretary or equivalent officer of the society at the society's principal office.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Commissioner shall include in a notice of disapproval a statement of the reasons for the disapproval.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Unless disapproved by the Commissioner, an amendment is deemed approved 60 days after it is filed with the Commissioner.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 90 days after approval by the Commissioner, each amendment or a synopsis of it shall be mailed by the society to each member of the society or published in full in the official publication of the society.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The affidavit of an individual authorized by the society to mail an amendment or synopsis, stating that the amendment or synopsis was addressed properly and mailed, is prima facie evidence that the amendment or synopsis was provided to the addressee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A printed copy of the laws as amended, certified by the secretary or equivalent officer of the society, is prima facie evidence of the amendment.</section>
  </text>
</law>
