<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-8-1207</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1207</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Work sharing benefits shall be determined in accordance with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To compute work sharing benefits:<section prefix="(i)">the weekly benefit amount of an affected employee under &#xA7; 8-803 of this title shall be multiplied by the percentage of reduction in the employee's normal weekly work hours under the approved work sharing plan; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the hours for which an affected employee receives holiday or vacation pay shall be counted as hours worked.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The product obtained under paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection shall be rounded to the next lower dollar.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An affected employee is eligible to receive not more than 26 weeks of work sharing benefits during each benefit year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The total amount of benefits payable under Subtitle 8 of this title and work sharing benefits payable under this section may not exceed the total for the benefit year under &#xA7; 8-808(c) of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An allowance for a dependent is payable to an affected employee in accordance with &#xA7; 8-804 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An affected employee who receives a work sharing benefit is not subject to the limitation on benefits for partial unemployment under &#xA7; 8-803(d) of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">During a week in which an individual who otherwise is eligible for benefits does not work for the work sharing employer:<section prefix="(1)">the individual shall be paid benefits in accordance with Subtitle 8 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the week does not count as a week for which a work sharing benefit is received.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">During a week in which an employee earns wages under an approved work sharing plan and other wages, the work sharing benefit shall be reduced by the same percentage that the combined wages are of wages for normal weekly work hours if the other wages:<section prefix="(i)">exceed the wages earned under the approved work sharing plan; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">do not exceed 90% of the wages the individual earns for normal weekly work hours.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The computation under paragraph (1) of this subsection applies regardless of whether the employee earned the other wage from the work sharing employer or another employer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">While an affected employee applies for or receives work sharing benefits, the affected employee is not eligible for:<section prefix="(1)">extended benefits;</section><section prefix="(2)">supplemental federal unemployment compensation; or</section><section prefix="(3)">benefits under any other federal or State program.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
