<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-3-428</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>428</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "complaint" includes a written or oral complaint, claim, or assertion of right by an employee, regarding the payment of wages under this subtitle, that is made to:<section prefix="(1)">the employer or a supervisor, manager, or foreman employed by the employer whether it is made through the employer's internal grievance process or otherwise; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the Commissioner or an authorized representative of the Commissioner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An employer may not:<section prefix="(i)">pay or agree to pay less than the wage required under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">hinder or delay the Commissioner or an authorized representative of the Commissioner in the enforcement of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(iii)">take adverse action against an employee because the employee:<section prefix="1.">makes a complaint that the employee has not been paid in accordance with this subtitle;</section><section prefix="2.">brings an action under this subtitle or a proceeding that relates to the subject of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="3.">has testified in an action under this subtitle or a proceeding related to the subject of this subtitle; or</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">violate any other provision of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Adverse action prohibited under paragraph (1) of this subsection includes:<section prefix="(i)">discharge;</section><section prefix="(ii)">demotion;</section><section prefix="(iii)">threatening the employee with discharge or demotion; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">any other retaliatory action that results in a change to the terms or conditions of employment that would dissuade a reasonable employee from making a complaint, bringing an action, or testifying in an action under this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An employee may not:<section prefix="(1)">make a groundless or malicious complaint to the Commissioner or an authorized representative of the Commissioner;</section><section prefix="(2)">in bad faith, bring an action under this subtitle or a proceeding related to the subject of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(3)">in bad faith, testify in an action under this subtitle or a proceeding related to the subject of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person who violates any provision of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $1,000.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An employer may not be convicted under this section unless the evidence demonstrates that the employer had knowledge of the relevant complaint, testimony, or action for which the prosecution for retaliation is sought.</section>
  </text>
</law>
