<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-509" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-509</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, the liability of an employer under this title is exclusive.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, the compensation provided under this title to a covered employee or the dependents of a covered employee is in place of any right of action against any person.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an employer fails to secure compensation in accordance with this title, a covered employee who has sustained an accidental personal injury, compensable hernia, or occupational disease or, in case of death, the personal representative of the covered employee may:<section prefix="(i)">bring a claim for compensation under this title; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">bring an action for damages.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In an action of a covered employee or personal representative under this subsection, an employer may not plead as a defense that:<section prefix="(i)">the covered employee assumed the risk of employment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the covered employee was contributorily negligent; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the negligence of a fellow servant caused the accidental personal injury, compensable hernia, or occupational disease.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a covered employee is injured or killed as the result of the deliberate intent of the employer to injure or kill the covered employee, the covered employee or, in the case of death, a surviving spouse, child, or dependent of the covered employee may:<section prefix="(1)">bring a claim for compensation under this title; or</section><section prefix="(2)">bring an action for damages against the employer.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
