<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="gle" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-8-629</section_number>
  <catch_line>If an employing unit fails to submit a contribution and employment report under &#xA7; 8-626 of this sub...</catch_line>
  <order_by>629</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If an employing unit fails to submit a contribution and employment report under &#xA7; 8-626 of this subtitle, the Secretary:<section prefix="(1)">may assess the penalty imposed under that section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">shall mail written notice of the assessment to the employer at the last known address of the employer or otherwise deliver the notice.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If an employing unit fails to submit a separation notice under &#xA7; 8-627 of this subtitle, the Secretary:<section prefix="(1)">may assess the penalty imposed under that section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">shall mail written notice of the assessment to the employer at the last known address of the employer or otherwise deliver the notice.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an employing unit submits a report for determination of the amount of contributions due under this title but fails to pay the contributions or interest, the Secretary:<section prefix="(i)">may assess the amount of contributions or interest due on the basis of the information in the report;</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall mail written notice of the assessment to the employing unit at the last known address of the employing unit or otherwise deliver the notice; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">notwithstanding subsection (f) of this section, may make an additional assessment if the report subsequently is found to be incorrect.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an employing unit under an election fails to make a reimbursement payment or pay interest on the payment, the Secretary:<section prefix="(i)">may assess the amount of the payment or interest due; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall mail written notice of the assessment to the employing unit at the last known address of the employing unit or otherwise deliver the notice.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Payments made by checks or other negotiable instruments returned for insufficient funds shall be considered a failure to pay contributions or reimbursements due under this subsection and are subject to an additional penalty of $25.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an employing unit fails to submit a report under an election or for determination of the amount of contributions due on or before the date required by regulation, or if the Secretary determines that a report submitted by an employing unit is incorrect or insufficient, the Secretary shall require by written notice that the employing unit submit a correct and sufficient report.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An employing unit shall submit a correct and sufficient report within 10 days after the Secretary requires it.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If an employing unit fails to comply with paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Secretary shall:<section prefix="(i)">make an assessment on the basis of any information that the Secretary is able to obtain; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">mail written notice of assessment to the employing unit at the last known address of the employing unit or otherwise deliver the notice.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Regardless of whether the time allowed under this title for submitting reports or contributions or making reimbursement payments has expired, if the Secretary believes that collection will be jeopardized by delay, the Secretary immediately may assess a contribution, reimbursement payment, or interest.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary shall mail written notice to an employing unit of an assessment under paragraph (1) of this subsection at the last known address of the employing unit or otherwise deliver the notice.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An assessment under this section is final unless:<section prefix="(i)">within 15 days after the mailing of the assessment an employing unit applies to the Board of Appeals for a hearing; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">on its own motion, the Board of Appeals reduces the contribution or interest.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After a hearing held under this subsection, the Board of Appeals shall:<section prefix="(i)">pass an order to affirm, modify, or set aside the assessment; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">promptly give an employing unit written notice of its decision.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an employing unit fails to pay an assessment under this section, the Secretary may file with the clerk of the circuit court of the county where the employing unit's principal place of business is located and any other county a notice of lien that states:<section prefix="(i)">the name of the employing unit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the address of the employing unit;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the amount of the assessment; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">that the time for filing an appeal for judicial review has expired without an appeal having been taken.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On the filing of a notice of a lien under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the clerk of the court shall:<section prefix="(i)">record and index the lien; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">enter the lien in the judgment docket of the court.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The docket entry shall include:<section prefix="(i)">the name of the person whose property is subject to the lien; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the amount and date of the lien.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On entry in the judgment docket of the information under subsection (e) of this section, the amount of the assessment, court costs, recording costs, and interest that continues to accrue on the assessment are a lien on the real and personal property of the employer against whom the assessment is made in the same manner and having the same force and effect as a judgment lien.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">No property that an employer uses in connection with its business is exempt from the lien.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
