<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-1012" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-1012</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, the Director shall notify an employer by certified mail, return receipt requested, that the license or permit of the employer to do business in the State may be suspended if the employer fails to:<section prefix="(i)">reimburse the Fund for payment of an award under &#xA7; 9-1002 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">pay an assessment under this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Director shall send a copy of the notice to each State, county, or municipal unit that has issued a license or permit to the employer for an activity for which workers' compensation coverage is required by law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 15 days after receipt of the notice, the licensing unit shall provide the employer with the notice and opportunity for a hearing as otherwise may be required by law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If law requires the licensing unit to hold a hearing, the licensing unit shall send written notice of the hearing date to the Director.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The licensing unit shall suspend the license or permit of the employer if the licensing unit finds that the employer has failed to:<section prefix="(i)">reimburse the Fund for payment of an award under &#xA7; 9-1002 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">pay an assessment under this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A suspension of a license or permit under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall continue until the employer:<section prefix="(i)">reimburses the Fund for payment of an award under &#xA7; 9-1002 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">pays the assessment due to the Fund; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">agrees to reimburse the Fund for payment of an award or to pay the assessment due to the Fund in a manner approved by the Board.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
