<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-1111" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-8-1111</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>** CONTINGENCY - IN EFFECT - CHAPTER 170 OF 2011 **<section prefix="(a)">In this section, "net costs" means benefits payable under this subtitle and that are reimbursed dollar for dollar to the Unemployment Insurance Fund established under &#xA7; 8-401 of this title less estimated tax revenue payable in connection with the benefits payable under this subtitle.</section><section prefix="(b)"><section prefix="(1)">There is an Extended Benefits Fund in the State Treasury.</section><section prefix="(2)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section><section prefix="(3)">The Fund may be used only to reimburse net costs for claims filed under &#xA7; 8-1103(f) of this title.</section><section prefix="(4)"><section prefix="(i)">The purpose of the Fund is to reimburse counties and municipal corporations for net costs, as determined by the Secretary.</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Fund may be used to reimburse an association that is voluntary, nonprofit, and controlled and maintained by municipal corporations for net costs, as determined by the Secretary.</section></section><section prefix="(5)">The Treasurer shall hold the Fund separately, and the Secretary shall administer the Fund.</section><section prefix="(6)">The Treasurer shall invest and reinvest the Fund in the same manner as other State funds.</section></section><section prefix="(c)">The Fund shall consist of:<section prefix="(1)">money appropriated in the State budget to the Fund;</section><section prefix="(2)">investment earnings of the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(3)">any other money from any other source accepted for the benefit of the Fund.</section></section><section prefix="(d)">The Secretary shall ensure that the money in the Fund is distributed in the manner that best accomplishes the purpose of the Fund.</section></text>
</law>
