<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-207" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-8-207</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Agricultural work" includes employment for a wage that is performed:<section prefix="(i)">on a farm in connection with:</section><section prefix="(ii)">for the owner, tenant, or other operator of a farm in connection with:</section><section prefix="(iii)">in connection with:</section><section prefix="(iv)">for a farmer, group of farm operators, or cooperative in which farmers are members in drying, freezing, grading, handling, packing, planting, processing, storing or delivering to storage, market, or a carrier for transportation to market any agricultural or horticultural commodity if:</section><section prefix="(v)">on a farm operated for profit if the employment is not in the course of the trade or business of the employer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Farm" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a dairy farm;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a fruit farm;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a furbearing animal farm;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a greenhouse or similar structure used primarily for raising agricultural or horticultural commodities;</section><section prefix="(v)">a nursery;</section><section prefix="(vi)">an orchard;</section><section prefix="(vii)">a plantation;</section><section prefix="(viii)">a poultry farm;</section><section prefix="(ix)">a ranch;</section><section prefix="(x)">a range;</section><section prefix="(xi)">a stock farm; and</section><section prefix="(xii)">a truck farm.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Crew leader" means an individual who:<section prefix="(i)">provides individuals to perform agricultural work for any person;</section><section prefix="(ii)">on behalf of the crew leader or person for whom the agricultural work is performed, pays the individuals for their agricultural work; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">has not entered into a written agreement with the person for whom the agricultural work is performed under which the individuals who perform the agricultural work are designated as employees of that person.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, agricultural work, including agricultural work performed by an alien admitted to the United States to perform agricultural work under &#xA7;&#xA7; 101(a)(15)(h) and 214(c) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, is not covered employment.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Agricultural work is covered employment if performed for a person who:<section prefix="(1)">during a calendar quarter of the current or preceding calendar year, pays cash wages of at least $20,000 to individuals who perform agricultural work; or</section><section prefix="(2)">for a part of a day in each of 20 consecutive or nonconsecutive weeks during the current or preceding calendar year, employs at least 10 individuals in agricultural work, regardless of whether the individuals are employed at the same moment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The crew leader is the employing unit for an individual employed in agricultural work who is not an employee of another employing unit if:<section prefix="(i)">the crew leader holds a valid certificate of registration under the federal Migrant and Seasonal Agricultural Worker Protection Act;</section><section prefix="(ii)">substantially all of the individuals maintain or operate tractors, mechanized harvesting or cropdusting equipment, or any other mechanized equipment that the crew leader provides; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the individual:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the crew leader is not the employing unit for an individual employed in agricultural work under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the person to whom the crew leader provides the individual is the employing unit of the individual.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If under subsection (d)(2) of this section the crew leader is not the employing unit for an individual employed in agricultural work, any cash wages that the crew leader pays to the individual shall be considered cash wages paid by the person who is the employing unit for the individual and to whom the crew leader provides the individual.</section>
  </text>
</law>
