<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-713" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-713</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, within 21 days of the mailing of the notice of the filing of a claim, the employer or its insurer shall:<section prefix="(1)">begin paying temporary total disability benefits; or</section><section prefix="(2)">file with the Commission any issue to contest the claim.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the Commission finds that an employer or insurer has failed, without good cause, to begin paying temporary total disability benefits or to file issues contesting a claim within 21 days of the mailing of the notice of the filing of a claim, the Commission may assess against the employer or insurer a fine not exceeding 20% of the amount of the payment.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the employer or its insurer does not begin paying benefits or file issues within 21 days under subsection (a) of this section, within 30 days of the mailing of the notice of the filing of a claim, the employer or its insurer shall:<section prefix="(1)">begin paying temporary total disability benefits; or</section><section prefix="(2)">file with the Commission any issue to contest the claim.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the Commission finds that an employer or insurer has failed, without good cause, to begin paying temporary total disability benefits or to file issues contesting a claim within 30 days of the mailing of the notice of the filing of a claim, the Commission may assess against the employer or insurer a fine not exceeding 40% of the payment.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commission shall order the employer or insurer to pay a fine assessed under this section to the covered employee.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Subject to &#xA7; 9-714 of this subtitle, payment by an employer or its insurer before an award does not waive the right of the employer or its insurer to contest the claim.</section>
  </text>
</law>
