<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="gle" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-3-904</section_number>
  <catch_line>An employer may not knowingly fail to properly classify an individual who performs work for remunera...</catch_line>
  <order_by>904</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An employer may not knowingly fail to properly classify an individual who performs work for remuneration paid by the employer.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An employer has knowingly failed to properly classify an individual when:<section prefix="(1)">an employer-employee relationship exists as determined under &#xA7; 3-903(c) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the employer has knowingly failed to properly classify the individual as an employee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner shall consider, as strong evidence that the employer did not knowingly fail to properly classify an individual, whether:<section prefix="(1)">before a complaint was filed against the employer or the Commissioner began an investigation of the employer, the employer:<section prefix="(i)">sought and obtained evidence that the individual:<section prefix="1.">is an exempt person; or</section><section prefix="2.">as an independent contractor:</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">provided to the exempt person or independent contractor a written notice as required by &#xA7; 3-914 of this subtitle; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the employer:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">classifies all workers who perform the same or substantially the same tasks for the employer as independent contractors; and</section><section prefix="2.">reports the income of the workers to the Internal Revenue Service as required by federal law; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">has received a determination from the Internal Revenue Service that the individual or a worker who performs the same or substantially the same task as the individual is an independent contractor.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commissioner shall adopt regulations to provide guidance as to what constitutes the evidence relevant to the determination of whether an employer knowingly failed to properly classify an employee.</section>
  </text>
</law>
