<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-681" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-681</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only to a covered employee of a municipal corporation or a county who is subject to &#xA7; 9-503 of this title and the dependents of those covered employees, unless the municipal corporation or county has made an election under &#xA7; 9-683.6 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If there are individuals who were wholly dependent on a deceased covered employee at the time of death resulting from an accidental personal injury or occupational disease, the employer or its insurer shall pay death benefits in accordance with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the death benefit payable under this section shall equal two-thirds of the average weekly wage of the deceased covered employee, but may not:<section prefix="(i)">exceed the State average weekly wage; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">be less than $25.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the average weekly wage of the deceased covered employee was less than $25 at the time of the accidental personal injury or the last injurious exposure to the hazards of the occupational disease, the weekly death benefit payable under this section shall equal the average weekly wage of the deceased covered employee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the employer or its insurer shall pay the weekly death benefit:<section prefix="(1)">for the period of total dependency; or</section><section prefix="(2)">until $45,000 has been paid.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a surviving spouse who was wholly dependent at the time of death continues to be wholly dependent after $45,000 has been paid, the employer or its insurer shall continue to make payments to the surviving spouse at the same weekly rate during the total dependency of the surviving spouse.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a surviving spouse who is wholly dependent at the time of death becomes wholly self-supporting before $45,000 has been paid, the employer or its insurer shall continue to pay death benefits until $45,000 has been paid.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a surviving spouse who is wholly dependent at the time of death becomes partly self-supporting, the employer or its insurer shall continue to make payments to the surviving spouse in accordance with &#xA7; 9-682 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, if a surviving spouse who is wholly dependent remarries, payment to the surviving spouse shall stop on the date of remarriage, even if $45,000 has not been paid.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a surviving spouse who is wholly dependent remarries and does not have dependent children at the time of the remarriage, the employer or its insurer shall continue to make payments to the surviving spouse for 2 years after the date of the remarriage.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">If a surviving child continues to be wholly dependent after the total amount of $45,000 has been paid, the employer or its insurer shall continue to make payments at the same weekly rate during the total dependency of the surviving child.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subsection (j) of this section, if a child who is wholly dependent at the time of death becomes wholly or partly self-supporting, the employer or its insurer shall continue to pay death benefits until $45,000 has been paid.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, the employer or its insurer shall continue to make payments to, or for the benefit of, a surviving child until the child reaches 18 years of age.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The employer or its insurer shall continue to make payments to, or for the benefit of, a child who is 18 years old or older for the period of dependency if the child is:<section prefix="(i)">wholly dependent on the deceased covered employee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">incapable of self-support because of mental or physical disability or other sufficient reason as determined by the Commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The employer or its insurer shall continue to make payments to, or for the benefit of, a child who is 18 years old or older for up to 5 years after reaching the age of 18 if:<section prefix="(i)">the child is attending school on a full-time basis; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the school offers an educational program or a vocational training program, that is accredited or approved by the State Department of Education.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The Commission has continuing jurisdiction to:<section prefix="(1)">determine whether a surviving spouse or child has become wholly or partly self-supporting;</section><section prefix="(2)">suspend or terminate payments of compensation; and</section><section prefix="(3)">reinstate payments of compensation that have been suspended or terminated.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
