<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-602" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-11-602</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Local area" means the local workforce investment areas established in this State under the federal Workforce Investment Act of 1998.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Low income" means not more than 150% of the federal poverty level.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Program" means the Maryland Summer Youth Connection Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Summer" means the period beginning June 1 of each year and ending September 30 of each year.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Maryland Summer Youth Connection Program in the Division.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The purpose of the Program is to provide summer jobs for youth who are not less than 14 years of age and not more than 21 years of age.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Program priorities are to provide jobs for youth who:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Director shall:<section prefix="(1)">make grants in furtherance of the Program objectives to fiscal agents for local areas in accordance with the allocation formulas established under the federal Workforce Investment Act;</section><section prefix="(2)">adopt regulations to carry out the Program; and</section><section prefix="(3)">evaluate the performances of the local areas in carrying out the purposes of the Program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Under the Program, the local areas shall:<section prefix="(1)">develop meaningful and well supervised work experiences in:<section prefix="(i)">public and private nonprofit, community-based sites; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">private for-profit sites, if the experiences developed in the private for-profit sites:</section></section><section prefix="(2)">provide activities to enhance job skills, including basic skills, computer skills, occupational skills, and basic employability skills;</section><section prefix="(3)">provide career-exposure activities, including field trips, guest speakers, job shadowing, aptitude and interest assessment, and college fairs;</section><section prefix="(4)">provide sufficient oversight and monitoring of work sites to ensure a quality experience for each participant;</section><section prefix="(5)">submit a plan to the Director detailing the local area's plan for summer activities; and</section><section prefix="(6)">submit an end-of-summer report.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A local area's allowable Program costs may include:<section prefix="(1)">wages paid to participants in the Program;</section><section prefix="(2)">the costs of supervision;</section><section prefix="(3)">the costs of materials and supplies related to the work provided;</section><section prefix="(4)">reasonable transportation costs to, from, and around the work site;</section><section prefix="(5)">related training costs; and</section><section prefix="(6)">reasonable administrative support costs, not exceeding 10% of the funding granted the local area.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A participating youth shall be paid not less than the federal minimum wage for each hour worked.</section>
  </text>
</law>
