<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="gle" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-8.5-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>On January 1, 2007, and annually thereafter, an employer shall submit on a form and in a manner appr...</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On January 1, 2007, and annually thereafter, an employer shall submit on a form and in a manner approved by the Secretary:<section prefix="(i)">the number of employees of the employer in the State as of 1 day in the year immediately preceding the previous calendar year as determined by the employer on an annual basis;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the amount spent by the employer in the year immediately preceding the previous calendar year on health insurance costs in the State; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the percentage of payroll that was spent by the employer in the year immediately preceding the previous calendar year on health insurance costs in the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary shall adopt regulations that specify the information that an employer shall submit under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The information required shall:<section prefix="(i)">be designated in a report signed by the principal executive officer or an individual performing a similar function; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">include an affidavit under penalty of perjury that the information required under paragraph (1) of this subsection:<section prefix="1.">was reviewed by the signing officer; and</section><section prefix="2.">is true to the best of the signing officer's knowledge, information, and belief.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">When calculating the percentage of payroll under subsection (a)(1)(iii) of this section, an employer may exempt:<section prefix="(1)">wages paid to any employee in excess of the median household income in the State as published by the United States Census Bureau; and</section><section prefix="(2)">wages paid to an employee who is enrolled in or eligible for Medicare.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
