<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-10-113</section_number>
  <catch_line>** IN EFFECT UNTIL OCTOBER 1, 2013 PER CHAPTER 570 OF 2012**...</catch_line>
  <order_by>113</order_by>
  <text>** IN EFFECT UNTIL OCTOBER 1, 2013 PER CHAPTER 570 OF 2012**<section prefix="(a)">The Board:<section prefix="(1)">shall appoint a President of the Fund;</section><section prefix="(2)">shall appoint or employ attorneys to advise and represent the Fund in all legal matters and, where necessary, to sue or defend suits in the name of the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(3)">may employ other staff.</section></section><section prefix="(b)"><section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, employees of the Fund are special appointments.</section><section prefix="(2)">A classified employee of the Fund hired before July 1, 1990 in a nonprofessional or nontechnical position shall remain a member of the classified service or its equivalent in the State Personnel Management System as long as the employee remains in a nonprofessional or nontechnical position with the Fund.</section></section><section prefix="(c)"><section prefix="(1)">The Board shall set compensation for its employees.</section><section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, an employee of the Fund is not subject to any law, regulation, or executive order governing State employee compensation, including furloughs, salary reductions, or any other General Fund cost savings measure.</section></section><section prefix="(d)"><section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to the layoff of an employee because of lack of work.</section><section prefix="(2)">An employee of the Fund may not be permanently removed unless:<section prefix="(i)">written charges are filed;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the employee has an opportunity for a hearing in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">there is cause for removal.</section></section></section></text>
</law>
