<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-736" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-736</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If aggravation, diminution, or termination of disability takes place or is discovered after the rate of compensation is set or compensation is terminated, the Commission, on the application of any party in interest or on its own motion, may:<section prefix="(1)">readjust for future application the rate of compensation; or</section><section prefix="(2)">if appropriate, terminate the payments.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission has continuing powers and jurisdiction over each claim under this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, the Commission may modify any finding or order as the Commission considers justified.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, the Commission may not modify an award unless the modification is applied for within 5 years after the latter of:<section prefix="(i)">the date of the accident;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the date of disablement; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the last compensation payment.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If it is established that a party failed to file an application for modification of an award because of fraud or facts and circumstances amounting to an estoppel, the party shall apply for modification of an award within 1 year after:<section prefix="(i)">the date of discovery of the fraud; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the date when the facts and circumstances amounting to an estoppel ceased to operate.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Failure to file an application for modification in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection bars modification under this title.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
