<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="gle" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-11-502</section_number>
  <catch_line>It is State policy to coordinate all the resources available from federal, State and local governmen...</catch_line>
  <order_by>502</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">It is State policy to coordinate all the resources available from federal, State and local governments, business, labor, and community based organizations to foster and promote a balanced, equitable, and cost-effective employment and training system. To effectuate this policy there shall be consultation between the Governor and the General Assembly in implementing the federal Workforce Investment Act and this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">It is the State's goal to assist its citizens in obtaining gainful employment and in reducing dependence on public assistance and unemployment insurance programs by:<section prefix="(1)">preparing unskilled youth and adults who are economically disadvantaged for entry into the work force;</section><section prefix="(2)">retraining those who have lost jobs or who must upgrade or replace their work skills or both; and</section><section prefix="(3)">providing training and related services, including supportive services for low-income individuals, to increase the employability of those who encounter barriers to employment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">It is also the State's goal to develop a well trained productive work force which meets the needs of a changing economy by:<section prefix="(1)">developing and ensuring maximum utilization of timely statewide labor market information;</section><section prefix="(2)">linking employment and training services with economic development efforts;</section><section prefix="(3)">providing enhanced employment and training capabilities specially designed to meet the needs of business and industry, including industries that utilize advanced technology applications; and</section><section prefix="(4)">encouraging and initiating innovative employment and training strategies.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
