<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="gle" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-807</section_number>
  <catch_line>In any case involving payment from the Subsequent Injury Fund, the Commission or any party in intere...</catch_line>
  <order_by>807</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In any case involving payment from the Subsequent Injury Fund, the Commission or any party in interest shall:<section prefix="(1)">give written notice to the State Treasurer or the attorney for the Subsequent Injury Fund that the Subsequent Injury Fund is or may be involved in the case; and</section><section prefix="(2)">implead the Fund, in writing, as a party.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Subsequent Injury Fund may be impleaded at any stage of the proceedings:<section prefix="(i)">before the Commission; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">on appeal.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Subsequent Injury Fund is impleaded on appeal before a circuit court or the Court of Special Appeals, the court:<section prefix="(i)">as to an impleader filed at least 60 days before the scheduled trial in the circuit court or at least 60 days before the hearing in the Court of Special Appeals, shall:<section prefix="1.">suspend further proceedings; and</section><section prefix="2.">remand the case to the Commission for further proceedings to give the Subsequent Injury Fund an opportunity to defend against the claim; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">as to an impleader filed less than 60 days before the trial in the circuit court or less than 60 days before the hearing in the Court of Special Appeals, may for good cause shown:<section prefix="1.">suspend further proceedings; and</section><section prefix="2.">remand the case to the Commission for further proceedings to give the Subsequent Injury Fund an opportunity to defend against the claim.</section></section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
