<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="gle" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-682</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only to a covered employee of a municipal corporation or a county who is subjec...</catch_line>
  <order_by>682</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only to a covered employee of a municipal corporation or a county who is subject to &#xA7; 9-503 of this title and the dependents of those covered employees, unless the municipal corporation or county has made an election under &#xA7; 9-683.6 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The employer or its insurer shall pay a death benefit in accordance with this section if:<section prefix="(1)">there are no individuals who were wholly dependent on the deceased covered employee at the time of death, but there are individuals who were partly dependent; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a surviving spouse who was wholly dependent on the deceased covered employee at the time of death becomes partly self-supporting.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The maximum weekly death benefit payable under this section shall equal two-thirds of the average weekly wage of the deceased covered employee, but may not exceed two-thirds of the State average weekly wage.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The weekly death benefit payable under this section shall be the percentage of the maximum weekly death benefit under paragraph (1) of this subsection that:<section prefix="(i)">the weekly earnings of the deceased covered employee bears to the combined weekly earnings of the deceased covered employee and the partly dependent individuals; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">does not exceed the maximum weekly death benefit.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the employer or its insurer shall pay the weekly death benefit:<section prefix="(1)">for the period of partial dependency; or</section><section prefix="(2)">until $75,000 has been paid, including any payments made during a period of total dependency under &#xA7; 9-681 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, if a surviving spouse who is partly dependent remarries and does not have dependent children at the time of the remarriage, the employer or its insurer shall make payments to the surviving spouse for 2 years after the date of the remarriage.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The total of the payments made before the remarriage may not exceed $75,000.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, the employer or its insurer shall continue to make payments to, or for the benefit of, a surviving child until the child reaches 18 years of age.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a child who is 18 years old or older remains partly dependent on the deceased covered employee, the employer or its insurer shall continue to make payments in accordance with subsections (c) and (d) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The employer or its insurer shall continue to make payments to, or for the benefit of, a child who is 18 years old or older for up to 5 years after reaching the age of 18 if:<section prefix="(i)">the child is attending school on a full-time basis; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the school offers an educational program or a vocational training program and the program is accredited or approved by the Maryland State Department of Education.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
