<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-6A-09</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>09</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To qualify for registration, a nurse case manager shall be certified as such by the State Board of Nursing.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To qualify for registration, a rehabilitation counselor shall:<section prefix="(1)">have a bachelor's degree from an accredited institution in rehabilitation counseling, human services, psychology, or a related field with at least 1 year of work experience in a human services occupation;</section><section prefix="(2)">have a master's or doctoral degree in rehabilitation counseling, human services, psychology, education, or a related field; or</section><section prefix="(3)">be a certified rehabilitation counselor, certified vocational evaluator, certified disability management specialist, hold an equivalent national certification that is acceptable to the Commission, or have met all of the education and experience requirements to be eligible to be certified.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To qualify for registration, a vocational evaluator shall:<section prefix="(1)">have a bachelor's degree from an accredited institution in vocational evaluation, rehabilitation psychology, human services, education, or a related field with 1 year of work experience in that field;</section><section prefix="(2)">have a master's or doctoral degree in rehabilitation, vocational evaluation, psychology, human services, education, or a related field; or</section><section prefix="(3)">be certified or have met all of the educational and experience requirements to be eligible to be certified in vocational evaluation by the Commission on certification of work adjustment and vocational evaluation specialists, or have met all of the education and experience requirements to be eligible for certification.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition to the requirements of subsections (b) and (c) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">a rehabilitation counselor who has met the education requirements under subsection (b)(1) or (2) of this section to qualify for registration shall work under the administrative supervision of a certified rehabilitation counselor, certified vocational evaluator, certified disability management specialist, certified case manager, or certified rehabilitation registered nurse; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a vocational evaluator who has met the education requirements under subsection (c)(1) or (2) of this section shall work under the administrative supervision of a certified vocational evaluator, certified rehabilitation counselor, certified disability management specialist, certified case manager, or certified rehabilitation registered nurse.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
