<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-11-1008</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1008</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The exercise by the Corporation of the powers conferred by this subtitle is the performance of an essential public function.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Corporation may:<section prefix="(1)">adopt bylaws;</section><section prefix="(2)">adopt a seal;</section><section prefix="(3)">maintain offices at a place in the State that the Corporation designates;</section><section prefix="(4)">apply for and accept loans, grants, or assistance in any form from federal, State, or local governments, colleges or universities, or foundations or other private sources to support workforce education and skills training programs;</section><section prefix="(5)">administer programs that further the goals and objectives of the Corporation;</section><section prefix="(6)">provide grants, funding, and other assistance to State and local agencies, colleges and universities, employers, administrators of labor/management training and upgrading funds, and nonprofit organizations for education and skills training programs;</section><section prefix="(7)">contract with training providers to conduct education and skills training programs;</section><section prefix="(8)">assist training providers by coordinating funding for training programs;</section><section prefix="(9)">make, execute, and enter into any contracts or legal instruments;</section><section prefix="(10)">sue or be sued;</section><section prefix="(11)">seek tax exempt status from the Internal Revenue Service;</section><section prefix="(12)">exercise a power usually possessed by a private corporation in performing similar functions unless to do so would conflict with the laws of the State; and</section><section prefix="(13)">do anything necessary or convenient to carry out the powers granted by this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Corporation may not offer or provide educational or skills training unless the Corporation determines that there are no other training providers available.</section>
  </text>
</law>
