<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-8-812</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>812</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Declining occupation" means an occupation in which:<section prefix="(i)">there is a current lack of employment opportunities in the individual's labor market area for the occupational skills for which the individual is qualified by training and experience; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the lack of employment opportunities is expected to continue for an extended period of time.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Demand occupation" means an occupation in a labor market area where work opportunities are available and qualified applicants are lacking.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Similar stipend" means an amount provided under a program with similar aims, such as providing training to increase employability, and in approximately the same amounts.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Similar stipend" does not include training costs such as payments for tuition and books.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An individual who is entitled to benefits under this title shall be eligible for additional training benefits under this section if the Secretary determines that the individual:<section prefix="(1)">is unemployed;</section><section prefix="(2)">has exhausted all rights to unemployment insurance benefits under federal and State law;</section><section prefix="(3)"><section prefix="(i)">separated from a declining occupation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">has been involuntarily and indefinitely separated from employment as a result of a permanent reduction of operations at the individual's place of employment; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">is enrolled in a training program approved by the Secretary or in a job training program authorized by the Workforce Investment Act of 1998, as amended, that prepares the individual for entry into a demand occupation if the Secretary determines that the individual:<section prefix="(i)">enrolled in the training before the end of the benefit year established with respect to the separation that made the individual eligible for the training benefit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is making satisfactory progress to complete the training; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">is not receiving similar stipends or other allowances for nontraining costs.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The additional weekly training benefit amount shall equal the individual's weekly benefit amount for the most recent benefit year less any deductible income as determined under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The maximum amount of additional training benefits payable to an individual shall be equal to 26 times the individual's average weekly benefit amount for the most recent benefit year.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An individual who is receiving additional training benefits may not be denied those benefits due to the application of &#xA7; 8-903(a)(1)(ii) and (iii) of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Additional training benefits may not be payable for more than 1 year following the end of the benefit year established with respect to the separation that made the individual eligible for additional training benefits.</section>
  </text>
</law>
