<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-1004" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-1004</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If the Fund pays compensation to a covered employee or the dependents of a covered employee, the Fund is subrogated to the rights of the uninsured employer under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the Fund and the uninsured employer both have paid compensation to or on behalf of a covered employee or the dependents of a covered employee, the Fund shall apply any money that it recovers from a third party:<section prefix="(1)">first, to repayment of the award paid by the Fund;</section><section prefix="(2)">second, to any unsatisfied demand for security and to assessments imposed against the uninsured employer under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(3)">finally, to the uninsured employer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the Fund and the uninsured employer both have paid compensation to or on behalf of a covered employee or the dependents of a covered employee, and the Fund recovers money from a third party exceeding the amount of compensation awarded to the covered employee or the dependents and the reasonable and necessary expenses incurred in making the recovery, the Fund shall:<section prefix="(1)">apportion the excess amount between the covered employee or the dependents and the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(2)">use the balance to:<section prefix="(i)">first, reimburse the Fund for its reasonable and necessary expenditures in making the recovery;</section><section prefix="(ii)">second, repay any award paid by the Fund;</section><section prefix="(iii)">third, satisfy any unsatisfied demand for security or assessments imposed against the uninsured employer under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">finally, return the remainder to the uninsured employer.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
