<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="gle" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-11-1015</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "Fund" means the Health Care Personnel Training Fund....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1015</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Fund" means the Health Care Personnel Training Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Health Care Personnel Training Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The purpose of the Fund is to provide grants to training consortiums that involve labor-management partnerships that train and upgrade the qualifications of health care personnel.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department shall administer the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Treasurer shall hold the Fund separately, and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Fund shall consist solely of:<section prefix="(1)">money received from the federal government; and</section><section prefix="(2)">investment earnings of the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Fund may be used only to provide grants to training consortiums that involve labor-management partnerships that train and upgrade the qualifications of health care personnel.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Treasurer shall invest the money of the Fund in the same manner as other State money may be invested.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any investment earnings of the Fund shall be credited to the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Expenditures from the Fund:<section prefix="(1)">may be made only in accordance with the State budget; and</section><section prefix="(2)">shall be made in consultation with the Governor's Workforce Investment Board.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
