<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5.5-118" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-5.5-118</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commissioner shall grant a hearing, if practicable, within 30 days after receipt of a notice that a railroad company or representative of a railroad company submits under &#xA7; 5.5-116 or &#xA7; 5.5-117 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commissioner shall give notice and hold a hearing under this title in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When the Commissioner appoints an administrative law judge to hold a hearing under this section, the administrative law judge shall prepare a record that includes testimony.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A written report that an administrative law judge submits shall become a final order of the Commissioner unless, within 15 working days after submission of the report, the:<section prefix="(i)">Commissioner orders a review of the proceeding; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">railroad company or any affected person submits to the Commissioner a written request for a review of the proceeding.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After review of a proceeding under subsection (b) of this section, with or without a hearing, the Commissioner shall pass an order that, based on findings of fact, affirms, modifies, or vacates the citation or proposed penalty or directs other appropriate relief.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An order of the Commissioner under paragraph (1) of this subsection is final on the date of issuance of the order.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">After an opportunity for a hearing under this section, the Commissioner may pass an order that affirms or modifies a requirement of a citation for abatement of a violation on a showing by the affected railroad company that it:<section prefix="(1)">made a good faith effort to comply with the requirement; and</section><section prefix="(2)">has not complied because of a factor beyond the reasonable control of the railroad company.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
