<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-5-214</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>214</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commissioner shall grant a hearing, if practicable, within 30 days after receipt of a notice that an employer or employee or representative of an employee submits under &#xA7; 5-213 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An employee whom a hearing under this section affects or a representative of the employee may participate as a party in a hearing under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner shall give notice and hold a hearing under this subtitle in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An employer may choose whether a hearing under this section is to be held in:<section prefix="(i)">Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the county where the violation allegedly occurred, in an office that the county provides; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">an office that the Commissioner has designated as a regional office.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The employer shall indicate the choice in the request for a hearing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When the Commissioner appoints a hearing examiner to hold a hearing under this section, the examiner shall prepare a record that includes testimony.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A report that a hearing examiner submits shall become a final order of the Commissioner unless, within 15 work days after submission of the report:<section prefix="(i)">the Commissioner orders a review of the proceeding; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an employee, representative of an employee, or employer whom the report affects submits to the Commissioner a written request for a review of the proceeding.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After review of a proceeding under subsection (e) of this section, with or without a hearing, the Commissioner shall pass an order that, on the bases of findings of fact, affirms, modifies, or vacates the citation or proposed penalty or directs other appropriate relief.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An order of the Commissioner under paragraph (1) of this subsection is final 15 days after passage of the order.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">After an opportunity for a hearing under this section, the Commissioner may pass an order that affirms or modifies a requirement of a citation for abatement of a violation if an employer shows that the employer:<section prefix="(1)">made a good faith effort to comply with the requirement; and</section><section prefix="(2)">has not complied because of a factor beyond the reasonable control of the employer.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
