<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-8-505</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>505</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To enforce this subtitle, a hearing examiner may:<section prefix="(1)">administer an oath;</section><section prefix="(2)">certify to an official act; and</section><section prefix="(3)">take a deposition.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To enforce this subtitle, a hearing examiner may issue a subpoena for the attendance of a witness to testify or for the production of books, correspondence, memoranda, papers, and other records.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A subpoena issued under this subsection shall be served in any manner in which court subpoenas are authorized to be served.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a person fails to comply with a subpoena issued under this subsection, on a complaint filed by the chief hearing examiner or an authorized representative of the chief hearing examiner, the circuit court for the county where the investigation or hearing is conducted or the person is present, resides, or transacts business may pass an order directing compliance with the subpoena or compelling testimony.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A person may not be excused from attending a proceeding and testifying or producing books, correspondence, memoranda, papers, and other records before a hearing examiner in obedience to a subpoena issued under this section on the ground that the testimony or evidence required of the person may tend to incriminate the person or subject the person to a penalty or forfeiture.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">After having claimed the privilege of the person against self-incrimination, a person may not be prosecuted or subjected to any penalty or forfeiture because of any transaction, matter, or thing about which the person is compelled to testify or produce evidence.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A person may be prosecuted and punished for perjury committed in testifying.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
