<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="gle" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-8-614</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following terms have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>614</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following terms have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Knowingly" means having actual knowledge or acting with deliberate ignorance or reckless disregard for the prohibition involved.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Person" means, as defined in &#xA7; 7701(a)(1) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, an individual, trust, estate, partnership, association, company, or corporation.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Trade or business" includes the employer's workforce.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Violates or attempts to violate" includes intent to evade, misrepresentation, or willful nondisclosure.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If, following a transfer of experience, the Secretary determines that the transfer of trade or business occurred primarily or solely to obtain a reduced liability for contributions:<section prefix="(1)">the experience rating accounts of the employing units involved shall be combined into a single account and a single rate assigned to the account; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the employing units shall be subject to the penalties set forth in this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If an employing unit knowingly violates or attempts to violate any provision of this subtitle related to determining the assignment of a contribution rate, the employing unit shall be subject to the following penalties:<section prefix="(1)">the employing unit shall be assigned the highest rate assignable under this subtitle for the rate year during which the violation or attempted violation occurred and the 3 rate years immediately following this rate year; or</section><section prefix="(2)">if the employing unit is already assigned the highest rate for any year, or if the amount of increase in the employing unit's rate would be less than 2% for that year, then a penalty rate of contributions of 2% of taxable wages shall be imposed for that year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a person, who is not an employing unit, violates, attempts to violate, or knowingly advises an employing unit in a manner that results in a violation of this subtitle, the person shall be subject to a civil money penalty of not more than $5,000.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Secretary shall establish procedures to identify the transfer or acquisition of a trade or business for purposes of this section and &#xA7; 8-613 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An employing unit that knowingly violates or attempts to violate any provision of this subtitle is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 1 year or a fine not exceeding $10,000 or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A person, who is not an employing unit, who violates, or attempts to violate, or who knowingly advises an employing unit or a prospective employing unit in a manner that results in a violation of this subtitle, is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 1 year or a fine not exceeding $10,000 or both.</section>
  </text>
</law>
