<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-3-711</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>711</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to an employer that is:<section prefix="(1)">required to inquire into an applicant's or employee's credit report or credit history under federal law or any provision of State law for the purpose of employment;</section><section prefix="(2)">a financial institution that accepts deposits that are insured by a federal agency, or an affiliate or subsidiary of the financial institution;</section><section prefix="(3)">a credit union share guaranty corporation that is approved by the Maryland Commissioner of Financial Regulation; or</section><section prefix="(4)">an entity, or an affiliate of the entity, that is registered as an investment advisor with the United States Securities and Exchange Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, an employer may not use an applicant's or employee's credit report or credit history in determining whether to:<section prefix="(1)">deny employment to the applicant;</section><section prefix="(2)">discharge the employee; or</section><section prefix="(3)">determine compensation or the terms, conditions, or privileges of employment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An employer may request or use an applicant's or employee's credit report or credit history if:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">the applicant has received an offer of employment; and</section><section prefix="2.">the credit report or credit history will be used for a purpose other than a purpose prohibited by subsection (b) of this section; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">the employer has a bona fide purpose for requesting or using information in the credit report or credit history that is:<section prefix="1.">substantially job-related; and</section><section prefix="2.">disclosed in writing to the employee or applicant.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For the purposes of this subsection, a position for which an employer has a bona fide purpose that is substantially job-related for requesting or using information in a credit report or credit history includes a position that:<section prefix="(i)">is managerial and involves setting the direction or control of a business, or a department, division, unit, or agency of a business;</section><section prefix="(ii)">involves access to personal information, as defined in &#xA7; 14-3501 of the Commercial Law Article, of a customer, employee, or employer, except for personal information customarily provided in a retail transaction;</section><section prefix="(iii)">involves a fiduciary responsibility to the employer, including the authority to issue payments, collect debts, transfer money, or enter into contracts;</section><section prefix="(iv)">is provided an expense account or a corporate debit or credit card; or</section><section prefix="(v)">has access to:<section prefix="1.">information, including a formula, pattern, compilation, program, device, method, technique, or process, that:</section><section prefix="2.">other confidential business information.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an employer violates subsection (b) of this section, the applicant or employee may file a written complaint with the Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Commissioner receives a written complaint under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Commissioner shall investigate the matter promptly.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the Commissioner determines that the employer has willfully or negligently violated subsection (b) or (c) of this section, the Commissioner shall try to resolve the matter informally.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the Commissioner is unable to resolve the matter informally, the Commissioner may:<section prefix="(i)">assess a civil penalty of:<section prefix="1.">up to $500 for an initial violation of subsection (b) or (c) of this section; or</section><section prefix="2.">up to $2,500 for a repeat violation of subsection (b) or (c) of this section; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">send an order to pay the civil penalty to the complainant and the employer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Within 30 days after an employer receives an order to pay a civil penalty under paragraph (4) of this section, the employer may request a de novo administrative hearing, subject to the requirements of Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">On receipt of a request for a hearing under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the Commissioner shall schedule a hearing.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If a hearing is not requested under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the order to pay a civil penalty becomes a final order of the Commissioner.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">If an employer fails to comply with a final order to pay a civil penalty, the Commissioner or the complainant may bring an action to enforce the order to pay a civil penalty in the circuit court in the county where the employer or the complainant is located.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This section may not be construed to prohibit an employer from performing an employment-related background investigation that:<section prefix="(1)">includes use of a consumer report or investigative consumer report;</section><section prefix="(2)">is authorized under the federal Fair Credit Reporting Act; and</section><section prefix="(3)">does not involve investigation of credit information.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
