<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-8-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Base period" means:<section prefix="(1)">the first 4 of the last 5 completed calendar quarters immediately preceding the start of the benefit year; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the 4 most recently completed calendar quarters immediately preceding the start of the benefit year only if the individual applying for benefits does not qualify for any benefits under &#xA7; 8-802 of this title using the definition in item (1) of this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Base period employer" means an employing unit who paid wages to an individual during the base period of the individual for covered employment.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Benefit year" means a 1-year period that begins:<section prefix="(1)">on the 1st day of the 1st week for which an individual first files a claim for benefits; or</section><section prefix="(2)">if an individual already has had a benefit year, on the 1st day of the 1st week for which the individual files a claim for benefits after the termination of the preceding benefit year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Benefits" means the money that is payable under this title to an individual who is unemployed.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Board of Appeals" means the Board of Appeals of the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Calendar quarter" means the period of 3 consecutive calendar months ending on March 31, June 30, September 30, or December 31, except as otherwise provided by the Secretary by regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Child support" means an obligation that is enforced under a plan that:<section prefix="(1)">is described in &#xA7; 454 of the Social Security Act; and</section><section prefix="(2)">has been approved by the United States Secretary of Health and Human Services under Part D of Title IV of the Social Security Act.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Child support enforcement unit" means a unit of a state or political subdivision of a state that operates under a plan that:<section prefix="(1)">is described in &#xA7; 454 of the Social Security Act; and</section><section prefix="(2)">has been approved by the United States Secretary of Health and Human Services under Part D of Title IV of the Social Security Act.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Claimant" means an individual who submits a claim for benefits.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Contributions" means money required to be paid to the Unemployment Insurance Fund under &#xA7; 8-607 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Covered employment" means work that an individual performs for an employing unit that is the basis for benefits.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Department" means the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Educational institution" means an institution that offers participants, students, or trainees an organized course of study or training that is academic, technical, trade-oriented, or preparatory for gainful employment in a recognized occupation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Educational institution" includes an institution of higher education.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Employer" means a person or governmental entity who employs at least 1 individual within the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Employing unit" means:<section prefix="(1)">an employer that has at least 1 employee engaged in covered employment for at least part of a day;</section><section prefix="(2)">an employer that has elected to become subject to this title under &#xA7; 8-203 of this title; or</section><section prefix="(3)">an employer that is not otherwise subject to this title but that:<section prefix="(i)">within the current or preceding calendar year, is liable for any federal tax against which credit may be taken for contributions required to be paid into a State unemployment fund; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">as a condition for approval for full credit of contributions against the tax imposed by the Federal Unemployment Tax Act, is required by that Act to be an employing unit.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Governmental entity" means:<section prefix="(1)">a governmental unit as defined in &#xA7; 1-101 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(2)">an instrumentality of:<section prefix="(i)">1 or more states;</section><section prefix="(ii)">1 or more political subdivisions of a state; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">1 or more states and political subdivisions of states.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Hospital" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 19-301 of the Health - General Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Institution of higher education" means an educational institution that:<section prefix="(i)">is a public or other not for profit institution;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is authorized to provide in the State a program of education beyond high school; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">admits as regular students only individuals with a certificate of graduation from high school or a recognized equivalent certificate for:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Institution of higher education" includes each college and university in the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Lower Appeals Division" means the Lower Appeals Division of the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">"Not for profit organization" means an organization that is:<section prefix="(1)">described in &#xA7; 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code; and</section><section prefix="(2)">exempt from income tax under &#xA7; 501(a) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(v)">"Part-time worker" means an individual:<section prefix="(1)">whose availability for work is restricted to part-time work; and</section><section prefix="(2)">who worked at least 20 hours per week in part-time work for a majority of the weeks of work in the base period.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(w)">"Secretary" means the Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(x)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"State" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 1-101 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"State" does not include a territory of the United States unless the territory enacted an unemployment insurance law that complies with the standards adopted by the Secretary of Labor of the United States under the Federal Unemployment Tax Act or Title III of the Social Security Act.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(y)">"Tip" means compensation that:<section prefix="(1)">an individual receives from a customer of the individual's employer while performing covered employment; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is included in a written statement provided to the employer under &#xA7; 6053(a) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(z)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Wages" means all compensation for personal services except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Wages" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a bonus;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a commission;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a tip; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the cash value of all compensation in any medium other than cash.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Wages" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">the amount of any payment made to or on behalf of an employee or any dependent of an employee under a plan or system established by an employing unit that provides for employees generally or for their dependents or for a class of employees and their dependents on account of:</section><section prefix="(ii)">any amount that an employing unit pays for insurance or an annuity or into a fund to provide for a payment described in item (i) of this paragraph;</section><section prefix="(iii)">any payment on account of sickness or accident disability or medical or hospitalization expenses in connection with sickness or accident disability made by the employing unit to or on behalf of an employee at least 6 calendar months after the last calendar month in which the employee worked for the employing unit;</section><section prefix="(iv)">any payment made to or on behalf of an employee or beneficiary of the employee:</section><section prefix="(v)">with respect to compensation paid to an employee for domestic service in a private home of the employing unit or for agricultural labor, the payment by an employing unit without deduction of the tax imposed on an employee under &#xA7; 3101 of the Internal Revenue Code;</section><section prefix="(vi)">any payment required from an employee under a state unemployment insurance law;</section><section prefix="(vii)">compensation paid in any medium other than cash to an employee for service not in the course of the trade or business of the employing unit;</section><section prefix="(viii)">any payment other than vacation or sick pay made to an employee after the month in which the employee becomes 65 years old if the employee did not work for the employing unit in the period for which the payment is made;</section><section prefix="(ix)">any payment, including an amount paid into a fund to provide for any payment by an employing unit to or on behalf of an employee under a plan or system that an employing unit establishes that provides for employees of the employing unit generally or a class or group of employees to supplement unemployment benefits;</section><section prefix="(x)">any payment to an individual as compensation for serving or being called to serve on a jury; or</section><section prefix="(xi)">any payment to an individual as allowance or reimbursement for travel or other expenses incurred on the business of the employer up to the amount of expenses actually incurred and accounted for by the individual to the employer.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(aa)">"Week" means a period of 7 consecutive days, as the Secretary sets by regulation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
