<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-810" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-5-810</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a civil penalty under &#xA7; 5-809 of this subtitle may not exceed:<section prefix="(i)">$7,000 for each violation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">if an employer does not correct a violation within the period allowed for correction, $7,000 for each day that the violation continues.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A civil penalty for a willful or repeated violation of a provision of this title, an order passed under this title, or a regulation adopted to carry out this title may not exceed $70,000 for each violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A civil penalty for a willful violation of a provision of this title, an order passed under this title, or a regulation adopted to carry out this title may not be less than $5,000.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Before the Commissioner assesses a civil penalty under &#xA7; 5-809 of this subtitle, the Commissioner shall consider the appropriateness of the penalty in relation to:<section prefix="(1)">the size of the business of the employer against whom the penalty is to be assessed;</section><section prefix="(2)">the gravity of the violation for which the penalty is to be assessed;</section><section prefix="(3)">the good faith of the employer;</section><section prefix="(4)">the history of violations by the employer;</section><section prefix="(5)">the injury and illness experience of the employer;</section><section prefix="(6)">the existence and quality of a safety and training program;</section><section prefix="(7)">the actual harm to human health including injury or illness;</section><section prefix="(8)">the extent to which the current violation is part of a recurrent pattern of the same or similar type of violation; and</section><section prefix="(9)">the extent to which the existence of the violation was known to the employer but remained not corrected.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
