<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-205" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-5-205</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To carry out a duty or exercise a power under this title, the Commissioner or authorized representative of the Commissioner may:<section prefix="(1)">administer oaths;</section><section prefix="(2)">certify to an official act; or</section><section prefix="(3)">depose witnesses.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To administer or enforce this title, the Commissioner or an authorized representative of the Commissioner may issue a subpoena for the attendance of a witness to testify or the production of books, documents, papers, and records.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a person fails to comply with a subpoena issued under this subsection or fails to testify on any matter on which the person lawfully may be interrogated, on a complaint filed by the Commissioner or an authorized representative of the Commissioner, the circuit court for the county where the person resides or is then present may pass an order directing compliance with the subpoena or compelling testimony.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">After consultation with other appropriate units, the Commissioner shall conduct:<section prefix="(1)">education programs to provide an adequate supply of qualified personnel to carry out this title;</section><section prefix="(2)">informal programs on the importance of and proper use of adequate safety and health equipment; and</section><section prefix="(3)">training programs of personnel engaged in work related to the responsibilities of the Commissioner under this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commissioner shall:<section prefix="(1)">provide for establishment and supervision of programs for the education and training of employers and employees in the recognition, avoidance and prevention of unsafe or unhealthful working conditions in employment covered by this title; and</section><section prefix="(2)">consult with and advise employers and employees and organizations representing employers and employees about effective means to prevent occupational injuries and illnesses.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">After consultation with other appropriate units, the Commissioner shall conduct demonstrations, experiments, and research that relate to:<section prefix="(1)">occupational safety and health; and</section><section prefix="(2)">innovative approaches, methods, and techniques to deal with occupational safety and health problems.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">On the basis of demonstrations, experiments, research, and other available information, the Commissioner shall develop criteria for exposure to toxic materials and harmful physical agents at levels that are safe for various periods of employment, including levels at which no employee will suffer impaired health or functional capacity or diminished life expectancy as a result of work experience.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Commissioner shall:<section prefix="(1)">develop and maintain an effective program of collection, compilation, and analysis of occupational safety and health statistics; and</section><section prefix="(2)">compile accurate statistics on:<section prefix="(i)">work-related illnesses that are disabling, serious, or significant; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">work-related injuries, whether or not involving loss of time from work, other than minor injuries that require only first aid treatment and do not involve loss of consciousness, medical treatment, restriction of motion or work, or transfer to another job.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">With the consent of a governmental unit, the Commissioner may use an employee, facility or service of the governmental unit, with or without reimbursement, to help the Commissioner carry out a function under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner shall inspect, investigate, and review work practices and work sites of each employer and industry that the Workers' Compensation Commission identifies under &#xA7; 9-312(b) of this article for evidence of excessive safety violations.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If evidence of an excessive safety violation is found, the Commissioner shall seek appropriate relief under Subtitle 8 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the Commissioner shall submit to the General Assembly an annual report of investigations under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">Whenever the Commissioner has reason to believe that a person has violated any provision of this title for which criminal prosecution is provided, the Commissioner shall refer the alleged violation to the State's Attorney of the county where the violation allegedly occurred or the person resides.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The Commissioner shall:<section prefix="(1)">assist employers in carrying out their responsibilities under this title; and</section><section prefix="(2)">recommend and suggest to employers and groups of employers methods and procedures to develop safety programs to carry out those responsibilities.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">On behalf of the Commissioner, the Safety Engineering and Education Service shall:<section prefix="(1)">investigate and analyze the causes of industrial and occupational accidents; and</section><section prefix="(2)">plan and conduct courses and programs that the service designs to reduce accidents.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">In addition to any duties set forth elsewhere, each safety inspector shall be responsible for enforcement of safety codes in construction and any other hazardous industry in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">In addition to any other authority the Commissioner may exercise under this title, if, as a result of the exercise of the Commissioner's authority under the provisions of this title, the Commissioner has reason to believe that a health care provider required under the Health Occupations Article to comply with the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention's guidelines on universal precautions is not complying with those provisions, the Commissioner shall refer that suspected violation to the health care provider's licensing board.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to any other authority the Commissioner may exercise under this title, if, as a result of the exercise of the Commissioner's authority under the provisions of this title, the Commissioner has reason to believe that an employee or member of the medical staff involved in patient care services of the hospital, related institution, freestanding medical facility, or freestanding birthing center is not complying with the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention's guidelines on universal precautions, the Commissioner shall refer that suspected violation to the chief executive officer of the hospital, related institution, freestanding medical facility, or freestanding birthing center.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to any other authority the Commissioner may exercise under this title, if, as a result of the exercise of the Commissioner's authority under the provisions of this title, the Commissioner has reasons to believe that a hospital, related institution, freestanding medical facility, or freestanding birthing center is demonstrating a willful and systematic disregard for the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention's guidelines on universal precautions, the Commissioner shall refer that suspected violation to:<section prefix="(i)">the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the chief executive officer of the hospital, related institution, freestanding medical facility, or freestanding birthing center.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
