<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="gle" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-319</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Workers' Compensation Fund that consists of:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>319</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Workers' Compensation Fund that consists of:<section prefix="(1)">all revenue received through the imposition and collection of the assessment tax under &#xA7; 9-316 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">income from investments that the Treasurer makes for the State Fund; and</section><section prefix="(3)">any other fee, examination assessment, or revenue received by the Commission under this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, the Commission shall pay all fines and penalties collected by the Commission under this title into the General Fund of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The purpose of the Fund is to pay:<section prefix="(1)">the costs and expenses incurred by the Commission that are related to the operation of the Commission, including:<section prefix="(i)">expenditures authorized under this title;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the cost of State employees specifically assigned to the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">reasonable expenses incurred by the Advisory Committee on the budget of the Commission established under &#xA7; 9-317 of this subtitle; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">any other expense authorized in the State budget, including costs specified under &#xA7; 9-315 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">All the costs and expenses of the Commission shall be included in the State budget.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any expenditures from the Fund to cover costs and expenses of the Commission may only be made:<section prefix="(i)">with an appropriation from the Fund approved by the General Assembly in the annual State budget; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">by the budget amendment procedure provided for in &#xA7; 7-209 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If, in any given fiscal year, the amount of the revenue collected by the Commission and deposited into the Fund exceeds the actual appropriation for the Commission, plus an additional 1 percent provision for unanticipated expenditures over the actual appropriation for the Commission, the excess amount shall be carried forward within the Fund for the purpose of reducing the assessment fee imposed by the Commission for the following fiscal year.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If, in any given year, the amount of revenue collected by the Commission and deposited into the Fund is insufficient to cover the expenditures of the Commission because of an unforeseen emergency and expenditures are made in accordance with the budget amendment procedure provided for in &#xA7; 7-209 of the State Finance and Procurement Article, an additional assessment for the expenditures may be made.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Treasurer is the custodian of the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Treasurer shall deposit payments received from the Commission into the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund is a continuing, nonlapsing fund and is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article, and may not be deemed a part of the General Fund of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless otherwise provided by law, no part of the Fund may revert or be credited to:<section prefix="(i)">the General Fund of the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a special fund of the State.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
