<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-8-612</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>612</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, on the basis of the earned rating record of an employing unit that qualifies for an earned rate of contribution under &#xA7; 8-610 of this subtitle, the Secretary shall compute to the 4th decimal place a benefit ratio for the employing unit in accordance with subsection (b) or (c) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary may not assign an earned rate of contribution that is less than 0.3% or more than 13.5%.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For an employing unit that qualifies under &#xA7; 8-610(a)(2) of this subtitle, the Secretary shall compute a benefit ratio by:<section prefix="(1)">adding the regular, work sharing, and extended benefits that were chargeable to the earned rating record of the employing unit and paid during the 3 rating years immediately preceding the computation date; and</section><section prefix="(2)">dividing the figure determined under item (1) of this subsection by the total of the reported taxable wages for the same period.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For an employing unit that qualifies under &#xA7; 8-610(a)(3) of this subtitle, the Secretary shall compute a benefit ratio for the employing unit by:<section prefix="(1)">adding the regular, work sharing, and extended benefits that were chargeable to the earned rating record of the employing unit and paid during the period beginning with the 1st day of the calendar quarter in which the employing unit first became subject to this title and ending on the June 30 immediately preceding the computation date; and</section><section prefix="(2)">dividing the figure obtained under item (1) of this subsection by the total of the reported taxable wages for the same period.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For any calendar year beginning on or after January 1, 2006, when the Unemployment Insurance Fund balance on September 30 of the immediately preceding calendar year exceeds 5% of the total taxable wages in covered employment for the 4 completed calendar quarters immediately preceding September 30, the Table of Rates in this paragraph of this subsection shall apply.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For any calendar year beginning on or after January 1, 2006, when the Unemployment Insurance Fund balance on September 30 of the immediately preceding calendar year exceeds 4.5%, but is not in excess of 5% of the total taxable wages in covered employment for the 4 completed calendar quarters immediately preceding September 30, the Table of Rates in this paragraph of this subsection shall apply.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For any calendar year beginning on or after January 1, 2006, when the Unemployment Insurance Fund balance on September 30 of the immediately preceding calendar year exceeds 4%, but is not in excess of 4.5% of the total taxable wages in covered employment for the 4 completed calendar quarters immediately preceding September 30, the Table of Rates in this paragraph of this subsection shall apply.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">For any calendar year beginning on or after January 1, 2006, when the Unemployment Insurance Fund balance on September 30 of the immediately preceding calendar year exceeds 3.5%, but is not in excess of 4% of the total taxable wages in covered employment for the 4 completed calendar quarters immediately preceding September 30, the Table of Rates in this paragraph of this subsection shall apply.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">For any calendar year beginning on or after January 1, 2006, when the Unemployment Insurance Fund balance on September 30 of the immediately preceding calendar year exceeds 3%, but is not in excess of 3.5% of the total taxable wages in covered employment for the 4 completed calendar quarters immediately preceding September 30, the Table of Rates in this paragraph of this subsection shall apply.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">For any calendar year beginning on or after January 1, 2006, when the Unemployment Insurance Fund balance on September 30 of the immediately preceding calendar year is not in excess of 3% of the total taxable wages in covered employment for the 4 completed calendar quarters immediately preceding September 30, the Table of Rates in this paragraph of this subsection shall apply.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">For the purpose of making any computation under this section:<section prefix="(1)">money that has been credited to the account of the State in the Unemployment Trust Fund under &#xA7; 903 of the Social Security Act and that has been appropriated for expenses of administration, whether or not withdrawn from the account, shall be excluded from the total amount available for benefits in the Unemployment Insurance Fund; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the total amount available for benefits in the Unemployment Insurance Fund includes:<section prefix="(i)">money receivable by the Unemployment Insurance Fund as federal reimbursement for shareable benefits under the Federal-State Extended Unemployment Compensation Act of 1970;</section><section prefix="(ii)">all advance payments made to the Unemployment Insurance Fund on behalf of eligible employing units who elect to make reimbursement payments; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">money receivable by the Unemployment Insurance Fund from an eligible employing unit who elects to make reimbursement payments.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
