<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="gle" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-206</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to subsection (b) of this section, an officer of a corporation or a member of a limited liab...</catch_line>
  <order_by>206</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to subsection (b) of this section, an officer of a corporation or a member of a limited liability company is a covered employee if the officer or member provides a service for the corporation or limited liability company for monetary compensation.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An individual who otherwise would be a covered employee under this section may elect to be exempt from coverage if:<section prefix="(1)">the individual:<section prefix="(i)">is an officer of a close corporation, as defined in &#xA7; 4-101(b) of the Corporations and Associations Article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">is an officer of a close corporation, as defined under the laws of the jurisdiction in which the corporation is incorporated;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">subject to subsection (c)(3) of this section, the individual is an officer of a corporation, other than a close corporation;</section><section prefix="(3)">the individual:<section prefix="(i)">is an officer of a corporation that earns at least 75% of its income from farm operations; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">owns at least 20% of the outstanding capital stock of the corporation;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">the individual:<section prefix="(i)">is an officer of a professional corporation, as defined in &#xA7; 5-101(c) or (f) of the Corporations and Associations Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">owns at least 20% of the outstanding capital stock of the corporation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">performs for the corporation a professional service, as defined in &#xA7; 5-101(g) of the Corporations and Associations Article; or</section></section><section prefix="(5)">the individual:<section prefix="(i)">is a member of a limited liability company, as defined in &#xA7; 4A-101(l) of the Corporations and Associations Article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">owns at least 20% of the outstanding interests in profits of the limited liability company.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A corporation or limited liability company shall submit to the Commission and to the insurer of the corporation or limited liability company a written notice that names the individual who has made an election to be exempt under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An election under subsection (b)(1) or (b)(4) of this section is not effective until a corporation or limited liability company complies with this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">No more than five officers of a corporation described in subsection (b)(2) of this section may elect to be exempt under subsection (b)(2) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commission shall adopt regulations to carry out this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
