<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-206" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-8-206</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Work is not covered employment when performed by a licensed barber or licensed cosmetologist who leases a chair or booth from a holder of a barbershop permit, a beauty salon permit, or an owner-manager permit who operates a barbershop or beauty salon, if the Secretary is satisfied that:<section prefix="(1)">the barber or cosmetologist as lessee and the permit holder have entered into a written lease that is in effect;</section><section prefix="(2)">the lessee pays a stipulated amount for use of the chair or booth and is not required to make any further accounting of income to the permit holder;</section><section prefix="(3)">the lessee has access to the premises at all hours and may set personal work hours and prices; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the lease expressly states that the lessee knows:<section prefix="(i)">of the responsibility to pay State and federal income taxes and make contributions to Social Security for self-employment; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">that the work is not covered employment.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Work that a direct seller performs is not covered employment if the Secretary is satisfied that:<section prefix="(1)">the direct seller is engaged in the trade or business of selling consumer products:<section prefix="(i)">in the home or at any other location outside of a permanent retail establishment; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">to a buyer on a buy-sell basis, a deposit-commission basis, or any similar basis for resale by the buyer or any other person in the home or at any other location outside of a permanent retail establishment;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the direct seller and the person for whom the work is performed have entered into a written agreement that is currently in effect;</section><section prefix="(3)">substantially all of the compensation for the employment is related directly to sales or other output, including the performance of a service, rather than to the number of hours worked; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the written agreement states that the direct seller will not be treated as an employee for the purpose of State and federal income taxes with respect to the employment performed under the agreement.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Work that an individual performs is not covered employment if the Secretary is satisfied that the individual:<section prefix="(1)">is engaged in the trade or business of delivering or distributing newspapers or shopping news, including any services directly related to the delivery or distribution of newspapers or shopping news; and</section><section prefix="(2)">meets the requirements for a direct seller under subsection (b)(2), (3), and (4) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "messenger service business" means a business that:<section prefix="(i)">principally and primarily offers and provides to the public or commercial establishments expedited, time critical, and same day as requested delivery service;</section><section prefix="(ii)">does not make, produce, sell, or distribute what it delivers; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">does not have an exclusive contractual delivery arrangement with an individual or a commercial establishment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Work that a messenger service driver performs for a person who is engaged in the messenger service business is not covered employment if the Secretary is satisfied that:<section prefix="(i)">the driver and the person who is engaged in the messenger service business have entered into a written agreement that is currently in effect;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the written agreement under item (i) of this paragraph does not prohibit the driver from performing for more than one person who is engaged in the messenger service business;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the driver is free to accept or reject delivery jobs from the person who is engaged in the messenger service business;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the driver personally provides the vehicle;</section><section prefix="(v)">compensation is by commission only;</section><section prefix="(vi)">the driver may set personal work hours; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">the written agreement states expressly and prominently that the driver knows:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A messenger service driver for a messenger service business whose work is not covered employment under paragraph (2) of this subsection may deliver to the public or commercial establishments on foot, by bicycle, or by motor vehicle:<section prefix="(i)">individually addressed mail, messages, and documents in paper or magnetic format; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">emergency medical supplies, records, parcels, or similar items if the messenger service business provides to the Secretary evidence of a worker status determination from the Internal Revenue Service or other evidence that the messenger service driver is excluded from coverage under the Federal Unemployment Tax Act.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Work is not covered employment when performed by a taxicab driver who uses a taxicab or taxicab equipment of a taxicab business that is carried on by the holder of a taxicab permit if the Secretary is satisfied that:<section prefix="(1)">the driver and permit holder have entered into a written agreement that is currently in effect for the use of the taxicab or taxicab equipment;</section><section prefix="(2)">the driver pays a stipulated amount for the use of the taxicab or taxicab equipment and is not required to make any further accounting to the permit holder;</section><section prefix="(3)">the driver has access to the taxicab or taxicab equipment at all hours and, subject to the Public Utilities Article, may set personal work hours and places; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the agreement states expressly that the driver knows:<section prefix="(i)">of the responsibility to pay State and federal income taxes; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">that the work is not covered employment.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This subsection applies to an individual who is an owner operator of:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">This subsection does not apply to an individual who is an owner operator of a vehicle registered as a Class T (tow truck) vehicle under &#xA7; 13-920 of the Transportation Article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Work is not covered employment when performed by an owner operator if the Secretary is satisfied that:<section prefix="(i)">the owner operator and a motor carrier have entered into a written agreement that is currently in effect for permanent or trip leasing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">under the agreement:</section><section prefix="(iii)">for federal tax purposes, the owner operator qualifies as an independent contractor; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the owner operator:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Work is not covered employment when performed by a home worker if the Secretary is satisfied that:<section prefix="(1)">the work is performed according to specifications furnished by the person for whom the services are performed;</section><section prefix="(2)">the work is performed on textiles furnished by the person for whom the services are performed; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the textiles must be returned to the person for whom the services are performed or that person's designee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Officiating services" means:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)"/>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Work that consists of officiating services performed by a recreational sports official is not covered employment.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
