<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5.5-123" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-5.5-123</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commissioner shall impose civil penalties under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For the purpose of this subsection, a violation is considered to be a serious violation if there is substantial probability that death or serious physical harm could result from a condition that exists or a practice, means, method, or operation that is in use by the railroad company, unless the railroad company did not know and with the exercise of reasonable diligence could not have known of the violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner may assess a civil penalty against a railroad company that:<section prefix="(i)">willfully violates this title, an order passed under this title, or a regulation or health and safety standard adopted to carry out this title and the violation is specifically determined to be of a serious nature, an amount not exceeding $10,000 for each violation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">receives a citation for a violation of a provision of this title, an order passed under this title, or a regulation or health and safety standard adopted to carry out this title and the violation is specifically determined to be of a serious nature, an amount not exceeding $1,000 for each violation; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">receives a citation for a violation of a provision of this title, an order passed under this title, or a regulation or health and safety standard adopted to carry out this title and the violation is specifically determined not to be of a serious nature, an amount not exceeding $500 for each violation.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner may assess a civil penalty not exceeding $100 against a railroad company for each violation of a requirement for posting imposed under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner may assess a civil penalty of not less than $100 and not exceeding $500 against a railroad company that violates a maintenance requirement for yard track margins and sidetracks for employee safety under &#xA7; 5.5-111 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each day of noncompliance with any order that the Commissioner issues under &#xA7; 5.5-111 of this title shall be considered a separate violation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commissioner shall assess against an agent of a railroad company a civil penalty of $100 for each employee that the agent requires to ride more than 5 miles without a seat as required under &#xA7; 5.5-110(a) of this title, regardless of whether the employee is in active service.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If a railroad company does not correct a violation for which a citation has been issued within the period set for correction in accordance with &#xA7; 5.5-116 of this title, the Commissioner may impose a civil penalty not exceeding $100 for each day that the violation continues.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Before the Commissioner assesses a civil penalty under this section, the Commissioner shall consider the appropriateness of the penalty in relation to:<section prefix="(1)">the size of the railroad company;</section><section prefix="(2)">the gravity of the violation for which the penalty is to be assessed;</section><section prefix="(3)">the good faith of the railroad company; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the history of violations by the railroad company.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each civil penalty under this section shall be payable into the General Fund of the State 90 days after the violation becomes final and nonreviewable.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner shall reduce the penalty by 50% if during the 90-day period:<section prefix="(i)">the railroad company had no reportable accidents attributable to a State or federal regulation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the railroad has not committed a willful or serious violation as described in this section.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
