<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="gle" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-5-809</section_number>
  <catch_line>For the purpose of this subsection, a violation is considered to be a serious violation if there is ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>809</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For the purpose of this subsection, a violation is considered to be a serious violation if there is a substantial probability that death or serious physical harm could result from a condition that exists or a practice, means, method, operation, or process that has been adopted or is in use, unless the employer did not and with the exercise of reasonable diligence could not know of the violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner shall assess a civil penalty against an employer who receives a citation for a serious violation of this title, an order passed under this title, or a regulation adopted to carry out this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commissioner shall assess a civil penalty against an employer who violates a requirement for posting imposed under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner may assess a civil penalty against an employer who:<section prefix="(1)">willfully or repeatedly violates this title, an order passed under this title, or a regulation adopted to carry out this title; or</section><section prefix="(2)">receives a citation for a violation of a provision of this title, an order passed under this title, or a regulation adopted to carry out this title and there is a specific determination that the violation is not of a serious nature.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commissioner may assess a civil penalty against an employer who does not correct a violation for which a citation is issued within the period set under this title for correction.</section>
  </text>
</law>
