<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-809" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-8-809</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary may recover benefits paid to a claimant if the Secretary finds that the claimant was not entitled to the benefits because:<section prefix="(1)">the claimant was not unemployed;</section><section prefix="(2)">the claimant received or retroactively was awarded wages; or</section><section prefix="(3)">due to a redetermination of an original claim by the Secretary, the claimant is disqualified or otherwise ineligible for benefits.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the Secretary finds that a claimant knowingly made a false statement or representation or knowingly failed to disclose a material fact to obtain or increase a benefit or other payment under this title, in addition to disqualification of the claimant, the Secretary may recover from the claimant:<section prefix="(1)">all benefits paid to the claimant for each week for which the false statement or representation was made or for which the claimant failed to disclose a material fact; and</section><section prefix="(2)">interest of 1.5% per month on the amount accruing from the date that the claimant is notified by the Secretary that the claimant was not entitled to benefits received.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the Secretary decides to recover benefits from a claimant under subsection (a) or (b) of this section, the Secretary shall notify the claimant of:<section prefix="(1)">the amount to be recovered;</section><section prefix="(2)">the weeks for which benefits were paid; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the provision of this title under which the Secretary determined that the claimant was ineligible for benefits.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary may recover an amount under subsection (a) or (b) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">by deduction from benefits payable to the claimant in the future, excluding interest due pursuant to subsection (b)(2) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(2)">in the manner provided in &#xA7; 8-630 of this title for the collection of past due contributions.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary may reconsider a decision to recover benefits under subsection (a) of this section within 1 year after the date that the decision was made.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary may not make a determination to recover benefits under subsection (a) or (b) of this section later than 3 years after the date that the benefits were paid to the claimant.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If an amount has not been recovered within 5 years after the date of the decision to recover the amount, the Secretary may consider the amount uncollectible.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the Secretary may recover, under a governmental offset agreement, an overpayment of benefits paid to any claimant under:<section prefix="(1)">the unemployment insurance law of another state; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a federal unemployment insurance benefit program.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
