<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-10-102</section_number>
  <catch_line>** TAKES EFFECT OCTOBER 1, 2013 PER CHAPTER 570 OF 2012 **...</catch_line>
  <order_by>102</order_by>
  <text>** TAKES EFFECT OCTOBER 1, 2013 PER CHAPTER 570 OF 2012 **<section prefix="(a)"><section prefix="(1)">There is an Injured Workers' Insurance Fund.</section><section prefix="(2)">The Fund is an instrumentality of the State.</section></section><section prefix="(b)">On and after October 1, 2013, the Company, and not the Fund, shall serve as the workers' compensation insurer of last resort for workers' compensation insurance.</section><section prefix="(c)">On and after October 1, 2013, the Fund:<section prefix="(1)">shall continue to exist; but</section><section prefix="(2)">may not issue new policies or otherwise engage in the business of insurance.</section></section><section prefix="(d)">On and after October 1, 2013, the Fund may continue to be the third party administrator for the State's Self-Insured Workers' Compensation Program for State Employees under a contract with the State.</section><section prefix="(e)"><section prefix="(1)">Subject to subsection (f) of this section, in the operation of the Company, the Company shall utilize employees of the Company.</section><section prefix="(2)">In the operation of the Fund, the Fund shall utilize employees of the Fund.</section><section prefix="(3)">The Fund shall:<section prefix="(i)">maintain a payroll and human resources system; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">be responsible for paying:<section prefix="1.">the employer portion of any payroll or other taxes and retirement or pension contributions for employees of the Fund; and</section><section prefix="2.">for any health or other employee benefits that are available to employees of the Fund.</section></section></section></section><section prefix="(f)"><section prefix="(1)">Employees of the Fund may be assigned to perform functions of the Company under a contract between the Fund and the Company.</section><section prefix="(2)">The Company and the Fund shall annually execute an agreement that lists the employees of the Fund who have been assigned to perform duties on behalf of the Company.</section><section prefix="(3)">The agreement shall:<section prefix="(i)">specify the employees who will be utilized by the Company and the Fund;</section><section prefix="(ii)">provide that, except with respect to assets necessary for the Fund to perform its duties under this subtitle, all assets and liabilities of the Fund are the assets and liabilities of the Company; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">be filed with the Administration.</section></section></section></text>
</law>
