<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-902" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-11-902</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Education and Workforce Training Coordinating Council for Correctional Institutions shall develop and recommend an educational and workforce training program for each correctional institution in the Division of Correction. The programs shall meet the special needs and circumstances of the inmates in each correctional institution.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Council shall adopt regulations for all correctional institutions in the Division of Correction for the implementation of a mandatory education program for all inmates who fail to attain a minimum educational standard as set forth in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The regulations adopted by the Council shall:<section prefix="(i)">require that the educational standard shall be the attainment of a General Educational Development (GED) diploma or a verified high school diploma;</section><section prefix="(ii)">apply only to any inmate who:</section><section prefix="(iii)">require any inmate who is not exempted under item (ii)3 of this paragraph to participate in:</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Division of Correction shall report to the Parole Commission the academic progress of an inmate in the mandatory education program.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Council shall adopt regulations for all correctional institutions in the Division of Correction for the implementation of a mandatory workforce skills training program for all inmates as provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The regulations shall apply only to an inmate who:<section prefix="(i)">has 18 months or more remaining to be served before a mandatory supervision release date; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is not exempted due to a medical, developmental, or learning disability.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Division of Correction shall report to the Parole Commission the academic progress of an inmate in the mandatory workforce skills training program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">On or before October 30 of each year, the Council shall report its activities to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Council shall actively advocate and promote the interests of educational programs and workforce skills training opportunities in correctional institutions.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Council shall seek to ensure that a quality education, equal educational opportunity, and workforce skills training are available to all inmates at correctional institutions.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Council, on a regular basis, shall review the educational and workforce skills training programs at correctional institutions to ensure that the unique educational and training needs of the populations of the correctional institutions are being satisfactorily met.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Council shall include in its review:<section prefix="(i)">curriculum guides;</section><section prefix="(ii)">courses of study;</section><section prefix="(iii)">resource materials;</section><section prefix="(iv)">textbooks;</section><section prefix="(v)">supplementary readers;</section><section prefix="(vi)">materials of instruction;</section><section prefix="(vii)">visual and auditory aids;</section><section prefix="(viii)">supplies;</section><section prefix="(ix)">teacher performance; and</section><section prefix="(x)">other teaching aids.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Based on its review, the Council shall recommend and advocate improvements to the educational and workforce skills training programs at correctional institutions.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
