<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-709" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-709</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, if a covered employee suffers an accidental personal injury, the covered employee, within 60 days after the date of the accidental personal injury, shall file with the Commission:<section prefix="(i)">a claim application form; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the covered employee was attended by a physician chosen by the covered employee, the report of the physician.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A claim application form filed under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall include an authorization by the claimant for the release, to the claimant's attorney, the claimant's employer, and the insurer of the claimant's employer, or an agent of the claimant's attorney, the claimant's employer, or the insurer of the claimant's employer, of medical information that is relevant to:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An authorization under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless excused by the Commission under paragraph (2) of this subsection, failure to file a claim in accordance with subsection (a) of this section bars a claim under this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission may excuse a failure to file a claim in accordance with subsection (a) of this section if the Commission finds:<section prefix="(i)">that the employer or its insurer has not been prejudiced by the failure to file the claim; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">another sufficient reason.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection, if a covered employee fails to file a claim within 2 years after the date of the accidental personal injury, the claim is completely barred.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a covered employee is disabled due to an accidental personal injury from ionizing radiation, the covered employee shall file a claim with the Commission within 2 years after:<section prefix="(1)">the date of disablement; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the date when the covered employee first knew that the disablement was due to ionizing radiation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If it is established that a failure to file a claim in accordance with this section was caused by fraud or by facts and circumstances amounting to an estoppel, the covered employee shall file a claim with the Commission within 1 year after:<section prefix="(i)">the date of the discovery of the fraud; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the date when the facts and circumstances that amount to estoppel ceased to operate.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Failure to file a claim in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection bars a claim under this title.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
