<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-670</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>670</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this Part XI of this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Disabled" means rendered unable as the result of an accidental personal injury or an occupational disease to perform work for which the person was previously qualified.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Suitable gainful employment" means employment, including self-employment, that restores the disabled covered employee, to the extent possible, to the level of support at the time of:<section prefix="(1)">if an accidental personal injury, the accidental personal injury; or</section><section prefix="(2)">if an occupational disease, disablement from the occupational disease.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Vocational assessment" means:<section prefix="(1)">collecting and analyzing each of the economic, educational, legal, medical, social, and vocational circumstances of a disabled covered employee, including the present mental and physical ability of the covered employee to participate in vocational rehabilitation services; and</section><section prefix="(2)">determining the appropriate vocational rehabilitation services reasonably necessary to return the disabled covered employee to suitable gainful employment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Vocational rehabilitation services" means professional services reasonably necessary during or after or both during and after medical treatment to enable a disabled covered employee, as soon as practical, to secure suitable gainful employment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Vocational rehabilitation services" includes:<section prefix="(i)">coordination of medical services;</section><section prefix="(ii)">vocational assessment;</section><section prefix="(iii)">vocational evaluation;</section><section prefix="(iv)">vocational counseling;</section><section prefix="(v)">vocational rehabilitation plan development;</section><section prefix="(vi)">vocational rehabilitation plan monitoring;</section><section prefix="(vii)">vocational rehabilitation training;</section><section prefix="(viii)">job development; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">job placement.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
