<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-4-322</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>322</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person who is charged with constructive criminal contempt for a violation of injunctive relief in a case that involves or grows out of a labor dispute is entitled:<section prefix="(1)">to pretrial release as provided for defendants in criminal cases;</section><section prefix="(2)">to notice of the accusation;</section><section prefix="(3)">to a reasonable time to make a defense; and</section><section prefix="(4)">except for an officer of the court who is charged with disobedience, misbehavior, or other misconduct in respect to process of the court, on demand, to a speedy and public trial by an impartial jury from the judicial district where the contempt is alleged to have been committed.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whenever the charge of constructive criminal contempt arises from an attack on the character or conduct of a judge, the defendant is entitled to recusal of the judge if the defendant files a demand for recusal before the hearing on the charge.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Whenever a defendant files a timely demand for recusal:<section prefix="(i)">the judge may not proceed further; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the presiding judge of the court shall designate another judge as a replacement.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who is guilty of constructive criminal contempt in a labor case is subject to a fine not exceeding $100 or imprisonment not exceeding 15 days or both.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who is imprisoned for failure to pay a fine imposed under this subsection shall be discharged:<section prefix="(i)">after 15 days; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if also imprisoned for a definite period, 15 days after the end of the period.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
