<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-806</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>806</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall impose an assessment of 6.5%, payable to the Subsequent Injury Fund, on:<section prefix="(i)">each award against an employer or its insurer for permanent disability or death, including awards for disfigurement and mutilation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, each amount payable by an employer or its insurer under a settlement agreement approved by the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">each amount payable under item (i) or (ii) of this paragraph by the Property and Casualty Guaranty Corporation on behalf of an insolvent insurer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The amount of medical benefits specified in a formal set-aside allocation that is part of an approved settlement agreement shall be excluded from the assessment imposed by the Commission under paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection if:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">the amount of medical benefits is in excess of $50,000; and</section><section prefix="2.">the payment of medical benefits by the employer or its insurer is directly to an authorized insurer that provides periodic payments to the covered employee pursuant to a single premium annuity; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">the amount of medical benefits is in any amount; and</section><section prefix="2.">the payment of medical benefits by the employer or its insurer is to an independent third-party administrator that controls and pays the medical services in accordance with the formal set-aside allocation, provided there is no reversionary interest to the covered employee or the covered employee's beneficiaries.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In computing the amount of an assessment, the Commission shall round off any fractional dollar to the nearest whole dollar.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Payment of an assessment under this section is in addition to any payment of compensation to a covered employee who has sustained an accidental personal injury, occupational disease, or compensable hernia or a dependent of the covered employee, as provided in this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Director of the Subsequent Injury Fund promptly shall remit to the State Treasurer each payment of assessment received by the Subsequent Injury Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Treasurer shall hold, manage, and disburse the money in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The assessment imposed under this section is for payment of claims submitted to the Subsequent Injury Fund and is not a tax intended to benefit the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
