<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-673" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-673</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">refer a covered employee who is entitled to vocational rehabilitation services under &#xA7; 9-672 of this Part XI of this subtitle to an appropriate vocational rehabilitation provider; and</section><section prefix="(2)">obtain from the provider a vocational rehabilitation plan that includes:<section prefix="(i)">a vocational assessment; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">recommendations for vocational rehabilitation services reasonably necessary to return the disabled covered employee to suitable gainful employment.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In determining whether employment is suitable gainful employment, consideration shall be given to:<section prefix="(1)">the qualifications, interests, incentives, earnings before the accidental personal injury or date of disablement from the occupational disease, and future earning capacity of the covered employee;</section><section prefix="(2)">the nature and extent of the disability of the covered employee; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the current and future condition of the labor market.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">On receipt of a vocational rehabilitation plan, the Commission promptly shall give written notice of the contents of the plan to each party.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 15 days after the day of written notification by the Commission of the contents of the vocational rehabilitation plan, any party in interest may request a hearing to contest the plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the hearing, the parties may present additional evidence as necessary.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">After the hearing, the Commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">wholly or partly accept or reject the vocational rehabilitation plan; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">pass an appropriate order about vocational rehabilitation of the covered employee.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
