<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-11-406</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Secretary shall appoint a Director of Apprenticeship and Training. The Director of Apprenticeshi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>406</order_by>
  <text>The Secretary shall appoint a Director of Apprenticeship and Training. The Director of Apprenticeship and Training shall have the responsibility of promoting apprenticeship and other forms of on-the-job training and shall obtain the assistance of the Bureau of Apprenticeship and Training, U.S. Department of Labor, and other federal and State agencies in this function. The Director's duties shall include, but shall not be limited to:<section prefix=""><section prefix="(1)">encouragement and promotion of the standards established in accordance with this subtitle and with the basic standards of the Bureau of Apprenticeship and Training, U.S. Department of Labor;</section><section prefix="(2)">bringing about the settlement of differences arising out of apprenticeship programs and agreements when the differences cannot be adjusted locally or in accordance with established trade procedure;</section><section prefix="(3)">supervision of the execution of agreements and the maintenance of standards;</section><section prefix="(4)">registration of apprenticeship programs and agreements;</section><section prefix="(5)">keeping a record of apprenticeship agreements and programs, and upon performance thereunder issuing certificates of completion of apprenticeship;</section><section prefix="(6)">encouragement of liaison and cooperation between all private, State, and federal agencies concerned with apprenticeship, trade, and industrial training;</section><section prefix="(7)">promotion of public awareness of apprenticeship and other occupational training; and</section><section prefix="(8)">keeping a record of the progress of apprenticeship and training programs initiated in accordance with the provisions of this subtitle and informing the Council periodically as to the results.</section></section></text>
</law>
