<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-701" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-8-701</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to subsections (b) and (c) of this section, the Secretary may enter into a reciprocal arrangement with an agency of another state or the federal government that is authorized to do so.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Under a reciprocal arrangement that the Secretary enters into under this section:<section prefix="(1)">services that an individual performs for a single employing unit for which services usually are performed in more than one state are considered to be performed entirely within:<section prefix="(i)">the state in which any part of the service is performed;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the state in which the individual resides; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a state in which the employing unit maintains a place of business;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">if services are considered to be performed entirely within one state, the employing unit shall have an election in effect that is approved by the agency responsible for administration of its unemployment insurance law under which all services that the individual performs for the employing unit are deemed to be performed entirely within the state;</section><section prefix="(3)">potential rights to benefits under this title may be the basis for payment of benefits under the law of another state or the federal government and potential rights to benefits under the law of another state or the federal government may be the basis for payment of benefits under this title;</section><section prefix="(4)">for the purpose of Part IV of Subtitle 6 of this title, contributions are deemed to have been paid to the Unemployment Insurance Fund on the day on which they were made under federal law or the law of the other state; and</section><section prefix="(5)">the Unemployment Insurance Fund shall be reimbursed for the amount of contributions made under federal law or the law of the other state plus interest that the Secretary considers to be fair and reasonable.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary may not enter into an arrangement under subsection (a) of this section unless it includes a provision to reimburse:<section prefix="(1)">the Unemployment Insurance Fund for benefits that are based on services and wages that are subject to federal law or the law of another state; and</section><section prefix="(2)">another state or the federal government from the Unemployment Insurance Fund for benefits it pays that are based on services and wages that are subject to this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In accordance with arrangements entered into under subsection (a) of this section, the Secretary may:<section prefix="(i)">use the Unemployment Insurance Fund to reimburse an agency of another state or the federal government; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">receive from an agency of another state or the federal government reimbursements to the Unemployment Insurance Fund.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Reimbursements made from the Unemployment Insurance Fund under this section shall be considered benefits for the purposes of this title.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
