<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-503" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-11-503</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the definitions set forth in &#xA7; 101 of the federal Act shall apply; definitions set forth below shall have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Dislocated worker" means an individual who:<section prefix="(1)">is unlikely to return to a previous industry or occupation and:<section prefix="(i)">has been terminated or laid off or has received a notice of termination or layoff from employment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is eligible for or has exhausted entitlement to unemployment compensation; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">has been employed for a duration sufficient to demonstrate, to the appropriate entity at a one-stop center referred to in &#xA7; 134(c) of the federal Act, attachment to the workforce, but is not eligible for unemployment compensation due to insufficient earnings or having performed services for an employer that were not covered under State unemployment compensation law;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">has been terminated or laid off, or has received a notice of termination or layoff, from employment as a result of any permanent closure of, or any substantial layoff at, a plant, facility, or enterprise;</section><section prefix="(3)">is employed at a facility at which the employer has made a general announcement that the facility will close within 180 days;</section><section prefix="(4)">for purposes of eligibility to receive services other than training services described in &#xA7; 134(d)(4) of the federal Act, intensive services described in &#xA7; 134(d)(4) of the federal Act, or supportive services, is employed at a facility at which the employer has made a general announcement that the facility will close;</section><section prefix="(5)">was self-employed (including employment as a farmer, a rancher, or a fisherman) but is unemployed as a result of general economic conditions in the community in which the individual resides or because of natural disasters; or</section><section prefix="(6)">is a displaced homemaker.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Federal Act" means the federal Workforce Investment Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Governor's plan" means the State plan as provided in &#xA7; 112 of the federal Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Individual with a disability" means any individual who has a physical or mental disability which for the individual constitutes or results in a substantial handicap to employment.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Local plan" means the comprehensive 5-year local plan required for each local workforce investment area as provided in &#xA7; 118 of the federal Act and any final plan or modification as provided in the federal Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Low-income individual" means an individual who:<section prefix="(1)">receives, or is a member of a family which receives, cash welfare payments under a federal, State, or local income-based public assistance program;</section><section prefix="(2)">received an income, or is a member of a family that received a total family income for the 6-month period prior to application for the program involved (exclusive of unemployment compensation, child support payments, payments described in paragraph (1) of this subsection, and old age and survivors insurance benefits received under Section 202 of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. &#xA7; 402)) that, in relation to family size, does not exceed the higher of:<section prefix="(i)">the poverty level for an equivalent period; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">70 percent of the lower living standard income level for an equivalent period;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">is a member of a household that receives food stamps or has been determined within the 6-month period prior to application for the program involved to be eligible to receive food stamps pursuant to the Food Stamp Act of 1977 (7 U.S.C. &#xA7; 2011 et seq.);</section><section prefix="(4)">is a foster child on behalf of whom State or local government payments are made;</section><section prefix="(5)">in cases permitted by regulations promulgated by the Secretary, is an adult individual with a disability whose own income meets the requirements of a program described in paragraph (1) or (2) of this subsection, but who is a member of a family whose income does not meet such requirements; or</section><section prefix="(6)">qualifies as a homeless individual, as defined in subsections (a) and (c) of &#xA7; 103 of the Stewart B. McKinney Homeless Assistance Act (42 U.S.C. &#xA7; 11302).</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Participant" means an individual who has been determined eligible to participate in and who is receiving services (except follow-up services authorized under this title) under a program authorized under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Performance standards" means the basic measures of performance for training programs to be prescribed by the Secretary and such variations of the standards as the Governor may prescribe.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Secretary" means the United States Secretary of Labor.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"State Workforce Investment Board" means the Governor's Workforce Investment Board, as provided in &#xA7; 111 of the federal Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Supportive services" means services such as transportation, child care, dependent care, housing, and needs-related payments that are necessary to enable an individual to participate in activities authorized under the federal Act, consistent with the federal Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Training organization" means an entity that provides training and employment services to individuals described in &#xA7; 11-504(b) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Workforce investment area" means a geographic area designated by the Governor in accordance with &#xA7; 116 of the federal Act.</section>
  </text>
</law>
