<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-638.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>638.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to:<section prefix="(1)">a nongovernmental unit that employs at least one covered employee;</section><section prefix="(2)">a county; and</section><section prefix="(3)">a municipal corporation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A covered employee under this section means an individual who:<section prefix="(1)">is entitled to compensation for claims arising from events occurring on or before January 1, 1988; and</section><section prefix="(2)">filed the claims for compensation paid by a nongovernmental unit, a county, or a municipal corporation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Compensation paid to a covered employee under this Part V of this subtitle is subject to an annual cost of living adjustment if the employer, county, or municipal corporation chooses to provide an adjustment.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">On or before June 30 of each year, the Department of Business and Economic Development shall determine and report to the Commission the rate of change in the Consumer Price Index in the preceding calendar year, using as the Consumer Price Index the lower of:<section prefix="(1)">the Consumer Price Index (all urban consumers, all item index) published by the United States Department of Labor for the Washington, D.C.-Baltimore CMSA; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the United States city average consumer price index (all urban consumers, all item index).</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">On or before July 31 of each year, the Commission shall publish the amount of the cost of living adjustment that shall become effective on January 1 of the following year.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The compensation payable to a covered employee under this Part V of this subtitle may be adjusted by:<section prefix="(1)">multiplying the initial rate of compensation by the cost of living adjustment; and</section><section prefix="(2)">adding the product to the compensation, as adjusted, paid during the prior year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a covered employee who is entitled to compensation under this Part V of this subtitle also receives federal Social Security disability insurance benefits, the adjusted annual compensation paid shall be reduced to the extent necessary to avoid a diminution of the federal Social Security disability insurance benefits.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If federal Social Security law on disability insurance benefits no longer imposes a diminution in the payment of  the adjustment in compensation, payments of compensation shall be made to the full extent allowed under this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
