<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-8-422</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>422</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The State Treasurer is custodian of the Special Administrative Expense Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Money in the Special Administrative Expense Fund shall be spent in accordance with appropriations in the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Money in the Special Administrative Expense Fund shall be available to the Secretary whenever it is needed for use in accordance with this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">When money is needed for reimbursement of interest and payment of administrative costs under &#xA7; 8-421(b)(2)(i) and (ii) of this subtitle, the Secretary may make the reimbursement or payment from money that:<section prefix="(1)">is in the Special Administrative Expense Fund; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the State Treasurer transfers for that purpose from the Special Administrative Expense Fund to the Unemployment Insurance Administration Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">When the Secretary acquires, repairs, or maintains office space with money from the Special Administrative Expense Fund that will be reimbursed from federal funds, until the reimbursement, the Secretary may transfer from the Unemployment Insurance Administration Fund to the Special Administrative Expense Fund money in an amount that:<section prefix="(1)">does not exceed the amount of federal funds specifically made available to the Secretary; and</section><section prefix="(2)">equals the fair reasonable rental value of:<section prefix="(i)">land or buildings that the Secretary acquires to use to carry out this title; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the proportionate amount of space that the Secretary uses in a building constructed by the State for another unit.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">On July 1 of each year, the Secretary shall direct the State Treasurer to transfer to the General Fund of the State the balance in the Special Administrative Expense Fund that:<section prefix="(1)">the Secretary has not allocated or encumbered; and</section><section prefix="(2)">exceeds $250,000.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Beginning December 31, 2007, and each year thereafter, the Secretary shall report to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the Senate Budget and Taxation Committee, the Senate Finance Committee, the House Appropriations Committee, and the House Economic Matters Committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The report shall include:<section prefix="(i)">the financial status of the Special Administrative Expense Fund and a summary of its activity for the preceding fiscal year; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a description of all projects receiving moneys from the Special Administrative Expense Fund in the preceding fiscal year.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
