<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-601" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-11-601</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "private sector entity" means a person that the Maryland Apprenticeship and Training Council approves under &#xA7; 11-405(b) of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Construction Apprenticeship Assistance Program in the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The purpose of the Construction Apprenticeship Assistance Program is to develop a well-trained, productive construction workforce which meets the needs of the State's economy.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Division shall administer the Construction Apprenticeship Assistance Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">As provided in the State budget, the Construction Apprenticeship Assistance Program shall award grants to eligible private sector entities that operate apprenticeship programs in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Secretary may adopt regulations necessary to carry out this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">By regulation, the Secretary shall establish:<section prefix="(1)">criteria to determine the eligibility of private sector entities; and</section><section prefix="(2)">an application process for determining eligibility.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A grant awarded by the Construction Apprenticeship Assistance Program under subsection (e) of this section shall be based on the number of participants in a program operated by an eligible private sector entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A grant shall consist of a maximum of $1,000 for each apprentice in an eligible private sector entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The Construction Apprenticeship Assistance Program shall distribute a grant awarded to a private sector entity:<section prefix="(1)">at the end of a Program year; and</section><section prefix="(2)">only to the extent that each apprentice has completed the Program year.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
