<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-8-105.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>105.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section or otherwise required by law, information provided to the Secretary under &#xA7; 8-1001(b)(3) of this title for purposes of determining whether a claimant left employment as a result of domestic violence shall be confidential and not subject to disclosure to any party.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary may notify the employing unit in general terms that a claimant has left employment as a result of domestic violence.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary may not disclose information provided to the Secretary under &#xA7; 8-1001(b)(3)(ii) of this title to the employing unit unless the employing unit can establish that:<section prefix="(i)">the employing unit has a legitimate need to question the veracity of the information;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the employing unit's need for the information outweighs the claimant's personal privacy interest; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the employing unit is unable to obtain the information from any other source.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Before disclosing information under this section, the Secretary shall:<section prefix="(i)">notify the claimant; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">redact unnecessary identifying information.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An employing unit that receives information under this section may not further disseminate the information.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Information related to the status of a claimant or a claimant's spouse, minor child, or parent as a victim of domestic violence is not public information subject to disclosure as part of the appeals process.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary may adopt regulations to further protect the privacy of the claimant.</section>
  </text>
</law>
