<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-210" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-210</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Farmer" includes a dairy farmer.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Migrant farm worker" means an individual who is engaged in seasonal or other temporary agricultural employment and who is:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Migrant farm worker" does not include an individual who performs a service included in subsection (b) of this section if the individual:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, an individual, including a migrant farm worker, is a covered employee if:<section prefix="(1)">the individual receives compensation from a farmer for any service other than office work, including:<section prefix="(i)">operating a machine connected with animal, crop, or soil management;</section><section prefix="(ii)">constructing or repairing a fixture or machine; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">handling an animal or crop with or without a machine; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the farmer has:<section prefix="(i)">at least 3 full-time employees; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an annual payroll of at least $15,000 for full-time employees.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An individual, other than a migrant farm worker, who receives compensation from a farmer for a service is not a covered employee if:<section prefix="(1)">the individual customarily is engaged in an independent business occupation of the same nature as that of the service performed;</section><section prefix="(2)">the individual is free from control and direction over the individual's performance of the service;</section><section prefix="(3)">the individual provides the individual's own equipment, materials, and tools; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the farmer is not required to withhold Social Security, unemployment, State, or federal taxes from the compensation paid to the individual.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
