<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-3-308</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>308</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An employer may not:<section prefix="(1)">willfully violate any provision of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">hinder, delay, or otherwise interfere with the Commissioner or an authorized representative of the Commissioner in the enforcement of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">refuse entry to the Commissioner or an authorized representative of the Commissioner into a place of employment that the Commissioner is authorized under this subtitle to inspect; or</section><section prefix="(4)">discharge or otherwise discriminate against an employee because the employee:<section prefix="(i)">makes a complaint to the employer, the Commissioner, or another person;</section><section prefix="(ii)">brings an action under this subtitle or a proceeding that relates to the subject of this subtitle or causes the action or proceeding to be brought; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">has testified or will testify in an action under this subtitle or a proceeding that relates to the subject of this subtitle.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An employee may not:<section prefix="(1)">make a groundless or malicious complaint to the Commissioner or an authorized representative of the Commissioner;</section><section prefix="(2)">in bad faith, bring an action under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">in bad faith, bring a proceeding that relates to the subject of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(4)">in bad faith, testify in an action under this subtitle or a proceeding that relates to the subject of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner may bring an action for injunctive relief and damages against a person who violates subsection (a)(1) or (4) or subsection (b)(1), (3), or (4) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An employer who violates any provision of subsection (a)(2) or (3) of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $300.</section>
  </text>
</law>
