<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-316</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>316</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Insured payroll" means the payroll of an employer who:<section prefix="(i)">is subject to this title; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">has obtained insurance for its covered employees from an insurer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Insurer" means:<section prefix="(i)">a stock corporation or mutual association that is authorized under the Insurance Article to provide workers' compensation insurance in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a governmental self-insurance group that meets the requirements of &#xA7; 9-404 of this title;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a self-insurance group of private employers that meets the requirements of Title 25, Subtitle 3 of the Insurance Article; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">an individual employer that self-insures in accordance with &#xA7; 9-405 of this title.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Out of money appropriated for the maintenance of the Commission, the State shall pay the salaries, administrative expenses, and all other expenses of the Commission, including:<section prefix="(1)">the costs of the administration of the Occupational Safety and Health Program by the Commissioner of Labor and Industry under Title 5 of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">the costs of the administration of the workforce fraud program by the Commissioner of Labor and Industry under Title 3, Subtitle 9 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(3)">any cost incurred by the State, including contribution as an employer, because of the participation of a Commissioner in the Judges' Retirement System of the State of Maryland.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission shall assess against and collect from each insurer a tax for the maintenance of the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before each fiscal year, the Commission shall calculate for each insurer the tax for the maintenance of the Commission in accordance with this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">First, the Commission shall calculate the assessment percentage by:<section prefix="(i)">determining the appropriation for the expenses of the Commission for the next fiscal year as:<section prefix="1.">decreasing by an amount equal to the revenues received during the current fiscal year under &#xA7; 9-319(a)(2) and (3) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="2.">decreasing by any amount the expenditures projected to the end of the current fiscal year that are expected to be less than the appropriation for that fiscal year; and</section><section prefix="3.">adjusting for any variances between the projected and actual expenditures for the previous fiscal year; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">dividing the amount determined under item (i) of this paragraph by the total insured payroll of all insurers.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Then, the Commission shall apply the assessment percentage determined under paragraph (2) of this subsection to the insured payroll of each insurer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Payment of the tax assessed under this section may be enforced by a civil action in the name of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commission shall pay the money that it collects for the tax under this section into the Workers' Compensation Fund in the State Treasury established under &#xA7; 9-319 of this subtitle to reimburse the State for the expense of administering this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Commission may:<section prefix="(1)">examine payrolls and require reports from employers and insurers as may be reasonable and necessary to carry out this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">adopt regulations to carry out this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
