<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5.5-122" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-5.5-122</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person who violates any regulation adopted by the Commissioner under &#xA7; 5.5-109 of this title is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction for each offense is subject to a fine not exceeding the lesser of the penalty provided by the regulation or $100.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a railroad company willfully violates any provision of this title or any order, regulation, or health and safety standard adopted under this title, and the violation caused death to an individual, on conviction the railroad company is subject to:<section prefix="(1)">for a first offense, a fine not exceeding $25,000; or</section><section prefix="(2)">for a subsequent offense, a fine not exceeding $50,000.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not knowingly make a false certification, false representation, or false statement in an application, plan, record, report, or other document that is filed or required to be kept under this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who violates paragraph (1) of this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $5,000 or imprisonment not exceeding 6 months or both.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless the Commissioner or an authorized representative of the Commissioner authorizes advance notice of an inspection, a person may not give advance notice of an inspection to be conducted under this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who violates paragraph (1) of this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $1,000 or imprisonment not exceeding 6 months or both.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
