<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="gle" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-5.5-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this title the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Labor and Industry.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Employee" includes each person in the service of a railroad who performs for the railroad any work defined as work of an employee in accordance with orders and decisions of the federal Department of Transportation and over whom the railroad maintains continuing authority to supervise and direct the manner of the work.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Employee" does not include any person who performs work for a rapid rail transit system or light rail system operating in the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Railroad" includes each common carrier by rail and all branches, bridges, cars, extensions, ferries, plants, spurs, stations, subways, switches, terminal facilities, tracks, tunnels, and all equipment used on or in connection with them.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Railroad" does not include a rapid rail transit system or light rail system operating in the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Railroad company" means:<section prefix="(1)">the operator of a railroad operating in the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the State or any political subdivision of the State, while operating a railroad.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Working day" means any day that occurs Monday through Friday unless the day is designated as a holiday for employees of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Working day" does not include a Saturday or Sunday.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
