<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-5-608</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>608</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 24-505 of the Health - General Article, an individual may not smoke in an indoor place of employment.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall adopt regulations that prohibit environmental tobacco smoke, as defined in &#xA7; 24-501 of the Health - General Article, in indoor places of employment not normally open to the general public.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to subsection (c) of this section, a person  who violates a regulation adopted under this subtitle:<section prefix="(i)">for a first violation, shall be issued a written  reprimand by the Commissioner or the Commissioner's designee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">for a second violation, is subject to a civil  penalty of $100; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">for each subsequent violation, is subject to a  civil penalty not less than $250.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner may waive a penalty established under  subsection (b) of this section, giving consideration to factors that  include:<section prefix="(1)">the seriousness of the violation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">any demonstrated good faith measures to comply  with the provisions of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A penalty collected by the Commissioner under this  section shall be paid to the Cigarette Restitution Fund established  under &#xA7; 7-317 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">On or before September 30 of each year, the Department shall report, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State  Government Article, to the General Assembly on:<section prefix="(1)">the enforcement efforts of the Department to eliminate environmental tobacco smoke, as defined in &#xA7; 24-501 of the Health - General Article, in indoor places of employment during the prior year; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the results of these enforcement efforts.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An employer who discharges or discriminates against an employee because that employee has made a complaint under this section, has given information to the Department in accordance with this section, has caused to be instituted or is about to cause to be instituted a proceeding under this section, or has testified or is about to testify in a proceeding, shall be deemed in  violation of this section and shall be subject to a civil penalty of at least $2,000 but not more than $10,000 for each violation.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An employee may not:<section prefix="(i)">make a groundless or malicious complaint to  the Commissioner or an authorized representative of the  Commissioner;</section><section prefix="(ii)">in bad faith, bring an action under this  subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">in bad faith, testify in an action under this  subtitle or a proceeding that relates to the subject of this  subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner may bring an action for injunctive  relief and damages against a person who violates the provisions of  paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
