<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="gle" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-3-211</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, a minor under the age of 16 years may not be e...</catch_line>
  <order_by>211</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, a minor under the age of 16 years may not be employed or allowed to be employed:<section prefix="(i)">before 7:00 a.m.;</section><section prefix="(ii)">from the day after Labor Day through the day before Memorial Day, after 8:00 p.m.;</section><section prefix="(iii)">from Memorial Day through Labor Day, after 9:00 p.m.; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">more than:<section prefix="1.">4 hours on a day when school is in session;</section><section prefix="2.">8 hours on a day when school is not in session;</section><section prefix="3.">23 hours in a week when school is in session for 5 days; or</section><section prefix="4.">40 hours in a week when school is not in session.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The hours of work allowed under paragraph (1)(iv) of this subsection do not include any hours that a minor works in a bona fide work-study or student-learner program while school normally is in session.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commissioner may grant to a minor an exception to the restrictions under this section if the Commissioner:<section prefix="(1)">receives the written consent of a parent of the minor or a person standing in the place of the parent; and</section><section prefix="(2)">determines that:<section prefix="(i)">there will be no hazard to the health or welfare of the minor; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">granting the exception will not impede the minor in fulfilling school graduation requirements.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
