<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="gle" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-5-323</section_number>
  <catch_line>To qualify for a temporary variance, an applicant shall establish that the applicant:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>323</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To qualify for a temporary variance, an applicant shall establish that the applicant:<section prefix="(1)">is unable to comply with a regulation or part of a regulation, by its effective date, because:<section prefix="(i)">equipment, material, or professional or technical staff that is needed to comply is unavailable; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">alteration or construction of a facility that is needed to comply cannot be completed by the effective date;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">has an effective program to comply with the regulation or part as soon as practicable; and</section><section prefix="(3)">is taking each available step to protect employees against each hazard that the regulation or part covers.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To qualify for a permanent variance, an applicant shall show, by a preponderance of the evidence, that the applicant will maintain conditions, means, methods, practices, procedures, or operations that make employment and places of employment at least as safe and healthful for employees as they would be if the applicant complied with the regulation from which the permanent variance is sought.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In addition to the bases under subsections (a) and (b) of this section, the Commissioner may grant an employer a variance from a regulation or part of a regulation if the Commissioner:<section prefix="(1)">approves an experiment to show or validate a new and improved method to protect the health or safety of employees; and</section><section prefix="(2)">determines that the employer needs the variance to participate in the experiment.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
