<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-909" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-3-909</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An employer found to have knowingly failed to properly classify an individual in violation of &#xA7; 3-904 of this subtitle shall be assessed a civil penalty of up to $5,000 for each employee who was not properly classified.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In determining the amount of the penalty, the Commissioner or the administrative law judge shall consider:<section prefix="(1)">the gravity of the violation;</section><section prefix="(2)">the size of the employer's business;</section><section prefix="(3)">the employer's good faith;</section><section prefix="(4)">the employer's history of violations under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(5)">whether the employer:<section prefix="(i)">has been found, by a court or an administrative unit, to have deprived the employee of any rights to which the employee would have been entitled under a State protective labor law, including but not limited to:</section><section prefix="(ii)">has made restitution and come into compliance with all such State protective labor laws with respect to the employee.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the court or an administrative unit determines that an individual or class of individuals is entitled to restitution as a result of the employer's violation of &#xA7; 3-904 of this subtitle, the court or administrative unit:<section prefix="(1)">shall award each individual any restitution to which the individual may be entitled; and</section><section prefix="(2)">may award each individual an additional amount up to three times the amount of such restitution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An employer in violation of &#xA7; 3-904 of this subtitle may be assessed double the administrative penalties set forth in subsection (a) of this section if the employer has been found previously to have violated this subtitle by a final order of a court or an administrative unit.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An employer who has been found by a final order of a court or an administrative unit to have violated &#xA7; 3-904 of this subtitle three or more times may be assessed an administrative penalty of up to $20,000 for each employee.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An employer may be assessed civil penalties under this section or &#xA7; 8-201.1 or &#xA7; 9-402.1 of this article by only one final order of a court or administrative unit for the same actions constituting a violation of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, an employer may be ordered to make restitution, pay any interest due, and otherwise comply with all applicable laws and regulations by orders of a court and all relevant administrative units, including the Comptroller, the Office of Unemployment Insurance, the Insurance Administration, and the Workers' Compensation Commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Any penalty issued under this section against an employer shall be in effect against any successor corporation or business entity that:<section prefix="(1)">has one or more of the same principals or officers as the employer against whom the penalty was assessed, unless the principal or officer did not or with the exercise of reasonable diligence could not know of the violation for which the penalty was imposed; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is engaged in the same or equivalent trade or activity.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
