<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-711" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-711</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a covered employee suffers a disablement or death as a result of an occupational disease, the covered employee or the dependents of the covered employee shall file a claim application form with the Commission within 2 years, or in the case of pulmonary dust disease within 3 years, after the date:<section prefix="(i)">of disablement or death; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">when the covered employee or the dependents of the covered employee first had actual knowledge that the disablement was caused by the employment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A claim application form filed under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall include an authorization by the claimant for the release, to the claimant's attorney, the claimant's  or covered employee's employer, and the insurer of the claimant's or covered employee's employer, or an agent of the claimant's attorney, the claimant's or covered employee's employer, or the insurer of the claimant's or covered employee's employer, of medical information that is relevant to:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An authorization under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Unless waived under subsection (c) of this section, failure to file a claim in accordance with subsection (a) of this section bars a claim under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The defense of failure to file a claim in accordance with subsection (a) of this section is waived if the employer or its insurer:<section prefix="(1)">fails to raise the defense of the failure to file the claim at a hearing on the claim before the Commission makes any award or decision;</section><section prefix="(2)">pays compensation for the disability or death resulting from the occupational disease; or</section><section prefix="(3)">by its affirmative conduct leads the covered employee or other claimant to reasonably believe that the requirement of filing a claim has been waived.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
