<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-11-1002</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1002</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Maryland Workforce Corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Corporation is a body politic and corporate and is an instrumentality of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The purpose of the Corporation is to:<section prefix="(1)">work in coordination with the Department and other State agencies to establish a plan and framework for innovative, demand-driven programs across the State that will give Maryland workers the opportunity to acquire and develop the education and skills needed to participate fully in the workforce;</section><section prefix="(2)">solicit, acquire, and coordinate private and public funding to assure a reliable funding stream for the programs developed under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">obtain resources for the statewide workforce programs developed under this subtitle from private and public sources including:<section prefix="(i)">local workforce investment boards;</section><section prefix="(ii)">community colleges;</section><section prefix="(iii)">adult learning programs;</section><section prefix="(iv)">correctional education and vocational programs;</section><section prefix="(v)">the Department of Human Resources;</section><section prefix="(vi)">the Department of Business and Economic Development;</section><section prefix="(vii)">the Higher Education Commission; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">the Department;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">administer the programs developed under this subtitle in accordance with the plan developed under item (1) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(5)">provide grants, funding, and other assistance to support the programs developed under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(6)">contract with training providers to conduct education and skills training programs;</section><section prefix="(7)">act as a research and development resource in finding solutions for new and emerging workforce issues; and</section><section prefix="(8)">evaluate the effectiveness of the programs developed under this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
