<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-8-5A-12</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>12</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A final decision of the Board of Appeals may be appealed to a circuit court by any party aggrieved by the decision, the Secretary, or both.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to standing authorized under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Secretary may appeal on behalf of the federal government any decision of the Board of Appeals in which the Secretary is an agent of the federal government and responsible for the administration of a federal unemployment compensation program.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board of Appeals may be a party to an appeal under this section and may be represented by the Attorney General or by any qualified lawyer who is a regular salaried employee of the Board of Appeals and who has been designated by it for that purpose on recommendation of the Attorney General.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A court or an officer of a court may not charge an individual who claims benefits a fee in any proceeding under this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An employer that is aggrieved by a final decision under &#xA7; 8-602 or &#xA7; 8-629 or &#xA7; 8-638 of this title may appeal to the circuit court for Baltimore City or for a county where the employer does business.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board of Appeals may certify to a circuit court a question of law that is involved in a decision by the Board of Appeals.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In a judicial proceeding under this section, findings of fact of the Board of Appeals are conclusive and the jurisdiction of the court is confined to questions of law if:<section prefix="(1)">findings of fact are supported by evidence that is competent, material, and substantial in view of the entire record; and</section><section prefix="(2)">there is no fraud.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A circuit court shall give priority to an appeal or a certified question of law under this section over all other civil cases except cases under the Workers' Compensation Law of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A circuit court shall hear an appeal or a certified question of law under this section in a summary manner.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In a judicial proceeding under this section, a circuit court may not require a person to:<section prefix="(1)">enter an exception to a ruling of the Board of Appeals; or</section><section prefix="(2)">post a bond for entering an appeal.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A party may appeal from a decision of a circuit court to the Court of Special Appeals in the same manner as provided for in civil cases, consistent with this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
