<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-7-401</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>401</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In accordance with this section, each farm labor contractor shall disclose to each migrant agricultural worker:<section prefix="(i)">each place of employment in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a description of the crops and activities involved;</section><section prefix="(iii)">each condition of employment at each place of employment, including:<section prefix="1.">the wage to be paid;</section><section prefix="2.">the person who will pay the wage; and</section><section prefix="3.">when the wage is due;</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">the housing, insurance, or transportation that will be provided to the migrant agricultural worker;</section><section prefix="(v)">any cost that will be charged to the migrant agricultural worker for housing, insurance, or transportation; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">each labor dispute that the farm labor contractor knows exists at a place of employment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each farm labor contractor shall disclose to a migrant agricultural worker the information required under this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">before the farm labor contractor causes the migrant agricultural worker to enter the State to perform agricultural work;</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the migrant agricultural worker is recruited in the State, before the farm labor contractor recruits the migrant agricultural worker to perform agricultural work; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">if the farm labor contractor is in the State with a migrant agricultural worker and has recruited the migrant agricultural worker when an agricultural operation asks the farm labor contractor to perform a farm labor contracting service, before the farm labor contractor performs the service.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each farm labor contractor who provides housing for a migrant agricultural worker, by agreement with an agricultural operation or otherwise, shall ensure that all of the conditions of occupancy are posted conspicuously while the migrant agricultural worker stays in the housing.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Information that a farm labor contractor is required to disclose under this section shall be:<section prefix="(1)">in writing; and</section><section prefix="(2)">in English or, as necessary and reasonable for migrant agricultural workers who are not fluent or literate in English, in Spanish or another language common to the migrant agricultural workers.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">On request, the Commissioner shall make available to a farm labor contractor forms to be used to disclose information as required under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
