<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="gle" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-6A-05</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is an Advisory Committee on the Registration of Rehabilitation Practitioners within the Commis...</catch_line>
  <order_by>05</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is an Advisory Committee on the Registration of Rehabilitation Practitioners within the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Advisory Committee consists of seven members appointed by the Commission in accordance with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Advisory Committee shall be comprised of registered rehabilitation practitioners, who are registered with the Commission under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall appoint members of the Advisory Committee so that its membership reflects the geographic, racial, ethnic, and gender makeup of the population of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The term of an Advisory Committee member is 3 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In making appointments to the Advisory Committee, the Commission shall provide for continuity and rotation through a staggering of terms.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A majority of the fully authorized Advisory Committee is a quorum.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Advisory Committee shall meet at the request of the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">In addition to the duties set forth elsewhere in this title, the Advisory Committee shall:<section prefix="(1)">review applications for registration submitted to the Commission whenever further clarification regarding the applicant is requested by the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(2)">after review and evaluation, provide recommendations to the Commission chairman on the applicant.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
