<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-8-619</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>619</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Two or more employing units that have made an election may submit a joint application to the Secretary for establishment of a group account to share the cost of benefits that are attributable to covered employment for those employing units.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The application shall identify and authorize a group representative to act as the agent of the group.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On receipt of an application, the Secretary shall approve or disapprove the application.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On approval of an application, the Secretary shall:<section prefix="(i)">establish a group account for the group, effective on the first day of the calendar quarter in which the Secretary receives the application; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">notify the group representative of the effective date of the account.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A group account shall continue to be effective:<section prefix="(i)">for at least 1 year; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">until terminated at the discretion of the Secretary or on application by the group.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">On receipt of a bill that the Secretary sends to the group, each member of the group is liable for reimbursement payments in an amount whose ratio to total benefits that are attributable to covered employment for all members of the group is the same as the ratio that as total wages paid by that member has to total wages paid by all members of the group.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary may adopt regulations for:<section prefix="(1)">application for the establishment, maintenance, and termination of a group account;</section><section prefix="(2)">addition of new members to a group account;</section><section prefix="(3)">withdrawal of active members from a group account;</section><section prefix="(4)">determination of the amounts that are payable under this section by each member of a group; and</section><section prefix="(5)">manner and time of payments by a member of a group.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
