<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="gle" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-5-213</section_number>
  <catch_line>Within a reasonable time after issuance of a citation under &#xA7; 5-212 of this subtitle to an employer...</catch_line>
  <order_by>213</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Within a reasonable time after issuance of a citation under &#xA7; 5-212 of this subtitle to an employer, the Commissioner shall send by certified mail to the employer a notice that:<section prefix="(1)">states the civil penalty, if any, that the Commissioner proposes to assess under this title; and</section><section prefix="(2)">informs the employer that, within 15 work days after receipt of the notice, the employer may submit to the Commissioner a written notice of contest on the citation or civil penalty.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A citation and any penalty that the Commissioner proposes to assess shall be considered a final order of the Commissioner unless:<section prefix="(1)">within 15 work days after receipt of a notice under subsection (a) of this section the employer notifies the Commissioner of an intent to contest the citation or any penalty; or</section><section prefix="(2)">within 15 work days after issuance of a citation, an employee or representative of an employee submits a written notice to the Commissioner that alleges that the period of time set in the citation for abatement of the violation is unreasonable.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An employer shall correct each violation for which the Commissioner issues a citation within the period set for correction in a final order under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the request of an employer for a hearing is made in good faith and not solely to delay or avoid payment of a penalty, the period for correction begins on the day when the order passed as a result of the hearing becomes final.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the Commissioner has reason to believe that an employer has failed to correct a violation within the time allowed, the Commissioner shall send by certified mail to the employer a notice that:<section prefix="(1)">states that the employer has failed to correct the violation;</section><section prefix="(2)">states the civil penalty, if any, that the Commissioner intends to assess under this title for the failure; and</section><section prefix="(3)">informs the employer that, within 15 work days after receipt of the notice, the employer may submit to the Commissioner a notice of contest on the notice or civil penalty.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Unless an employer notifies the Commissioner of an intent to contest as provided in subsection (b) of this section, the notice, including any civil penalty, is a final order.</section>
  </text>
</law>
