<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="gle" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-5.5-108</section_number>
  <catch_line>As necessary, the Commissioner shall adopt appropriate health and safety standards and other regulat...</catch_line>
  <order_by>108</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">As necessary, the Commissioner shall adopt appropriate health and safety standards and other regulations relating to:<section prefix="(1)">sanitation on railroad property as it affects the health of railroad employees, including clerical employees, engine workers, express employees, freight house employees, highway crossing watchmen, maintenance of way employees, platform employees, train workers, and yard workers; and</section><section prefix="(2)">all other areas of railroad safety and health.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To adopt a railroad health and safety standard or other regulation, the Commissioner shall comply with this section and Title 10, Subtitle 1 of the State Government Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An economic impact statement prepared in accordance with &#xA7; 10-111(c) of the State Government Article shall:<section prefix="(i)">include direct and indirect effects of the regulation on the railroad industry, the public, and railroad employees; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">set forth any alternative approach available.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If acceptable alternative approaches are available in adoption of a regulation, the Commissioner shall adopt the approach that has the least burdensome economic impact on the railroad industry, the public, and railroad employees.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, railroad health and safety standards and other regulations that the Commissioner adopts shall be effective as provided in &#xA7; 10-117 of the State Government Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner may delay the effective date of a regulation for not more than 90 days to ensure that railroad companies have an opportunity to familiarize their agents and employees with the requirements of the regulation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this title but subject to the limitations on emergency adoption in Title 10, Subtitle 1 of the State Government Article, the Commissioner may adopt immediately an emergency health and safety standard that the Commissioner determines is needed to protect the public and employees from the grave danger of exposure to an agent or condition determined to be toxic or physically harmful.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An emergency health and safety standard adopted under this subsection remains in effect until the earlier of:<section prefix="(i)">expiration of a period that the Joint Committee on Administrative, Executive, and Legislative Review sets;</section><section prefix="(ii)">expiration of a period, not exceeding 6 months, that the Commissioner sets; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">replacement of the emergency health and safety standard by another regulation adopted in accordance with this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On request of a railroad company:<section prefix="(i)">the Commissioner shall hold a hearing and receive evidence pertaining to any emergency temporary health and safety standard; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">within 10 days after the request for a hearing, the Commissioner shall revoke, modify, or continue the standard.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If a railroad company is aggrieved by an emergency temporary standard:<section prefix="(i)">the railroad company shall have the right to an immediate appeal to a court of competent jurisdiction; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the court shall hear and decide the appeal.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner shall keep in the office of the Commissioner a set of the current regulations adopted to carry out this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner may set a fee for the cost to prepare and mail a copy of the current regulations.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On request and payment of the fee, if any, the Commissioner shall send a person a copy of the current regulations.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
