<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="gle" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-3-906</section_number>
  <catch_line>After the employer has provided all the records requested under &#xA7; 3-905(d) of this subtitle, the Co...</catch_line>
  <order_by>906</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">After the employer has provided all the records requested under &#xA7; 3-905(d) of this subtitle, the Commissioner shall issue a citation to the employer or close the investigation within 90 days.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each citation shall:<section prefix="(1)">describe in detail the nature of the alleged violation;</section><section prefix="(2)">cite the provision of this subtitle or any regulation that the employer is alleged to have violated; and</section><section prefix="(3)">state the civil penalty, if any, that the Commissioner proposes to assess.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Within a reasonable time after issuance of a citation, the Commissioner shall send by certified mail to the employer:<section prefix="(1)">a copy of the citation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">notice of the opportunity to request a hearing.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Within 15 days after an employer receives a notice under subsection (c) of this section, the employer may submit a written request for a hearing on the citation and proposed penalty.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a hearing is not requested within 15 days, the citation, including any penalties, shall become a final order of the Commissioner.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the employer requests a hearing, the Commissioner shall delegate to the Office of Administrative Hearings the authority to hold a hearing and issue findings of fact, conclusions of law, and an order, and assess a penalty under &#xA7; 3-909 of this subtitle in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The employer is entitled to a hearing within 90 days after a timely request is made under this subsection, unless the employer waives that right.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Within 15 days after a request, in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 6 of the State Government Article and the applicable regulations of the Department and the Office of Administrative Hearings, the Commissioner shall provide copies of all relevant evidence, including a list of potential witnesses, on which the Commissioner intends to rely at any administrative hearing under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Commissioner has the burden of proof to show that an employer has knowingly failed to properly classify an individual as an employee.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A decision of an administrative law judge issued in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article shall become a final order of the Commissioner.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">Any party aggrieved by a final order of the Commissioner under subsection (i) of this section may seek judicial review and appeal under &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-222 and 10-223 of the State Government Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
