<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-402" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-402</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to subsections (b) through (f) of this section, each employer shall secure compensation for covered employees of the employer by:<section prefix="(1)">maintaining insurance with the Chesapeake Employers' Insurance Company;</section><section prefix="(2)">maintaining insurance with an authorized insurer;</section><section prefix="(3)">participating in a governmental self-insurance group that meets the requirements of &#xA7; 9-404 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(4)">participating in a self-insurance group of private employers that meets the requirements of Title 25, Subtitle 3 of the Insurance Article;</section><section prefix="(5)">maintaining self-insurance for an individual employer in accordance with &#xA7;  9-405 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(6)">having a county board of education or private noncollegiate institution secure compensation under &#xA7; 8-402(c) or &#xA7; 7-114(d) of the Education Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The State shall secure compensation for jurors by maintaining insurance with the Chesapeake Employers' Insurance Company and paying to the Company the premiums set by the Board for the Company as necessary to provide compensation for jurors.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Adjutant General shall secure compensation for officers and enlisted members of the organized militia of the State by maintaining insurance with the Chesapeake Employers' Insurance Company or an authorized insurer.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A licensed owner or trainer of a racehorse who is considered an employer under &#xA7; 9-212 of this title is in compliance with the requirements of this subtitle if the owner or trainer is in compliance with the requirements of &#xA7; 11-906 of the Business Regulation Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Secretary of Human Resources shall secure compensation for a recipient of public assistance who is a covered employee under &#xA7; 9-224 of this title by maintaining insurance with the Chesapeake Employers' Insurance Company and paying to the Company the premiums set by the Board for the Company as necessary to provide compensation for those individuals.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Anne Arundel, Kent, and Prince George's counties shall secure compensation for members of a volunteer fire company or volunteer rescue squad by maintaining insurance with the Chesapeake Employers' Insurance Company or an authorized insurer.</section>
  </text>
</law>
