<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="gle" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-3-712</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>712</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Applicant" means an applicant for employment.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Electronic communications device" means any device that uses electronic signals to create, transmit, and receive information.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Electronic communications device" includes computers, telephones, personal digital assistants, and other similar devices.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Employer" means:<section prefix="1.">a person engaged in a business, an industry, a profession, a trade, or other enterprise in the State; or</section><section prefix="2.">a unit of State or local government.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Employer" includes an agent, a representative, and a designee of the employer.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, an employer may not request or require that an employee or applicant disclose any user name, password, or other means for accessing a personal account or service through an electronic communications device.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An employer may require an employee to disclose any user name, password, or other means for accessing nonpersonal accounts or services that provide access to the employer's internal computer or information systems.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An employer may not:<section prefix="(1)">discharge, discipline, or otherwise penalize or threaten to discharge, discipline, or otherwise penalize an employee for an employee's refusal to disclose any information specified in subsection (b)(1) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(2)">fail or refuse to hire any applicant as a result of the applicant's refusal to disclose any information specified in subsection (b)(1) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An employee may not download unauthorized employer proprietary information or financial data to an employee's personal Web site, an Internet Web site, a Web-based account, or a similar account.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This section does not prevent an employer:<section prefix="(1)">based on the receipt of information about the use of a personal Web site, Internet Web site, Web-based account, or similar account by an employee for business purposes, from conducting an investigation for the purpose of ensuring compliance with applicable securities or financial law, or regulatory requirements; or</section><section prefix="(2)">based on the receipt of information about the unauthorized downloading of an employer's proprietary information or financial data to a personal Web site, Internet Web site, Web-based account, or similar account by an employee, from investigating an employee's actions under subsection (d) of this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
