<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-415" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-3-415</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, each employer shall pay an overtime wage of at least 1.5 times the usual hourly wage, computed in accordance with &#xA7; 3-420 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to an employer that is:<section prefix="(1)">subject to 49 U.S.C. &#xA7; 10501;</section><section prefix="(2)">an establishment that is a hotel or motel;</section><section prefix="(3)">an establishment that is a restaurant;</section><section prefix="(4)">considered a gasoline service station because the employer is engaged primarily in selling gasoline and lubricating oil, even if the employer sells other merchandise or performs minor repair work;</section><section prefix="(5)">a bona fide private country club;</section><section prefix="(6)">a not for profit entity and is engaged primarily in providing temporary at-home care services, such as companionship or delivery of prepared meals, to aged or sick individuals, individuals with disabilities, or individuals with a mental disorder;</section><section prefix="(7)">a not for profit concert promoter, legitimate theater, music festival, music pavilion, or theatrical show; or</section><section prefix="(8)">an amusement or recreational establishment, including a swimming pool, if the establishment:<section prefix="(i)">operates for no more than 7 months in a calendar year; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">for any 6 months during the preceding calendar year, has average receipts in excess of one-third of the average receipts for the other 6 months.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section does not apply to an employer with respect to:<section prefix="(1)">an employee for whom the United States Secretary of Transportation may set qualifications and maximum hours of service under 49 U.S.C. &#xA7; 31502;</section><section prefix="(2)">a mechanic, partsperson, or salesperson who primarily sells or services automobiles, farm equipment, trailers, or trucks, if the employer is engaged primarily in selling those vehicles to ultimate buyers and is not a manufacturer; or</section><section prefix="(3)">a driver if the employer is engaged in the business of operating taxicabs.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
