<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-302" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-302</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission consists of 10 members, appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each member of the Commission:<section prefix="(i)">at the time of appointment, shall be at least 30 years old; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">for at least 5 years immediately before appointment, shall have been a resident of the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each member of the Commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">be a resident of the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">be a citizen and qualified voter of the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">have been admitted to practice law in the State; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">be distinguished for integrity, sound legal knowledge, and wisdom.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before taking office, each appointee to the Commission shall take the oath required by Article I, &#xA7; 9 of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 12 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Commission on October 1, 1991.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the hearing requirements of this subsection, the Governor may remove a member from office for:<section prefix="(i)">inefficiency;</section><section prefix="(ii)">neglect of duty; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">malfeasance in office.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before the Governor removes a member, the Governor shall give the member:<section prefix="(i)">a copy of the charges against the member; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">an opportunity for a public hearing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At least 10 days before the hearing, the Governor shall give the member notice of the time and place of the hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The member may be represented at the hearing by counsel.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "former commissioner" means a commissioner who previously served as a member of the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, the Chairman may assign a former commissioner to conduct hearings if the former commissioner:<section prefix="(i)">served, in the aggregate, at least 3 years as a commissioner;</section><section prefix="(ii)">meets the standards established by this section as well as any additional standards established by rules of the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">consents to the temporary assignment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A former commissioner may not be recalled for temporary assignment if the commissioner:<section prefix="(i)">was removed or involuntarily retired from the Commission pursuant to the Constitution or laws of this State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">voluntarily retired by reason of disability; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">had the most recent service as a commissioner terminated by rejection of confirmation by the Senate.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A former commissioner recalled under this section may not be temporarily assigned for more than 120 working days in any calendar year.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If on the 120th working day in a calendar year that a former commissioner has served in a temporary assignment under this section the hearing on the case then being heard by the commissioner is not concluded, the Commission may extend the commissioner's assignment until that case is concluded.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A former commissioner temporarily assigned under this section has all the power and authority of a member of this Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)"/>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iii)">In addition to the per diem compensation provided for in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, a former commissioner shall be reimbursed for reasonable expenses actually incurred by reason of the temporary assignment, in accordance with Standard State Travel Regulations.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The Commission shall adopt regulations consistent with those for the recall of former circuit and District Court judges.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
