<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="gle" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-3-213</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, a minor may not be employed or allowed to work:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>213</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, a minor may not be employed or allowed to work:<section prefix="(1)">in, about, or in connection with the manufacturing of a hazardous substance;</section><section prefix="(2)">in, about, or in connection with:<section prefix="(i)">a blast furnace;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a distillery where an alcoholic beverage is manufactured, bottled, wrapped, or packed;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a railroad;</section><section prefix="(iv)">an engineer, fireman, or pilot on a vessel that is engaged in commerce; or</section><section prefix="(v)">a dock or wharf other than a marina where pleasure vessels are sold or served; or</section></section><section prefix="(3)">in, about, or in connection with:<section prefix="(i)">the erection or repair of an electrical wire;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the cleaning, oiling, or wiping of machinery; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">an occupation that is prohibited by law.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, a minor under the age of 16 may not be employed or allowed to work:<section prefix="(1)">during the school hours set for that minor;</section><section prefix="(2)">about or in connection with an acid, dye, gas, lye, or paint;</section><section prefix="(3)">at, about, or in connection with:<section prefix="(i)">an airport;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a brickyard;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a lumberyard;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a workroom or work site where goods are manufactured or processed;</section><section prefix="(v)">scaffolding; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">a vessel when engaged in navigation or commerce; or</section></section><section prefix="(4)">in, about, or in connection with:<section prefix="(i)">construction;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an occupation that causes dust in an injurious quantity;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a manufacturing occupation;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a mechanical occupation;</section><section prefix="(v)">a processing occupation; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">the adjustment, cleaning, or operation of power-driven machinery except:<section prefix="1.">an office machine; or</section><section prefix="2.">machinery used in a school or government institution as part of vocational training.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner may prohibit minors being employed in an occupation if:<section prefix="(1)">after a public hearing, the Commissioner determines that employment in the occupation should be prohibited to minors;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Commissioner adopts by reference a determination by the United States Secretary of Labor under the federal Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 that the occupation is hazardous; or</section><section prefix="(3)">after investigation, the Commissioner determines that the occupation is injurious to:<section prefix="(i)">the health or welfare of minors; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the morals of minors under the age of 16 years.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
