<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-11-505.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>505.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor's Workforce Investment Board shall establish an advisory committee to:<section prefix="(i)">identify the workforce needs and the education and training requirements of employment fields with available or growing opportunities;</section><section prefix="(ii)">identify the workforce and education and training needs of regions of the State that have high levels of unemployment;</section><section prefix="(iii)">examine the use of individual educational training accounts by other states that assist state residents in paying for education and training programs;</section><section prefix="(iv)">make recommendations regarding an individual educational training account pilot program; and</section><section prefix="(v)">recommend a pathways for academic career and employment program to provide grants to community colleges for the development of projects in coordination with:<section prefix="1.">institutions of postsecondary education located in the State;</section><section prefix="2.">the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation;</section><section prefix="3.">the Department of Business and Economic Development; and</section><section prefix="4.">the Governor's Workforce Investment Board.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The advisory committee shall include representatives from:<section prefix="(i)">the Governor's Workforce Investment Board;</section><section prefix="(ii)">institutions of postsecondary education located in the State, including community colleges and private career schools;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Department of Business and Economic Development;</section><section prefix="(v)">businesses and industries located in the State, including at least one representative from the biotechnology industry; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">labor organizations located in the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Governor's Workforce Investment Board shall provide staff for the advisory committee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On or before June 1 of each year, the Governor's Workforce Investment Board shall submit a report on its findings and recommendations to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the Senate Education, Health, and Environmental Affairs Committee and the House Committee on Ways and Means on the implementation of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
