<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-909" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-8-909</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the provisions of this section, benefits based on service in covered employment under &#xA7;&#xA7; 8-208(a) and 8-212(c) of this title shall be payable in the same amount, on the same terms, and subject to the same conditions as benefits payable on the basis of other service in covered employment.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With respect to services performed in an instructional, research, or principal administrative capacity for an educational institution, benefits may not be paid based on those services for any week of unemployment that begins during:<section prefix="(i)">a period between 2 successive academic years;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a similar period between 2 regular but not successive terms; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a period of contractually provided paid sabbatical leave.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection applies only to any individual who:<section prefix="(i)">performs the services in an instructional, research, or principal administrative capacity in the first of 2 academic years or terms; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">has a contract or reasonable assurance that the individual will perform the services in an instructional, research, or principal administrative capacity for any educational institution in the second of the 2 academic years or terms.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With respect to services performed for an educational institution in any capacity other than instructional, research, or principal administrative, benefits may not be paid on the basis of the services for any week of unemployment that begins during a period between 2 successive academic years or terms.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection applies to any individual who:<section prefix="(i)">performs the services described in this subsection in the first of 2 academic years or terms; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">has a reasonable assurance that the individual will perform the services in the second of the 2 successive academic years or terms.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Before July 1 of each year, each educational institution shall provide the Department with the name and Social Security number of each individual who has a reasonable assurance of performing covered employment described under this subsection in the next academic year.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If an individual whose name and Social Security number are required to be submitted to the Department under paragraph (3) of this subsection is not given an opportunity to perform the services for the educational institution for the next successive year or term, the individual shall be eligible for benefits retroactively if the individual:<section prefix="(i)">files a timely claim for each week;</section><section prefix="(ii)">was denied benefits solely under this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">is otherwise eligible for benefits.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With respect to services described in subsections (b) and (c) of this section, an individual may not be eligible for benefits based on the services for any week that begins during an established and customary vacation period or holiday recess.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection applies to any individual who:<section prefix="(i)">performs the services in the period immediately before the vacation period or holiday recess; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">has a reasonable assurance that the individual will perform the services in the period immediately following the vacation period or holiday recess.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "educational service agency" means a governmental entity that is established and operated exclusively to provide educational service to one or more educational institutions.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If any service described in subsection (b) or (c) of this section is performed by an individual in an educational institution while in the employ of an educational service agency, the individual is subject to subsections (b), (c), and (d) of this section and benefits may not be paid if not allowed under subsection (b), (c), or (d) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If any service described in subsection (a) of this section is provided by an individual to or on behalf of an educational institution, the individual is subject to subsections (b), (c), and (d) of this section and benefits may not be paid if not allowed under subsections (b), (c), and (d) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
