<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-4-315</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>315</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If, in addition to meeting the requirements for an injunction under &#xA7; 4-314 of this subtitle, a plaintiff alleges that, unless a temporary restraining order is issued before a court holds a hearing on issuance of other injunctive relief in a case that involves or grows out of a labor dispute, substantial and irreparable injury to the property of the plaintiff is unavoidable, the court may issue a temporary restraining order in accordance with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The court shall pass a show cause order that gives each party whom the plaintiff seeks to have restrained a reasonable period of at least 48 hours in which to show cause why the court should not issue a temporary restraining order.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A show cause order shall be served on each party whom the plaintiff seeks to have restrained as provided in the show cause order.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On expiration of the period to show cause, the court may issue a temporary restraining order if on the basis of testimony or, in the discretion of the court, an affidavit, the court finds that issuance of a temporary injunction would be justified if a hearing were held.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A temporary restraining order issued under this section is effective for the period that the court sets but not more than 5 days.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a hearing for a temporary injunction begins before the expiration of the period set under this subsection, the court may continue the temporary restraining order until the court decides whether to issue the temporary injunction.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Unless the court continues a temporary restraining order in accordance with paragraph (2) of this subsection, then on expiration of the period set under this subsection, the order is void and may not be renewed or extended.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
