<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-11-901</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>901</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is an Education and Workforce Training Coordinating Council for Correctional Institutions under the jurisdiction of the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services and the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Council consists of 14 members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Four of the members of the Council shall be residents of this State appointed by the Governor for a term of 4 years who each shall serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies as follows:<section prefix="(i)">two representing the business community;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a former offender; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">one member of the general public.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The following officials shall serve ex officio:<section prefix="(i)">the Secretary of Public Safety and Correctional Services;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the State Superintendent of Schools;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Secretary of Higher Education;</section><section prefix="(v)">the Secretary of Business and Economic Development;</section><section prefix="(vi)">the president of a community college in the State;</section><section prefix="(vii)">the Chair of the Governor's Workforce Investment Board;</section><section prefix="(viii)">the Director of Education and Workforce Skills Training for Correctional Institutions;</section><section prefix="(ix)">an official from a local correctional facility; and</section><section prefix="(x)">the county superintendent of schools from a county where a correctional institution of the Division of Correction is located, who shall be selected by the State Superintendent.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each member of the Council:<section prefix="(1)">serves without compensation; but</section><section prefix="(2)">is entitled to reimbursement for expenses in accordance with the Standard State Travel Regulations.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary of Public Safety and Correctional Services and the Secretary shall serve as cochairs of the Council.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Council:<section prefix="(i)">shall meet at least four times per year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall designate the time and place of its meetings; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">may adopt rules for the conduct of its meetings.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Council shall be within the Department for administrative and budgetary purposes.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Department shall provide technical and clerical assistance and support to the Council.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
