<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-105" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-105</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Before a governmental unit may issue a license or permit to an employer to engage in an activity in which the employer might employ a covered employee, the employer shall submit to the governmental unit:<section prefix="(1)">a certificate of compliance with this title; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the number of a workers' compensation insurance policy or binder.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall provide blank application forms to each governmental unit that issues a license or permit under State law for applicants for the license or permit to use to get a certificate of compliance.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The application form shall require information that will allow the Commission to determine whether the employer is in compliance with this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To get a certificate of compliance with this title, an employer shall submit to the Commission an application on the form that the Commission provides.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Within 10 days after the Commission receives an application form under this section, the Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">determine whether the applicant is in compliance with this title; and</section><section prefix="(2)">mail to the applicant:<section prefix="(i)">a certificate of compliance; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a notice of rejection, which shall include a statement of the reasons for the rejection.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An applicant who receives a notice of rejection may:<section prefix="(1)">reapply for a certificate of compliance; or</section><section prefix="(2)">appeal the rejection in accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-222 and 10-223 of the State Government Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commission shall adopt reasonable regulations to administer this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Money for the administration of this section shall be included in the annual State budget.</section>
  </text>
</law>
