<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-3-903</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>903</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An employer may not fail to properly classify an individual who performs work for remuneration paid by the employer.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An employer has failed to properly classify an individual when an employer-employee relationship exists as determined under subsection (c) of this section but the employer has not classified the individual as an employee.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 3-903.1 of this subtitle, for purposes of enforcement of this subtitle only, work performed by an individual for remuneration paid by an employer shall be presumed to create an employer-employee relationship, unless:<section prefix="(i)">the individual is an exempt person; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an employer demonstrates that:<section prefix="1.">the individual who performs the work is free from control and direction over its performance both in fact and under the contract;</section><section prefix="2.">the individual customarily is engaged in an independent business or occupation of the same nature as that involved in the work; and</section><section prefix="3.">the work is:</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Work is outside of the usual course of business of the person for whom it is performed under paragraph (1) of this subsection if:<section prefix="(i)">the individual performs the work off the employer's premises;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the individual performs work that is not integrated into the employer's operation; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the work performed is unrelated to the employer's business.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">By contract, an employer may engage another business entity, which may have its own employees, to do the same type of work in which the employer engages, at the same location where the employer is working, without establishing an employer-employee relationship between the two contracting entities.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commissioner shall adopt regulations to explain further and provide specific examples of the application of subsection (c) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
