<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="gle" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-3-414</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "federal certificate" means a certificate that the United States Department of Labo...</catch_line>
  <order_by>414</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "federal certificate" means a certificate that the United States Department of Labor issues to a work activities center or other sheltered workshop to allow the workshop to pay an individual less than the wage otherwise required for that individual under the federal Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to a blind individual who works in a sheltered workshop of Blind Industries and Services of Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subject to the limitations in this section, the Commissioner may authorize a work activities center or other sheltered workshop to pay a mentally or physically disabled employee of the workshop less than the minimum wage otherwise required under this subtitle for the employee.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To authorize a work activities center or other sheltered workshop to pay less than the minimum wage, the Commissioner shall:<section prefix="(i)">issue a State certificate that sets wages for employees of the workshop;</section><section prefix="(ii)">accept a federal certificate for the workshop; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">grant an exception for the workshop but only if:<section prefix="1.">the Commissioner has not issued a State certificate for the workshop;</section><section prefix="2.">the workshop is not eligible for a federal certificate; and</section><section prefix="3.">the Commissioner investigates and holds a hearing on the exception.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner shall accept a federal certificate if a work activities center or other sheltered workshop submits that certificate to the Commissioner within 10 days after the workshop receives the certificate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each certificate that the Commissioner issues under this section shall state the period for which the certificate is in effect.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The acceptance of a federal certificate does not apply automatically to an individual whom a work activities center or other sheltered workshop continues to employ after the individual completes a training program that the workshop runs.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner may revoke acceptance of a federal certificate if:<section prefix="(i)">the United States Department of Labor revokes the federal certificate; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">at any time before revocation by the Department of Labor and after an investigation and hearing, the Commissioner finds good cause to revoke the acceptance.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner shall send notice of a hearing under this subsection, by certified mail, to the holder of the federal certificate at least 30 days before the hearing.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
