<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="gle" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-10-126</section_number>
  <catch_line>** IN EFFECT UNTIL OCTOBER 1, 2013 PER CHAPTER 570 OF 2012**...</catch_line>
  <order_by>126</order_by>
  <text>** IN EFFECT UNTIL OCTOBER 1, 2013 PER CHAPTER 570 OF 2012**<section prefix="(a)">Within 90 days after the close of each fiscal year, the Board shall submit to the Governor an annual report that includes a detailed statement of:<section prefix="(1)">the condition and expenses of the Fund in detail;</section><section prefix="(2)">growth of the Fund;</section><section prefix="(3)">changes in earned premiums of the Fund;</section><section prefix="(4)">changes in the number of policyholders of the Fund;</section><section prefix="(5)">the degree of the Fund's personnel flexibility;</section><section prefix="(6)">trends in the overall market share; and</section><section prefix="(7)">trends in the premium to expense ratio.</section></section><section prefix="(b)"><section prefix="(1)">On or before October 1 of each year, the Fund shall submit to the Governor:<section prefix="(i)">a copy of each policy form that the Fund will use during the next calendar year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the schedule of premium rates that the Fund will charge for the next calendar year;</section><section prefix="(iii)">information about provision for claim payment, as defined in &#xA7; 11-330(a) of the Insurance Article, for each class for which the Fund writes coverage; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">other information that the Governor requests about premium rates, including classes, financial information, and losses.</section></section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">Information required under paragraph (1)(ii) through (iv) of this subsection shall be submitted on the form that the Governor requires.</section><section prefix="(ii)">The form shall conform as closely as possible to the form that a rating organization uses to comply with &#xA7;&#xA7; 11-307, 11-329, and 11-330 of the Insurance Article.</section></section></section></text>
</law>
