<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-506" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-8-506</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A hearing examiner shall conduct a hearing or appeal in a manner that ascertains the substantial rights of the parties.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A hearing examiner is not bound by statutory or common law rules of evidence or technical rules of procedure.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A hearing examiner shall consider evidence offered in accordance with &#xA7; 10-213 of the State Government Article.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A hearing examiner may not participate in any proceeding in which the hearing examiner has a direct or indirect interest.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The status of the Secretary as a party to a case may not constitute a direct or indirect interest as to a hearing examiner.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, ex parte communications are subject to &#xA7; 10-219 of the State Government Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Section 10-219(d) of the State Government Article does not apply to ex parte communications under this subtitle.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A hearing examiner may consolidate claims by more than one individual or claims by a single individual for 2 or more weeks of unemployment if:<section prefix="(i)">the same or substantially similar evidence is relevant and material to the matters at issue; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">in the judgment of the hearing examiner, the consolidation would not be prejudicial to a party.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When claims are consolidated under this subsection, the hearing examiner may:<section prefix="(i)">set the same time and place for considering each claim;</section><section prefix="(ii)">conduct joint hearings;</section><section prefix="(iii)">make a single record of the proceedings; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">consider evidence that is introduced in a proceeding for one claim as having been introduced for another claim.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A record shall be kept, in accordance with &#xA7; 10-218 of the State Government Article, of all testimony and proceedings before a hearing examiner.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Testimony shall be transcribed if:<section prefix="(i)">judicial review is initiated; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the hearing examiner or the Board of Appeals orders a transcription.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A witness who is subpoenaed under this subtitle is entitled to compensation at a rate that the chief hearing examiner sets.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The compensation of a witness who is subpoenaed on behalf of the Lower Appeals Division or a claimant shall be considered part of the expense of administering this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Lower Appeals Division may not charge a claimant a fee in any proceeding under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A hearing examiner promptly shall give each party to a proceeding before it written notice of its decision by mailing the notice to each party at the last known address of the party or business address of a licensee in accordance with &#xA7; 10-209(a) of the State Government Article, or otherwise delivering the notice.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice shall:<section prefix="(i)">include the findings of fact and conclusions of law that support the decision;</section><section prefix="(ii)">be accompanied by any order necessary to give effect to the decision; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">conform to the requirements of &#xA7; 10-221 of the State Government Article.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
