<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-8-1201</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Affected employee" means an individual who has been continuously on the payroll of an affected unit for at least 3 months immediately before the employing unit submits a work sharing plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Affected unit" means a specific plant, department, shift, or other definable unit of an employing unit:<section prefix="(1)">that has at least 2 employees; and</section><section prefix="(2)">to which an approved work sharing plan applies.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Approved work sharing plan" means a plan that satisfies the purpose under &#xA7; 8-1202 of this subtitle and receives the approval of the Secretary.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Employer association" means:<section prefix="(1)">an association that is a party to a collective bargaining agreement under which it may negotiate a work sharing plan; or</section><section prefix="(2)">an association authorized by all of its members to become a party to a work sharing plan.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Normal weekly work hours" means the lesser of:<section prefix="(1)">the number of hours in a week that an employee usually works for the regular employing unit; or</section><section prefix="(2)">40 hours.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Work sharing benefit" means benefits payable to an affected employee for work performed under an approved work sharing plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Work sharing benefit" includes benefits payable to a federal civilian employee or former servicemember under Title 5, Chapter 85 of the United States Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Work sharing benefit" does not include benefits that are otherwise payable under this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Work sharing employer" means an employing unit or employer association for which a work sharing plan has been approved.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Work sharing plan" means a plan of an employing unit or employer association under which:<section prefix="(1)">normal weekly work hours of affected employees are reduced; and</section><section prefix="(2)">affected employees share the work that remains after the reduction.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
