<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-10-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>** TAKES EFFECT OCTOBER 1, 2013 PER CHAPTER 570 OF 2012 **...</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>** TAKES EFFECT OCTOBER 1, 2013 PER CHAPTER 570 OF 2012 **<section prefix="(a)">On and after October 1, 2013:<section prefix="(1)">the Fund may not hire new employees; and</section><section prefix="(2)">employees of the Fund:<section prefix="(i)">may remain employees of the Fund;</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall continue to be State employees only if they remain employees of the Fund;</section><section prefix="(iii)">may not be required to be employees of the Company;</section><section prefix="(iv)">shall be subject to each law that applied to employees of the Fund immediately before October 1, 2013;</section><section prefix="(v)">shall be subject to the same terms and conditions of employment as existed immediately before October 1, 2013, including benefits, leave, and pay grade;</section><section prefix="(vi)">shall remain in the State retirement system only if they remain employees of the Fund;</section><section prefix="(vii)">except for changes in benefits or compensation applicable to State employees generally, may not be denied any compensation or benefit provided to employees of the Fund as of October 1, 2013;</section><section prefix="(viii)">may not be denied a promotion, based on the employee's status as an employee of the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">subject to subsection (b) of this section, may elect to be an employee of the Company.</section></section></section><section prefix="(b)">If an employee of the Fund intends to elect to be an employee of the Company under subsection (a)(2)(ix) of this section, the Company shall:<section prefix="(1)">require the employee to make the election in writing; and</section><section prefix="(2)">provide the employee with information that:<section prefix="(i)">states that the election of the employee to become an employee of the Company is voluntary and irrevocable; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">fully discloses the terms of employment with the Company.</section></section></section><section prefix="(c)">An employee of the Company may not elect to be an employee of the Fund.</section></text>
</law>
