<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-107" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-2-107</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to any other units, the Division shall include the units enumerated in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is an Employment Standards Service Unit in the Division.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Under the direction of the Commissioner, the Employment Standards Service Unit shall:<section prefix="(i)">enforce Title 3, Subtitle 2 of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">carry out Title 3, Subtitle 3 of this article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">enforce Title 3, Subtitle 4 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">enforce Title 3, Subtitle 5 of this article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">There is a State Mediation and Conciliation Service in the Division.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a research and information unit in the Division.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Under the direction of the Commissioner, the research and information unit shall collect, organize, and report statistical information on matters within the jurisdiction of the Division.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">There is a Safety Engineering and Education Service in the Division.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Prevailing Wage Unit in the Division.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Under the direction of the Commissioner, the Prevailing Wage Unit shall administer and enforce Title 17, Subtitle 2 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Notwithstanding the funding provisions of &#xA7; 3-919 of this article, for fiscal year 2007 and for each subsequent fiscal year, the Governor shall include in the annual budget bill submitted to the General Assembly an appropriation for the Division of Labor and Industry sufficient to implement the provisions of this section, including amounts not less than:<section prefix="(1)">$315,000 for implementation of the Employment Standards Service Unit in the Division; and</section><section prefix="(2)">$385,000 for implementation of the Prevailing Wage Unit in the Division.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
