<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-1002" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-1002</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An award is payable out of the Fund in accordance with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Unless an application for review has been timely filed under subsection (g) of this section or a notice of appeal timely served, an employer is in default on a claim by a covered employee or the dependents of a covered employee if the employer fails to:<section prefix="(1)">secure payment of compensation in accordance with &#xA7; 9-402 of this title;</section><section prefix="(2)">except for a governmental self-insurance group authorized by &#xA7; 9-404 of this title, deposit security in accordance with &#xA7; 9-405 of this title that is:<section prefix="(i)">sufficient to cover a claim by a covered employee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">at least $100,000; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">pay compensation in accordance with an award within 30 days after the date of the award.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If an employer is in default under subsection (b) of this section, promptly after the expiration of 30 days after the date of the award, the Commission shall notify the employer that:<section prefix="(1)">the employer is in default; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the license or permit of the employer to do business in the State may be suspended.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On receipt of a notice of default, an employer promptly shall pay the award.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To object to an award, the employer, within 30 days after receipt of the notice of default, shall notify the Commission of the reasons why the employer objects to the award.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The notice of objection by the employer to the Commission serves as an application for review under subsection (g) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the employer does not pay the award and does not notify the Commission of its objection to the award in accordance with subsection (d) of this section, the covered employee or the dependents of the covered employee may apply to the Director for payment from the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">On receipt of an application for payment, the Fund may:<section prefix="(1)">pay the award; or</section><section prefix="(2)">apply for review under subsection (g) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The provisions of Subtitle 7 of this title about procedure and the right to appeal apply to:<section prefix="(i)">a covered employee or the dependents of a covered employee who file a claim;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the uninsured employer; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Fund.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The right of review of the Fund includes:<section prefix="(i)">raising issues;</section><section prefix="(ii)">discovery; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">a hearing before the Commission.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
