<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-313</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>313</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission may require an insurer or a self-insurer to submit a report or analysis that the Commission considers useful to increase public understanding of the purpose, administrative procedures, costs, coverage, or effectiveness of workers' compensation in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each insurer and each self-insurer, that provides workers' compensation insurance in the State, shall submit a quarterly case payment report to the Commission:<section prefix="(i)">on the printed forms or computer tapes provided to the insurer or self-insurer by the Commission, including a specially designated printed form or computer tape for the last case payment report for each covered employee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">that includes all information required by the Commission or an explanation of why any required information is omitted from the report.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An insurer or a self-insurer who is required to submit a report under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall submit the report within 40 days after the date on which the Commission mails the printed forms or computer tapes to the insurer or self-insurer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission may assess a fine not exceeding $1,000 against an insurer or a self-insurer if the insurer or self-insurer:<section prefix="(1)">fails to timely file a report under subsection (b) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(2)">files a report under subsection (b) of this section that includes inaccurate or insufficient information.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the Commission determines that, after due diligence an insurer or a self-insurer is unable to timely submit the report required under subsection (b) of this section, the Commission may:<section prefix="(1)">waive the fine specified under subsection (c) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">grant the insurer or self-insurer the additional time that may be necessary.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
