<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-8-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"American aircraft" means an aircraft registered under the laws of the United States.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"American employer" means:<section prefix="(i)">a corporation organized under the laws of a state;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a partnership, if at least two-thirds of the partners are residents of the United States;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a resident of the United States; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">a trust, if all of the trustees are residents of the United States.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Vessel" means:<section prefix="(i)">a vessel that is documented or numbered under the laws of the United States; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a vessel that is not documented or numbered under the laws of the United States and is not documented under the laws of any foreign country whose crew performs service solely for:<section prefix="1.">a citizen or resident of the United States; or</section><section prefix="2.">a corporation organized under the laws of a state.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Employment that otherwise meets the requirements of &#xA7; 8-201 of this subtitle is covered employment if the employment is:<section prefix="(1)">performed in the State, including:<section prefix="(i)">employment performed on land that the United States government holds or owns; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">employment performed in interstate commerce; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">deemed to be performed in the State under an election made by an employer and approved by the Secretary under a reciprocal arrangement between the Secretary and a unit of another state or the federal government in accordance with Subtitle 7 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Employment that otherwise meets the requirements of &#xA7; 8-201 of this subtitle and is performed partly in this State is covered employment in its entirety if:<section prefix="(1)">the employment that is performed outside this State is incidental to the employment that is performed in this State, including employment that is temporary or transitory or that consists of isolated transactions;</section><section prefix="(2)">the employment that is performed in this State is not incidental to employment that is performed in any particular state but:<section prefix="(i)">the base of operations is in this State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the place from which the employment is controlled or directed is in this State; or</section></section><section prefix="(3)">the employment:<section prefix="(i)">is performed by an individual who is a resident of this State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is not performed in part in a state in which the employment is controlled or directed or in which the base of operations is located.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Employment that otherwise meets the requirements of &#xA7; 8-201 of this subtitle is covered employment if:<section prefix="(1)">the employment is:<section prefix="(i)">controlled or directed from this State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">performed in any state, the Virgin Islands, or Canada; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">not insured under the unemployment insurance law of any other state, the Virgin Islands, or Canada;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">notwithstanding &#xA7; 8-210(a) of this subtitle and except as provided in &#xA7; 8-210(b) of this subtitle, the employment is performed by an officer or crew member of a vessel or American aircraft on or in connection with it if:<section prefix="(i)">the office from which the operations of the vessel on navigable waters or the American aircraft are conducted is within this State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the operation of the vessel or American aircraft within this State or both in and outside the United States ordinarily and regularly is controlled and directed from in this State; or</section></section><section prefix="(3)">the employment is performed by a citizen of the United States for an American employer outside of the United States, the Virgin Islands, and Canada and is not otherwise covered under this section if the American employer:<section prefix="(i)">has its principal place of business in the United States located in this State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">does not have a place of business in the United States, but the American employer is:<section prefix="1.">a resident of this State;</section><section prefix="2.">a corporation that is organized under the laws of this State; or</section><section prefix="3.">a partnership or a trust and a plurality of the partners or trustees are residents of this State;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">has elected coverage under this title; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">has failed to elect coverage in any state and, not being covered under the unemployment insurance law in any other state, the employee has filed a claim for benefits under the law of this State based on the employment.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
