<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="gle" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-8-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>"Public employment office" means an employment office that does not charge a fee to provide services...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Public employment office" means an employment office that does not charge a fee to provide services and is:<section prefix="(i)">operated by the Department; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">maintained as part of a local, State, or federal system of employment offices.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Public employment office" includes a branch public employment office.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The General Assembly accepts the provisions of the Wagner-Peyser Act for establishment of a national employment system and for cooperation in promotion of the system in conformity with &#xA7; 4 of the Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Division of Workforce Development, established under &#xA7; 11-102 of this article, is the unit of the State designated to carry out &#xA7; 4 of the Wagner-Peyser Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary shall employ a staff for the Division of Workforce Development in accordance with &#xA7; 8-304 of this subtitle and regulations adopted by the United States Secretary of Labor.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">As necessary for administration of this title, the Division of Workforce Development shall establish and maintain public employment offices that do not charge a fee to individuals who seek employment.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">To establish and maintain public employment offices, the Secretary:<section prefix="(1)">may enter into an agreement with the Railroad Retirement Board or any other federal unit that is responsible for administration of an unemployment insurance law, a political subdivision of the State, or any private not-for-profit organization; and</section><section prefix="(2)">as part of the agreement, may accept money, services, or office space as a contribution to the Unemployment Insurance Administration Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Money in the Unemployment Insurance Administration Fund that the State receives under the Wagner-Peyser Act is available to the Division of Workforce Development for use under this section in accordance with that Act.</section>
  </text>
</law>
