<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-302" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-7-302</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An applicant for a license shall:<section prefix="(1)">submit to the Commissioner:<section prefix="(i)">an application on the form that the Commissioner provides; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">two recent, passport sized, color photographs of the applicant; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">pay to the Commissioner an application fee of $25.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The application shall state:<section prefix="(1)">the permanent place of residence of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(2)">each address where the applicant expects to reside while in the State;</section><section prefix="(3)">each farm labor contracting service that the applicant will perform for consideration;</section><section prefix="(4)">the name and address of each agricultural operation for whom the applicant will perform a farm labor contracting service, in the State, for consideration;</section><section prefix="(5)">the name and permanent address of each person who will act as custodian of records of wages that are required under this title to be kept;</section><section prefix="(6)">the number of migrant agricultural workers that the applicant expects to use in the State to perform a farm labor contracting service for consideration;</section><section prefix="(7)">if the applicant will provide housing or cause housing to be provided to a migrant agricultural worker:<section prefix="(i)">the name of each person who will provide the housing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">each address where the housing will be provided;</section></section><section prefix="(8)">if registration is required under the federal Migrant and Seasonal Agricultural Worker Protection Act, the registration identification number of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(9)">the name of a resident agent who is acceptable to the Commissioner;</section><section prefix="(10)">the consent of the applicant to service of process on the resident agent whenever the applicant leaves the State or otherwise is unavailable to accept service; and</section><section prefix="(11)">other relevant information that the Commissioner requires.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If information required under subsection (b) of this section changes, the applicant or, if a license has been issued, the licensee shall give the Commissioner notice of the change within 10 days after the applicant or licensee knows or should have known of the change.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Information in an application or in a notice of change may not be used to imply legal responsibility on an agricultural operation for the care, custody, or activities of a migrant agricultural worker whom a farm labor contractor provides.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commissioner shall make application forms reasonably available at convenient locations throughout the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
