<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-317" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-317</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is an Advisory Committee on the budget of the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Advisory Committee consists of 12 members, appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each member appointed by the Governor serves at the pleasure of the Governor.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Governor shall appoint a chairman from among the members of the Advisory Committee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In making the appointments, the Governor shall:<section prefix="(1)">ensure that each geographic region of the State is represented;</section><section prefix="(2)">ensure that various disciplines within the workers' compensation community are represented, including:<section prefix="(i)">business;</section><section prefix="(ii)">labor;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the insurance industry;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the vocational rehabilitation industry;</section><section prefix="(v)">the medical profession;</section><section prefix="(vi)">claimants' bar; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">defense bar; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">consider, in consultation with the chairman, the recommendations made by representatives of each of these disciplines.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of an appointed member is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of members are staggered.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member may be reappointed.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Members of the Advisory Committee shall serve without compensation, but each member shall be reimbursed for necessary travel and other expenses incurred in the performance of official committee duties in accordance with the Standard State Travel Regulations.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commission shall provide meeting space, budget analysis, and staff support for the Advisory Committee.</section>
  </text>
</law>
