<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-638" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-8-638</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An employer that has paid to the Secretary, wholly or partly, contributions or interest alleged to be due may submit to the Secretary an application for:<section prefix="(1)">an adjustment in connection with contributions then due; or</section><section prefix="(2)">if an adjustment cannot be made, a refund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An employing unit that wishes to apply for an adjustment or refund shall apply within the later of:<section prefix="(1)">1 year from the date on which the payment was made; or</section><section prefix="(2)">3 years from the last day of the calendar quarter for which the payment was made.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Secretary determines that the contested amount or any part of it was collected erroneously, the Secretary shall:<section prefix="(i)">allow the employing unit to make an adjustment without interest to the contribution then due by the employing unit; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if an adjustment cannot be made, refund the amount without interest.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary shall refund a contribution that was collected erroneously from the Unemployment Insurance Fund and interest that was collected erroneously from the Special Administrative Expense Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If an employing unit reported wages that have been included in the determination of an eligible claimant for benefits, the Secretary shall reduce any adjustment or refund by the amount of benefits received by the claimant that are chargeable to the employing unit.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Within the time limitation for an application under subsection (b) of this section and in accordance with subsection (c) of this section, the Secretary, on the Secretary's own initiative, may make an adjustment or grant a refund without interest.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a claim for an adjustment or refund is rejected, the Secretary shall mail a written notice of rejection to the employing unit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Within 15 days after receiving a notice of rejection, the employing unit may petition the Appeals Board for a formal hearing.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The petition shall state the grounds on which the refund or adjustment is claimed.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board of Appeals shall:<section prefix="(i)">grant a hearing requested under this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">notify the employing unit of the time and place of the hearing;</section><section prefix="(iii)">after the hearing, pass an order that the Board of Appeals considers to be just and lawful; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">give a copy of the order to the employing unit.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">This title does not:<section prefix="(1)">authorize an adjustment or refund of money that was due under the law in effect at the time that the money was paid; or</section><section prefix="(2)">prohibit a refund required under &#xA7; 8-640 of this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
