<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-1105" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-8-1105</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The weekly amount of extended benefits payable for a week of total unemployment during an individual's eligibility period is equal to the amount of regular benefits, including allowances for dependents, payable to the individual for a week of total unemployment during the applicable benefit year.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The total amount of extended benefits payable to an eligible individual for the applicable benefit year of the individual may not be less than the lesser of:<section prefix="(1)">50% of the total amount of regular benefits, including allowances for dependents, payable to the individual during that benefit year;</section><section prefix="(2)">13 times the average weekly benefit amount of the individual; or</section><section prefix="(3)">39 times the average weekly benefit amount of the individual, reduced by the amount of regular benefits paid or deemed paid to the individual during that benefit year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the benefit year of an individual ends during an extended benefit period, the balance of extended benefits to which the individual is entitled for weeks of unemployment beginning after the benefit year shall be reduced, but not below zero, by an amount computed by:<section prefix="(1)">determining the number of weeks for which the individual received any amounts as trade readjustment allowances under the federal Trade Act of 1974 within that benefit year; and</section><section prefix="(2)">multiplying the number determined under item (1) of this subsection by the weekly amount of extended benefits of the individual.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An individual who otherwise is eligible to receive benefits may not be denied regular benefits or extended benefits for any week because the individual:<section prefix="(1)">is in a training program that the United States Secretary of Labor approves under 19 U.S.C. &#xA7; 2296(a)(1); or</section><section prefix="(2)">leaves work that is not suitable to enter a training program that the United States Secretary of Labor approves under 19 U.S.C. &#xA7; 2296(a)(1) because:<section prefix="(i)">the work was not of substantially equal or a higher skill level than the past adversely affected employment of the individual as defined under 19 U.S.C. &#xA7; 2296(f); and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the wages for the work were less than 80% of the average weekly wage of the individual as determined under 19 U.S.C. &#xA7; 2296(e).</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
