<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-5-210</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>210</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "apparatus" means any apparatus, device, machinery, or mechanical equipment.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commissioner or an authorized representative of the Commissioner may prohibit use of any apparatus, if, after an inspection, the Commissioner or authorized representative of the Commissioner determines that:<section prefix="(1)">the apparatus or part of the apparatus violates an occupational safety and health standard; and</section><section prefix="(2)">there is a substantial probability that death or serious physical harm could result from continued use.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To prohibit use of any apparatus or part of any apparatus, the Commissioner or authorized representative of the Commissioner shall give an employer or the agent in charge of such operation written notice that prohibits use.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A copy of a notice under subsection (c) of this section:<section prefix="(i)">shall be attached to the apparatus; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">may not be removed until the apparatus is made safe and each required safeguard is provided.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Use of any apparatus is prohibited while a notice under this section is posted on the apparatus.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any person aggrieved by a decision of the Commissioner under this section may bring an action to modify or vacate the decision on the ground that it is unlawful or unreasonable.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An action under this subsection shall be brought in the circuit court for the county where the place of employment is located.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In a proceeding under this subsection, a court may not stay an order of the Commissioner unless:<section prefix="(i)">the court gives the Commissioner notice and an opportunity for a hearing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the aggrieved person posts security or meets each other condition that the court considers proper.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
