<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-11-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is an Apprenticeship and Training Council as part of the Division of Labor and Industry. The Council consists of 12 members all of whom shall be appointed by the Governor of Maryland, with the advice of the Secretary and with the advice and consent of the Senate of Maryland.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Four of the members shall be representatives of employee organizations; one shall be an employee; five shall be representatives of employers and two shall be appointed from the general public.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The membership of the Council shall include representation by black and female persons and individuals with disabilities. Consultants to the Council shall include representation by black and female persons and individuals with disabilities.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In advising the Governor, the Secretary shall give consideration to a balanced geographic representation from all of Maryland and a representative sampling and mix of Maryland industry.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">One member shall be appointed as Chairman by the Governor, with the advice of the Secretary, and serve as Chairman at the pleasure of the Governor. The Assistant State Superintendent, Career and Technology Education, and the Maryland State Director of the Bureau of Apprenticeship and Training, U.S. Department of Labor, shall serve as consultants to the Council without vote.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Governor, with the advice of the Secretary may appoint up to three additional consultants to the Council from the public at large.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">All appointments as members of the Council shall be for terms of 4 years.</section>
  </text>
</law>
