<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="gle" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-506</section_number>
  <catch_line>A covered employee or a dependent of a covered employee is not entitled to compensation or benefits ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>506</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A covered employee or a dependent of a covered employee is not entitled to compensation or benefits under this title as a result of:<section prefix="(1)">an intentional, self-inflicted accidental personal injury, compensable hernia, or occupational disease; or</section><section prefix="(2)">an attempt to injure or kill another.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A covered employee or a dependent of a covered employee is not entitled to compensation or benefits under this title as a result of an accidental personal injury, compensable hernia, or occupational disease if:<section prefix="(1)">the accidental personal injury, compensable hernia, or occupational disease was caused solely by the effect on the covered employee of:<section prefix="(i)">a depressant, hallucinogenic, hypnotic, narcotic, or stimulant drug; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">another drug that makes the covered employee incapable of satisfactory job performance; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the drug was not administered or taken in accordance with the prescription of a physician.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A covered employee or a dependent of a covered employee is not entitled to compensation or benefits under this title as a result of an accidental personal injury, compensable hernia, or occupational disease if the accidental personal injury, compensable hernia, or occupational disease was caused solely by the intoxication of the covered employee while on duty.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "primary cause" means the cause that is first in importance.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, a covered employee or dependent of a covered employee is not entitled to compensation or benefits under this title, except for medical benefits under &#xA7;&#xA7; 9-660 and 9-661 of this title, as a result of an accidental personal injury, compensable hernia, or occupational disease, if the primary cause of the accidental personal injury, compensable hernia, or occupational disease was the effect on the covered employee of a controlled dangerous substance defined in &#xA7; 5-101 of the Criminal Law Article or listed in Title 5, Subtitle 4 of the Criminal Law Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Compensation or benefits shall not be denied under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph if the controlled dangerous substance was administered, taken, or used in accordance with the prescription of a physician and the administering, taking, or use of the controlled dangerous substance was not excessive or abusive.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except for medical benefits under &#xA7;&#xA7; 9-660 and 9-661 of this title, a covered employee or dependent of a covered employee is not entitled to compensation or benefits under this title as a result of an accidental personal injury, compensable hernia, or occupational disease, if the primary cause of the accidental personal injury, compensable hernia, or occupational disease was the intoxication of the covered employee while on duty.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A covered employee or a dependent of a covered employee is not entitled to compensation or benefits under this title as a result of an accidental personal injury, compensable hernia, or occupational disease if the accidental personal injury, compensable hernia, or occupational disease was caused by the willful misconduct of the covered employee.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In a proceeding on a claim for compensation, there is, absent substantial evidence to the contrary, a presumption that an accidental personal injury, compensable hernia, or occupational disease:<section prefix="(1)">was not caused by the intent of the covered employee to injure or kill the covered employee or another individual;</section><section prefix="(2)">was not caused solely by the effect on the covered employee of:<section prefix="(i)">a depressant, hallucinogenic, hypnotic, narcotic, or stimulant drug; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">another drug that makes the covered employee incapable of satisfactory job performance; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">was not caused solely by the intoxication of the covered employee while on duty.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In a proceeding on a claim for compensation under subsection (d) of this section, there is, absent substantial evidence to the contrary, a presumption that:<section prefix="(1)">the effect on the covered employee of a controlled dangerous substance was not the primary cause of the accidental personal injury, compensable hernia, or occupational disease; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the intoxication of the covered employee was not the primary cause of the accidental personal injury, compensable hernia, or occupational disease.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
