<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="gle" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-602</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided in this section, the average weekly wage of a covered employee shall be...</catch_line>
  <order_by>602</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the average weekly wage of a covered employee shall be computed by determining the average of the weekly wages of the covered employee:<section prefix="(i)">when the covered employee is working full time; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">at the time of:<section prefix="1.">the accidental personal injury; or</section><section prefix="2.">the last injurious exposure of the covered employee to the hazards of an occupational disease.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of a computation under paragraph (1) of this subsection, wages shall include:<section prefix="(i)">tips; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the reasonable value of housing, lodging, meals, rent, and other similar advantages that the covered employee received from the employer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a covered employee establishes that, because of the age and experience of the covered employee at the time of the accidental personal injury or last injurious exposure to the hazards of the occupational disease, the wages of the covered employee could be expected to increase under normal circumstances, the expected increase may be taken into account when computing the average weekly wage of the covered employee under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For the purpose of computing the average weekly wage of an auxiliary police officer of Baltimore County who is a covered employee under &#xA7; 9-220(a) of this title or a member of a volunteer ambulance, ambulance and rescue, or fire company in Baltimore County who is a covered employee under &#xA7; 9-234 of this title, the wages of the covered employee shall be:<section prefix="(1)">if the covered employee had other employment at the time of the accidental personal injury or last injurious exposure, the salary or wages from the other employment;</section><section prefix="(2)">if the covered employee had had other employment but was not otherwise employed at the time of the accidental personal injury or last injurious exposure, the salary or wages last received by the covered employee from the other employment; or</section><section prefix="(3)">if the covered employee had never had other employment at the time of the accidental personal injury or last injurious exposure, an amount that allows minimum death or disability benefits under this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For the purpose of computing the average weekly wage of an individual engaged for fire fighting by the Department of Natural Resources who is a covered employee under &#xA7; 9-207 of this title, the wages of the covered employee shall be:<section prefix="(1)">the greater of:<section prefix="(i)">any salary or wages received by the covered employee for fire fighting; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">any salary or wages earned by the covered employee in other employment at the time of the accidental personal injury or last injurious exposure; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">if the covered employee did not receive wages for fire fighting or from other employment at the time of the accidental personal injury or last injurious exposure, an amount that allows the minimum compensation or death benefits under this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For the purpose of computing the average weekly wage of a handicapped student who is a covered employee under &#xA7; 9-228(a) of this title, the wages of the covered employee shall be the federal minimum wage that is in effect at the time of the accidental personal injury or last injurious exposure.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">For the purpose of computing the average weekly wage of a jockey who is a covered employee under &#xA7; 9-212 of this title, the wages of the covered employee shall be all of the earnings that the jockey earns as a jockey, including those derived from outside the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">For the purpose of computing the average weekly wage of a member of the organized militia of the State who is a covered employee under &#xA7; 9-215 of this title, the wages of the covered employee shall be the greater of:<section prefix="(1)">the wage provided for active duty in &#xA7; 13-406(b) of the Public Safety Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">the actual wages earned by the covered employee in employment in the National Guard; or</section><section prefix="(3)">the actual wages earned by the covered employee in the employee's civilian employment at the time of entry into State active duty.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, for the purpose of computing the average weekly wage of an individual who is a covered employee under &#xA7; 9-234 of this title, the wages of the covered employee shall be:<section prefix="(i)">for a covered employee who received a salary or wages from other employment at the time of the accidental personal injury or last injurious exposure, the salary or wages from the other employment; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">for a covered employee who did not receive a salary or wages from other employment at the time of the accidental personal injury or last injurious exposure:<section prefix="1.">if the covered employee derived income from a source other than salary or wages at the time of the accidental personal injury or last injurious exposure, an amount that allows the maximum compensation under this title;</section><section prefix="2.">if the covered employee was not engaged in a business enterprise at the time of the accidental personal injury or last injurious exposure, the weekly income last received by the covered employee when engaged in a business enterprise; or</section><section prefix="3.">if the covered employee had never been engaged in a business enterprise at the time of the accidental personal injury or last injurious exposure, an amount that allows the minimum compensation under this title.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A yearly stipend of $5,200 or less to help offset out-of-pocket expenses that a volunteer company, as defined in &#xA7; 9-234 of this title, pays to a member may not be used when determining the average weekly wage of the member.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">For the purpose of computing the average weekly wage of a prisoner who is a covered employee under &#xA7; 9-221 of this title, the wages of the covered employee shall be:<section prefix="(1)">the wages paid to the prisoner by the county; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a fair and reasonable amount determined by the Commission for meals and maintenance of the prisoner, but not more than the amount customarily received by the county for its own use by prisoners engaged in employment by other employers.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">For the purpose of computing the average weekly wage of a covered employee whose wages from full-time employment are paid partly by an employer and partly by the United States under a federal veterans' benefit law, the wages of the covered employee shall be the total amounts jointly paid to the covered employee when working full time.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">For the purpose of computing the average weekly wage of a volunteer deputy sheriff of Cecil County or an auxiliary volunteer of the Charles County Sheriff's Office who is a covered employee under &#xA7; 9-233 of this title, the wages of the covered employee shall be:<section prefix="(1)">if the covered employee had other employment at the time of the accidental personal injury or last injurious exposure, the wages from the other employment;</section><section prefix="(2)">if the covered employee had had other employment but was not otherwise employed at the time of the accidental personal injury or last injurious exposure, the wages last received by the covered employee from the other employment; or</section><section prefix="(3)">if the covered employee had never had other employment at the time of the accidental personal injury or last injurious exposure, an amount that allows minimum compensation under this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">For the purpose of computing the average weekly wage of a juror who is a covered employee under &#xA7; 9-213(a) of this title, the wages of the juror shall be the per diem received by the juror for jury duty.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only to a covered employee who:<section prefix="(i)">has suffered:<section prefix="1.">a serious permanent partial disability under &#xA7; 9-630 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="2.">a permanent total disability under &#xA7; 9-637 of this subtitle;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">was concurrently employed by more than one employer at the time of the accidental personal injury;</section><section prefix="(iii)">worked, on average, 20 hours per week or less in the employment in which the accidental personal injury occurred; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">as a result of the accidental personal injury, is unable to work at any employment the covered employee was engaged in at the time of the accidental personal injury or any similar type of employment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the covered employee earned weekly wages from another employment that exceeded the weekly wages the covered employee earned from the employment in which the accidental personal injury occurred, the average weekly wage of the covered employee shall be based on the weekly wages the covered employee earned in the other employment.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the covered employee earned weekly wages from two or more other employments and, for more than one of such employments, the weekly wages earned by the employee exceeded the weekly wages of the covered employee from the employment in which the accidental personal injury occurred, the average weekly wage of the covered employee shall be based on weekly wages of the employment where the employee earned the highest wages.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This subsection may not be interpreted as:<section prefix="(i)">except as provided in &#xA7;&#xA7; 9-630 and 9-637 of this subtitle, relieving from liability to pay compensation the employer in whose employment the accidental personal injury occurred;</section><section prefix="(ii)">creating any liability to pay compensation on the part of another employer in whose employment the accidental personal injury did not occur; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">requiring the weekly wages from the employments the employee was engaged in at the time of the accidental personal injury to be combined for purposes of computing the average weekly wage of the covered employee.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
