<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-8.5-106</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>106</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "health insurance benefits" includes payments for medical care, prescription drugs, vision care, medical savings accounts, and any other costs to provide health benefits, as defined in &#xA7; 213(d) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On or before March 15 of each year, the Secretary shall report to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly on:<section prefix="(1)">the name of each nonprofit and for profit employer with 10,000 or more employees in the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">the employer's definition of full-time employee and part-time employee;</section><section prefix="(3)">the number of full-time employees;</section><section prefix="(4)">the number of full-time employees eligible to receive health insurance benefits;</section><section prefix="(5)">the number of full-time employees receiving health insurance benefits from the employer;</section><section prefix="(6)">the source of health insurance benefits for those eligible full-time employees not receiving health insurance benefits through an employer subject to reporting under this title;</section><section prefix="(7)">the number of part-time employees;</section><section prefix="(8)">the number of part-time employees eligible to receive health insurance benefits;</section><section prefix="(9)">the number of part-time employees receiving health insurance benefits from the employer; and</section><section prefix="(10)">the source of health insurance benefits for those eligible part-time employees not receiving health insurance benefits through an employer subject to reporting under this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The information required under subsection (b) of this section shall be reported as of the information reporting date determined by the employer under &#xA7; 8.5-103(a)(1)(i) of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
