<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="gle" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-8-1001</section_number>
  <catch_line>An individual who otherwise is eligible to receive benefits is disqualified from receiving benefits ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1001</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual who otherwise is eligible to receive benefits is disqualified from receiving benefits if the Secretary finds that unemployment results from voluntarily leaving work without good cause.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A claimant who is otherwise eligible for benefits from the loss of full-time employment may not be disqualified from the benefits attributable to the full-time employment because the claimant voluntarily quit a part-time employment, if the claimant quit the part-time employment before the loss of the full-time employment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Secretary may find that a cause for voluntarily leaving is good cause only if:<section prefix="(1)">the cause is directly attributable to, arising from, or connected with:<section prefix="(i)">the conditions of employment; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the actions of the employing unit;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">an individual:<section prefix="(i)">is laid off from employment through no fault of the individual;</section><section prefix="(ii)">obtains subsequent employment that pays weekly wages that total less than 50% of the weekly wage earned in the employment from which the individual was laid off; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">leaves the subsequent employment to attend a training program for which the individual has been chosen that:<section prefix="1.">is offered under the Maryland Workforce Investment Act; or</section><section prefix="2.">otherwise is approved by the Secretary; or</section></section></section><section prefix="(3)">the cause is directly attributable to the individual or the individual's spouse, minor child, or parent being a victim of domestic violence as defined in &#xA7; 4-513 of the Family Law Article and the individual:<section prefix="(i)">reasonably believes that the individual's continued employment would jeopardize the individual's safety or the safety of the individual's spouse, minor child, or parent; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">provides one of the following types of documentation to the Secretary substantiating domestic violence:<section prefix="1.">an active or a recently issued temporary protective order under &#xA7; 4-505 of the Family Law Article, a protective order under &#xA7; 4-506 of the Family Law Article, or any other court order documenting the domestic violence; or</section><section prefix="2.">a police record documenting recent domestic violence.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A circumstance for voluntarily leaving work is valid only if it is:<section prefix="(i)">a substantial cause that is directly attributable to, arising from, or connected with conditions of employment or actions of the employing unit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">of such necessitous or compelling nature that the individual has no reasonable alternative other than leaving the employment; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">caused by the individual leaving employment to follow a spouse if:<section prefix="1.">the spouse:</section><section prefix="2.">the spouse's employer requires a mandatory transfer to a new location.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For determination of the application of paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection to an individual who leaves employment because of the health of the individual or another for whom the individual must care, the individual shall submit a written statement or other documentary evidence of the health problem from a hospital or physician.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition to other circumstances for which a disqualification may be imposed, neither good cause nor a valid circumstance exists and a disqualification shall be imposed if an individual leaves employment:<section prefix="(1)">to become self-employed;</section><section prefix="(2)">to accompany a spouse to a new location or to join a spouse in a new location, unless the requirements of subsection (c)(1)(iii) of this section are met; or</section><section prefix="(3)">to attend an educational institution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A disqualification under this section:<section prefix="(1)">shall begin with the first week for which unemployment is caused by voluntarily leaving without good cause; and</section><section prefix="(2)">subject to subsection (c) of this section, shall continue:<section prefix="(i)">if a valid circumstance exists, for a total of at least 5 but not more than 10 weeks, as determined by the Secretary based on the seriousness of the circumstance; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if a valid circumstance does not exist, until the individual is reemployed and has earned wages for covered employment that equal at least 15 times the weekly benefit amount of the individual.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
