<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-504" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-11-504</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A workforce investment training program is established to implement the federal Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This program shall provide employment, training, supportive and related services for unemployed individuals who are low income, for dislocated workers, and for those who are not low income, but who qualify under the federal Act as having barriers to employment, including, but not limited to, displaced homemakers, school dropouts, teenage parents, individuals with disabilities, older workers, veterans, and other participants as defined by the federal Act.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (iv) of this paragraph, the State Department of Transportation shall issue to training organizations weekly transit passes, in the form of magnetic passes or loaded smart cards, for local bus, light rail, or metro subway service provided by the Maryland Transit Administration.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The training organizations shall provide the weekly transit passes issued under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph to individuals receiving employment and training services under the program established in accordance with subsection (a) of this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A training organization shall reimburse the Department of Transportation for the cost of transit passes provided to the training organization under this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">To be eligible to receive transit passes under this paragraph, a training organization shall include in its contract with the local workforce investment board or local workforce investment agency a provision requiring reimbursement of the training organization for its costs under subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The County Commissioners of Carroll County may appropriate funds necessary to enter into contracts with private or public enterprises for the training or retraining of workers of those enterprises.</section>
  </text>
</law>
