<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-414" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-8-414</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Unemployment Insurance Administration Fund shall consist of:<section prefix="(1)">money received from a unit of the federal government or of another state to pay for a facility or service provided to the unit;</section><section prefix="(2)">money received under an insurance policy or surety bond or from any other source for loss that the Unemployment Insurance Administration Fund sustains or for damage to equipment or supplies bought with money from the Fund;</section><section prefix="(3)">money transferred from the Special Administrative Expense Fund under &#xA7; 8-422(d) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(4)">proceeds from the disposal of surplus equipment or supplies that were bought with money from the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(5)">money received under the Wagner-Peyser Act for use in accordance with that Act and money for administration of this title that:<section prefix="(i)">is appropriated by the General Assembly;</section><section prefix="(ii)">subject to &#xA7; 8-405 of this subtitle, is received from a unit of the federal government; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">is received from any other source.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to &#xA7; 8-405 of this subtitle and paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Secretary shall use the Unemployment Insurance Administration Fund to pay the administrative costs of this title including the costs of:<section prefix="(i)">office space in accordance with &#xA7; 8-421(c) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the surety bond of the State Treasurer under &#xA7; 5-102.1 of the State Government Article for the Unemployment Insurance Administration Fund.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Money in the Unemployment Insurance Administration Fund received from a unit of the federal government or appropriated by the General Assembly to carry out this title may be used only for the purposes and in the amounts that the United States Secretary of Labor finds necessary to administer this title efficiently and properly.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
