<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="gle" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-733</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section does not apply to a termination of temporary total disability benefits if:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>733</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section does not apply to a termination of temporary total disability benefits if:<section prefix="(i)">the covered employee has returned to the current employment of the covered employee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a treating physician chosen by the covered employee has advised the covered employee that the covered employee has reached maximum improvement from the disability of the covered employee; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the termination is made after the termination date contained in an order of the Commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not apply to a termination of medical benefits if:<section prefix="(i)">the treatment by a physician or health care provider was not authorized by an insurer or self-insurer; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a treating physician or health care provider chosen by the covered employee has advised the covered employee that the covered employee has reached maximum medical improvement from the disability of the covered employee.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Before terminating the payment of temporary total disability benefits, an insurer or self-insurer shall give the covered employee written notice of the date that the benefits are to be terminated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Before terminating the payment of medical benefits, an insurer or self-insurer shall give the covered employee and the covered employee's treating physician or health care provider written notice of the date that the benefits are to be terminated.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the case of temporary total benefits, the notice shall accompany the final payment of temporary total disability benefits to the covered employee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The notice of termination under this section shall state:<section prefix="(i)">the reasons for the termination;</section><section prefix="(ii)">that the covered employee has a right to request a hearing before the Commission on the issue of the termination; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the procedure and time for requesting a hearing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the case of medical benefits, a copy of any medical record or report relied upon by the insurer or self-insurer in making the termination shall be attached to the notice.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
