<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-731" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-731</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless approved by the Commission, a person may not charge or collect a fee for:<section prefix="(i)">legal services in connection with a claim under this title;</section><section prefix="(ii)">medical services, supplies, or treatment provided under Subtitle 6, Part IX of this title; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">funeral expenses under Subtitle 6, Part XIII of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When the Commission approves a fee, the fee is a lien on the compensation awarded.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding paragraph (2) of this subsection, a fee shall be paid from an award of compensation only in the manner set by the Commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may order that a fee payable from compensation under subsection (a) of this section be paid in a lump sum.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Commission grants a lump-sum payment under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">reduce the weekly rate of compensation until the amount of the lump sum would have been paid if it had been paid in weekly payments; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">state in the award the dollar amount and the number of weeks that the reduced rate shall be paid by:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">On application of a party, the Commission may:<section prefix="(1)">hear and decide any question concerning legal services performed in connection with a claim; and</section><section prefix="(2)">order a person who received a fee for legal services to refund to the payer any part of the fee that the Commission may find to be excessive.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An order of the Commission regulating payment or refund of payment for legal services may be enforced or appealed in the same manner as a compensation award.</section>
  </text>
</law>
