<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-502" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-3-502</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each employer:<section prefix="(i)">shall set regular pay periods; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, shall pay each employee at least once in every 2 weeks or twice in each month.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An employer may pay an administrative, executive, or professional employee less frequently than required under paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the regular payday of an employee is a nonworkday, an employer shall pay the employee on the preceding workday.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each employer shall pay a wage:<section prefix="(1)">in United States currency; or</section><section prefix="(2)">by a check that, on demand, is convertible at face value into United States currency.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "employer" includes a governmental unit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An employer may not print or cause to be printed an employee's Social Security number on the employee's wage payment check, an attachment to an employee's wage payment check, a notice of direct deposit of an employee's wage, or a notice of credit of an employee's wage to a debit card or card account.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This section does not prohibit the:<section prefix="(1)">direct deposit of the wage of an employee into a personal bank account of the employee in accordance with an authorization of the employee; or</section><section prefix="(2)">credit of the wage of an employee to a debit card or card account from which the employee is able to access the funds through withdrawal, purchase, or transfer if:<section prefix="(i)">authorized by the employee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any fees applicable to the debit card or card account are disclosed to the employee in writing in at least 12 point font.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An agreement to work for less than the wage required under this subtitle is void.</section>
  </text>
</law>
