<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-5-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Labor and Industry.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Employee" means, except as provided in &#xA7; 5-401 of this title, an individual whom an employer employs, for a wage or other compensation, in the business of the employer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Employee" includes:<section prefix="(i)">an individual whom a governmental unit employs;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an individual who is licensed as a taxicab driver and leases or rents a taxicab from a person who operates or owns a taxicab business in Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an individual who is employed for part-time or temporary help by a governmental unit or person who engages in a business that directly employs individuals to provide part-time or temporary help to another governmental unit or person; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">an individual who performs work for a governmental unit or person to whom the individual is provided by another governmental unit or person who engages in a business that directly employs individuals to provide part-time or temporary help.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Employer" means:<section prefix="(i)">except as provided in &#xA7; 5-401 of this title, a person who is engaged in commerce, industry, trade, or other business in the State and employs at least one employee in that business; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a public body.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Employer" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a person who operates or owns a taxicab business in Baltimore City and leases or rents a taxicab to a licensed taxicab driver, to provide services to the public;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a governmental unit or person who engages in a business that directly employs individuals to provide part-time or temporary help to another governmental unit or person; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">a governmental unit or person who contracts directly with another governmental unit or person who engages in a business that directly employs individuals to provide part-time or temporary help to another governmental unit or person.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Occupational safety and health standard" means a regulation that requires:<section prefix="(1)">a condition that is reasonably appropriate or necessary to make employment and places of employment safe and healthful; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the adoption or use of a means, method, operation, practice, or process that is reasonably appropriate or necessary to make employment and places of employment safe and healthful.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Person" includes a successor.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Place of employment" means a place in or about which an employee is allowed to work.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Public body" means:<section prefix="(1)">a governmental unit;</section><section prefix="(2)">a public or quasi-public corporation of the State;</section><section prefix="(3)">a school district in the State or any unit of the district; or</section><section prefix="(4)">a special district in the State or any unit of the district.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
