<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-702" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-3-702</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "employer" means:<section prefix="(1)">a person engaged in a business, industry, profession, trade, or other enterprise in the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">the State;</section><section prefix="(3)">a county; and</section><section prefix="(4)">a municipal corporation in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section does not apply to the federal government or any of its units.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not apply to an individual who is an employee of or applies for assignment to the Internal Investigative Unit of the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This section does not apply to an individual who applies for employment or is employed:<section prefix="(i)">as a law enforcement officer, as defined in &#xA7; 3-101 of the Public Safety Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">as an employee of a law enforcement agency of the State, a county, or a municipal corporation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">as a communications officer of the Calvert County Control Center;</section><section prefix="(iv)">as a correctional officer of the Calvert County Detention Center or in any other capacity that involves direct personal contact with an inmate in the Detention Center;</section><section prefix="(v)">as a correctional officer of the Washington County Detention Center or in any other capacity that involves direct personal contact with an inmate in the Center; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">as a correctional officer of:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">This section does not apply to an applicant for employment as a correctional officer of a State or local correctional facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">This section does not apply to an applicant for employment with either the Anne Arundel County Department of Detention Facilities or the Caroline County Department of Corrections in any capacity that involves direct contact with an inmate in either the Anne Arundel County Department of Detention Facilities or the Caroline County Department of Corrections.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">This section does not apply to an applicant for employment with the Washington County Emergency Communications Center.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An employer may not require or demand, as a condition of employment, prospective employment, or continued employment, that an individual submit to or take a polygraph examination or similar test.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each application for employment shall set out, in bold-faced upper case type, the following notice:</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each application shall provide a space for an applicant to sign an acknowledgment of the notice required under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An applicant shall sign the acknowledgment of the notice required under subsection (d) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If an employer violates subsection (c) or (d) of this section, an applicant for employment or prospective employment or an employee may submit to the Commissioner a written complaint.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whenever the Commissioner determines that this section has been violated, the Commissioner may:<section prefix="(i)">try to resolve any issue involved in the violation informally by mediation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">ask the Attorney General to bring an action on behalf of the applicant or employee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Attorney General may bring an action under this section in the county where the violation allegedly occurred, for injunctive relief, damages, or other relief.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">An employer who violates any provision of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $100.</section>
  </text>
</law>
