<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-404</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>404</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall adopt regulations:<section prefix="(i)">setting procedures and other requirements for a governmental self-insurance group to establish joint self-insurance coverage; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">establishing guidelines to govern the investment of surplus moneys not needed to meet current obligations in a manner that will ensure solvency of the Fund and timely payment of claims.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding the local government guidelines set forth in Article 95, &#xA7; 22 of the Code, the guidelines required by paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">state the types of investment in which moneys may be invested;</section><section prefix="(ii)">include guidance for the prudent investment of moneys based on claim experience, cash flow projections, income, liquidity, investment ratings, and risk;</section><section prefix="(iii)">authorize investments of moneys in equities, provided that investments do not exceed 30 percent of the surplus moneys;</section><section prefix="(iv)">provide that moneys not invested in equities shall be invested in accordance with Article 95, &#xA7; 22 of the Code; and</section><section prefix="(v)">prohibit borrowing of funds for the express purpose of investing those funds.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, a governmental self-insurance group may be formed by any combination of:<section prefix="(i)">counties;</section><section prefix="(ii)">municipal corporations;</section><section prefix="(iii)">boards of education; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">community colleges.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A board of education or a community college may not participate in a governmental self-insurance group unless its participation is approved by its county governing body.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subject to the approval of the Commission, a county that participates in a governmental self-insurance group may include in the coverage:<section prefix="(1)">any unit created or funded by the county; and</section><section prefix="(2)">regardless of funding:<section prefix="(i)">the board of education of the county;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a community college in the county;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a regional community college in the county;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a housing agency of the county created under Division II of the Housing and Community Development Article;</section><section prefix="(v)">a municipal corporation in the county;</section><section prefix="(vi)">a multicounty unit that operates in the county; or</section><section prefix="(vii)">a revenue authority in the county created by the State.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A governmental self-insurance group shall get a certificate of authority from the Commission before the governmental self-insurance group may self-insure.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To qualify for a certificate under this subsection, a governmental self-insurance group shall satisfy the Commission that the governmental self-insurance group:<section prefix="(i)">is financially able to pay compensation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">will have annual gross premiums of at least $250,000; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">meets each other requirement under this section, &#xA7; 9-403 of this subtitle, or a regulation of the Commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission shall issue a certificate of authority to each governmental self-insurance group that meets the requirements of paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At any time, the Commission may require a governmental self-insurance group to secure payment of compensation by depositing with the Commission security:<section prefix="(i)">in a form accepted by a circuit court for investment of trust money; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">in the amount set by the Commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On application and subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, the Commission shall return security that a governmental self-insurance group has deposited under this subsection if:<section prefix="(i)">the members of the governmental self-insurance group cease to be subject to this title or secure compensation through an authorized insurer or the Chesapeake Employers' Insurance Company; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the governmental self-insurance group has not been liable on a claim for compensation during the 5 years immediately after the day on which the event described in item (i) of this paragraph occurred.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">After reviewing the application and before returning security to a governmental self-insurance group, the Commission may require the governmental self-insurance group to submit to the Commission an indemnity bond in an amount equal to the value of the security.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Each governmental self-insurance group to which the Commission issues a certificate of authority shall have excess insurance in the amount set by the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each governmental self-insurance group shall have in the State an office run by a competent individual who handles all of the workers' compensation work in the State for the governmental self-insurance group.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each governmental self-insurance group shall establish a toll-free telephone number through which an employee or claimant, or a representative of an employee or claimant, may make direct telephone inquiries during regular business hours.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission may assess a fine not exceeding $1,000 on a governmental self-insurance group that does not comply with this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Commission shall provide for advance premium discounts that are competitive with private insurance advance premium discounts.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To be informed of the continuing financial responsibility of each governmental self-insurance group, the Commission:<section prefix="(i)">shall require each governmental self-insurance group to submit a report at least once each year; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">may examine the governmental self-insurance group under oath and make other examination of the business of the governmental self-insurance group.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each year, the Commission shall assess each governmental self-insurance group an amount not exceeding $1,500 to be used for actuarial studies and audits.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall revoke the approval of a governmental self-insurance group to self-insure under this section if the governmental self-insurance group:<section prefix="(i)">fails to deposit securities with or submit a bond to the Commission in accordance with subsection (e) of this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">fails to submit satisfactory reports to the Commission in accordance with subsection (i)(1)(i) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">otherwise fails to satisfy the Commission that it is financially able to self-insure.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Whenever the Commission revokes approval for a governmental self-insurance group to self-insure under this section, the members of the governmental self-insurance group immediately shall secure compensation through an authorized insurer or the Chesapeake Employers' Insurance Company.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a member of a governmental self-insurance group fails to secure compensation as required by paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Commission shall order the member of the governmental self-insurance group to secure compensation through the Chesapeake Employers' Insurance Company.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">If a governmental self-insurance group becomes insolvent, the Uninsured Employers' Fund shall pay the outstanding obligations of the governmental self-insurance group for compensation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
