<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-234</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>234</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"On duty" means:<section prefix="1.">fighting a fire;</section><section prefix="2.">performing a duty of a member of an advanced life support unit or an ambulance, first aid, or rescue squad in a volunteer company;</section><section prefix="3.">except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, performing a duty that the volunteer company assigns to the member;</section><section prefix="4.">performing a duty that a written bylaw or rule of government adopted for the volunteer company assigns to the member;</section><section prefix="5.">going to or from performing a duty included under item 1, 2, 3, or 4 of this subparagraph;</section><section prefix="6.">accompanying an accident or fire victim while being transported to a hospital in a helicopter;</section><section prefix="7.">returning to the home station of the individual after accompanying a victim under item 6 of this subparagraph;</section><section prefix="8.">performing a duty assigned to a member of a fire company appointed as a deputy sheriff under &#xA7; 7-302 or &#xA7; 7-303 of the Public Safety Article; or</section><section prefix="9.">performing a duty assigned to an individual appointed to serve as a member of the fire police in Washington County under &#xA7; 7-304 of the Public Safety Article.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"On duty" does not include attendance of a member of a volunteer company at a social function unless a written bylaw or rule of government adopted for the volunteer company requires the attendance or participation of the member.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Volunteer company" means:<section prefix="(i)">a volunteer advanced life support unit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a volunteer ambulance company or squad;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a volunteer fire company or department;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a volunteer rescue company, department, or squad; and</section><section prefix="(v)">a volunteer fire police unit.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An individual who is a covered employee under subsection (h)(2), (k), (n), (o)(2), (p)(1)(ii), (r)(3), (v), or (x)(1) of this section continues to be a covered employee while:<section prefix="(1)">accompanying an accident or fire victim who is being transported to a hospital in a helicopter; and</section><section prefix="(2)">returning to the home station of the individual after accompanying a victim under item (1) of this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless an election is made under paragraph (2) of this subsection, a member of a volunteer company in Allegany County is not a covered employee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board of County Commissioners for Allegany County may provide by resolution for members of a volunteer company in the county to be covered employees while on duty.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A member of a volunteer company in Anne Arundel County is a covered employee while on duty.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A member of a volunteer company in Baltimore County is a covered employee while on duty.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A member of a volunteer company in Calvert County is a covered employee while on duty.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A member of a volunteer company in Caroline County is a covered employee while on duty.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless an election is made in accordance with this subsection, a member of a volunteer company in Carroll County is not a covered employee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A volunteer fire company in Carroll County may elect to make its members covered employees.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A volunteer fire company that elects to make its members covered employees shall pay the premium for the coverage.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A member of a volunteer company in Cecil County who meets the guidelines set under paragraph (2) of this subsection is a covered employee while on duty.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board of County Commissioners of Cecil County may set guidelines to determine the eligibility of members of a volunteer company in the county for coverage under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The guidelines under paragraph (2) of this subsection may not limit the number of covered employees in a volunteer company.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless an election is made in accordance with this subsection, a member of a volunteer company in Charles County is not a covered employee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board of County Commissioners of Charles County may provide by resolution for members of a volunteer company in the county to be covered employees while on duty.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">A member of a volunteer company in Dorchester County is a covered employee.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">A member of a volunteer company in Frederick County is a covered employee while on duty.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless an election is made under paragraph (2) of this subsection, a member of a volunteer company in Garrett County is not a covered employee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board of County Commissioners for Garrett County may provide by resolution for members of a volunteer company in the county to be covered employees while on duty.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">A member of a volunteer company in Harford County is a covered employee.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">An individual is a covered employee:<section prefix="(1)">while on duty as an actively participating member of a volunteer company in Howard County; or</section><section prefix="(2)">if not covered under item (1) of this subsection, while a member of a volunteer company in Howard County participating in the activities of the volunteer company.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual is a covered employee:<section prefix="(i)">while on duty as an actively participating member of a volunteer company in Kent County; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if not covered under item (i) of this paragraph, while a member of a volunteer company in Kent County.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board of County Commissioners of Kent County shall impose annually a tax on assessable property in the county in an amount that is sufficient to pay for coverage under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board of County Commissioners of Kent County may limit the number of members in a volunteer company in the county.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(q)">A member of a volunteer company in Montgomery County is a covered employee while on duty.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">An individual is a covered employee:<section prefix="(1)">while on duty as a member of the Laurel volunteer rescue squad in Prince George's County; or</section><section prefix="(2)">while a member of a volunteer company in Prince George's County.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(s)">A member of a volunteer company in Queen Anne's County is a covered employee while on duty.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless an election is made under paragraph (2) of this subsection, a member of a volunteer company in St. Mary's County is not a covered employee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board of County Commissioners for St. Mary's County may provide by resolution for the members of a volunteer company in the county to be covered employees while on duty.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(u)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless an election is made under paragraph (2) of this subsection, a member of a volunteer company in Somerset County is not a covered employee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board of County Commissioners for Somerset County may provide by resolution for members of a volunteer company in the county to be covered employees while on duty.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(v)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A member of a volunteer company in Talbot County is a covered employee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The County Council of Talbot County may provide by resolution for members of a volunteer company in the county to be covered employees while on duty.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(w)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless an election is made under paragraph (2) of this subsection, a member of a volunteer company in Washington County is not a covered employee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board of County Commissioners for Washington County may provide by resolution for members of a volunteer company in the county to be covered employees while on duty.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(x)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A member of a volunteer company in Wicomico County is a covered employee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The County Council of Wicomico County may provide by resolution for members of a volunteer company in the county to be covered employees while on duty.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(y)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless an election is made under paragraph (2) of this subsection, a member of a volunteer company in Worcester County is not a covered employee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board of County Commissioners for Worcester County may provide by resolution for members of a volunteer company in the county to be covered employees while on duty.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(z)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For the purposes of this title, a member of a volunteer company who is a covered employee under this section is an employee of the political subdivision of the State where the volunteer company is organized.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member of a volunteer company shall be covered while on duty by a policy of workers' compensation insurance.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(aa)">A member of a volunteer company who is a covered employee under this section may not be considered a paid covered employee of the volunteer company for receiving as a membership benefit a yearly stipend of $5,200 or less to help offset out-of-pocket expenses.</section>
  </text>
</law>
