<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="gle" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-3-908</section_number>
  <catch_line>An employer in violation of &#xA7; 3-903 of this subtitle who comes into timely compliance with all appl...</catch_line>
  <order_by>908</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An employer in violation of &#xA7; 3-903 of this subtitle who comes into timely compliance with all applicable labor laws as required by &#xA7; 3-907(b) of this subtitle may not be assessed a civil penalty.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An employer in violation of &#xA7; 3-903 of this subtitle who fails to come into timely compliance with all applicable labor laws as required by &#xA7; 3-907(b) of this subtitle shall be assessed a civil penalty of up to $1,000 for each employee for whom the employer is not in compliance.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In determining the amount of the penalty, the Commissioner shall consider the factors set forth in &#xA7; 3-909(b) of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An employer may be assessed civil penalties under this section by only one final order of a court or administrative unit for the same actions constituting noncompliance with applicable labor laws as required by &#xA7; 3-907(b) and (c) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, an employer may be ordered to make restitution, pay any interest due, and otherwise comply with all applicable laws and regulations by multiple final orders of a court and all relevant administrative units, including the Comptroller, the Office of Unemployment Insurance, the Insurance Administration, and the Workers' Compensation Commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Any penalty issued under this section against an employer shall be in effect against any successor corporation or business entity that:<section prefix="(1)">has one or more of the same principals or officers as the employer against whom the penalty was assessed; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is engaged in the same or equivalent trade or activity.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
