<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-742" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-742</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission retains jurisdiction pending an appeal to consider:<section prefix="(1)">a request for additional medical treatment and attention;</section><section prefix="(2)">a request for temporary total disability benefits, provided that the covered employee's temporary total disability benefits were granted in the order on appeal, and were terminated by the insurer or self-insurer pending adjudication or resolution of the appeal; and</section><section prefix="(3)">a request for approval of a proposed settlement of all or part of a claim.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Commission finds that a covered employee needs additional medical attention pending an appeal, the Commission may pass a supplemental order requiring the employer to provide additional medical treatment and attention.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Commission finds that a covered employee's temporary total disability benefits were terminated pending adjudication or resolution of the appeal, and that the employee was temporarily totally disabled at the time of termination, the Commission may pass a supplemental order requiring the employer to provide the employee with temporary total disability benefits.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the Commission's decision to reinstate temporary total disability benefits is reversed or modified on appeal, the insurer or self-insurer shall be entitled to an offset or credit for overpayment of the temporary total disability benefits granted in the supplemental order.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A supplemental order passed by the Commission under this section is subject to review on the pending appeal.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">When an appeal that is pending relates solely to a penalty imposed by the Commission, the Commission retains jurisdiction over all matters in the case other than imposition of the penalty.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This section may not be construed to prevent the Commission from ordering an offset or credit against an award for temporary total or permanent partial disability benefits for any temporary total disability benefits previously paid to a covered employee, as authorized under any other provision of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
