<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="gle" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-8-626.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "date of employment" means the date on which an employee commences working for an e...</catch_line>
  <order_by>626.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "date of employment" means the date on which an employee commences working for an employing unit.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, within 20 days of an employee's beginning employment, the employee's employing unit shall submit to the Secretary:<section prefix="(1)">the Social Security number of the employee;</section><section prefix="(2)">the name of the employee;</section><section prefix="(3)">the address of the employee;</section><section prefix="(4)">the date of employment;</section><section prefix="(5)">the employing unit's name and address;</section><section prefix="(6)">the employee's starting wage;</section><section prefix="(7)">whether the employee has health insurance provided by the employing unit;</section><section prefix="(8)">the federal employer identification number of the employing unit; and</section><section prefix="(9)">the State unemployment insurance account number of the employing unit.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The employing unit shall report the required information by:<section prefix="(i)">mail;</section><section prefix="(ii)">magnetically or electronically; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">other means as determined by the Secretary.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an employing unit chooses to transmit data magnetically or electronically at a rate of twice per month, then the report must be submitted not less than 12 days or more than 16 days apart.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An employing unit that has employees in two or more states and that transmits reports magnetically or electronically may designate one state in which to transmit the report.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An employing unit that chooses to transmit the data to another state shall provide the Secretary with the name of the state receiving the report.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any employing unit that fails to report as required:<section prefix="(i)">shall be given a written warning for the first violation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall be subject to a civil penalty of $20 for each month in which a subsequent violation occurs, or $500 if the failure is the result of a conspiracy between the employer and the employee to not supply the required report or to supply a false or incomplete report, unless the Secretary waives the penalty for cause.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">All violations occurring in a single month to the same employing unit shall be considered a single violation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An assessment under this section is final unless, within 15 days after the mailing of the assessment, an employing unit applies to the Secretary for a hearing. The Secretary may forward the application to the Office of Administrative Hearings for adjudication.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department of Human Resources shall reimburse the Secretary for all costs incurred to carry out this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
