<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-9-683</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>683</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only to a covered employee of a municipal corporation or a county who is subject to &#xA7; 9-503 of this title and the dependents of those covered employees, unless the municipal corporation or county has made an election under &#xA7; 9-683.6 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If there are multiple dependents entitled to death benefits, the Commission may apportion an award of death benefits among the dependents in the manner that the Commission considers just and equitable.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If there are wholly and partly dependent individuals entitled to death benefits, the Commission may:<section prefix="(1)">award the death benefits to the wholly dependent individuals only; or</section><section prefix="(2)">apportion the award among the wholly and partly dependent individuals in the manner that the Commission considers to be fair and equitable under all of the facts and circumstances of the case.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Death benefits shall be paid to 1 or more of the dependents of a covered employee who are entitled to death benefits, as determined by the Commission, for the benefit of all of the dependents who are entitled to death benefits.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A dependent to whom death benefits are paid shall apply the death benefits to the use of all of the dependents who are entitled to death benefits:<section prefix="(i)">according to the respective claims of the dependents on the deceased covered employee for support; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">in compliance with the findings and direction of the Commission.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
