<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-5-406</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>406</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 15 days after an employer prepares or revises a chemical information list, the employer shall submit a copy of the list to the Department of the Environment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 5 working days after an employer receives a written request from the Department of the Environment for a copy of a material safety data sheet, the employer shall submit to the Department a copy of that sheet.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department of the Environment shall:<section prefix="(1)">review, for completeness and sufficiency, each:<section prefix="(i)">chemical information list that an employer submits under subsection (a) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">material safety data sheet that the Department requests; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">give the Commissioner notice of any noncompliance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department of the Environment shall provide access to information on a chemical information list only to:<section prefix="(1)">a person who provides fire, ambulance, or rescue service for the appropriate geographic area;</section><section prefix="(2)">a nurse, physician, or physician assistant who is treating an individual in a medical emergency;</section><section prefix="(3)">a former employee of an inactive employer;</section><section prefix="(4)">the Commissioner; and</section><section prefix="(5)">an independent contractor or employer as provided in &#xA7; 5-408 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c) of this section and &#xA7; 6-503 of the Environment Article, the Department of the Environment:<section prefix="(1)">shall treat as confidential information in a chemical information list; and</section><section prefix="(2)">may not disclose the information:<section prefix="(i)">in any civil proceeding; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">to any person.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
