<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gle" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-1204" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-8-1204</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>The Secretary shall approve a work sharing plan that meets the following requirements:<section prefix=""><section prefix="(1)">the work sharing plan shall apply to:<section prefix="(i)">at least 10% of the employees in the affected unit; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">at least 20 employees in an affected unit in which the work sharing plan applies equally to all affected employees.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the normal weekly work hours of affected employees in the affected unit shall be reduced by at least 10% but, unless waived by the Secretary, the reduction may not exceed 50%.</section><section prefix="(3)">a work sharing plan shall:<section prefix="(i)">identify the affected unit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">identify each employee in the affected unit by name, Social Security number, and any other information that the Secretary requires;</section><section prefix="(iii)">specify an expiration date that is not more than 6 months after the effective date of the work sharing plan;</section><section prefix="(iv)">specify the effect that work sharing will have on the fringe benefits of each employee in the affected unit including:</section><section prefix="(v)">certify that:</section><section prefix="(vi)">contain the written approval of:</section></section><section prefix="(4)">if a work sharing plan serves the work sharing employer as a transitional step to permanent staff reduction, the work sharing plan shall contain a reemployment assistance plan for each affected employee that the work sharing employer develops with the Secretary.</section><section prefix="(5)">the work sharing employer shall agree to:<section prefix="(i)">submit to the Secretary reports that are necessary to administer the work sharing plan; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">allow the Department to have access to all records necessary:</section></section><section prefix="(6)">a work sharing plan may not subsidize an employing unit that traditionally has used employees who work less than 30 hours a week.</section></section></text>
</law>
