<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="gle" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-11-505</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Governor's Workforce Investment Board is established and shall have the membership as provided i...</catch_line>
  <order_by>505</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Governor's Workforce Investment Board is established and shall have the membership as provided in &#xA7; 111 of the federal Act and U.S. Department of Labor regulations.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to subsection (a) of this section, the members of the Governor's Workforce Investment Board shall be appointed by the Governor for staggered terms set by the Governor by executive order.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To the extent practicable, the composition of the Governor's Workforce Investment Board shall reflect the race, gender, and geographic diversity of the population of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Governor's Workforce Investment Board shall be funded consistent with &#xA7;&#xA7; 111 and 128 of the federal Act and shall have personnel and appropriations as are provided in the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Governor's Workforce Investment Board shall perform the duties and functions identified in &#xA7; 111 of the federal Act and other functions designated by the Governor as necessary to improve the quality of the State's workforce.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Governor's Workforce Investment Board may adopt any rule or regulations necessary to carry out its powers and duties.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">As soon after January 1 of each year as reasonably possible, the Governor's Workforce Investment Board shall submit an annual report to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly.</section>
  </text>
</law>
