<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gle" order_by="gle" level="1">Labor and Employment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gle-8-310</section_number>
  <catch_line>In the administration of this title, the Secretary shall cooperate with the United States Secretary ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>310</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In the administration of this title, the Secretary shall cooperate with the United States Secretary of Labor to the fullest extent that this title allows.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary shall:<section prefix="(i)">make each report in the form and containing the information that the Secretary of Labor requires;</section><section prefix="(ii)">comply with each provision that the Secretary of Labor considers necessary to ensure the accuracy of a report; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">comply with each regulation that the Secretary of Labor adopts to govern the expenditure of any money that may be allotted and paid to the State under Chapter 7, Subchapter III of the Social Security Act to assist in the administration of this title.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary may afford reasonable cooperation with each federal unit that administers an unemployment insurance law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On request, the Secretary shall provide to a federal unit that administers public works or assistance through public employment:<section prefix="(i)">the name, address, usual occupation, and employment status of each recipient of benefits; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">information about the right of the individual to receive benefits.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary:<section prefix="(1)">may make available to the Railroad Retirement Board any record of the State that relates to administration of this title; and</section><section prefix="(2)">at the expense of the Railroad Retirement Board, may provide to the Board a copy of any record that the Board considers necessary for its purposes.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
