<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="glu" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-3-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>When a local jurisdiction initially implements the zoning powers under this division, the planning c...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When a local jurisdiction initially implements the zoning powers under this division, the planning commission shall recommend the boundaries of the original districts and zones and appropriate regulations to be enforced in the districts and zones.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The planning commission shall make a preliminary report on the proposed districts, zones, and regulations and hold at least one public hearing on the preliminary report before submitting its final report to the legislative body.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The legislative body may not hold a public hearing or take action until it receives the final report of the planning commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A planning commission shall hold at least one public hearing before the commission recommends the adoption of a plan or any part or amendment to a plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The planning commission shall publish at least one notice of the time and place of the hearing in a newspaper of general circulation in the local jurisdiction.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">At least 60 days before the public hearing, the planning commission shall provide copies of the recommended plan and amendments to the plan to:<section prefix="(1)">adjoining jurisdictions; and</section><section prefix="(2)">State units and local jurisdictions responsible for financing or constructing public improvements necessary to implement the plan.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The planning commission shall include in its report to the legislative body the recommendation of each unit and jurisdiction that comments on the plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A majority of the planning commission, by resolution, shall approve the plan or any part of or amendment to the plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The resolution shall refer expressly to the text, map, and other matter that the commission intends to form the whole or part of the plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The action taken shall be recorded on the map, plan, text, or other matter by the identifying signature of:<section prefix="(i)">the chair of the planning commission; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the secretary of the commission.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An attested copy of the plan or part of the plan shall be certified to the legislative body.</section>
  </text>
</law>
