<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-405" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-10-405</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An appeal to the Board may be filed by:<section prefix="(1)">a person aggrieved by a decision of the administrative officer or unit; or</section><section prefix="(2)">an officer or unit of Baltimore City affected by a decision of the administrative officer or unit.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person shall file an appeal within a reasonable time provided by local law or the rules of the Board by filing with the administrative officer or unit from whose action the appeal is taken and with the Board a notice of appeal specifying the grounds of the appeal.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">On receiving the notice of appeal, the administrative officer or unit from whose action the appeal is taken shall transmit to the Board all papers constituting the record of the action appealed.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless the administrative officer or unit from whose action an appeal is taken, after receiving the notice of appeal, certifies facts to the Board that the administrative officer or unit believes that a stay would cause imminent peril to life or property, an appeal stays all proceedings in the action appealed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the administrative officer or unit provides facts showing that a stay would cause imminent peril to life or property, the proceedings may be stayed only by a restraining order granted by:<section prefix="(i)">the Board; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Circuit Court for Baltimore City.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A restraining order may be issued only:<section prefix="(i)">on application;</section><section prefix="(ii)">for good cause shown; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">after notice is given to the administrative officer or unit from whose action the appeal is taken.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">establish a reasonable time for the hearing of an appeal;</section><section prefix="(ii)">give public notice of the existence of the appeal and of the hearing, and due notice to the parties in interest and to other persons entitled to notice under local law or the rules of the Board; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">decide the appeal within a reasonable time.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At a hearing, a party may:<section prefix="(i)">appear in person; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">be represented by an agent or attorney.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may, in conformity with this title:<section prefix="(i)">wholly or partly reverse the order, requirement, or decision that is the subject of the appeal;</section><section prefix="(ii)">wholly or partly affirm the order, requirement, or decision that is the subject of the appeal; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">modify the order, requirement, or decision that is the subject of the appeal.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall have the powers of the administrative officer or unit from whose action the appeal is taken.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
