<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-24-305</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>305</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An agreement shall include:<section prefix="(1)">a legal description of the real property subject to the agreement;</section><section prefix="(2)">the names of all persons having a legal or equitable interest in the property;</section><section prefix="(3)">the duration of the agreement;</section><section prefix="(4)">the permissible uses of the real property;</section><section prefix="(5)">the permissible density or intensity of use of the real property;</section><section prefix="(6)">the maximum height and size of structures;</section><section prefix="(7)">the general location of all structures and supporting facilities and features;</section><section prefix="(8)">a description of all anticipated permits required or already approved for the development of the real property;</section><section prefix="(9)">a statement that the proposed development is consistent with:<section prefix="(i)">the Commission's general plan; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">all applicable development laws and regulations administered by the county planning board;</section></section><section prefix="(10)">a description of the requirements determined by a county planning board to be necessary to ensure the public health, safety, and welfare; and</section><section prefix="(11)">to the extent applicable, provisions for the:<section prefix="(i)">dedication of a portion of the real property for immediate or future public use;</section><section prefix="(ii)">protection of sensitive areas;</section><section prefix="(iii)">preservation and restoration of historic structures; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">construction or financing of public facilities.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An agreement may:<section prefix="(1)">establish the terms by which, and any period of time when, development or individual phases shall begin and be completed;</section><section prefix="(2)">incorporate the terms and conditions that would be included in other enforceable agreements and instruments between the parties required as part of a regulatory plan; and</section><section prefix="(3)">provide for other matters in accordance with this division.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An agreement may not prevent a county planning board, district council, County Executive, or other local, State, or federal government from requiring a person to comply with laws, rules, regulations, and policies enacted after the parties executed the agreement if the district council or the County Executive determines that compliance with the laws, rules, regulations, and policies is essential to ensure the public health, safety, or welfare.</section>
  </text>
</law>
