<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="glu" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-18-304</section_number>
  <catch_line>The tax required under this subsection:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The tax required under this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">applies to property in the metropolitan district in Montgomery County; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall be imposed whether any bonds have been issued under this title or whether interest is due on any bonds issued under this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each year, Montgomery County shall impose on each $100 of assessed valuation of:<section prefix="(i)">real property, a tax of 3.6 cents; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">personal property and operating real property described in &#xA7; 8-109(c) of the Tax - Property Article, a tax of 9 cents.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Every 60 days the county shall pay to the Commission the tax collected under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Commission may use the revenues from the tax imposed under this subsection, after providing for debt service on bonds issued under Subtitle 2 of this title, to:<section prefix="(i)">police the parks or other areas under its jurisdiction;</section><section prefix="(ii)">acquire, develop, beautify, or maintain parks or other areas; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">establish playground and recreational facilities in the parks or other areas.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">It is the intent of this subsection to provide the Commission with funds to:<section prefix="(i)">finance the acquisition of parklands in the metropolitan district in Prince George's County from current revenues or by the issue of bonds; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">maintain, operate, and develop acquired parklands.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The tax required under this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">applies to property in the metropolitan district in Prince George's County; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall be imposed whether any bonds have been issued under this title or whether interest is due on any bonds issued under this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each fiscal year, Prince George's County shall impose on each $100 of assessed valuation of:<section prefix="(i)">real property, a tax of at least 4 cents; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">personal property and operating real property described in &#xA7; 8-109(c) of the Tax - Property Article, a tax of at least 10 cents.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Every 60 days the county shall pay to the Commission the tax collected under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Commission shall use the revenues from the tax imposed under this subsection primarily to pay the principal of and interest on any bonds issued by the Commission for the acquisition of parklands in the metropolitan district in Prince George's County as authorized under this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The county shall pay to the Commission the tax collected under this subsection whether any principal or interest is due on any bonds issued for the acquisition of parklands or whether any bonds for that purpose have been issued or are outstanding in the fiscal year in which the tax is collected.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The tax authorized under this subsection applies to property in the metropolitan district in Montgomery County and Prince George's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each year the County Council of Montgomery County and the County Council of Prince George's County may impose an ad valorem tax in addition to all other taxes imposed for the benefit of and on behalf of the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each county may pay to the Commission the aggregate amount collected under this subsection in the same manner as the county pays other taxes under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Commission shall use the proceeds of the tax under this subsection to:<section prefix="(i)">acquire, maintain, develop, and operate the park systems in the counties; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">pay the debt service required by its outstanding bonds or bonds issued in the future.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Commission shall expend or disburse that proportion of tax collected from Montgomery County in Montgomery County and that proportion collected from Prince George's County in Prince George's County.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The tax authorized under this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">applies to property in the metropolitan district in Montgomery County; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall be in lieu of, and in complete satisfaction of, any obligations of Montgomery County to pay for maintenance of the Commission's park system in accordance with Chapter 761, &#xA7; 8 of the Acts of 1953 and all agreements executed under the terms of that law.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each year, in addition to the tax imposed under subsection (a) of this section, Montgomery County shall impose on each $100 of assessed valuation of:<section prefix="(i)">real property, a tax of 0.8 cents; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">personal property and operating real property described in &#xA7; 8-109(c) of the Tax - Property Article, a tax of 2 cents.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A tax authorized under this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">be imposed and collected as county taxes are imposed and collected;</section><section prefix="(2)">have the same priority rights as county taxes;</section><section prefix="(3)">bear the same interest and penalties as county taxes; and</section><section prefix="(4)">be treated the same as county taxes in every other respect.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">At least 30 days before the end of the fiscal year, the Commission shall certify and submit to the appropriate fiscal officers of the counties the net unexpended balances from money received by the Commission from taxes imposed under this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In Montgomery County, the Commission also shall furnish at the time requested by the County Council an estimate of unexpended balances as of the end of the fiscal year as information for the county's tax resolution.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To calculate the net unexpended balance for each county, the Commission shall deduct, from its actual unexpended cash receipts from taxes collected under this section, an amount equal to the sum of:<section prefix="(i)">the debt service for the next succeeding fiscal year on bonds issued by it and outstanding with respect to property acquired by it in the county;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Commission's fixed obligations under contracts the first 6 months of the fiscal year;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the amounts credited to the Commission's self-insurance fund;</section><section prefix="(iv)">$200,000 with respect to Montgomery County; and</section><section prefix="(v)">$150,000 with respect to Prince George's County.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection, when the county receives the certification from the Commission of its net unexpended balance with respect to that county as calculated under paragraph (2) of this subsection, the county may:<section prefix="1.">deduct the net unexpended balance from its estimate of the amount of money to be raised in the next succeeding fiscal year by taxes collected under this section; and</section><section prefix="2.">impose the tax for the next succeeding fiscal year at a rate that the county estimates will produce the amount calculated under item 1 of this subparagraph.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The amount calculated under subparagraph (i)1 of this paragraph shall be the amount the county is obligated to pay the Commission in that fiscal year under this section.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The tax rate may not be reduced under this subsection to a rate insufficient to pay debt service on bonds issued by the Commission and guaranteed by the county.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
