<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="glu" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-25-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies to land in a municipal corporation that is in the metropolitan district and is:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to land in a municipal corporation that is in the metropolitan district and is:<section prefix="(1)">zoned for residential or commercial use; or</section><section prefix="(2)">adjacent to residential or commercial zones.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other law, and for the purpose of preserving, improving, or protecting the general character and design of lands and improvements in a municipal corporation, the legislative body of the municipal corporation, by local law, may impose stricter or additional conditions, restrictions, or limitations than are otherwise required by State, regional, or county zoning laws or agencies exercising zoning and planning jurisdiction over the municipal corporation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The stricter or additional conditions, restrictions, or limitations may apply only to:<section prefix="(i)">fences;</section><section prefix="(ii)">residential parking; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">residential storage.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The legislative body of a municipal corporation may not enact a local law under this section without holding a public hearing on all issues.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A municipal corporation that enacts a zoning law in accordance with this section shall deliver a certified copy of the local law to the district council within 5 days after the enactment and at least 30 days before the effective date of the local law.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the district council does not approve the local law before the effective date of the local law, the local law shall be considered disapproved and may not take effect.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The local law may not take effect unless approved by the district council.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
