<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-16-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Arbitration" means a procedure by which the parties involved in a grievance submit their differences to an impartial third party for a final and binding decision.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Bargaining unit" means all employees except a confidential employee.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Collective bargaining" means the performance by the exclusive representative of the bargaining unit and the Commission of their mutual obligations to negotiate in good faith with respect to wages, hours, and other terms and conditions of employment.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Collective bargaining agreement" means a written contract between the Commission and an employee organization implementing collective bargaining.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Confidential employee" means an employee who:<section prefix="(1)">acts in a confidential capacity and formulates and effectuates Commission policies that relate to collective bargaining with employees; or</section><section prefix="(2)">has access to confidential information not generally available to employees regarding the formulation and effectuation of Commission policies that relate to collective bargaining.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Employee" means a police officer who is ranked as a sergeant or below employed by the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Employee organization" means an organization that has as one of its primary purposes representing employees in collective bargaining.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Exclusive representative" means an employee organization that has been certified by the Labor Commissioner as representing the employees in the bargaining unit.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Grievance" means a dispute concerning the application or interpretation of the terms of a collective bargaining agreement or the regulations of the Commission that relate to terms and conditions of employment.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Impasse" means failure of the Commission and an exclusive representative to enter into a collective bargaining agreement at least 30 days before the day on which the Commission's budget is due for submission to the Montgomery County Council and the Prince George's County Council.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Labor Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Labor and Industry or the Commissioner's designee.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Mediation" means assistance by an impartial third party to reconcile a dispute arising out of collective bargaining through interpretation, suggestion, and advice.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Strike" means the action:<section prefix="(1)">of an employee, in concert with others, to:<section prefix="(i)">refuse to report to work;</section><section prefix="(ii)">be willfully absent from the employee's position;</section><section prefix="(iii)">stop or slow down work; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">abstain wholly or partially from the proper performance of duties; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">taken for the purpose of inducing, influencing, or coercing a change in wages, hours, or other terms and conditions of employment.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
