<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="glu" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-16-304</section_number>
  <catch_line>An employee organization that is certified or that seeks certification as an exclusive representativ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An employee organization that is certified or that seeks certification as an exclusive representative under this subtitle shall:<section prefix="(1)">file with the Commission and the Labor Commissioner a copy of the employee organization's constitution and bylaws; and</section><section prefix="(2)">report promptly any change in the constitution or bylaws.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The constitution or bylaws shall include:<section prefix="(1)">a pledge that the employee organization accepts members without regard to age, race, gender, religion, marital status, or national origin;</section><section prefix="(2)">the right of members to participate in the affairs of the employee organization;</section><section prefix="(3)">procedures for periodic elections of officers by secret ballot;</section><section prefix="(4)">fair procedures governing disciplinary actions;</section><section prefix="(5)">procedures for the accurate accounting of income and expenditures;</section><section prefix="(6)">a requirement that an annual financial report be produced; and</section><section prefix="(7)">	the right of members to inspect the employee organization's accounts.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An employee organization shall file an annual report with the Commission and the Labor Commissioner.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The annual report shall include a financial report that:<section prefix="(1)">is signed by the president and treasurer or corresponding principal officers of the employee organization; and</section><section prefix="(2)">contains information in detail sufficient to accurately disclose the financial condition and operations of the employee organization.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An employee organization that has not filed an annual report or the constitution and bylaws of which do not conform to the requirements of subsection (b) of this section may not be or remain certified as an exclusive representative under this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
