<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-9-1902</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1902</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "public facilities" means schools, roads, water, wastewater, and stormwater management facilities, and other infrastructure supported by the federal, State, or local government for public purposes.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to the authority granted in Title 7, Subtitle 1 of this article, the county commissioners may provide by local law for the provision and financing of adequate public facilities concurrently with the need for those facilities.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The local law may include the authority for the county commissioners to:<section prefix="(1)">determine the functional or design capacity of public facilities;</section><section prefix="(2)">establish standards for determining the adequacy of public facilities;</section><section prefix="(3)">determine school capacity standards;</section><section prefix="(4)">determine the student yield factors for schools at various levels;</section><section prefix="(5)">establish categories of developments that will be exempt from the application of the local law;</section><section prefix="(6)">establish formulas for measuring available capacity of public facilities;</section><section prefix="(7)">determine the adequacy of public facilities in areas affected by new developments in the development plan review process;</section><section prefix="(8)">enter into agreements with developers providing for the payment of monetary compensation to address inadequacies in public facilities caused by proposed developments as a part of the development plan approval process;</section><section prefix="(9)">determine the value of in-kind contributions of equivalent value such as real estate;</section><section prefix="(10)">require forfeiture of contributions 3 years after final plat approval;</section><section prefix="(11)">establish an appeal process for decisions made under the local law;</section><section prefix="(12)">limit the number of building permits in any school district; and</section><section prefix="(13)">limit the number of residential building lots approved for development on an annual basis.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The local law may authorize the county commissioners to impose civil fines and penalties for any violation of the local law.</section>
  </text>
</law>
