<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="glu" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-16-305</section_number>
  <catch_line>A petition for an election of an exclusive representative may be submitted to the Labor Commissioner...</catch_line>
  <order_by>305</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A petition for an election of an exclusive representative may be submitted to the Labor Commissioner by:<section prefix="(i)">an employee organization that demonstrates that at least 30% of the eligible employees in the bargaining unit support representation by an exclusive representative for collective bargaining;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an employee, a group of employees, or an employee organization that demonstrates that at least 35% of the eligible employees in the bargaining unit certify that a majority of the eligible employees in the bargaining unit no longer support the current exclusive representative; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Commission, demonstrating that one or more employee organizations have presented to it a claim, supported by substantial proof, to be certified as the exclusive representative.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Labor Commissioner may accept a petition from the Commission only if the Labor Commissioner finds, on investigation of the petition, that a valid question of representation exists.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Elections shall be conducted by:<section prefix="(1)">the Labor Commissioner; and</section><section prefix="(2)">secret ballot.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each ballot shall contain:<section prefix="(1)">the name of each employee organization that submits a valid petition;</section><section prefix="(2)">the name of any other employee organization supported by a valid petition signed by more than 10% of the eligible employees in the bargaining unit; and</section><section prefix="(3)">an option for no representation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If none of the choices on the ballot receives a majority of the votes cast, the Labor Commissioner shall conduct a runoff election.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the runoff election, the ballot shall contain the two choices receiving the highest number of votes cast in the initial election.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After the election, the Labor Commissioner shall certify the employee organization that received a majority of the votes cast as the exclusive representative.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An employee organization may not be certified as an exclusive representative except as provided in this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Elections may not be conducted within 2 years after a valid election held under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
