<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-305" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-15-305</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The conditions and limitations established in this section apply to contracts or amendments to contracts entered into under this subtitle to acquire parkland in the metropolitan district in accordance with &#xA7; 1(a) and (b) of the Capper-Cramton Act, Public Law 71-284, 46 Stat. 482.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, the Commission may amend a contract.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An amendment to a contract shall be ratified by the appropriate county council before the amendment becomes binding on the State, the Commission, or the county.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may enter into a contract with a governmental unit to:<section prefix="(i)">adopt a general or revised plan for the acquisition of parklands in the metropolitan district; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">specify the method to finance the acquisition.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The appropriate county council shall ratify a contract before the contract becomes binding on the State, the Commission, or the county.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may enter into a supplemental agreement to a contract or amendment to a contract with a governmental unit in accordance with this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A supplemental agreement shall:<section prefix="(i)">be for the acquisition of specific units of land in the metropolitan district that comprise portions of the general park plan adopted in the contract or amendment to the contract; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">specify the financing for the acquisition.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A supplemental agreement for a specific unit of land located in Montgomery County or Prince George's County shall be submitted to the appropriate county council for ratification.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The appropriate county council shall ratify a supplemental agreement if the county finds that:<section prefix="(i)">the boundaries of the unit of land to be acquired under the supplemental agreement are in the general park plan adopted by the contract or amendment that the agreement supplements; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the proceeds from the taxes authorized under the supplemental agreement will allow the Commission to satisfy the obligations of the supplemental agreement, including any interest.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In determining whether the Commission will be able to meet an obligation with the proceeds of the taxes authorized under the supplemental agreement, the appropriate county council shall:<section prefix="(i)">compute the proceeds on the assessable basis of the parts of the metropolitan district lying in the county for the fiscal year in which approval is sought; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">assume that the entire tax imposed will be collected so long as there is an outstanding and unpaid obligation.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The appropriate county council may ratify the supplemental agreement by simple resolution authorizing the chair of the county council to:<section prefix="(i)">endorse the supplemental agreement; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">execute a guarantee in accordance with this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Ratification by the Montgomery County Council is not necessary to approve:<section prefix="(i)">contracts or amendments that are not related to the acquisition of a specific unit of parkland; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">supplemental agreements to contracts related only to the acquisition of specific units of parkland.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
