<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="glu" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-16-308</section_number>
  <catch_line>If the parties to collective bargaining have not reached an agreement on or before December 1 or any...</catch_line>
  <order_by>308</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the parties to collective bargaining have not reached an agreement on or before December 1 or any later date determined by mutual agreement of the parties on a collective bargaining agreement that would succeed the existing collective bargaining agreement:<section prefix="(i)">either party may declare a bargaining impasse; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the parties jointly shall appoint an arbitrator.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the parties are unable to agree on an arbitrator, the labor relations administrator shall appoint the arbitrator on or before December 7 or any later date determined by mutual agreement of the parties.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding appointment of the arbitrator, this subtitle does not require arbitration to begin before February 1 or any later date determined by mutual agreement of the parties.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On or before February 1 or any later date determined by mutual agreement of the parties, the arbitrator shall direct the parties to submit:<section prefix="(1)">a joint memorandum listing all items to which the parties previously agreed; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a separate memorandum of each party's last final offer presented in negotiations on all items to which the parties previously did not agree.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before February 10 or any later date determined by mutual agreement of the parties, the arbitrator shall hold a closed hearing on the parties' proposals at a time, date, and place selected by the arbitrator.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each party shall submit evidence or make oral and written arguments in support of the party's last final offer.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The arbitrator may not open the hearing to a person that is not a party to the arbitration.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before February 15 or any later date determined by mutual agreement of the parties, the arbitrator shall issue a report selecting the last final offer submitted by the parties that the arbitrator determines to be more reasonable when viewed as a whole.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In determining which last final offer is more reasonable, the arbitrator may consider only:<section prefix="(i)">past collective bargaining agreements between the parties, including the past bargaining history that led to the collective bargaining agreement or the precollective bargaining history of employee wages, hours, benefits, and other working conditions;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a comparison of wages, hours, benefits, and other conditions of employment of police officers in Montgomery County and Prince George's County;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the public interest and welfare;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the ability of the Commission to finance any economic adjustments required under the proposed collective bargaining agreement; and</section><section prefix="(v)">the effects of any economic adjustments on the standard of public services normally provided by the Commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In determining which last final offer is more reasonable, the arbitrator shall consider all items on which the parties agreed before the arbitration began to be integrated into each offer.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The arbitrator may not:<section prefix="(i)">receive or consider the history of collective bargaining relating to the immediate dispute, including any offers of settlement not contained in the last final offer submitted to the arbitrator; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">compromise or alter the last final offer that the arbitrator selects.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to &#xA7; 16-310(a) of this subtitle, the last final offer selected by the arbitrator, as integrated with the items on which the parties previously agreed, shall be the final agreement between the Commission and the exclusive representative without ratification by the parties.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The parties shall execute a collective bargaining agreement incorporating the final agreement, including arbitration awards and all issues agreed to under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commission and the exclusive representative shall share equally the costs of the arbitrator's services.</section>
  </text>
</law>
