<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-205" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-16-205</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The labor relations administrator shall conduct an election for an exclusive representative after:<section prefix="(1)">an employee organization demonstrates, by petition, that at least 30% of the eligible employees in a bargaining unit support representation by an exclusive representative for collective bargaining; or</section><section prefix="(2)">an employee or an employee organization demonstrates, by petition, that at least 30% of the eligible employees in a bargaining unit no longer support the current exclusive representative.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 30 days before an election under subsection (a) of this section, the labor relations administrator shall obtain from the Commission and provide to the employee organization a list of the names, addresses, and telephone numbers of every employee in the bargaining unit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The provision of a list under this subsection by the Commission, the labor relations administrator, or a Commission official, employee, or other agent does not constitute a violation of &#xA7; 10-617(e) of the State Government Article or any State or local law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Elections shall be conducted by secret ballot containing:<section prefix="(1)">the name of each employee organization that submits a valid petition requiring an election;</section><section prefix="(2)">the name of any other employee organization supported by a petition signed by at least 10% of the eligible employees in the bargaining unit; and</section><section prefix="(3)">an option for no representation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a petition described in subsection (a)(1) of this section is submitted at the same time that a petition described in subsection (a)(2) of this section is submitted, one election shall be held to determine which employee organization, if any, shall be the exclusive representative.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The ballot shall contain:<section prefix="(i)">the name of the current certified employee organization;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the name of the petitioning employee organization; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">an option for no representation.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If none of the choices on the ballot receives a majority of the votes cast, the labor relations administrator shall hold a runoff election.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the runoff election, the ballot shall contain the two choices that received the highest number of votes cast in the initial election.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">After the election, the labor relations administrator shall certify the employee organization that received a majority of the votes cast as the exclusive representative.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If the petitioning employee organization is certified as the result of an election held under subsection (d) of this section, that employee organization shall be treated as a successor in interest and party to any collective bargaining agreement to which the previous employee organization was a party.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Commission and the employee organization shall share equally the costs of the election procedures.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Elections may not be conducted:<section prefix="(i)">within 1 year after the date of a valid election under this section; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, during the term of a collective bargaining agreement.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">During the term of a collective bargaining agreement, a petition for an election may be filed only during November of the fiscal year in which the agreement expires.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
