<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="glu" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-1-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>A regulation adopted under this division that conflicts with any statute, local law, or other regula...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A regulation adopted under this division that conflicts with any statute, local law, or other regulation shall govern if the regulation adopted under this division:<section prefix="(1)">requires a greater width or size of yards, courts, or other open spaces;</section><section prefix="(2)">requires a lower height of buildings;</section><section prefix="(3)">requires a reduced number of stories;</section><section prefix="(4)">requires a greater percentage of lot left unoccupied; or</section><section prefix="(5)">imposes a more restrictive standard.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A statute, local law, or other regulation that conflicts with a regulation adopted under this division shall govern if the statute, local law, or other regulation:<section prefix="(1)">requires a greater width or size of yards, courts, or other open spaces;</section><section prefix="(2)">requires a lower height of buildings;</section><section prefix="(3)">requires a reduced number of stories;</section><section prefix="(4)">requires a greater percentage of lot left unoccupied; or</section><section prefix="(5)">imposes a more restrictive standard.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to the Maryland-Washington Regional District established under Chapter 992 of the Acts of the General Assembly of 1943.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This division does not supplement Chapter 992 of the Acts of the General Assembly of 1943 if a local agency located within the Maryland-Washington Regional District administers municipal and regional planning and zoning.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In the Maryland-Washington Regional District, the additional and supplemental powers vested by this division in a legislative body may not be considered vested in and may not be exercised by a county council acting as a district council under Chapter 992 of the Acts of the General Assembly of 1943.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In the Maryland-Washington Regional District, the powers vested by this division in a planning commission or board of appeals may not be considered vested in and may not be exercised by the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission, the planning board, or the board of zoning appeals of the affected county.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Provisions of this division that are inconsistent with or contrary to Chapter 992 of the Acts of the General Assembly of 1943 do not apply in the Maryland-Washington Regional District.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">This division does not affect the validity of Chapter 992 of the Acts of the General Assembly of 1943.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
