<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="glu" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-22-107</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only in Montgomery County....</catch_line>
  <order_by>107</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section applies only in Montgomery County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The requirements of this section do not apply to an application for a zoning map amendment filed by the district council or by the Commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the district council for Montgomery County may not receive an application for a zoning map amendment on land that was:<section prefix="(i)">the subject of a prior application for a zoning map amendment filed after June 1, 1965; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">for the same zoning classification on which there was a decision on the merits.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An application may be refiled after 36 months have elapsed since the filing of the application for the prior zoning map amendment that was decided on the merits.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "substantial interest" includes an individual or corporate interest of 5% or more of the full cash value of property that is subject to an application for a zoning map amendment under this section, excluding all mortgages, deeds of trust, liens, and encumbrances on the property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An application for a zoning map amendment shall include the name of:<section prefix="(i)">each person that has a substantial interest in the property that is the subject of the application;</section><section prefix="(ii)">each contract purchaser; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">each person holding a mortgage, deed of trust, or option to purchase the property.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
