<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-114" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-15-114</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission shall establish an adequate comprehensive insurance program.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The comprehensive insurance program shall provide:<section prefix="(i)">compensation for personal injury or death or property damage resulting from negligence, malpractice, or any other civil or tortious act or omission of the Commission, or of its commissioners, employees, and agents acting within the scope of their duties and without malice or gross negligence; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">protection for property of the Commission and for officials and employees acting within the scope of their duties, including a comprehensive workers' compensation program.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission may purchase any other liability insurance the Commission considers necessary.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission may establish a program of group health, life, hospitalization, and disability insurance by purchasing insurance coverage from insurance companies authorized to do business in the State and, except for disability insurance, not by self-insurance.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The insurance required under subsection (b) of this section and the disability insurance authorized under subsection (c) of this section may be provided by:<section prefix="(i)">purchasing insurance coverage from insurance companies authorized to do business in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a self-insurance program; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a combination of purchased insurance coverage and self-insurance.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a self-insurance program is established and funded to cover all or part of the insurance required under subsection (b) of this section:<section prefix="(i)">the Commission shall adopt rules and regulations for the administration of the program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">funding for the program shall be included in the annual operating budget.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The insurance program established by the Commission shall provide for:<section prefix="(i)">defense of claims; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">compensation for damages.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Within the limits of appropriations for the insurance program, the Commission may:<section prefix="(i)">engage necessary claims investigators and adjustors; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">provide for the defense and settlement of claims and payment of judgments.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, the Commission may cooperate with and enter into agreements to obtain and provide insurance coverage in the most economical manner with:<section prefix="(i)">Montgomery County;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Prince George's County;</section><section prefix="(iii)">both Montgomery County and Prince George's County; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">subject to the approval of the county government of a county affected by the agreement, other units of government.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An agreement under paragraph (1) of this subsection may provide for any type of insurance protection, including:<section prefix="(i)">public liability;</section><section prefix="(ii)">group health, life, hospitalization, and disability;</section><section prefix="(iii)">real and personal property; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">workers' compensation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This subsection does not authorize the Commission to establish a self-insurance program for group health, life, and hospitalization insurance.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, a payment made to a police officer employed by the Commission for an illness or injury received in the line of duty in accordance with any disability program or disability insurance program authorized under this section is considered in the nature of workers' compensation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A payment described in this subsection is independent of any payment made under the Maryland Workers' Compensation Act.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This subsection does not affect:<section prefix="(i)">the offset provision under &#xA7; 9-610 of the Labor and Employment Article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the presumption of a police officer's entitlement to benefits under &#xA7; 9-503 of the Labor and Employment Article.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
