<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="1-207" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-1-207</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "planning commission" includes a planning commission or board established under:<section prefix="(1)">Title 2 of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">Division II of this article; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Article 25A of the Code.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On or before July 1 of each year, a planning commission shall prepare, adopt, and file an annual report for the previous calendar year with the legislative body.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The annual report shall:<section prefix="(1)">index and locate on a map any changes in development patterns that occurred during the period covered by the report, including:<section prefix="(i)">land use;</section><section prefix="(ii)">transportation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">community facilities patterns;</section><section prefix="(iv)">zoning map amendments; and</section><section prefix="(v)">subdivision plats;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">state whether the changes under item (1) of this subsection are consistent with:<section prefix="(i)">each other;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the recommendations of the last annual report;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the adopted plans of the local jurisdiction;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the adopted plans of all adjoining local jurisdictions; and</section><section prefix="(v)">the adopted plans of State and local jurisdictions that have responsibility for financing or constructing public improvements necessary to implement the local jurisdiction's plan;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">contain statements and recommendations for improving the planning and development process within the local jurisdiction;</section><section prefix="(4)">state which local laws or regulations have been adopted or changed to implement the visions in &#xA7; 1-201 of this subtitle as required under &#xA7; 1-417 of this title or &#xA7; 3-303 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(5)">contain the measures and indicators required under &#xA7; 1-208(c) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The legislative body shall review the annual report and direct that any appropriate and necessary studies and other actions be undertaken to ensure the continuation of a viable planning and development process.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The local jurisdiction shall make the annual report available for public inspection.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The local jurisdiction shall mail a copy of the report to the Secretary of Planning.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department of Planning may comment on the report.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
