<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="22-216" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-22-216</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "custodian" means the custodian of the records of a zoning map amendment case in the county.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before the Commission sends a zoning map amendment case to the district council, the Commission is the custodian.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After the Commission sends a zoning map amendment case to the district council, the district council is the custodian.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Correspondence or documents submitted to a custodian shall be received in a record only in accordance with any applicable statute, local law, rule of evidence, or case law.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, each application for a zoning map amendment and all official correspondence and records relating to the application, prepared or received in a record by the custodian, shall be made available to the public during the custodian's regular business hours.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the custodian may publish rules to prevent any access provided under paragraph (1) of this subsection from unreasonably disrupting the custodian's official business.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Copies of technical staff reports shall be available for the public at the office of the custodian under all circumstances.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An individual who personally appears at the office of the custodian may obtain, without charge, a copy of a public document if the document:<section prefix="(1)">is of letter or legal size; and</section><section prefix="(2)">pertains to a specific zoning case, including zoning applications and justification statements.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
