<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="22-309" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-22-309</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a board of appeals in Prince George's County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The County Council of Prince George's County shall appoint three members to the board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each member of the board shall be a resident of the regional district in Prince George's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The term of a member is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed to fill a vacancy shall serve for the rest of the term.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The board each year shall elect a chair and vice-chair.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">All meetings of the board shall be public.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The board shall keep minutes of its proceedings.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The board shall act by resolution.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">At least two members of the board must concur in any resolution.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The board or any officer of the board may administer oaths and compel the attendance of witnesses.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The district council may adopt regulations consistent with this subtitle to govern the organization and procedure of the board.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The board may adopt supplemental rules of procedure consistent with this subtitle and the regulations of the district council.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The County Council shall determine the compensation of the members of the board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The County Council may provide staff for the board.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
