<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-4-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Zoning regulations and boundaries may be amended or repealed.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the purpose and effect of a proposed map amendment is to change a zoning classification, the legislative body shall make findings of fact that address:<section prefix="(i)">population change;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the availability of public facilities;</section><section prefix="(iii)">present and future transportation patterns;</section><section prefix="(iv)">compatibility with existing and proposed development for the area;</section><section prefix="(v)">the recommendation of the planning commission; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">the relationship of the proposed amendment to the local jurisdiction's plan.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The legislative body may grant the amendment to change the zoning classification based on a finding that there was:<section prefix="(i)">a substantial change in the character of the neighborhood where the property is located; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a mistake in the existing zoning classification.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The legislative body shall keep a complete record of a hearing on an application for reclassification and the votes of the members of the legislative body.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A legislative body may not allow the filing of an application for a reclassification of all or part of any land for which a reclassification has been denied by the legislative body on the merits in the 12 months before the date of the application.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The provisions of &#xA7; 4-203(b) of this subtitle concerning public hearings and notice apply to applications for reclassification.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
