<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="glu" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-5-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Community sewerage system" means a publicly or privately owned sewerage system that serves at least two lots.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Major subdivision" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 9-206 of the Environment Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"On-site sewage disposal system" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 9-206 of the Environment Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Planning board" means a planning board established under this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Planning board" includes a planning commission or board established under Division II of this article or Article 25A of the Code.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Shared facility" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 9-206 of the Environment Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only to a residential major subdivision in a Tier III area served by:<section prefix="(1)">on-site sewage disposal systems;</section><section prefix="(2)">a shared facility; or</section><section prefix="(3)">a community sewerage system.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a local jurisdiction establishes the growth tiers under Title 1, Subtitle 5 of this article, a residential major subdivision in a Tier III area may not be approved unless the planning board has reviewed and recommended the approval of the major subdivision in the Tier III area.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before recommending the approval of a proposed major subdivision in a Tier III area, the planning board shall hold at least one public hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The planning board shall conduct the public hearing in accordance with its rules and procedures.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The review of a residential major subdivision by the planning board shall include:<section prefix="(1)">the cost of providing local governmental services to the residential major subdivision unless a local jurisdiction's adequate public facilities law already requires a review of government services; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the potential environmental issues or a natural resources inventory related to the proposed residential major subdivision.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The planning board shall recommend the proposed residential major subdivision by resolution of the planning board.</section>
  </text>
</law>
