<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-106" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-15-106</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The County Executive of Prince George's County, with the approval of a majority of the members of the County Council, and the Montgomery County Council, with the approval of the County Executive in accordance with subsection (b) of this section, shall each designate a commissioner for the position of chair or vice chair.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 3 days after making a designation, the Montgomery County Council shall submit the name of the designee to the County Executive.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 30 days after the designation is submitted, the County Executive shall approve or disapprove the designation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the County Executive disapproves a designee, the County Executive shall return the name of the designee to the County Council with the reasons for the disapproval stated in writing.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">By the affirmative vote of six of its members, the County Council may designate a commissioner for the position of chair or vice chair over the disapproval of the County Executive.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A designation that has not been disapproved by the County Executive in accordance with this subsection is deemed to be approved.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission shall elect a chair and vice chair from the commissioners designated in accordance with subsections (a) and (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The chair shall:<section prefix="(i)">preside at meetings of the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">perform the other customary duties of the office.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The vice chair shall preside in the absence of the chair.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The chair and vice chair of the Commission also serve as chairs of their respective county planning boards.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
