<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-4-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A legislative body may authorize the planning director or another designee to grant an administrative adjustment from the following requirements in a zoning law enacted by the legislative body:<section prefix="(1)">height;</section><section prefix="(2)">setback;</section><section prefix="(3)">bulk;</section><section prefix="(4)">parking;</section><section prefix="(5)">loading, dimensional, or area; or</section><section prefix="(6)">similar requirements.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Before developing criteria and procedures for administrative adjustments under this section, the legislative body shall:<section prefix="(1)">consult with the planning commission and the board of appeals; and</section><section prefix="(2)">provide:<section prefix="(i)">reasonable public notice of the proposed criteria and procedures;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an opportunity for a public hearing; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">an opportunity for public review and comment.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The criteria for an administrative adjustment shall include:<section prefix="(1)">standards for actions on requests;</section><section prefix="(2)">standards for the classes of development that are eligible for an administrative adjustment; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the maximum variation from a zoning requirement that is allowed under an administrative adjustment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Procedures for administrative adjustments may address:<section prefix="(1)">applications;</section><section prefix="(2)">notice to the public and to the parties in interest;</section><section prefix="(3)">an opportunity for a public hearing;</section><section prefix="(4)">an opportunity for the taking of testimony and evidence; and</section><section prefix="(5)">decision making.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A decision on an application for an administrative adjustment shall include written findings of fact and conclusions of law.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">By enacting a local law or adopting a procedure, a legislative body may authorize the appeal to the board of appeals of a decision to approve or deny an administrative adjustment.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Nothing in this section is intended to authorize a local jurisdiction to allow an administrative adjustment to State or local requirements that are intended to protect environmentally sensitive areas such as streams, slopes, wetlands, natural heritage areas, or critical areas.</section>
  </text>
</law>
