<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="25-302" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-25-302</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, any party of record to an action of the governing body of a municipal corporation exercised under &#xA7; 25-301(c) of this subtitle shall have the same right to judicial review by the circuit court as the party would have if the district council had taken the action.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any party to an action of the governing body of a municipal corporation or the county planning board exercised under &#xA7; 25-301(d) of this subtitle shall have the same right to judicial review by the circuit court as the party would have if the district council had taken the action.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With respect to an action taken under the general delegation authorized under &#xA7; 25-301(c) of this subtitle, before exercising the right to judicial review under subsection (a)(1) of this section, a party of record shall appeal the action of the governing body of the municipal corporation to the district council for review on the record if the action concerns:<section prefix="(i)">certification, revocation, or revision of nonconforming uses; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">detailed site plans.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On appeal, the district council may:<section prefix="(i)">approve the action of the municipal corporation by a majority vote of its members; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">approve the action of the municipal corporation with conditions or overrule the action by a vote of at least six members.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A person aggrieved by the action of the district council under this subsection may request judicial review of the action by the circuit court.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The municipal corporation whose action is affected by the action of the district council shall be considered an aggrieved person.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
