<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="glu" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-14-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this division the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this division the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Commission" means the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Commissioner" means a member of the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"County" means a county of the State or Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"County planning board" means a planning board for a county established under Title 20, Subtitle 2 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"District council" means:<section prefix="(1)">for a single county, the county council sitting as the district council of the county with respect to that portion of the regional district in the county under &#xA7; 22-101 of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">for the district council as a whole, the county councils of both counties sitting jointly as the bi-county district council of the regional district under &#xA7; 22-102 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(3)">for a municipal corporation, the governing body of the municipal corporation sitting as the district council for the municipal corporation under an agreement authorized under &#xA7; 20-704(c) of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Governed special taxing district" or "governed district" means a special taxing district that:<section prefix="(1)">has an elected local governing body; and</section><section prefix="(2)">performs general municipal functions.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Local law" means an enactment of the legislative body of a local jurisdiction, whether by ordinance, resolution, or otherwise.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Local law" does not include a public local law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Metropolitan district" means the Maryland-Washington Metropolitan District established under Title 19 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Park" includes a public playground, play field, and any other recreational ground, space, or facility.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Person" means an individual, receiver, trustee, guardian, personal representative, fiduciary, representative of any kind, partnership, firm, association, corporation, limited liability company, or other entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Regional district" means the Maryland-Washington Regional District established under Title 20, Subtitle 1 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Road" includes a highway, freeway, boulevard, parkway, street, avenue, lane, alley, viaduct, bridge, and any other way or part of a way.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Sensitive area" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 1-101 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, "state" means:<section prefix="(i)">a state, possession, territory, or commonwealth of the United States; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the District of Columbia.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When capitalized, "State" means Maryland.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Subdivision" means:<section prefix="(i)">the process and configuration of land by which one or more lots, tracts, or parcels of land are divided, consolidated, or established as one or more lots or parcels, or other divisions of land, consistent with criteria established by the legislative body of the local jurisdiction; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the land so subdivided.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Subdivision" includes resubdivision.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Zoning law" means the legislative implementation of regulations for zoning by a local jurisdiction.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Zoning law" includes a zoning ordinance, zoning regulation, zoning code, and any similar legislative action to implement zoning controls in a local jurisdiction.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
