<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="glu" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-23-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>In exercising the subdivision powers under &#xA7;&#xA7; 23-102 and 23-103 of this subtitle, the Commission o...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In exercising the subdivision powers under &#xA7;&#xA7; 23-102 and 23-103 of this subtitle, the Commission or the governing body of Montgomery County or Prince George's County may adopt subdivision regulations and amendments governing a subdivision in:<section prefix="(i)">the regional district; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the respective portion of the regional district in the county.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, the regulations and amendments adopted under this section:<section prefix="(i)">shall be adopted by the respective governing body of the county;</section><section prefix="(ii)">may be amended by the respective governing body of the county; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">shall be effective from:<section prefix="1.">the date of adoption; or</section><section prefix="2.">the date designated by the respective governing body of the county.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the governing body of the county designates an effective date for the subdivision regulations, the effective date may not affect:<section prefix="(i)">the county planning board's administration of the regulations; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the county planning board's functions under &#xA7;&#xA7; 23-102 and 23-103 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Montgomery County:<section prefix="(i)">within 3 days after adopting a subdivision regulation or amendment, the district council shall submit the regulation or amendment to the County Executive; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">within 10 days after the subdivision regulation or amendment is submitted, the County Executive shall approve or disapprove the regulation or amendment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the County Executive disapproves the subdivision regulation or amendment, the County Executive shall return the regulation or amendment to the district council with the reasons for the disapproval stated in writing.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">By the affirmative vote of six of its members, the district council may enact the subdivision regulation or amendment over the disapproval of the County Executive.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A subdivision regulation or amendment that has not been disapproved by the County Executive in accordance with this subsection is considered to be approved.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection and subsection (d) of this section, the subdivision regulations may include provisions for:<section prefix="(i)">the harmonious development of the regional district;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the coordination of roads within the subdivision with:<section prefix="1.">existing planned or platted roads;</section><section prefix="2.">features of the regional district;</section><section prefix="3.">that county's general plan; or</section><section prefix="4.">a transportation plan adopted by the Commission as part of that county's general plan;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)"><section prefix="1.">adequate open spaces for transportation, recreation, light, and air, by dedication or otherwise;</section><section prefix="2.">the dedication to public use or conveyance of areas designated for dedication under the zoning and subdivision regulations; and</section><section prefix="3.">in lieu of dedication, the payment of a monetary fee that meets the requirements of subsection (d) of this section;</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">the reservation of land for:<section prefix="1.">public buildings, including schools;</section><section prefix="2.">parks and playgrounds;</section><section prefix="3.">roads;</section><section prefix="4.">mass transit facilities, including busways or light rail facilities; and</section><section prefix="5.">any other public purpose;</section></section><section prefix="(v)">the conservation or production of adequate transportation, water drainage, and sanitary facilities;</section><section prefix="(vi)">the preservation of the location of, the volume and flow of water in, and other characteristics of natural streams and other waterways, including the establishment of a stormwater management program in Montgomery County for the purpose of:<section prefix="1.">allowing the county to accept monetary contributions;</section><section prefix="2.">granting an easement; or</section><section prefix="3.">dedicating land;</section></section><section prefix="(vii)">the avoidance of undue population congestion;</section><section prefix="(viii)">the avoidance of a scattered or premature subdivision that otherwise may:<section prefix="1.">result in danger or injury to health, safety, or welfare due to the lack of water supply, drainage, transportation, or other public services; or</section><section prefix="2.">necessitate an excessive expenditure of public funds for the supply of services;</section></section><section prefix="(ix)">the conformity of resubdivided lots to the character of lots within the existing subdivision with respect to area, frontage, and alignment to existing lots and roads;</section><section prefix="(x)">except for agricultural or recreational purposes, the control of subdivision or building in floodplain areas and in streams and drainage courses, and on unsafe land areas;</section><section prefix="(xi)">the preservation of outstanding natural or cultural features and historic sites or structures;</section><section prefix="(xii)">any benefit to the health, comfort, safety, or welfare of the present and future population of the regional district;</section><section prefix="(xiii)">the extent and manner to which the following actions shall be taken before the approval of a plat:<section prefix="1.">the grading and improvement of roads;</section><section prefix="2.">the building of curbs, gutters, and sidewalks;</section><section prefix="3.">the installation of water, sewer, and other utility mains, piping, connections, and facilities; and</section><section prefix="4.">the planting or conservation of trees; or</section></section><section prefix="(xiv)">in Montgomery County:<section prefix="1.">adequate recreational facilities; or</section><section prefix="2.">in lieu of providing recreational facilities, the payment of a fee that does not exceed the cost of providing adequate recreational facilities to serve the subdivision.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Unless each person that owns a legal or equitable interest in the property has provided written approval, the subdivision regulations may not provide for a reservation of land for traffic, recreation, or any other public purpose for a period longer than 3 years.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A property that is reserved for public use under the subdivision regulations shall be exempt from all State, county, and local taxes during the period of reservation.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, a monetary fee that is paid in lieu of a dedication of land for the use and benefit of the subdivision in cases where dedication would be impractical under subsection (c)(1)(iii) of this section shall:<section prefix="(i)">be based on the current market value of the land after the land is approved for development; and</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">be used by the Commission to purchase open spaces; or</section><section prefix="2.">be used by the Commission to develop or otherwise improve land or recreational facilities that will assist in supplying the overall recreational needs of the subdivision if:</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the subdivision is in a municipal corporation in Prince George's County that is not in the metropolitan district but is in the regional district, on request by the municipal corporation, the mandatory fee in lieu of dedication received by the Commission shall be paid to and used by the municipal corporation to:<section prefix="(i)">purchase open space for the use and benefit of the subdivision; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">develop or otherwise improve land or recreational facilities that will assist in supplying the overall recreational and open space needs of the subdivision.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
