<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="glu" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-17-115</section_number>
  <catch_line>In addition to any other authorized payment, the Commission shall make an additional relocation paym...</catch_line>
  <order_by>115</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to any other authorized payment, the Commission shall make an additional relocation payment not to exceed $15,000 to a person who is displaced from a dwelling that the person owns and has occupied for at least 180 days immediately preceding the start of negotiations to acquire the property.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The additional relocation payment shall include:<section prefix="(1)">any additional amount that, added to the acquisition cost of the dwelling acquired by the Commission, equals the reasonable cost of a comparable replacement dwelling that is a habitable dwelling:<section prefix="(i)">adequate to accommodate the displaced person;</section><section prefix="(ii)">reasonably accessible to public services and places of employment; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">available on the private market;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">subject to subsection (c) of this section, any additional amount that the displaced person must pay to finance acquisition of a comparable replacement dwelling; and</section><section prefix="(3)">reasonable expenses the displaced person incurs for title insurance, recording and transfer fees and taxes, and other taxes and closing costs incident to the purchase of the replacement dwelling, other than prepaid expenses.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall include financing under subsection (b)(2) of this section in an additional relocation payment only if the dwelling was encumbered by a mortgage that was a valid lien on the dwelling for at least 180 days immediately preceding the start of negotiations to acquire the dwelling.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The amount payable under subsection (b)(2) of this section shall be computed for the period of time remaining under the mortgage on the acquired dwelling as the product of:<section prefix="(i)">the net present value of the difference, if any, between:<section prefix="1.">the interest and other debt service costs to be incurred to finance the replacement dwelling for that period; and</section><section prefix="2.">those costs that would have been incurred for that period to finance the acquired dwelling; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">the unpaid principal balance of the mortgage on the acquired dwelling at the time of acquisition divided by the principal amount of the purchase money mortgage on the replacement dwelling.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The discount rate shall be the prevailing interest rate paid on savings deposits by commercial banks in the general area where the replacement dwelling is located.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commission shall make the additional relocation payment only to a displaced person who purchases and occupies a habitable replacement dwelling by the later of:<section prefix="(1)">1 year after the person receives from the Commission final payment of all costs of the acquired dwelling; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the date when the person moves from the acquired dwelling.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
