<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-120" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-15-120</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not prohibit a commissioner from:<section prefix="(1)">appearing in the pursuit of the commissioner's private interests as a citizen;</section><section prefix="(2)">accepting or receiving any benefit by operation of law; or</section><section prefix="(3)">prosecuting or pursuing any claim, right, privilege, or remedy that accrues to the commissioner by operation of law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This subsection does not prohibit a commissioner from having or holding a private investment, business, or professional interest, unless the interest is or reasonably may be in conflict with the proper performance of the commissioner's duty.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A private investment, business, or professional interest is presumed to be in conflict with the proper performance of the commissioner's duty if the commissioner or the commissioner's spouse, parent, child, brother, or sister:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection does not apply to or include:<section prefix="(i)">an interest or investment in land geographically remote from the land involved in the decision;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the ownership of a recorded single-family lot on which the commissioner actually resides; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a possibility of reverter, a mortgage, or other security interest in real property not otherwise described in this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A commissioner may not:<section prefix="(i)">decide, or participate in, a decision in which the commissioner has a financial interest, whether as an owner, member, partner, officer, employee, stockholder, or other participant of or in any private business or professional enterprise, that will be affected by the decision; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">knowingly participate in a decision affecting the financial interest, jointly or severally, of a person related to the commissioner or the commissioner's spouse, parent, child, brother, or sister.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A commissioner may not:<section prefix="(1)">act as a broker, agent, attorney, representative, or employee of any person in the person's business dealings with:<section prefix="(i)">Montgomery County;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Prince George's County;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Commission;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">decide, or participate in, a decision on any matter in which a close business or professional associate has acted as a broker, agent, attorney, representative, or employee of any person or represented private interests before:<section prefix="(i)">Montgomery County;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Prince George's County;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Commission; or</section></section><section prefix="(3)">represent a private interest or appear in a position of advocacy, other than in the performance of the commissioner's official duties, either in person or through an associate, in any matter or proceeding pending before:<section prefix="(i)">the Montgomery County Council;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Prince George's County Council;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Commission;</section><section prefix="(v)">the Montgomery County Board of Appeals; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">the Prince George's County Board of Appeals.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A commissioner may not solicit or accept any gift, favor, loan, service, promise, employment, or thing that might influence or tend to influence the proper performance of the commissioner's duty.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A commissioner may not:<section prefix="(1)">disclose confidential information concerning the property, management, or affairs of:<section prefix="(i)">Montgomery County;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Prince George's County;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Commission; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">use any information described in item (1) of this subsection to advance the financial or other private interests of the commissioner or other persons.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A commissioner may not attempt to influence for a purpose contrary to this section any other county or State official in the conduct of the other official's duties.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a commissioner has any interest described in this section that is or reasonably may be incompatible with or in conflict with any of the commissioner's official duties or acts, the commissioner:<section prefix="(i)">shall disclose the interest in a regular public meeting of the Commission or the county planning boards; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is disqualified and may not participate in the decision or act affected by the interest.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A disclosure made under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall appear in the minutes of the meeting.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A commissioner who violates any provision of subsections (b) through (f) of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to:<section prefix="(1)">imprisonment not exceeding 6 months or a fine not exceeding $1,000 or both;</section><section prefix="(2)">suspension from the Commission or employment not exceeding 6 months;</section><section prefix="(3)">forfeiture and removal from office; or</section><section prefix="(4)">any combination of the penalties described in items (1) through (3) of this subsection.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
