<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="glu" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-21-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>The general plan and any amendment to the general plan shall contain:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The general plan and any amendment to the general plan shall contain:<section prefix="(1)">the Commission's recommendations for development within the regional district;</section><section prefix="(2)">any descriptive or supporting material that:<section prefix="(i)">the appropriate district council requires; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Commission determines to be necessary and feasible; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">the elements required under Title 1, Subtitle 4 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In accordance with the procedure set forth in this subtitle, the appropriate district council may require the Commission to prepare the general plan, or any amendment to the plan, considering elements such as:<section prefix="(i)">existing and forecasted:<section prefix="1.">population, including population distribution and other appropriate characteristics;</section><section prefix="2.">amount, type, intensity, general location, and characteristics of commercial, industrial, and public sector facilities and related employment;</section><section prefix="3.">amount, type, need, and location of major public services, facilities, and utilities;</section><section prefix="4.">transportation needs, facilities, routes, and systems; and</section><section prefix="5.">housing demand and needs, and the amount, type, quality, and general location of housing;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">existing land uses, forecasts of land absorption rates or markets, and analyses of the amount, general location, and interrelationships among different categories of land use;</section><section prefix="(iii)">staging or scheduling of development and capital improvements, and the fiscal or economic impact of those improvements;</section><section prefix="(iv)">physical resources and conditions, including topography, soils, geology and mineral deposits, hydrology and waterways, wetlands and shorelines, water and air quality, climate, noise, open spaces, scenic areas, vegetation, forests, agricultural lands, fisheries, wildlife and wildlife habitats, and other areas of environmental or ecological importance or sensitivity;</section><section prefix="(v)">sites, structures, areas, or settings of archaeological, historical, architectural, cultural, or scenic value or significance;</section><section prefix="(vi)">extent and general location of physically blighted or deteriorated areas and related factors;</section><section prefix="(vii)">evaluation of the probable consequences of major recommendations of the general plan on the general physical and social environment and population of the regional district;</section><section prefix="(viii)">estimates of the probable consequences on public revenues and expenditures of major recommendations of the general plan; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">any other matter that the appropriate district council or the Commission determines to be necessary and feasible to the preparation or presentation of the general plan.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The appropriate district council may provide, to the extent necessary and feasible, that:<section prefix="(i)">the Commission shall:<section prefix="1.">consider various alternative concepts of growth or development in preparing the general plan; and</section><section prefix="2.">appropriately describe the alternative concepts considered by the Commission; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">the general plan shall include material to contain and explain the appropriate district council's recommendations with respect to any matter in this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The materials in paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection are guidelines for the basis, content, and consideration of:<section prefix="(i)">the general plan;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a functional master plan;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an area master plan; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">any amendment to the plans.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Subject to paragraph (5) of this subsection, a general plan, a functional master plan, or an area master plan or any amendment to a plan may not be deemed void, inapplicable, or inoperative on the ground that the basis, content, or consideration of the plan or amendment is inconsistent with this division.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">With respect to judicial review on the record of a governmental action concerning development, this section does not prevent the consideration of the reasonableness of a general plan or the appropriateness and completeness of a general plan in relation to the governmental action and review.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
