<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="17-204" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-17-204</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may lease to any responsible person any land in the metropolitan district acquired for park purposes under this division.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The term of a lease may not exceed 20 years without the prior approval of the lease by legislative enactment of the county where the lease property is located.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The initial term of a lease may not exceed 40 years.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A lease may be renewed for additional terms not exceeding 10 years each.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A lease agreement shall contain provisions for reversion without cost to the Commission of the property and its improvements regardless of whether the improvements were added to the property by the lessee during the term of the lease or any extension of the lease.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may grant privileges, permits, and concessions, and may enter into contracts relating to them, with any responsible person to engage in any business or enterprise on land in the metropolitan district acquired for park purposes under this division.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any privilege, permit, or concession granted under this subsection shall be on terms and conditions the Commission considers advantageous to the development of the park system as a part of the plan for the physical development of the metropolitan district and the plan of the regional district within the metropolitan district.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The purpose for which property is leased, or for which a privilege, permit, or concession is granted, may not be inconsistent with the use of the property for park purposes.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any lease or contract executed under this section shall contain a condition stating specifically the purposes for which the property is leased or for which the privilege, permit, or concession is granted.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An agreement the Commission enters into in accordance with this division shall contain provisions prohibiting the assignment of the agreement without the consent of the Commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In Montgomery County, a lease, contract, or agreement entered into under this section may not:<section prefix="(1)">authorize a person other than the Commission to close a park or park facility; or</section><section prefix="(2)">grant a person other than the Commission the authority to close or require the closing of an existing park or park facility under the jurisdiction of the Commission to prevent competition.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This division does not limit the Commission's authority to require an agreement to contain more restrictive provisions the Commission considers to be in the public interest.</section>
  </text>
</law>
