<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="18-401" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-18-401</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Fund" means an Advance Land Acquisition Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is an Advance Land Acquisition Fund in each county.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The purpose of each Fund is to purchase land and related facilities consistent with the purposes of this section and &#xA7;&#xA7; 18-402 and 18-403 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commission shall administer each Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to reversion under &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article or provisions of this division relating to unexpended balances.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Each Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">money allocated to the Fund for the respective county in the annual budgets of the Commission under Subtitle 1 of this title;</section><section prefix="(2)">proceeds of bonds issued under this section and allocated to the Fund;</section><section prefix="(3)">investment earnings of the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(4)">any other money from any other source accepted for the benefit of the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Any investment earnings of a Fund shall be paid into the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Expenditures from a Fund may be made only in accordance with this section and &#xA7;&#xA7; 18-402 and 18-403 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At any time after acquiring land, on repayment to the Commission of the amount disbursed by the Commission for the land plus interest, the Commission may transfer the land to:<section prefix="(i)">a construction agency of the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Montgomery County;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Prince George's County;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the redevelopment authority of Prince George's County;</section><section prefix="(v)">the revenue authority of Prince George's County; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">a municipal corporation or governed special taxing district in Montgomery County or Prince George's County.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall place any amount received in repayment for land in the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the State construction agency for Montgomery County or a municipal corporation or governed district in Montgomery County determines that acquired land is not required for a public use specified on the county's plan required under &#xA7; 18-402(b) of this subtitle, the Commission may use the land as a part of its park system.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A use of land by the Commission for park or recreation purposes under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph is not a dedication for these purposes.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If the Commission at any time determines that the land is not needed for park purposes, the Commission may dispose of the land in the manner provided for elsewhere in this division.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the State construction agency for Prince George's County or a municipal corporation or governed district in Prince George's County, the redevelopment authority for Prince George's County, or the revenue authority of Prince George's County determines that acquired land is not required for public use, the Commission may use the land as a part of its park system, subject to the approval of the Prince George's County Council.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A use of land by the Commission for park or recreation purposes under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph is not a dedication for these purposes.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If the Commission at any time determines that the land is not needed for park purposes, the Commission may dispose of the land in the manner provided for elsewhere in this division.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Commission may issue and sell bonds in amounts it considers necessary for the purposes of the Funds.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In Prince George's County, the Commission's issuance and sale of bonds concerning the county is subject to approval by the County Council.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the amount of the bonds outstanding at any time may not exceed an amount that is redeemable within 30 years from the date of issue by a tax of 1.2 cents on each $100 assessed valuation of real property in Montgomery County and Prince George's County and 3 cents on each $100 assessed valuation of personal property and operating real property described in &#xA7; 8-109(c) of the Tax - Property Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">To determine the amount of bonds outstanding under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the Commission may assume:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The provisions of Subtitle 2 of this title relating to form, interest rate, sale, redemption, guaranty, and liability apply to bonds issued under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
