<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="glu" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-1-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this division the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this division the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Adaptive reuse" means a change granted by a legislative body under &#xA7; 4-207 of this article to the use restrictions in a zoning classification, as those restrictions are applied to a particular improved property.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Charter county" means a county that has adopted charter home rule under Article XI-A of the Maryland Constitution and Article 25A of the Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Code county" means a county that has adopted code home rule under Article XI-F of the Maryland Constitution and Article 25B of the Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"County" means a county of the State or Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Development" means an activity that materially affects the existing condition or use of any land or structure.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Development" does not include a normal agricultural activity.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Legislative body" means the elected body of a local jurisdiction.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Legislative body" includes:<section prefix="(i)">the board of county commissioners;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the county council; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the governing body of a municipal corporation.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Local executive" means the chief executive of a local jurisdiction.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Local executive" includes:<section prefix="(i)">the board of county commissioners;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the county executive;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the executive head; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the mayor.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Local jurisdiction" means a county or municipal corporation and the territory within which its powers may be exercised.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Local law" means an enactment of the legislative body of a local jurisdiction, whether by ordinance, resolution, or otherwise.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Local law" does not include a public local law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Person" means an individual, receiver, trustee, guardian, personal representative, fiduciary, representative of any kind, partnership, firm, association, corporation, limited liability company, or other entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Plan" means the policies, statements, goals, and interrelated plans for private and public land use, transportation, and community facilities documented in texts and maps that constitute the guide for an area's future development.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Plan" includes a general plan, master plan, comprehensive plan, functional plan, or community plan adopted in accordance with Subtitle 4 of this title and Title 3 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Priority funding area" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 5-7B-02 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Regulation" means a rule of general applicability and future effect.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Regulation" includes a map or plan.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Sensitive area" includes:<section prefix="(1)">a stream or wetland, and its buffers;</section><section prefix="(2)">a 100-year flood plain;</section><section prefix="(3)">a habitat of a threatened or endangered species;</section><section prefix="(4)">a steep slope;</section><section prefix="(5)">agricultural or forest land intended for resource protection or conservation; and</section><section prefix="(6)">any other area in need of special protection, as determined in a plan.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Special exception" means a grant of a specific use that:<section prefix="(1)">would not be appropriate generally or without restriction; and</section><section prefix="(2)">shall be based on a finding that:<section prefix="(i)">the requirements of the zoning law governing the special exception on the subject property are satisfied; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the use on the subject property is consistent with the plan and is compatible with the existing neighborhood.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, "state" means:<section prefix="(i)">a state, possession, territory, or commonwealth of the United States; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the District of Columbia.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When capitalized, "State" means Maryland.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(r)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Subdivision" means:<section prefix="(i)">the process and configuration of land by which one or more lots, tracts, or parcels of land are divided, consolidated, or established as one or more lots or parcels, or other divisions of land, consistent with criteria established by the legislative body of the local jurisdiction; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the land so subdivided.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Subdivision" includes resubdivision.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Variance" means a modification only of density, bulk, dimensional, or area requirements in the zoning law that is not contrary to the public interest, and where, owing to conditions peculiar to the property and not because of any action taken by the applicant, a literal enforcement of the zoning law would result in unnecessary hardship or practical difficulty, as specified in the zoning law.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Zoning law" means the legislative implementation of regulations for zoning by a local jurisdiction.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Zoning law" includes a zoning ordinance, zoning regulation, zoning code, and any similar legislative action to implement zoning controls in a local jurisdiction.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
