<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="26-105" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-26-105</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Montgomery County Historic Preservation Grant Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">There is a Prince George's County Historic Property Grant Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each county planning board administers its Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each county planning board shall deposit in its Fund those amounts authorized in accordance with Title 18, Subtitle 1 of this article to:<section prefix="(1)">implement and encourage restoration and preservation of historic properties; and</section><section prefix="(2)">implement the purposes of its Program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each county planning board shall expend the amounts in its Fund to make grants to nonprofit organizations or foundations.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Montgomery County:<section prefix="(i)">grants may also be made for research, developing educational materials, and generally promoting historic preservation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">in making grants, the county planning board, if practical to do so, shall obtain and implement the recommendations of the Montgomery County Historic Preservation Commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In Prince George's County:<section prefix="(i)">grants may also be made to political subdivisions or individuals to acquire, preserve, restore, or rehabilitate historic properties; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">in making grants, the county planning board shall solicit and consider the recommendations of the Prince George's County Historic Preservation Commission.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">When a county planning board awards a grant, the grant recipient shall convey a perpetual preservation easement to the county planning board.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Decisions by a county planning board concerning grants shall be made without regard to the financial status or annual income of the applicant.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, a county planning board may require matching funds in whatever proportion the county planning board considers appropriate.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
