<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="20-509" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-20-509</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to subsections (b), (c), and (d) of this section, by local law, the legislative body of a municipal corporation or governed special taxing district may impose an additional or stricter building requirement than is required by a State, regional, or county unit that exercises zoning or planning authority over the municipal corporation or governed district if the authority is exercised in addition to the State, regional, or county zoning or planning authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A building requirement adopted under this section:<section prefix="(1)">shall be imposed for:<section prefix="(i)">the protection of the public health, safety, and welfare; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the preservation, improvement, or protection of lands, water, and improvements in the municipal corporation or governed special taxing district; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">may regulate only the construction, repair, or remodeling of single-family residential houses or buildings on land zoned for single-family residential use as it relates to:<section prefix="(i)">fences, walls, hedges, and similar barriers;</section><section prefix="(ii)">signs;</section><section prefix="(iii)">residential parking;</section><section prefix="(iv)">residential storage;</section><section prefix="(v)">the location of structures, including setback requirements;</section><section prefix="(vi)">the dimensions of structures, including height, bulk, massing, and design; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">lot coverage, including impervious surfaces.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before adopting a local law under this section, a municipal corporation or governed special taxing district shall:<section prefix="(1)">hold a public hearing; and</section><section prefix="(2)">at least 30 days before the public hearing, transmit a copy of the proposed local law to the county council.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A local law that a municipal corporation or governed special taxing district adopts under this section shall provide a procedure for a waiver from the strict application of the building requirements.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">By local law, a municipal corporation or governed special taxing district may enact an additional or stricter commercial sign regulation than is imposed by the State, the Commission, or the county.</section>
  </text>
</law>
