<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="17-114" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-17-114</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "average annual net earnings":<section prefix="(1)">means one-half of any net earnings of the business or farm operation, before federal, State, and local income taxes, during:<section prefix="(i)">the 2 taxable years immediately preceding the taxable year when the business or farm operation moves from the real property acquired for the project; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a different period the Commission determines to be more equitable for establishing the earnings; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">includes any compensation paid by the business or farm operation to the owner or the owner's spouse or dependents during the period.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person who is displaced by the acquisition of real property for a program or project the Commission undertakes may apply to the appropriate county planning board for a relocation payment under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission shall make the relocation payment to the displaced person after the county planning board approves the application.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The relocation payment shall include:<section prefix="(i)">actual reasonable expenses to move the person and the person's family, business, farm operation, or other personal property;</section><section prefix="(ii)">actual direct losses of tangible personal property as a result of moving or discontinuing a business or farm operation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">actual reasonable expenses in searching for a replacement business or farm.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The losses payable under paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection may not exceed the reasonable expenses that would have been required to relocate the property, as determined by the appropriate county planning board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A displaced person eligible for a relocation payment under subsection (c) of this section who is displaced from a dwelling and who chooses to accept a relocation payment under this subsection instead of a relocation payment under subsection (c) of this section may receive:<section prefix="(1)">a moving expense allowance determined according to a schedule established by the Commission, not to exceed $300; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a relocation allowance of $200.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to subsection (g) of this section, a displaced person eligible for a relocation payment under subsection (c) of this section who is displaced from the person's place of business or farm operation and who chooses to accept a relocation payment under this subsection instead of a relocation payment under subsection (c) of this section may receive a fixed payment in an amount equal to the average annual net earnings of the business or farm operation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A relocation payment under this subsection shall be at least $2,500 and may not exceed $10,000.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A business is not eligible to receive a relocation payment under subsection (f) of this section unless the Commission is satisfied that the business:<section prefix="(1)">cannot be relocated without a substantial loss of its existing patronage; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is not a part of a commercial enterprise that has at least one other location that:<section prefix="(i)">the Commission is not acquiring; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is engaged in the same or a similar business.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
