<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-17-210</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>210</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If a park police officer apprehends a person for violating any law punishable as a misdemeanor under &#xA7; 17-209 of this subtitle, the officer may prepare and sign a written citation.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A citation issued under subsection (a) of this section shall include:<section prefix="(1)">a notice to appear in court;</section><section prefix="(2)">the name and address of the person charged;</section><section prefix="(3)">appropriate license numbers, if any;</section><section prefix="(4)">the violation charged;</section><section prefix="(5)">the time and place the person shall appear in court; and</section><section prefix="(6)">other pertinent information the Commission requires.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person charged under subsection (a) of this section may give a written promise to appear in court by signing the citation prepared by the officer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An officer shall arrest a person charged under subsection (a) of this section if: <section prefix="(i)">the person does not furnish satisfactory identification;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the officer has reasonable grounds to believe the person will disregard a written promise to appear; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the person refuses to sign a written promise to appear.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person shall comply with the written promise to appear in court unless the person:<section prefix="(1)">posts sufficient collateral for the violation;</section><section prefix="(2)">pays the fine in advance of trial; or</section><section prefix="(3)">is represented by counsel in court.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a person fails to comply with the notice to appear in a citation issued under this section, the court may:<section prefix="(i)">except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, issue a warrant for the person's arrest; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">after 5 days, notify the court clerk of the person's noncompliance.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On receipt of notice of noncompliance from the court, the clerk shall notify the person by mail at the address indicated on the citation that the court may issue a warrant for the person's arrest unless, within 15 days after the notice is mailed, the person:<section prefix="(i)">pays the fine on the charge as provided for in the original citation and an additional fine of $100 for failing to appear; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">posts bond or a penalty deposit and requests a new trial date.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a person fails to pay the fines or post the bond or penalty deposit under paragraph (2) of this subsection, the court may issue a warrant for the person's arrest.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the original violation is not punishable by imprisonment, the court may not issue a warrant for the person's arrest under this subsection for at least 20 days after the original trial date.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
