<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="17-209" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-17-209</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Animal" means any bird or mammal or any part, egg, offspring, or dead body part of any bird or mammal.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Hunt" means to pursue, capture, kill, gig, trap, shoot, or attempt to pursue, capture, kill, gig, trap, or shoot, or in any manner reduce any animal to personal possession.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not hunt an animal on property owned by, operated by, or leased by the Commission without prior written authorization from the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For the purpose of this section, each animal taken illegally by hunting, offered for purchase, sold, bartered, or exchanged in excess of the bag limit or possessed illegally constitutes a separate violation.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to:<section prefix="(i)">for a first violation, a fine not exceeding $1,500, with costs imposed at the discretion of the court; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">for each subsequent violation, imprisonment not exceeding 1 year or a fine not exceeding $4,000 or both, with costs imposed at the discretion of the court.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For the purpose of this subsection, a subsequent violation is a violation that:<section prefix="(i)">occurs within 2 years after any prior violation of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">arises out of a separate set of circumstances.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In addition to the penalties in paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection, the court may order the license under which the person operated in committing the violation to be suspended for 12 months from the date of the subsequent conviction.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may adopt regulations necessary to administer and enforce this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Violation of any regulation adopted by the Commission under this subsection is a misdemeanor and is punishable as provided in subsection (d) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Chief Judge of the District Court may establish, by administrative regulation under &#xA7; 1-605 of the Courts Article, a schedule of prepayable fines for a first offense misdemeanor violation of this section and regulations adopted under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The amount of a prepayable fine may be not more than the maximum and not less than the minimum criminal penalty established in this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">By paying a fine set under this section instead of appearing for trial in District Court, a person is voluntarily accepting a conviction for the violation charged.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If the District Court or circuit court imposes a fine for a violation of this section, the court shall collect the fine and remit it to the Commission.</section>
  </text>
</law>
