<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-22-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Montgomery County district council or the Prince George's County district council, in accordance with the requirements of this division as to the portion of the regional district located in the respective county, may:<section prefix="(1)">by local law adopt and amend the text of the zoning law for that county; and</section><section prefix="(2)">by local law adopt and amend any map accompanying the text of the zoning law for that county.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The local law may regulate:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">the location, height, bulk, and size of each building or other structure, and any unit in the building or structure;</section><section prefix="(ii)">building lines;</section><section prefix="(iii)">minimum frontage;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the depth and area of each lot; and</section><section prefix="(v)">the percentage of a lot that may be occupied;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the size of lots, yards, courts, and other open spaces;</section><section prefix="(3)">the construction of temporary stands and structures;</section><section prefix="(4)">the density and distribution of population;</section><section prefix="(5)">the location and uses of buildings and structures and any units in those buildings and structures for:<section prefix="(i)">trade;</section><section prefix="(ii)">industry;</section><section prefix="(iii)">residential purposes;</section><section prefix="(iv)">recreation;</section><section prefix="(v)">agriculture;</section><section prefix="(vi)">public activities; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">other purposes; and</section></section><section prefix="(6)">the uses of land, including surface, subsurface, and air rights for the land, for building or for any of the purposes described in item (5) of this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The exercise of authority by a district council under this section is limited by &#xA7;&#xA7; 17-402 and 25-211 of this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
