<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="22-206" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-22-206</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A district council may amend its zoning laws, including any maps:<section prefix="(1)">in accordance with procedures established in its zoning laws; and</section><section prefix="(2)">after holding an advertised public hearing.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The procedures and zoning laws may include:<section prefix="(1)">procedures limiting the times when amendments may be adopted;</section><section prefix="(2)">provisions for hearings and preliminary determinations by an examiner, a board, or any other unit;</section><section prefix="(3)">procedures for quorums, number of votes required to enact amendments, and variations or increases based on factors such as master plans, recommendations of the hearing examiner, county planning board, municipal corporation, governed special taxing district, or other body, and petitions of abutting property owners, and the evidentiary value that may be accorded to any of these factors; and</section><section prefix="(4)">procedures for hearings, notice, costs, fees, amendment of applications, recordings, reverter, lapse, and reconsideration de novo of undeveloped zoning amendments.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Prince George's County, the district council may provide for notice of the public hearing on a proposed amendment to its zoning plan or zoning laws to be given to the owners of properties, as they appear on the assessment rolls of the county, adjoining, across the road from, on the same block as, or in the general vicinity of the property that is the subject of the proposed amendment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A zoning law adopted under this subsection may require notice to be given by mail or by posting the notice on or in the vicinity of the property involved in the proposed amendment or both.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In a year in which a district council is elected, the district council may not amend a zoning law from November 1 and until the newly elected district council has taken office.</section>
  </text>
</law>
