<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="18-308" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-18-308</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Montgomery County Council shall impose against all of the property assessed for the purposes of county taxation an annual tax of:<section prefix="(i)">not less than 0.4 cents or more than 1.2 cents on each $100 of assessed valuation of real property; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">not less than 1 cent or more than 3 cents on each $100 of assessed valuation of personal property and operating real property described in &#xA7; 8-109(c) of the Tax - Property Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The County Council shall impose the tax even if no interest is due on the bonds or notes or no bonds or notes have been issued under Subtitle 2 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to the limits in paragraph (1) of this subsection, if a tax is imposed under this section, the County Council shall continue to impose a tax sufficient to pay the interest on the bonds as the interest comes due and to pay the principal of the bonds as they mature.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The County Council does not need to impose the tax required under this section if money is available to make the payments in any year and have been applied to or authorized for payment by the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Every 60 days, the county shall remit the tax collected under this section to the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Commission may use any proceeds from the tax that are not used for debt service on the principal and interest of the bonds for:<section prefix="(i)">the Advance Land Acquisition Revolving Funds under Subtitle 4 of this title for the uses specified in this section and Subtitle 4 of this title; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">payment of debt service bonds issued under this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the Prince George's County Council has approved the issue and sale of bonds under Subtitle 2 of this title, the County Council shall impose an annual amount on all property assessed for the purposes of county taxation that is sufficient to pay the interest on the bonds as they become due and to pay the principal of the bonds as they mature.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subject to &#xA7; 18-303 of this subtitle, a tax authorized under this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">be imposed and collected as county taxes are imposed and collected;</section><section prefix="(2)">have the same priority rights as county taxes;</section><section prefix="(3)">bear the same interest as county taxes; and</section><section prefix="(4)">be treated the same as county taxes in every other respect.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
