<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="23-102" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-23-102</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, a subdivision plat of land in the regional district may not be admitted to the land records of Montgomery County or Prince George's County, or received or recorded by the clerks of the courts of the respective county, unless:<section prefix="(i)">the plat has been submitted to and approved by the applicable county planning board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the chair of the county planning board and the secretary-treasurer of the Commission endorse an approval in writing on the plat.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The recordation of a subdivision plat without the approval of the county planning board is void.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Prince George's County, if the subdivision regulations distinguish between a major subdivision and a minor subdivision, the Commission may provide for the approval of a minor subdivision plat by the planning director.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The planning director's endorsement in writing on the minor subdivision plat is sufficient evidence of approval for the purpose of filing or recording the plat.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A subdivision in a municipal corporation with subdivision authority under Article 23A of the Code that is in the regional district may be recorded in the land records of Montgomery County or Prince George's County if:<section prefix="(1)">the subdivision plat has been submitted to and approved by the municipal corporation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the appropriate official of the municipal corporation endorses an approval in writing on the plat.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The county planning board may set a schedule of fees to be paid to the Commission for performance of the county planning board's subdivision functions.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The fees shall be:<section prefix="(i)">based on the estimated costs of services to be performed by the county planning board in connection with the consideration of subdivision plats and incidental work; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">paid into the Commission's administrative fund established under &#xA7; 18-307 of this article before a subdivision plat is approved or disapproved.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After a subdivision plat has been recorded by the clerk of the appropriate circuit court, the plat shall be firmly fixed in a well-bound book kept by the clerk of the court for recording plats.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The clerk may collect a fee that the clerk determines is reasonable for recording a subdivision plat.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A subdivision plat shall be prepared in a manner required by the Commission by regulation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An approved subdivision shall have permanent markers, bound stones, or stations:<section prefix="(i)">as required by the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">that are shown on the subdivision plat.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A copy of an approved subdivision plat shall be provided to the Commission and to the district council of the county where the land is located.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
