<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="25-807" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-25-807</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Enterprise Fund" means the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission Enterprise Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Marina" means the Bladensburg Marina and Boat Basin established by Chapter 618 of the Acts of 1959, and all improvements, facilities, and appurtenances of the Bladensburg Marina and Boat Basin.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission shall administer, maintain, and operate the Marina.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission:<section prefix="(1)">shall adopt regulations for the use and enjoyment of the Marina to assure that the improvements and facilities are open to all residents on equal terms;</section><section prefix="(2)">shall set the fees for the use of the public and commercial navigation facilities; and</section><section prefix="(3)">may contract with the Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission for dredging activities relating to the maintenance and operation of the Marina.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission Enterprise Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Enterprise Fund shall finance and account for the maintenance and operation of the Marina.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission shall record revenues from the maintenance and operation of the Marina in the Enterprise Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Commission shall use the revenues of the Enterprise Fund:<section prefix="(i)">to offset expenditures relating to the Marina; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">for other enterprise funds of the Commission's park and recreational facilities located in the regional district in the county.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each year the County Council shall impose on all property assessed for county tax purposes in the county an ad valorem tax at a rate that the Commission certifies as necessary to produce the amount required to pay the annual cost of the Marina, less the proceeds of the Enterprise Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual cost includes the cost of dredging operations relating to the maintenance and operation of the Marina.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Montgomery County is not liable for any cost, debt, expense, or obligation relating to the administration, operation, or maintenance of the Marina.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Funds for the administration, operation, or maintenance of the Marina may not be obtained from:<section prefix="(i)">Montgomery County's portion of the budget; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Montgomery County's portion of unbudgeted funds of the Commission.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
