<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="glu" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-15-102</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Commission consists of 10 members....</catch_line>
  <order_by>102</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission consists of 10 members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 10 members of the Commission:<section prefix="(i)">five shall be residents and registered voters of Montgomery County; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">five shall be residents and registered voters of Prince George's County.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to the approval of the County Executive, the County Council shall appoint each commissioner from Montgomery County.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subject to the approval of the County Council, the County Executive shall appoint each commissioner from Prince George's County.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each commissioner shall be an individual of ability, experience, and integrity.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Of the commissioners from each county, not more than three shall be members of the same political party.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A commissioner may not be selected as representing or supporting any special interest.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a commissioner is 4 years and begins on June 15.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of commissioners are staggered as required by the terms provided for commissioners on October 1, 2012.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a commissioner continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A commissioner who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A commissioner who is appointed to fill a vacancy for an unexpired term shall be a member of the same political party as the commissioner who vacated the office.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A commissioner appointed from Montgomery County may not be appointed for three consecutive full terms.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
