<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-3-201</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A planning commission shall prepare a plan by carefully and comprehensively surveying and studying:<section prefix="(i)">the present conditions and projections of future growth of the local jurisdiction; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the relation of the local jurisdiction to neighboring jurisdictions.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A planning commission shall make the plan with the general purpose of guiding and accomplishing the coordinated, adjusted, and harmonious development of the local jurisdiction and its environs.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The plan shall serve as a guide to public and private actions and decisions to ensure the development of public and private property in appropriate relationships.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In accordance with present and future needs, a plan shall promote:<section prefix="(i)">good civic design and arrangement;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a healthy and convenient distribution of population;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the health, safety, and general welfare of the local jurisdiction; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">efficiency and economy in the development process.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A plan shall:<section prefix="(i)">include any areas outside the boundaries of the plan that, in the planning commission's judgment, relate to the planning responsibilities of the commission; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">provide for:<section prefix="1.">transportation needs;</section><section prefix="2.">the promotion of public safety;</section><section prefix="3.">light and air;</section><section prefix="4.">the conservation of natural resources;</section><section prefix="5.">the prevention of environmental pollution;</section><section prefix="6.">the wise and efficient expenditure of public funds;</section><section prefix="7.">adequate public utilities; and</section><section prefix="8.">an adequate supply of other public requirements.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In addition to the requirements for the plan under Subtitle 1 of this title, a planning commission shall implement through the plan the visions set forth in &#xA7; 1-201 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A planning commission may promote public interest in and understanding of the plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A planning commission shall consult with public officials and agencies, public utility companies, civic, educational, professional, and other organizations, and citizens about protecting or executing the plan.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
