<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-20-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, a county planning board:<section prefix="(i)">is responsible for planning, subdivision, and zoning functions that are primarily local in scope; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall exercise, within the county planning board's jurisdiction, the following powers:<section prefix="1.">planning;</section><section prefix="2.">zoning;</section><section prefix="3.">subdivision;</section><section prefix="4.">assignment of street names and house numbers; and</section><section prefix="5.">any related matter.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The functions under paragraph (1) of this subsection do not include the regional planning functions of the Commission relating to or affecting the regional district as a planning unit.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A county planning board has exclusive jurisdiction over:<section prefix="(i)">local functions, including:<section prefix="1.">the administration of subdivision regulations;</section><section prefix="2.">the preparation and adoption of recommendations to the district council with respect to zoning map amendments; and</section><section prefix="3.">the assignment of street names and house numbers in the regional district; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">mandatory referrals made in accordance with Subtitle 3, Part I of this title by the county planning board's respective county government or any unit of the county government.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Montgomery County Planning Board has exclusive jurisdiction over a mandatory referral made in accordance with Subtitle 3, Part I of this title by the County Board of Education, a municipal corporation or special taxing district, or a publicly owned or privately owned public utility.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Montgomery County Planning Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">review the annual capital budgets of the county and future capital budget projections; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">submit recommendations to the county council.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The county government shall have sole responsibility for the preparation of the capital budgets and programs of public works.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each county planning board shall:<section prefix="(1)">meet from time to time with its respective county council; and</section><section prefix="(2)">perform surveys, studies, and other planning duties the county council assigns to the county planning board.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
