<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-15-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to each commissioner appointed by the Montgomery County Council under &#xA7;&#xA7; 15-102 and 15-103 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Montgomery County Council may require an applicant for appointment as a commissioner to be interviewed by the County Council or its designated agent in private regarding possible or potential conflicts of interest.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before the appointment is made, the County Council or its designated agent shall interview in private an applicant who is selected for appointment regarding possible or potential conflicts of interest.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An applicant may not be appointed unless the applicant:<section prefix="(1)">has filed a financial disclosure statement as required by &#xA7; 15-820 of the State Government Article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">has been interviewed as required by subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In an interview under this section, the applicant shall be interviewed:<section prefix="(i)">under oath;</section><section prefix="(ii)">in a question and answer format; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">about information and interests including all sources of income, property holdings, business interests, and financial interests of the applicant and the applicant's spouse, parent, child, brother, or sister.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The County Council may require the applicant to produce relevant documents.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A written transcript shall be made of all questions and answers in an interview under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless the examination is waived by the applicant:<section prefix="(i)">the transcript shall be submitted to the applicant for examination;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the transcribing officer shall make any changes in the transcript that the applicant desires to make, accompanied by a statement of the reason given by the applicant for the changes; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the applicant shall sign the transcript.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The transcribing officer shall certify on the transcript that:<section prefix="(i)">the applicant was sworn by the officer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the transcript is a true record of the testimony given by the applicant.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The County Council shall:<section prefix="(i)">publicly disclose the complete transcript of an appointee within 3 weeks after the date of the appointment; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">when the appointee takes office, destroy immediately the complete transcript of any other applicant without disclosure of any information contained in the transcript.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before June 1 of each year, an appointee shall disclose, in writing, to the County Council all information available to make current the property holdings, business interests, and financial interests in the State and the greater Washington metropolitan area of the appointee and the appointee's spouse, parent, child, brother, or sister.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The County Council shall publicly disclose the information received from the appointee.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the County Council determines it necessary, the County Council may require substantiation and additional information.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
