<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-209" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-16-209</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the parties have not reached an agreement on or before December 1 on a collective bargaining agreement that would become effective the following July 1, the parties jointly shall appoint a mediator-arbitrator.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the parties are unable to agree on a mediator-arbitrator, the labor relations administrator shall appoint the mediator-arbitrator on or before December 7.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding appointment of the mediator-arbitrator, this section does not require mediation-arbitration to begin before the date set forth in subsection (c) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">During the course of the collective bargaining:<section prefix="(1)">either party may declare an impasse and request the services of the mediator-arbitrator; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the parties jointly may request the services of a mediator-arbitrator before an impasse is declared.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the mediator-arbitrator finds in the mediator-arbitrator's sole discretion that the parties are at a bona fide impasse or on February 1, whichever occurs earlier, the mediator-arbitrator shall direct the parties to submit:<section prefix="(1)">a joint memorandum listing all items to which the parties previously agreed; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a separate memorandum of each party's last final offer presented in negotiations on all items to which the parties previously did not agree.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before February 10, the mediator-arbitrator shall hold a closed hearing on the parties' proposals at a time, date, and place selected by the mediator-arbitrator.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each party shall submit evidence or make oral and written arguments in support of the party's last final offer.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The mediator-arbitrator may not open the hearing to a person that is not a party to the mediation-arbitration.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before February 15, the mediator-arbitrator shall issue a report selecting the final offer submitted by the party that the mediator-arbitrator determines to be more reasonable when viewed as a whole.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In determining which offer is more reasonable, the mediator-arbitrator:<section prefix="(i)">may consider only:</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall consider all items on which the parties agreed before the mediation-arbitration began to be integrated into each offer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The mediator-arbitrator may not receive or consider the history of collective bargaining relating to the immediate dispute, including any offers of settlement not contained in the offer submitted to the mediator-arbitrator.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The mediator-arbitrator may not compromise or alter the final offer that the mediator-arbitrator selects.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the offer selected by the mediator-arbitrator, as integrated with the items on which the parties previously agreed, shall be the final agreement between the Commission and the exclusive representative without ratification by the parties.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The economic provisions of the final agreement are subject to funding by the Montgomery County Council and Prince George's County Council.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Commission shall request funds in the Commission's final budget from the county councils for all economic provisions of the final agreement.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The parties shall execute an agreement incorporating the final agreement, including arbitration awards and all issues agreed to under this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Commission and the employee organization shall share equally the costs of the mediator-arbitrator's services.</section>
  </text>
</law>
