<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="22-119" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-22-119</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, within the regional district, the zoning powers vested by Division I of this article in a municipal corporation or the council of a municipal corporation within the regional district shall be construed to be vested exclusively in the appropriate district council.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A municipal corporation in Prince George's County has concurrent jurisdiction with Prince George's County to enforce zoning laws in the boundaries of the municipal corporation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The power to enforce zoning laws for the City of Takoma Park and the Town of Kensington is as provided in &#xA7;&#xA7; 24-201 and 24-202 of this article, respectively.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Before exercising the authority granted by this section, a municipal corporation in Prince George's County shall enter into a written agreement with the district council concerning:<section prefix="(1)">the method by which the county will be advised of citations issued by a municipal inspector;</section><section prefix="(2)">the responsibility of the municipal corporation or the county to prosecute violations cited by the municipal corporation;</section><section prefix="(3)">the disposition of fines imposed for violations cited by the municipal corporation;</section><section prefix="(4)">the resolution of disagreements between the municipal corporation and the county about the interpretation of zoning laws; and</section><section prefix="(5)">any other matter that the district council considers necessary for the proper exercise of the authority granted by this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
