<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-23-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Montgomery County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The subdivision regulations shall provide that before the county planning board takes action on a preliminary subdivision plan, the plan shall be referred to the County Executive for a recommendation as to whether public facilities are adequate to support and service the area of the proposed subdivision.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The County Executive shall return the preliminary subdivision plan to the county planning board with a recommendation of approval or disapproval based on:<section prefix="(i)">criteria developed by the County Executive and approved by the district council; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">standards set forth in the county subdivision regulations.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to property that:<section prefix="(i)">is located in a municipal corporation or governed special taxing district; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">shares a common boundary line, or a part of a common boundary line, with property located entirely in a municipal corporation or governed district.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection does not apply to a municipal corporation that exercises zoning, planning, and subdivision authority under Division I of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The subdivision regulations and zoning law shall provide that, before any action is taken by the county planning board on an application for a preliminary subdivision plan, project plan, or site plan review for property described in paragraph (1) of this subsection, a copy of the application shall be referred promptly to the municipal corporation or governed district for review and comment.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the municipal corporation or governed district chooses to comment, the municipal corporation or governed district promptly shall forward its written comments to the county planning board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On referral of a preliminary plan proposing the resubdivision of residentially zoned property located in a municipal corporation or governed special taxing district, the municipal corporation or governed district shall make an initial determination whether to transmit a recommendation concerning the plan to the county planning board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the municipal corporation or governed district chooses to transmit a recommendation, the municipal corporation or governed district shall:<section prefix="(i)">hold a hearing before it transmits the recommendation to the county planning board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">provide reasonable public notice of the hearing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A recommendation transmitted under this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">be in writing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">based on the record of the hearing, include all pertinent findings of fact and conclusions of law supporting the recommendation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A municipal corporation or governed district may recommend denial of a plan under this subsection only if the municipal corporation or governed district determines that the plan does not comply with a particular provision of the subdivision regulations.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If a municipal corporation or governed district recommends denial of a plan, it shall transmit a written record of the hearing to the county planning board for inclusion in the record compiled by the county planning board.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A municipal corporation or governed district shall be considered to have waived its right to make a recommendation under this subsection unless it transmits its written recommendation and complete record, if required, to the county planning board within 45 days after the delivery of the plan and application by the county planning board.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">A two-thirds majority vote of the members of the county planning board then present and participating is required to override a recommendation of a municipal corporation or governed district to deny a residential resubdivision application.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
