<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-17-212</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>212</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission may:<section prefix="(1)">except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, name and rename any street or highway and number and renumber the houses in the metropolitan district if each new number or change of number is reported to the owner or occupant of the building for the purpose of:<section prefix="(i)">correcting mistakes;</section><section prefix="(ii)">removing confusion because of a duplication of street names; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">securing a uniformity of street names and numbering of houses;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">place or have placed new numbers on the buildings or premises and proper signs indicating the names of streets and highways; and</section><section prefix="(3)">appropriate and expend as much of any surplus from fees for building permits issued in each county as is necessary to pay for the expenses in carrying out this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may adopt reasonable regulations for carrying out any changes in street or highway names or the numbering of houses.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A violation of a regulation adopted under this subsection is a misdemeanor punishable under the general penalty provisions of this division.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may not rename any street or renumber any house located in a municipal corporation in Prince George's County unless the proposed change is approved by the legislative body of the municipal corporation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Any party aggrieved by the refusal of a municipal corporation to approve a proposed change may appeal to the Prince George's County Council.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">After public hearing and on a finding of need for public health, safety, and welfare, the County Council by resolution may authorize the change notwithstanding the objections of the municipal corporation.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The resolution shall require the affirmative vote of two-thirds of all the members of the County Council.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
