<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-22-402</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>402</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Judicial review of a final action of the district council on an application for a map amendment may be requested by:<section prefix="(i)">a person aggrieved by the action; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a person or municipal corporation that appeared at the hearing in person, by attorney, or in writing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A petition for judicial review shall be filed in the Circuit Court for Montgomery County within 30 days after the district council takes the final action.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The court may:<section prefix="(i)">affirm or reverse the action;</section><section prefix="(ii)">for any reason, remand the action to the district council for further consideration; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">dismiss the petition.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When a petition for judicial review is filed, a copy of the petition shall be served on the district council in accordance with Maryland Rule 7-202(d).</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On receiving a copy of the petition, the district council shall:<section prefix="(i)">promptly give notice of the petition to all parties to the proceeding before it; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">within 30 days after the filing of the petition, file with the circuit court:<section prefix="1.">the originals or certified copies of all papers and evidence presented to the district council in the proceeding before it; and</section><section prefix="2.">a copy of its opinion and resolution deciding the application.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any party to the proceeding in the circuit court aggrieved by the judgment of the court may appeal from the judgment to the Court of Special Appeals.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The review proceedings provided by this section are exclusive.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The action of the district council shall be considered final unless, within 30 days after the action, the district council, on its own motion for any reason, reconsiders the action.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The time for appeal provided in this section shall be stayed until any reconsideration is concluded.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
