<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-5-102</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>102</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Before exercising subdivision powers under &#xA7;&#xA7; 5-202 and 5-203 of this title, the planning commission shall recommend subdivision regulations to the legislative body.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The subdivision regulations shall be for the health, safety, welfare, and common interest of the citizens of the local jurisdiction.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The subdivision regulations may include provisions for the purposes of:<section prefix="(1)">adequately controlling shore erosion;</section><section prefix="(2)">controlling sediment and ensuring protection from flooding;</section><section prefix="(3)">arranging streets in relation to each other and to the comprehensive plan;</section><section prefix="(4)">adequately and conveniently placing public school sites and open spaces for traffic, utilities, access of fire-fighting apparatus, recreation, and access to light and air;</section><section prefix="(5)">avoiding inappropriate population congestion;</section><section prefix="(6)">setting minimum lot widths and areas; and</section><section prefix="(7)">determining the extent to which the following actions shall be taken before the approval of a plat:<section prefix="(i)">the grading and improvement of streets and other ways;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the provision of soil erosion or sediment control; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the installation of water, sewer, other utility mains, piping, or other facilities.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subdivision regulations shall require that an appropriate easement be provided for any burial site located on the land.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The easement shall be subject to the subdivision plat for entry to and exit from the burial site by an individual related by blood or marriage or a person in interest, as defined in &#xA7; 14-121 of the Real Property Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The existing right-of-way need not be extended for any improvements on the burial site.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
