<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="glu" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-17-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Commission has received property as a gift under the last will of Violet Blair Janin to establis...</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission has received property as a gift under the last will of Violet Blair Janin to establish a public park in memory of Jesup Blair.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The property received under paragraph (1) of this subsection is the portion of the farm, "The Moorings", from the trees fronting on Georgia Avenue and Blair Road, including all improvements.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In accordance with the conditions set forth in the will, the Commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">make ample provision for the maintenance of the property as a public park;</section><section prefix="(ii)">unless it is absolutely necessary to remove trees in connection with the laying out of the public park, preserve all of the trees on the property; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">replace any trees on the property that are destroyed or die.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission may possess, manage, control, and maintain the property as a public park and memorial to Jesup Blair by:<section prefix="(1)">preserving trees on the property;</section><section prefix="(2)">maintaining good order in the public park;</section><section prefix="(3)">building and maintaining roads, buildings, and conveniences as necessary or advisable;</section><section prefix="(4)">replacing trees that die or are destroyed; and</section><section prefix="(5)">taking other actions necessary to maintain the public park in good condition and carry out the purposes of the gift.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission shall make yearly expenditures from the general revenues of the Commission received under this division to pay the cost of the maintenance, development, and use of the public park as necessary to accomplish the purposes of this division.</section>
  </text>
</law>
