<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="glu" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-23-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, in connection with the approval of a subdivisi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, in connection with the approval of a subdivision plat, the appropriate county planning board may require a dedication of land for:<section prefix="(1)">an interior subdivision road;</section><section prefix="(2)">a road that abuts the subdivision for the purpose of creating a new road as part of the plan of subdivision to provide for traffic access to another subdivision road; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the widening of an existing or public road that abuts the subdivision for the purpose of providing additional right-of-way adequate to serve additional traffic that will be generated by the subdivision.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The county planning board may not require a dedication of land under subsection (a) of this section that:<section prefix="(1)">exceeds the area required to produce a total right-of-way for:<section prefix="(i)">a secondary road, as defined by local law; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a primary road if the applicable master plan designates the road as a primary or arterial road;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">has a width that exceeds the area that is required for a primary road; and</section><section prefix="(3)">has a width that exceeds the area that is required for a secondary road, unless the applicable master plan designates the road as a primary or arterial road.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b) of this section, in Montgomery County, in connection with the approval of a subdivision plat, the Commission may require a dedication of land in accordance with the standards and limitations set forth in the subdivision regulations.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The standards established by the subdivision regulations shall relate the area of dedication to:<section prefix="(i)">the total size of the subdivision;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the maximum road right-of-way or improvement required for that category of land use as established by local law of the applicable jurisdiction; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the increased traffic, lane, and right-of-way requirements that would be created by the maximum utilization and development of the subject property:<section prefix="1.">in the property's present zone classification; or</section><section prefix="2.">in the property's higher use zone classification, as shown on an adopted and approved master plan of the applicable jurisdiction.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In accordance with the standards established by the subdivision regulations and except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the subdivision regulations may require dedication of a road to public use to the full extent of the required right-of-way.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a road is classified in the subdivision regulations as a limited access or controlled highway, a dedication of a road to public use may be required only for adequate traffic access to those subdivisions to which access is allowed.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In Prince George's County, a master plan of transportation shall be approved by the district council.</section>
  </text>
</law>
