<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="glu" order_by="" level="1">Land Use</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>glu-16-201</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Confidential employee" means an employee who acts in a confidential capacity with respect to an individual who formulates, determines, or implements management policies in the field of labor-management relations.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Probationary employee" means a merit system employee during the employee's initial probationary period following employment.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The rights granted to Commission merit system employees under this subtitle do not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">attorneys in the General Counsel's office;</section><section prefix="(ii)">confidential employees;</section><section prefix="(iii)">employees who are at grade J or above;</section><section prefix="(iv)">park police officers;</section><section prefix="(v)">probationary employees; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">supervisors, as defined in &#xA7; 2(11) of the National Labor Relations Act, 29 U.S.C. &#xA7; 152(11).</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Commission employees are divided into four bargaining units consisting of:<section prefix="(i)">the office unit that includes office classification titles in which employees are responsible for internal and external communications, recording and retrieving information, and paperwork required in an office;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the professional/technical unit that includes:<section prefix="1.">professional classification titles in which employees have special or theoretical knowledge that usually is acquired through college training, other training that provides comparable knowledge, or work experience;</section><section prefix="2.">paraprofessional classification titles in which employees perform, in a supportive role, some of the duties of a professional or technician but that usually require less formal training or experience than those duties performed by those with professional or technical status; and</section><section prefix="3.">technical classification titles in which employees have a combination of basic scientific or technical knowledge and manual skill that usually are acquired through specialized postsecondary school education or through equivalent on-the-job training;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">the service/labor unit that includes classification titles in which employees perform service and maintenance, may operate specialized machinery or heavy equipment, and whose duties contribute to the comfort and convenience of the public or to the upkeep and care of Commission buildings, facilities, or grounds; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the trade unit that includes classification titles in which employees are required to have a special manual skill and a thorough knowledge of processes that are acquired through on-the-job training, experience, apprenticeship, or other formal training programs.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A bargaining unit may not be defined by county boundaries.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If an employee organization is certified to represent more than one bargaining unit, the Commission shall negotiate a single contract with that organization covering all employees the organization represents.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
