<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-11A-05</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>05</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to leasing in an Aquaculture Enterprise Zone in the Chesapeake Bay.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In consultation with the Department of the Environment and the Wetlands Administrator of the Board of Public Works, the Department shall establish Aquaculture Enterprise Zones in the Chesapeake Bay.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An Aquaculture Enterprise Zone may not be located:<section prefix="(i)">Within a minimum of 50 feet of shoreline or any pier without the written permission of the riparian owner at the time of designation of the Aquaculture Enterprise Zone;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Within 150 feet of the public shellfish fishery or a registered pound net site;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Within 150 feet of an oyster reserve or any Yates Bar located in an oyster sanctuary;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Within 150 feet of a federal navigational channel;</section><section prefix="(v)">In any creek, cove, bay, or inlet less than 300 feet wide at its mouth at mean low tide; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">In an SAV Protection Zone.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In determining the location of an Aquaculture Enterprise Zone, the Department shall consider potential conflicts presented by other uses of the proposed area, to include navigation, recreation, and commercial fishing.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Before adopting regulations establishing an Aquaculture Enterprise Zone, the Department shall hold a public hearing in the county or counties immediately adjacent to the proposed location of the Aquaculture Enterprise Zone.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Department may issue to any person an aquaculture lease in an Aquaculture Enterprise Zone.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">
          <section prefix="1.">The Department shall set aside 25% of each Aquaculture Enterprise Zone for leasing to persons who hold tidal fish licenses under Subtitle 7 of this title and who have actively used those licenses during the 3 years preceding June 1, 2009.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">An applicant for a lease under this subparagraph shall comply with the provisions for leasing set forth in this subtitle.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">The set-aside provided for in subsubparagraph 1 of this subparagraph shall expire June 1, 2011.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Department may issue an aquaculture lease to a corporation only if:<section prefix="1.">The corporation is organized under the laws of the State; and</section><section prefix="2.">More than 50% of the stock in the corporation is owned by residents of the State.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department may establish a buffer between leased areas within an Aquaculture Enterprise Zone.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person who leases an area in an Aquaculture Enterprise Zone may cultivate shellfish:<section prefix="(1)">On the submerged land;</section><section prefix="(2)">In temporary protective enclosures approved by the Department on the surface of the submerged land;</section><section prefix="(3)">Subject to approval by the United States Army Corps of Engineers, on or under the surface of the water in a floating structure or in a structure on the submerged bottom, except that the height of the structure may not exceed 18 inches; or</section><section prefix="(4)">In any other manner authorized by the Department.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, an Aquaculture Enterprise Zone located within a sanctuary must be compatible with oyster restoration and must satisfy the criteria for permissible leasing within a sanctuary as provided in regulations adopted under this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
