<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-1-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Secretary shall, within the limits of any appropriation made for this purpose, appoint Natural R...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary shall, within the limits of any appropriation made for this purpose, appoint Natural Resources police officers as the Secretary deems necessary for the efficient administration of the Natural Resources Police Force. All appointments shall be made from a list of eligible persons prepared in accordance with the provisions of the State Personnel and Pensions Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Secretary shall issue to each person appointed as a Natural Resources police officer a commission and badge stating "Natural Resources Police Officer".</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except when on detective duty, every Natural Resources police officer shall wear in plain view a "Natural Resources Police Officer" badge when acting in his official capacity.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The badge is property of the State, and upon the termination of a commission of any Natural Resources police officer, it shall be returned with the commission to the Secretary.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">All Natural Resources police officers, including persons appointed for training prior to regular assignment as a Natural Resources police officer, shall remain in a probationary status for a period of 2 years from the date of initial appointment to the Natural Resources Police Force. The Secretary may discharge an employee in probationary status for any cause which is deemed sufficient in the sole discretion of the Secretary.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Subject to &#xA7; 1-107 of this title, in cases of inconsistency between this subtitle and the provisions of the State Personnel and Pensions Article, the provisions of this subtitle shall control as to all matters relating to the Natural Resources Police Force.</section>
  </text>
</law>
