<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-11A-08</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>08</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to a water column lease in the waters of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department may issue to a person a water column lease in waters of the State after the Department of the Environment classifies the waters as:<section prefix="(1)">Approved, conditionally approved, or restricted for harvest; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Prohibited, provided that the lease is used exclusively for the planting and gathering of seed for aquaculture and the leaseholder complies with the requirements of the National Shellfish Sanitation Program as implemented by the Department.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A water column lease may not be located:<section prefix="(i)">Within a minimum of 50 feet of shoreline or any pier without the written permission of the riparian owner at the time of initial application for the lease;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Within 150 feet of the public shellfish fishery or a registered pound net site;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Within 150 feet of an oyster reserve or any Yates Bar located in an oyster sanctuary;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Within 150 feet of a federal navigational channel;</section><section prefix="(v)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, in any creek, cove, bay, or inlet less than 300 feet wide at its mouth at mean low tide;</section><section prefix="(vi)">In an SAV Protection Zone; or</section><section prefix="(vii)">In a setback or buffer from the Assateague Island National Seashore established by the Department.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The provisions of paragraph (1)(v) of this subsection do not apply to the riparian owner or a lawful occupant of the riparian property.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person with a water column lease in the waters of the State may cultivate shellfish:<section prefix="(1)">Subject to approval by the United States Army Corps of Engineers, on or under the surface of the water in a floating structure; or</section><section prefix="(2)">In any other manner authorized by the Department.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
