<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-5-701</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>701</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A forest or park warden shall enforce every forest and park law, rule, and regulation of the State and protect State forest reserves, State parks, scenic preserves, parkways, historic monuments, and recreational areas.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The forest or park warden shall report any violation of law to the Secretary as soon as possible, assist in apprehending and convicting offenders, and make an annual report to the Secretary on forest conditions in the forest or park warden's immediate neighborhood.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If any forest or park warden sees a forest fire, or is requested by a fire company to assist with a fire plow or provide incident command expertise at the scene, the forest or park warden shall:<section prefix="(1)">Go immediately to the fire and employ those persons and means as the forest or park warden deems necessary to extinguish the fire;</section><section prefix="(2)">Keep an itemized account of all expenses thus incurred and send the account immediately to the Secretary;</section><section prefix="(3)">Control and direct any person and apparatus engaged in extinguishing forest fires;</section><section prefix="(4)">Summon inhabitants of the county over the age of 18 years, if able, to assist in extinguishing fires, and also require use of personal property needed for this purpose; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Use the members of the Junior Forest Fire Fighters Service between the ages of 14 and 18 years inclusive, either paid or unpaid, provided they have the written consent of their parents or guardians.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Any person summoned who is physically able, but who refuses or neglects to assist, or allow the use of man power, equipment, or other material required, is liable to a penalty of $10.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An action for trespass may not lie against a forest or park warden or anyone working under the forest or park warden's direction, for entering on any person's land to extinguish a fire, plow furrows, tear down fences, or start a back fire to check a fire that may be approaching.</section>
  </text>
</law>
