<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-1015.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-1015.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle or regulation promulgated thereunder, a person who catches oysters from the waters of this State using any sort of diving apparatus shall cull the oysters on the natural bar from which they were caught, and return to the bar all shells, stones, gravel, and slag. Any oyster whose shell measures less than 3 inches in distance between its longest or widest points, whether or not attached to a marketable oyster, shall be included in the culling and replaced on the bar from which caught. Oyster culling shall be completed before any oyster is thrown or deposited in the hold or bottom of any boat.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After culling and placing in the hold or bottom of a boat, a diver's possession of oysters may not include a combined total of more than 5 percent of oysters which measure less than 3 inches between its longest or widest points, and cultch consisting of shells, stones, gravel, and slag. In ascertaining this percentage the Department shall select by random sample an amount of oysters from any pile, hold, bin, house, or place as deemed proper and require it to be culled and disposed of, as provided by this section. All small oysters and cultch that adhere to marketable oysters shall be separated, and the marketable oysters shall be excluded from any measurement of small oysters and cultch. However, a person may possess marketable oysters that have undersized oysters or spat less than 1 inch in distance between their longest or widest points attached to them that cannot be separated without destroying the small oyster.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle or regulation promulgated pursuant to this subtitle, persons aboard a boat who are using diving apparatus to catch oysters from the waters of this State may not catch more than a total of 30 bushels per boat in any day. Any person aboard a boat on which more than 30 bushels have been caught in a day may be charged with violating this subsection.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">On or after July 1, 1983 and before September 30, 1983, the Department shall by rule and regulation set aside certain waters of this State to be used exclusively by hand tongers in catching oysters. Before adopting the regulations in their final form, the Department shall consult each of the local hand tonger committees.</section>
  </text>
</law>
