<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-1920" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-1920</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Corps Program's projects and activities shall meet an identifiable public need, with specific emphasis on projects that result in long-term preservation, protection, and conservation of the environment, in areas including environmental restoration, agricultural and forestry, infrastructure, and educational improvements.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Environmental restoration projects may include:<section prefix="(1)">Specific nutrient reduction activities, such as planting of bay grasses and oysters and installing natural shorelines on public spaces; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Working with communities to improve their environmental impacts and activities and to encourage appropriate environmental stewardship.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Agricultural and forestry projects may include working with Corps Program volunteers from rural areas of the State in partnership with the agricultural community in projects to prevent or reduce nutrient runoff.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Infrastructure projects may include:<section prefix="(1)">Improving the energy efficiency of housing for elderly and low-income households;</section><section prefix="(2)">Implementing clean energy projects in communities to enhance the use of renewable energy, including free and low-cost energy audits; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Building or assisting in building infrastructure to promote environmental education including outdoor classrooms, nature trails, and schoolyard habitats and watershed restoration, stream restoration, rain gardens, and other low-impact development projects.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Educational projects may include:<section prefix="(1)">Developing interactive environmental education and energy conservation education for elementary and secondary school students and the public;</section><section prefix="(2)">Developing curriculum targeted at training high school students and apprentices to obtain skills necessary to create and implement clean energy projects in their communities and to compete for jobs in the emerging clean energy sector; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Assisting schools to become "green schools" and reduce energy costs through hands-on projects with their students.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Energy conservation projects may include the projects defined in &#xA7; 8-1913(d) of this part.</section>
  </text>
</law>
