<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-301" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-10-301</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "child" includes:<section prefix="(1)">Foster child;</section><section prefix="(2)">Foster grandchild;</section><section prefix="(3)">Grandchild;</section><section prefix="(4)">Stepchild; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Stepgrandchild.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To provide a fund to pay the expense of protecting and managing wildlife, and preventing unauthorized persons from hunting them, a person may not hunt or attempt to hunt during open season and in any permitted manner any game birds and mammals in the State without first having procured either a resident or nonresident hunter's license. A person may not hunt or attempt to hunt nongame birds and mammals in Baltimore County or Frederick County without first obtaining a license. A permanent resident of a government reservation may obtain a resident hunter's license.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the following persons are not required to obtain a hunter's license, bow and arrow stamp, black powder stamp, or bonus antlered deer stamp:<section prefix="(i)">With respect to hunting on farmland only:</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any resident serving in the armed forces of the United States while on leave in the State, during the resident's leave period, if, while hunting, the resident possesses a copy of the resident's official leave order;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any person serving in the armed forces of the United States who has a service-connected disability, if, while hunting, the person possesses valid military identification; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any unarmed person participating in an organized foxhunt.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, in order to qualify for the license and stamp exemption in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection, a child or child's spouse must be eligible to purchase a junior resident or junior nonresident hunting license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a child or child's spouse is ineligible to purchase a junior resident or junior nonresident hunting license, the child or child's spouse shall qualify for the license and stamp exemption if the child or child's spouse:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person may apply for a hunter's license to any person designated by the Department. The application shall be on a form the Department prepares and supplies. The applicant shall fill out, sign, and submit the application to the person designated to issue the hunter's license. A person may apply by mail.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The application shall contain the applicant's name, height, color of eyes and hair, occupation, place of residence, and Social Security number. If the applicant is a nonresident, the applicant also shall present the applicant's driver's license, voter's card, or resident hunter's license.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Before a hunting license may be issued the applicant for the license shall sign a statement which says:</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There shall be the following types of hunting licenses in the State:<section prefix="(i)">A resident hunting license that enables the purchaser to hunt all legal game birds and mammals during any appropriate season in Maryland without the purchase of additional stamps, unless the purchaser is hunting migratory game birds or deer during bow and arrow season or black powder season. To hunt migratory game birds the purchaser must also buy a Maryland migratory game bird stamp and to hunt wild waterfowl the purchaser must buy both a Maryland migratory game bird stamp and a federal migratory bird hunting and conservation stamp. To hunt deer during bow and arrow season and black powder season the purchaser must also purchase a bow and arrow or black powder stamp.</section><section prefix="(ii)">A nonresident hunting license that enables the purchaser to hunt all legal game birds and mammals during any appropriate season without the purchase of additional stamps unless the purchaser is hunting migratory game birds or deer during bow and arrow season or black powder season. This license enables the purchaser to hunt migratory game birds only with the purchase of a Maryland migratory game bird stamp and to hunt wild waterfowl only with the purchase of both a Maryland migratory game bird stamp and a federal migratory bird hunting and conservation stamp. This license enables the purchaser to hunt deer during bow and arrow season and black powder season only with the purchase of a nonresident bow and arrow or black powder stamp.</section><section prefix="(iii)">A nonresident 3-day hunting license that enables the purchaser to hunt all legal game birds and mammals except deer and turkey for the 3 consecutive legal hunting days in a single season that are specified on the license by the issuing agent. The purchaser must also purchase a Maryland migratory game bird stamp to hunt migratory game birds and a federal migratory bird hunting and conservation stamp to hunt wild waterfowl with this license. Under no circumstance does this license authorize the purchaser to hunt deer and turkey.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Residents may purchase a senior hunting license beginning in the calendar year in which they attain the age of 65.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A nonresident of any age must purchase either a nonresident hunting license or a nonresident 3-day hunting license to hunt in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The fees for hunting licenses are according to the following schedule:<section prefix="(i)">Resident, junior, under the age of 16 years$ 10.50</section><section prefix="(ii)">Resident, regular, at least 16 years old and under the age of 65 years......................................................................................................................$ 24.50</section><section prefix="(iii)">Resident, senior, at least 65 years old$ 5.00</section><section prefix="(iv)">Nonresident, regular, at least 16 years old$ 130.00</section><section prefix="(v)">Nonresident, junior, under the age of 16 years$ 65.00</section><section prefix="(vi)">Complimentary license authorized to be issued under &#xA7; 10-303 of this subtitle...................................................................................................... No fee</section><section prefix="(vii)">Nonresident 3-day hunting license$ 45.00</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The fees for individual hunting stamps are according to the following schedule:<section prefix="(i)">Bow and arrow stamp$ 6.00</section><section prefix="(ii)">Nonresident bow and arrow stamp$ 25.00</section><section prefix="(iii)">Black powder stamp$ 6.00</section><section prefix="(iv)">Nonresident black powder stamp$ 25.00</section><section prefix="(v)">Maryland migratory game bird stamp$ 9.00</section><section prefix="(vi)">Resident bonus antlered deer stamp$ 10.00</section><section prefix="(vii)">Nonresident bonus antlered deer stamp for each type of deer hunting season................................................................................................................$ 25</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The person designated to sell the hunting licenses and individual hunting stamps shall issue the hunting licenses and individual hunting stamps and collect the fee prescribed in subsection (g) of this section. A hunting license may not be issued to any person under the age of 16 years without the written consent of the person's parent or guardian. The Department shall furnish the hunting licenses and individual hunting stamps to the designated person. The issuing person shall countersign the license, and retain the duplicate copy of the license. The duplicate copies and money collected every month shall be mailed to the Department on the first day of the succeeding month each year. The designated person who sells and issues the hunting licenses and individual hunting stamps shall retain as compensation 75 cents for each resident senior hunting license and individual hunting stamp sold and issued and shall retain as compensation $1.50 for each resident junior, nonresident junior, resident regular, nonresident regular, and nonresident 3-day hunting license sold and issued.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A hunting license shall be valid for the period August 1 through July 31, of each year.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The licensee shall sign the licensee's name in ink on the hunting license at the time the licensee obtains the hunting license. It may not be transferred to any other person.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">Upon issuing any hunting license, the Department shall furnish the licensee with a list of the names and addresses of every general hospital in the State which offers emergency medical treatment.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">When the Department has adequate computer capability, the Department shall compile statistics after the close of the hunting season each year concerning the sale of hunting licenses for the previous season, including the names, addresses, counties of residence, and ages of the persons who purchased the hunting licenses and the types of hunting licenses sold.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">Repealed.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">The Department may enter into contracts with farmers in the State to reimburse the farmer for planting and leaving grains, grasses, and legumes, including clover, alfalfa, and soybeans, unharvested in the fields in order to be used to provide food or cover for any upland game birds and mammals and wetland game birds in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "Fund" means the Upland Wildlife Habitat Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">There is an Upland Wildlife Habitat Fund in the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The purpose of the Fund is to facilitate the implementation and management of upland habitat programs.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Department shall administer the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Treasurer shall hold the Fund separately and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(i)">Voluntary contributions made to the Fund at the time of purchase of a hunting license under this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any other donations made to the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any investment earnings of the Fund.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Fund may be used only for:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Secretary may prioritize the duties under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph to maximize the effectiveness of upland wildlife habitat programs.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A designated person who sells hunting licenses under this section and who also collects donations for the Fund may retain as compensation 10% of each donation the person receives.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(8)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Treasurer shall invest the money of the Fund in the same manner as other State money may be invested.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Any investment earnings of the Fund may not be transferred or revert to the General Fund of the State, but shall remain in the Fund.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(9)">Expenditures from the Fund may be made only in accordance with the State budget.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
