<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-710</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person may not catch finfish for any purpose in the tidal waters of the State by use of any gig, g...</catch_line>
  <order_by>710</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not catch finfish for any purpose in the tidal waters of the State by use of any gig, gig iron, purse net, beam trawl, otter trawl, trammel net, troll net, or drag net. Any person who violates this section by catching fish with any of the equipment or devices referred to in this subsection, with the exception of a gig or gig iron, is guilty of a misdemeanor and upon conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $1,000 or imprisonment not exceeding one year, or both, with costs imposed in the discretion of the court. Any person who illegally catches fish with a gig or gig iron is subject to the penalties provided by this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An appropriately licensed person may fish in the waters of the Atlantic Ocean with an otter trawl or beam trawl, subject to Department rules and regulations, if the person is at least one mile from the shoreline. The Department rules and regulations shall include:<section prefix="(1)">Setting seasons when otter trawl or beam trawl fishing is permitted; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Enumerating the species of fish which may be taken.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not fish with any net whose size of stretched mesh, allowing a reasonable tolerance for shrinkage, is less than the following: pound net, 1 1/2 inches; haul seine, 1 1/2 inches; gill net, 2 1/2 inches; fyke or hoop net, 1 1/2 inches.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any hedging or lead attached to a fish trap, fyke net, or pound net shall be constructed of materials which have meshes having a twine size of #12 or larger.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In the Chesapeake Bay and its tributaries, a person may not set or fish any gill net whose size of stretched mesh is more than 6 inches.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">This subsection does not apply to catching eels with a net.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, a person may not install, set, operate, or maintain in any tidal water of the Chesapeake Bay or its tributaries any monofilament gill net webbing of any description to catch fish.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may use a monofilament cast net or a monofilament throw net to catch baitfish in any tidal water of the Chesapeake Bay or its tributaries.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In casting a monofilament net as provided under paragraph (2) of this subsection, a person:<section prefix="(i)">May not use a cast net that has a radius greater than 10 feet; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May cast a cast net only by hand.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person may not set any anchored gill net or fyke or hoop net or any line of these nets which has a length more than one third the distance across the waters of the bay, sound, river, creek, cove, or inlet where it is set, or is set so that it impedes or obstructs navigation on or blocks in any way the main channel of the bay, sound, river, creek, cove, or inlet. The outer end of the submerged gear of any nets referred to in this subsection shall be marked by means of a paddle, a board, or a buoy or other floating device which shows the name and license number of the net owner.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person may not haul any seine or net more than one third of the distance across the body of water, bay, sound, river, creek, cove, or inlet.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A person may take or shoot carp, garfish, skate, bullfish, shark, oyster toads, swelling toads, sting rays, or any other ray fish with bow and arrow, except a crossbow, and snag these fish by means of hooks in the tidal waters of the State under the supervision, regulation, and control of the Department. This subsection only applies to the fish referred to in it.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A person may not catch or attempt to catch finfish by the use of any stationary fishing gear, or set an anchor or mooring buoy, or in any way obstruct the normal taking of finfish by drift net from December 1 through April 1.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except in State waters in the Atlantic Ocean, a person may not use more than 2 hooks or 2 sets of hooks for each rod or line.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For the purposes of this subsection, artificial lures or plugs with multiple or gang hooks are considered 1 set of hooks.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
