<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-10-302</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>302</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Any person engaged in a retail business who desires to sell the resident hunting license, either nonresident hunting license or individual hunting stamps as an agent under the Department's control and supervision shall apply to the Department on forms prepared and prescribed by the Department. The Department may furnish resident and nonresident hunting licenses of any type and individual hunting stamps on consignment to any agent who provides a bond or other security deemed sufficient and adequate by the Department to insure payment for the resident and nonresident hunting licenses of any type and individual hunting stamps.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The agent shall fill out every license and duplicate license in a legible and proper manner.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The agent shall submit any necessary report of sale together with the duplicate license after the first day of each month as long as the agent sells these licenses in accordance with &#xA7; 10-301 of this subtitle. The report and duplicate licenses shall reach the Department by the seventh day of each succeeding month.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department shall reimburse any agent not operating on consignment the sum paid for unissued resident and nonresident hunting licenses of any type and individual hunting stamps provided they are returned intact, and still attached in the issuing books by June 30 of each year, and have been checked and found to be correct by the Department. Every hunting license and individual hunting stamp not returned by June 30 shall be deemed sold and not reimbursable unless accompanied by a statement under oath stating why the hunting license or individual hunting stamp is returned late. The Department, after review, may reimburse the agent.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A designated person may not make any false statement concerning any date of issuance or other resident or nonresident hunting license of any type or individual hunting stamp data. Every hunting license book, duplicate individual hunting license, or individual hunting stamp shall be available for any law enforcement officer to inspect at any time during the regular business day. An agent may not issue any hunting license or individual hunting stamp without receiving the fees required by law. A receipt may not be issued in lieu of a hunting license or individual hunting stamp.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition to any other penalty provided for by the provisions of this title, any agent convicted of violating the provisions of this section shall have the agent's hunting license and individual hunting stamp issuing privilege rescinded.</section>
  </text>
</law>
