<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-2A-01</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>01</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"BayStat Program" means the program established under &#xA7; 8-2A-03 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Nonpoint source pollution control project" means a project to improve water quality by a reduction of nitrogen, phosphorus, or sediment pollution.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Nonpoint source pollution control project" includes:<section prefix="(i)">An agricultural best management implementation practice, including cover crops, riparian forested buffer, manure processing, grassed waterways, animal waste storage structures, and livestock fencing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An urban or suburban stormwater practice;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A sustainable forest management practice, including a forest stewardship plan or a nonornamental urban and suburban tree planting project;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Stream and wetland restoration;</section><section prefix="(v)">Riparian buffer planting;</section><section prefix="(vi)">A project that demonstrates the effectiveness of an innovative nonpoint source pollution reduction measure provided that the measure is capable of integration into existing nonpoint source pollution programs;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Technical assistance necessary to implement a nonpoint source pollution control project;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Improvement of a municipal park located on or adjacent to a waterway, provided that the improvement is limited to state-of-the-art and sustainable nonpoint source pollution control measures that demonstrably improve water quality by reducing nitrogen, phosphorus, and sediment pollution; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">Strategic monitoring of water quality improvements from nonpoint source pollution control projects that have been funded, in whole or in part, with grants from the Trust Fund.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Tributary strategies" means each of Maryland's 10 watershed-specific plans as amended from time to time to reduce the amount of nitrogen, phosphorus, and sediment pollution that enters the Chesapeake and Atlantic Coastal Bays and their tributaries.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Trust Fund" means the Chesapeake and Atlantic Coastal Bays 2010 Trust Fund.</section>
  </text>
</law>
