<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="1-205" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-1-205</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If a Natural Resources police officer apprehends a person for violating any law punishable as a misdemeanor, the officer may prepare a written or electronic citation containing:<section prefix="(1)">A notice to appear in court;</section><section prefix="(2)">The name and address of the person charged;</section><section prefix="(3)">Relevant license numbers, if any;</section><section prefix="(4)">The offense charged;</section><section prefix="(5)">The time and place the person shall appear in court;</section><section prefix="(6)">An acknowledgment of receipt of the citation by the person charged made in a manner determined by the Department; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Other pertinent information required by the Secretary.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The person charged may promise to appear in court by acknowledging receipt of the citation prepared by the officer in a manner determined by the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the person charged acknowledges receipt of the citation, the officer is not required to take the person into physical custody for the violation unless:<section prefix="(i)">The person charged does not furnish satisfactory evidence of identity; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The officer has reasonable grounds to believe the person charged will not appear.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not fail to comply with a notice to appear in a citation issued under this section unless:<section prefix="(1)">Sufficient collateral for the offense is posted;</section><section prefix="(2)">The fine is paid in advance of trial; or</section><section prefix="(3)">The person is represented by counsel in court.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a person fails to comply with the notice to appear in a citation issued under this section, the court may:<section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, issue a warrant for the person's arrest; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">After 5 days, notify the court's clerk of the person's noncompliance.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On receipt of notice of noncompliance from the court, the clerk shall notify the person by mail at the address indicated on the citation that a warrant for the person's arrest may be issued by the court unless, by the end of the 15th day after the date on which the notice is mailed, the person:<section prefix="(i)">Pays the fine on the original charge as provided for in the original citations and a fine of $100 for failing to appear; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Posts bond or a penalty deposit and requests a new trial date.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a person fails to pay the fines or post the bond or penalty deposit under paragraph (2) of this subsection, the court may issue a warrant.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">When the original offense is not punishable by incarceration, a warrant may not be issued for the person under this subsection until 20 days after the original trial date.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
