<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-3-9A-01</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>01</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">By resolution or ordinance of its legislative body, any charter county not a party to the Northeast Maryland Waste Disposal Authority provided for in &#xA7; 3-903 of this title may enter into contracts with any industrial concern for the collection, storage, treatment, utilization, processing or final disposition of solid waste or for the recovery of material or energy therefrom, or any combination thereof.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The contracts:<section prefix="(1)">Shall be only in connection with solid waste disposal facilities financed under this article located within the charter county or another participating county; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May not be in connection with a landfill.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The contracts may be for a period not to exceed 30 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The contracts may provide for minimum amounts of waste to be delivered or processed, and payment based thereon, whether or not the waste is actually delivered or processed, and may contain other terms and conditions as the parties consider appropriate.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Any contract may not be deemed a debt of or gift of the county within the meaning of any provision of law or charter, but shall constitute only the contractual liability provided by its terms.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The county may award or negotiate contracts which it deems to be in its best interest in the manner provided with respect to State competitive sealed proposals under &#xA7; 13-104 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If construction of any waste disposal facility subject to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section is proposed within 1 mile of the border of an adjoining county, the government of the county in which construction is proposed shall provide the government of the adjoining county with a copy of the filings and notice of public hearings required under &#xA7; 9-209 of the Environment Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
