<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-5-218</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>218</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated:<section prefix="(1)">"Corps" means the Maryland Conservation Corps.</section><section prefix="(2)">"Youth" means a Maryland resident who is age 16 through 24.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Maryland Conservation Corps in the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Corps shall provide meaningful and productive employment for available manpower of this State in the field of development and maintenance of the State's natural resources. The General Assembly finds that employing Maryland's youth to conserve or develop natural resources and enhance and maintain environmentally important lands and waters is:<section prefix="(1)">Beneficial to the youth of the State because it provides them with educational and work opportunities; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Beneficial to the State's economy and environment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The purpose of this section is to provide Maryland's youth with a work experience opportunity that will:<section prefix="(1)">Further their understanding and appreciation of natural resources; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Teach them basic and fundamental work ethics, including:<section prefix="(i)">Discipline;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Cooperation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The ability to live and work with others; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The value of a day's work.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Corps shall engage in projects for:<section prefix="(1)">Conserving, improving, and developing natural resources; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Enhancing, preserving, and maintaining environmentally important public lands and waters.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Corps projects shall conserve, improve, or develop natural resources or enhance, preserve, and maintain environmentally important public lands and waters, while providing youths with an opportunity for personal development in a variety of basic skills. Projects shall be undertaken in both urban and rural areas on the basis of:<section prefix="(1)">The environmental and natural resource benefits the project offers;</section><section prefix="(2)">The opportunity for public use the project offers; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The on-the-job training value of the project.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Youths participating in the Corps shall work in projects which do the following:<section prefix="(1)">Preserve, maintain, and enhance environmentally important lands and waters;</section><section prefix="(2)">Work on public works projects in urban and rural areas;</section><section prefix="(3)">Conserve, maintain, improve, and develop natural resources in urban and rural areas;</section><section prefix="(4)">Assist in emergency operations, such as natural disaster relief and the rescue of lost and injured individuals;</section><section prefix="(5)">Assist in fire prevention and suppression;</section><section prefix="(6)">Directly contribute to the conservation of energy;</section><section prefix="(7)">Contribute toward making public facilities accessible to individuals with disabilities; and</section><section prefix="(8)">Assist other State agencies in developing, rehabilitating, and restoring parklands, recreational facilities, historical resources, fish spawning and rearing habitats, wildlife habitats, and the Chesapeake Bay.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall recruit and employ youths for the Corps through existing State service delivery systems.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall recruit youths for employment in the Corps without regard to their prior employment or educational background.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A youth recruited for the Corps may not be hired through mechanisms for the employment of skilled service or professional service employees in the State Personnel Management System and may not earn any of the benefits of a skilled service or professional service employee, with the exception of special appointments.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Annual funding for the Corps will be from:<section prefix="(1)">Appropriated funds; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The Forest and Park Reserve Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The Department shall use any federal appropriations that:<section prefix="(1)">May become available; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Are designated for State employment programs in the field of natural resources conservation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The Department shall adopt rules and regulations to carry out the provisions of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
