<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-10-1108</section_number>
  <catch_line>In addition to any other penalty provided by this title, the Department or the court may suspend for...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1108</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to any other penalty provided by this title, the Department or the court may suspend for a period not exceeding 5 years the hunting license or hunting privileges of a person who is convicted of a State or federal hunting violation.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department shall adopt regulations:<section prefix="(1)">To implement this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">That list the criteria for the suspension of a hunting license or the hunting privileges of a person.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">During a period of suspension of a hunting license or the hunting privileges of a person imposed by the Department or the court, the person may not:<section prefix="(i)">Hunt, trap, or pursue game in the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Purchase or attempt to purchase another hunting license.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The following are grounds for an immediate suspension of a hunting license or hunting privileges:<section prefix="(i)">Knowingly making a false statement in a license application;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A second conviction for violations occurring on separate days within any 12-month period for violations of State or federal hunting law that are not administrative or minor in nature as determined by the Department;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Failure to submit a report or report to a checking station as required under this title or by regulation; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Failure of a nonresident of the State to appear in court in accordance with a citation issued by a Natural Resources police officer, or to any other process issued by any court of Maryland, for a violation of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A suspension imposed in accordance with this section is in addition to any other penalty authorized under this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Department shall initiate any proceeding to suspend a hunting license or hunting privileges under paragraph (2)(ii) of this subsection immediately after the time for filing an appeal of the second conviction has passed.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Before the suspension of a hunting license or hunting privileges under this section, the Department shall notify the licensee or person in writing of the licensee's or person's right to a hearing on request.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a licensee or person submits a written request for a hearing to the Department within 30 days after the date that the notice required under this paragraph is mailed, the Department shall:<section prefix="1.">Hold a hearing after providing at least 10 days' notice to the licensee or person; and</section><section prefix="2.">Conduct the hearing in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Department may suspend a hunting license or hunting privileges without a hearing if:<section prefix="1.">The licensee or person does not submit a written request for a hearing; or</section><section prefix="2.">The licensee or person fails to appear for a scheduled hearing for which the Department provided notice.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
