<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-715</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>715</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not fish with rod or hook and line from any kind of boat or float, or fish with nets of any kind within 1500 feet of any occupied duck blind for the period beginning two days prior to the open season, as promulgated by the Department of Interior of the United States for hunting wild waterfowl, and ending the day following the closing of the season in the following waters:<section prefix="(1)">Back River, except in the portion lying west of a line drawn from Stansbury's Point on the south shore to Walnut Point on the north shore;</section><section prefix="(2)">Bird River and its tributaries lying within Baltimore County;</section><section prefix="(3)">Dark Head Creek, except in the portion lying north of a line drawn from Clark Point on the west shore directly across the creek to Sharp Point on Bull Neck Shore;</section><section prefix="(4)">Frog Mortar Creek, except in the portion lying northerly of a line drawn from Strawberry Point on the west shore to Weiskettle's Landing on the east shore;</section><section prefix="(5)">Gunpowder River and its tributaries lying within Baltimore County;</section><section prefix="(6)">Hogpen Creek, except in the portion lying southwest of natural headlands marking entrance into the creek;</section><section prefix="(7)">Middle River, except in the portion lying west of a line drawn from Clark Point, also known as Maryland Yacht Club Point, on the north shore to the point of shore directly south of Clark Point;</section><section prefix="(8)">Norman Creek, except in the portion lying west of a line drawn from Cape May Beach on the south shore to Barren Point on the north shore;</section><section prefix="(9)">Seneca Creek, except in the portion lying northwest of a line drawn from Gun Point on the north shore directly south to Blackberry or Flying Point on the south shore;</section><section prefix="(10)">Seneca River; Saltpeter Creek; Dundee Creek and in the waters of their tributaries;</section><section prefix="(11)">Stansbury's Creek, except in the portion lying northwest of a line drawn from Wilson Point on south shore to Strawberry Point on north shore; and</section><section prefix="(12)">Sue Creek, except in the portion lying west of a line drawn from the northeasternmost point of Sue's Island to extremity of Rockaway Beach Road at the southern tip of Turkey Point.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not set a pound net or any similar device in the waters of Back River and its tributaries.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not fish with rod, hook and line or a net in the waters of Bird River between November 1 and January 31, both dates inclusive. A person shall remove every net or stake used for taking fish before midnight on October 31.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person may not fish with a net of any kind in the waters of Dundee Creek west of a line drawn from Levering's Point on the north to Marshy Point on the south.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a person may not fish in the waters of Gunpowder River lying in Baltimore County, with nets, from May 15 to September 15, both dates inclusive.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except in areas where it is prohibited by the Department, in the waters of the Gunpowder River lying in Baltimore County or Harford County, on prior notification to the Department a person may catch carp 6 weeks before and during Passover in each year and 4 weeks before and during Rosh Hashanah through Yom Kippur in each year. If a person catches any fish variety other than carp under this paragraph, the person shall return them immediately to the water unharmed.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Department, by regulation:<section prefix="1.">Shall establish procedures for the prior notification required under subparagraph (2)(i) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="2.">May prohibit fishing for carp and catfish in certain areas as provided in subparagraph (2)(i) of this subsection.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person may not fish with nets or seines of any kind in the waters of Middle River and its tributaries, defined as those waters northeast of a line drawn from Bowley Point southwesterly to the navigation light at the western end of Sue Island, between March 1 and June 1, both dates inclusive.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A person may not fish with seines or nets of any kind in the waters of Sue's Creek west of a line drawn from the northeasternmost point of Sue's Island to extremity of Rockaway Beach Road at the southern tip of Turkey Point.</section>
  </text>
</law>
