<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-10-418</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section does not apply to any person who:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>418</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to any person who:<section prefix="(1)">Hunts any wildlife on the person's property with or without a hunter's license;</section><section prefix="(2)">Hunts deer with a bow and arrow during the season restricted to hunting with a bow and arrow;</section><section prefix="(3)">Hunts game birds or mammals during the open season using falcons, hawks, or owls; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Hunts or accompanies, aids, or assists another person hunting the following species:<section prefix="(i)">Wetland game birds;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Fur-bearing mammals;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Crows;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Doves; or</section><section prefix="(v)">Wild turkeys.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (a) of this section, a person who hunts any wildlife and a person who accompanies, aids, or assists another person in a field, wooded area, marsh, or on the water to hunt any wildlife shall wear:<section prefix="(1)">A cap of a solid daylight fluorescent orange color;</section><section prefix="(2)">A vest, jacket, or jacket containing back and front panels of at least 250 square inches of a solid daylight fluorescent orange color; or</section><section prefix="(3)">An outer garment of camouflage fluorescent orange worn above the waist which contains at least 50 percent daylight fluorescent orange color.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">By regulation, the Department may define the term "daylight fluorescent orange" consistent with the recommendations of the North American Association of Hunter Safety Coordinators.</section>
  </text>
</law>
