<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-9B-06" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-5-9B-06</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department of Natural Resources shall:<section prefix="(1)">Provide technical support and assistance to local governments in the development of local land preservation programs, including mapping, and identification of smaller parcels that may be aggregated for protection under local land preservation programs;</section><section prefix="(2)">Adopt criteria for distributing available State funding to local land preservation programs in accordance with the purposes of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">Assist sponsors to coordinate land preservation efforts in their regions under local land preservation and recreation plans with related efforts under Program Open Space, the Rural Legacy Program, the Heritage Area Program, the Agricultural Land Preservation Program, and the GreenPrint Program; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Consult with other federal, State, and local units and private land trusts in order to facilitate conservation efforts under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The purposes of the criteria adopted under subsection (a) of this section include:<section prefix="(1)">Preservation of open space;</section><section prefix="(2)">Containment of sprawl development; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Improvement of water quality in the Chesapeake Bay and other watersheds of the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The criteria shall be based on:<section prefix="(1)">The current population of participating jurisdictions and adjacent areas;</section><section prefix="(2)">Projected population growth in those areas;</section><section prefix="(3)">The sensitivity of surface and ground waters in and derived from those areas to degradation from point and nonpoint source pollution; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Giving higher priority to applications for the protection of lands and land uses that provide the highest level of protection for water quality.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The criteria shall be used at the start of each fiscal year to allocate funding available to local programs in participating local governments in order to provide for appropriate and timely deliberation and review of eligible proposals for acquisition by each participating local government.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Department may initially establish allocations of available funding based on the funding that is made available to each participating local government under Program Open Space in the same proportion that the local government receives Program Open Space funding in relation to the Program Open Space allocations of all participating local governments.</section>
  </text>
</law>
