<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-1019.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1019.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">An individual who takes or uses oysters for personal use or consumption purposes; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Old oyster shells that are dredged from the Chesapeake Bay or its tributaries.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, any licensed oyster dealer shall reserve for 8 months after the opening of each annual public shellfish fishery season all shells of oysters harvested from the Chesapeake Bay or its tributaries and commercially shucked in the State for purchase by the Department for oyster restoration, unless the dealer plants or provides the shells for planting:<section prefix="(1)">In an area privately leased for aquaculture purposes;</section><section prefix="(2)">On riparian bottom as provided in &#xA7; 4-11A-17 of this title for the propagation of oysters; or</section><section prefix="(3)">On public shellfish fishery areas designated by the Department.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall determine whether sufficient funds are available for the Oyster Shell Purchase Program under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall notify every licensed oyster dealer not later than September 1 of each year whether the Oyster Shell Purchase Program will be carried out during the ensuing license year.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the Department does not notify licensed oyster dealers that the Oyster Shell Purchase Program will be carried out during the ensuing license year, a licensed oyster dealer may sell or dispose of fresh oyster shell at any time to any person for any lawful purpose.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(i)">Establish procedures for the expeditious notice, payment, and removal of shells purchased; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provide for the transportation, storage, and placement on public oyster bars in State waters.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">All existing contracts executed prior to July 1, 1988 concerning the purchase of oyster shell shall be valid and exempt from the provisions of this section for the length of time for which the contract covers.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Unless permission has been obtained from the Department, it shall be unlawful for any person to take or catch oysters or shell in any of the waters of the State for the purpose of converting the oysters or shell into lime, chickenmeal, or road construction materials.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In consultation with the Oyster Advisory Commission and the Tidal Fisheries Advisory Commission, the Department shall determine annually the fair market value that the Department pays for:<section prefix="(i)">Fresh oyster shells; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Transportation and placement of fresh oyster shells.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary shall adopt regulations to implement the requirement set forth in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
