<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-5-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"County" includes Baltimore City unless otherwise indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Department" means Department of Natural Resources.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Environmental services" means the benefits generated for society by the existence and dynamic development of forests, including:<section prefix="(1)">Producing oxygen and removing carbon dioxide from the atmosphere;</section><section prefix="(2)">Regulating the surface and underground flow of water;</section><section prefix="(3)">Providing effective filtration systems for higher water quality;</section><section prefix="(4)">Supporting a myriad of native flora and fauna; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Providing goods and services ranging from forest products to aesthetics.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Forest land" means a biological community dominated by trees and other woody plants that are capable of producing timber or other wood products with a stocking of at least 100 trees per acre with at least 50% of those trees having a 2-inch or greater diameter at 4.5 feet above the ground.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Forest land" includes forested areas that have been cut but not converted to other land uses.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Forest stewardship plan" means a document written by a professional forester who is licensed under Title 7, Subtitle 3 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article, regarding a parcel of land comprised of not less than 5 contiguous forested acres that lists activities that enhance or improve forest resources, including soil, water, timber, recreation, and aesthetics over a 15-year period.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Forestry" or "silviculture" means the science, art, and practice of creating, managing, using, and conserving forests and associated resources for human benefit and in a sustainable manner to meet desired goals, including goals for:<section prefix="(1)">Clean air and water;</section><section prefix="(2)">Biodiversity;</section><section prefix="(3)">Wildlife habitat;</section><section prefix="(4)">Fiber production; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Recreation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Forestry practices" means activities conducted to achieve land management objectives.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Forestry practices" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Planting;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Prescribed burning;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Thinning;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Pruning;</section><section prefix="(v)">Harvesting;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Fertilizing; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">Pesticide and herbicide application.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Person" includes the State, any county, municipal corporation, or other political subdivision of the State, or any of their units, or an individual, receiver, trustee, guardian, executor, administrator, fiduciary, or representative of any kind, or any partnership, firm, association, public or private corporation, or any other entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Secretary" means Secretary of Natural Resources.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Silvicultural product" or "forest product" means any raw material yielded by a forest, including:<section prefix="(1)">Timber;</section><section prefix="(2)">Timber products; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Any other forest materials, such as lumber, poles, pulpwood, firewood, and pine straw.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Sustainable forestry" or "sustainable forestry management" means an internationally accepted and applied stewardship concept for the use of forests and forest lands in a manner and at a rate that maintains a forest's:<section prefix="(1)">Biodiversity;</section><section prefix="(2)">Productivity;</section><section prefix="(3)">Regeneration capacity;</section><section prefix="(4)">Nutrient reduction benefits;</section><section prefix="(5)">Vitality; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Ecological, economic, and social purposes at local and national levels that do not cause damage to other ecosystems.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Working landscapes" means:<section prefix="(1)">Forest lands that are managed consistently with the requirements of a forest stewardship plan or a forest conservation plan, approved by the Department or a professional forester who is licensed under Title 7, Subtitle 3 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article, that advances sustainable forestry management as defined in subsection (l) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Agricultural lands that are managed consistently with criteria set forth by the Department of Agriculture.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
