<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-2A-03</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>03</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a BayStat Program to:<section prefix="(i)">Measure and evaluate efforts to restore the Chesapeake and Atlantic Coastal Bays; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Administer the Trust Fund.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The BayStat Subcabinet shall oversee the administration of the BayStat Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The BayStat Subcabinet is composed of:<section prefix="(i)">The Secretary of Natural Resources;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Secretary of the Environment;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Secretary of Planning;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The Secretary of Agriculture;</section><section prefix="(v)">The President of the University of Maryland Center for Environmental Science;</section><section prefix="(vi)">The Dean of the College of Agriculture and Natural Resources at the University of Maryland, College Park; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">The chair of the Critical Area Commission for the Chesapeake and Atlantic Coastal Bays.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The BayStat Program shall:<section prefix="(1)">Provide accurate and timely data to policymakers and the public about the efficacy and cost-effectiveness of local, State, and federal programs to restore the Chesapeake and Atlantic Coastal Bays;</section><section prefix="(2)">Track and assess the progress of State and federal programs to improve the health of the Chesapeake and Atlantic Coastal Bays;</section><section prefix="(3)">Assess the effectiveness of enforcement programs in curbing pollution and achieving Chesapeake and Atlantic Coastal Bays restoration goals and institute actions to improve the effectiveness of enforcement programs;</section><section prefix="(4)">Adopt measurable goals for Chesapeake and Atlantic Coastal Bays restoration;</section><section prefix="(5)">Identify new threats to the health of the Chesapeake and Atlantic Coastal Bays;</section><section prefix="(6)">Increase public awareness of, and participation in, efforts to restore the vitality of the Chesapeake and Atlantic Coastal Bays; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Direct the administration of the Trust Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The BayStat Subcabinet shall:<section prefix="(1)">Report annually to the public regarding:<section prefix="(i)">The health of the Chesapeake Bay tributary basin;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The health of the Atlantic Coastal Bays and their tributaries;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The status of local, State, and federal programs to restore the Chesapeake and Atlantic Coastal Bays; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Estimated nutrient reductions achieved through projects financed by the Trust Fund; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">Develop an annual work plan that identifies the planned work to be funded with money from the Trust Fund for the next fiscal year, including annual nutrient and sediment reduction targets, performance measures, and accountability criteria; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Develop an annual expenditure plan that identifies planned expenditures for the work plan and includes an accounting of all moneys distributed from the Trust Fund in the previous fiscal year.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Governor shall submit the annual work and expenditure plans to the General Assembly as part of the annual budget submission.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">On an annual basis the BayStat Subcabinet shall prepare a final work and expenditure plan based on the budget approved by the General Assembly.</section>
  </text>
</law>
