<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-309" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-10-309</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Waterfowl hunting guide" means an individual who:<section prefix="(i)">Is an employee of a waterfowl outfitter; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Furnishes personal guiding services in assisting individuals to hunt wild waterfowl.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Waterfowl outfitter" means an individual who receives monetary consideration for the outfitting or guiding of hunters to hunt wild waterfowl.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A "waterfowl outfitter" may be:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Waterfowl outfitter" does not include a waterfowl hunting guide, agent, employee, or helper of a waterfowl outfitter.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An individual must be licensed by the Department as a waterfowl outfitter or a waterfowl guide before the individual may receive monetary consideration for outfitting or guiding a hunter to hunt wild waterfowl.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department shall adopt regulations that include:<section prefix="(1)">Minimum qualifications to obtain a waterfowl outfitter and waterfowl hunting guide license and other application requirements;</section><section prefix="(2)">Procedures for the review of applications;</section><section prefix="(3)">Criteria for the issuance and denial of licenses;</section><section prefix="(4)">Grounds for license suspension and revocation;</section><section prefix="(5)">Standards for the conduct of waterfowl outfitters and waterfowl hunting guides; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Any other provisions the Department finds necessary to regulate waterfowl outfitters and waterfowl hunting guides.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The fees for licenses are as follows:<section prefix="(i)">Waterfowl outfitter $300</section><section prefix="(ii)">Waterfowl hunting guide $50</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The term of a waterfowl outfitter license and a waterfowl hunting guide license is 1 year from August 1 through July 31 of each year.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Department may suspend or revoke a waterfowl outfitter license of an individual based on a conviction for a violation by a waterfowl hunting guide committed while the waterfowl hunting guide was employed by the waterfowl outfitter.</section>
  </text>
</law>
