<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-1918</section_number>
  <catch_line>For stipend volunteer programs, the Trust and qualified organizations shall principally recruit indi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1918</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For stipend volunteer programs, the Trust and qualified organizations shall principally recruit individuals for a minimum 6-month commitment who, at the time of enrollment, are at least 18 years of age and not more than 25 years of age.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For summer volunteer programs, including summer stipend programs, the Trust and qualified organizations shall principally recruit individuals who, at the time of enrollment, are at least 15 years of age and not more than 18 years of age.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Qualified organizations may not undertake a project if the project would replace regular workers or duplicate or replace an existing service in the same locality.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A stipend volunteer:<section prefix="(1)">May not receive a salary as a stipend volunteer; but</section><section prefix="(2)">May receive a stipend, as determined by the Trust, based on the needs of the stipend volunteer and the limits of budgetary appropriations.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A stipend volunteer may not participate in any partisan political activity while engaged in the performance of duties as a stipend volunteer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This part is effective only to the extent that it does not conflict with any federal or State laws or regulations relating to participation in partisan political activities.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A volunteer or stipend volunteer may not participate in any regulatory or statutory enforcement activities while engaged in the performance of duties as a member of the Corps Program.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
