<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-5-1605</section_number>
  <catch_line>Upon receipt of notice that the forest stand delineation is complete and correct, the applicant shal...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1605</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Upon receipt of notice that the forest stand delineation is complete and correct, the applicant shall submit to the State or local authority a proposed forest conservation plan for the site.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The forest conservation plan shall be developed by a licensed forester, licensed landscape architect, or other qualified professionals that may be approved by the State or a local authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A proposed forest conservation plan shall contain:<section prefix="(1)">A map of the site drawn at the same scale as the grading or subdivision plan;</section><section prefix="(2)">A table listing the net tract area in square feet, the square foot area of forest conservation required for the site, and the square foot area of forest conservation provided by the applicant on-site and off-site, if applicable;</section><section prefix="(3)">A clear graphic indication of the forest conservation provided on the site showing areas where both retention of existing forest or afforestation, by any and all methods, is planned;</section><section prefix="(4)">An anticipated construction timetable, including the sequence for tree conservation procedures;</section><section prefix="(5)">An afforestation or reforestation plan with a timetable and description of needed site and soil preparation, species, size, and spacing to be utilized;</section><section prefix="(6)">Locations and types of protective devices to be used during construction activities to protect trees and areas of forest designated for conservation;</section><section prefix="(7)">Limits of disturbance delineated;</section><section prefix="(8)">Stockpile areas delineated;</section><section prefix="(9)">A binding 2-year management agreement that details how the areas designated for afforestation or reforestation will be maintained to ensure protection or satisfactory establishment including:<section prefix="(i)">Watering; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Reinforcement planting provisions if survival falls below required standards; and</section></section><section prefix="(10)">Any other requirement established in regulations adopted by the Department, or imposed by a local authority.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Within 45 days from receipt of the forest conservation plan, the Department or local authority shall notify the applicant whether the forest conservation plan is complete. If the Department or local authority fails to notify the applicant about the forest conservation plan within 45 days, the plan shall be treated as complete and approved. The Department or local authority may require further information or provide for an extension of this deadline for an additional 15 days for extenuating circumstances. In addition, at the request of the applicant, the State or local authority may extend this deadline for extenuating circumstances.</section>
  </text>
</law>
