<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-5-1203</section_number>
  <catch_line>In order to assure that an increasing population, accompanied by expanding settlement and growing me...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In order to assure that an increasing population, accompanied by expanding settlement and growing mechanization, does not occupy and modify all areas within the State, leaving no lands designated for preservation and protection in their natural condition, it is the policy of the General Assembly to secure for the people of present and future generations the benefits of an enduring resource of State wildlands. For this purpose there is established a State wildlands preservation system composed of areas in the State designated by the General Assembly as "wildland areas". The wildland areas shall be administered for the use and enjoyment of the people of Maryland in a manner that will leave them unimpaired for the future use and enjoyment as wildlands, to provide for their protection, preservation of their wildland character, and for gathering and dissemination of information regarding their use and enjoyment as wildlands. A State land may not be designated as "wildland areas" except as provided for in this section or by a subsequent act.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section that property in Garrett County containing approximately 2,691 acres and described as follows is a Type 1 State wildland and shall be named the "Big Savage Mountain Wildland":</section>
    <section prefix="(b-1)">Pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, that property in Garrett County containing approximately 650 acres and described as follows is a Type 1 State wildland and shall be named the "High Rock Wildland":</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section that property in Worcester County containing approximately 1,784 acres and described as follows is a Type 2 wildland and shall be named the "Cypress Swamp Wildland":</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section that property situated in Worcester County containing approximately 2,481 acres and described as follows is a Type 2 State wildland and shall be named the "Pocomoke River Wildland":</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within the part of Pocomoke River Wildland lying north of the Pocomoke River and east of Milburn Landing area, Pocomoke River State Park, safety zone signs may be posted to protect the State park camping area in hunting seasons.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a county or State road is the boundary of any area designated a wildland pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, the county or State is exempt from the requirement to obtain approval from the General Assembly for activities within the wildland, which are 200 feet of the road edge, if they are necessary for the maintenance or improvement of the roadway for public safety. These activities are subject to normal review, permit, and approval actions as required by law.</section>
    <section prefix="(e-1)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this Part II of this subtitle, the designation of an area as a wildland may not be construed to preclude:<section prefix="(1)">The normal maintenance of an electrical transmission line, distribution line, telephone line, natural gas line, or other above ground or underground line, or of any easement held in conjunction with such line, in the manner such line or easement is normally maintained; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The upgrading or expansion of any electrical transmission line, distribution line, telephone line, natural gas line, or other above ground or underground line if the person responsible for the line had the right, subject to any required approval, to upgrade or expand the line in the designated area immediately before the designation of the area as wildlands.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Any activities related to the maintenance of existing public drainage within Worcester County is exempt from the requirement to obtain approval from the General Assembly. These activities are subject to normal review, permit, and approval actions as required by law.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, that property situated in Frederick County containing approximately 3,452 acres and designated as follows, is a Type 1 State wildland, and shall be named, "The Cunningham Falls State Park Wildland".</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, that property in Howard and Montgomery counties containing approximately 1579 acres and described as follows is a Type 2 State wildland and shall be named the "Patuxent River Wildland":</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, that property in Baltimore County containing approximately 792 acres and described as follows is a Type 2 wildland, and shall be named the "Gunpowder Falls Wildland":</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within part of the Gunpowder Falls Wildland is eight-tenths (0.8) of an acre of nonconforming use located approximately 1,600 feet northeast of Evna Road along the north side of Falls Road. This use may continue for a period not to exceed 20 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A twenty-five hundredths (0.25) of an acre parking area located approximately 600 feet southwest of the Gunpowder River along the northwest side of Falls Road shall be excluded from the Gunpowder Falls Wildland.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, that property in Allegany County containing approximately 943 acres and described as follows is a Type 2 State wildland and shall be named "Rocky Gap Wildland":</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to or prevent any future development that may be planned by the Department within the area of Rocky Gap State Park that lies outside of and that is not part of the described "Rocky Gap Wildland".</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">Under the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, that property in Prince George's County, containing approximately 610 acres and described as follows is a Type 2 State wildland and shall be named the "Belt Woods Wildland":</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">Under the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, that property in Allegany County, containing approximately 2,330 acres described as follows is a Type 2 State wildland and shall be named the "Potomac Bends Wildland":</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">In accordance with the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, the property in Calvert County containing approximately 1079 acres of land and described as follows is a Type 2 State wildland and shall be named the "Calvert Cliffs Wildland":</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In accordance with the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, the property in Baltimore County within North Point State Park containing approximately 667 acres of land and described as follows is a Type 2 State wildland and shall be named the "Black Marsh Wildland":</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of this subsection, a 60-foot wide park access corridor shall be recognized between Parcel 1 and Parcel 2. The corridor shall be defined as 30 feet from each side of the centerline of the existing haul road. The surface of the park access road to be placed in the corridor shall be no more than 24 feet in width.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, the Department may:<section prefix="(i)">Convert existing dirt roads in Parcel 1 of the Black Marsh Wildland to pedestrian trails of not more than 8 feet in width, and vehicular use of the trails shall be limited to construction and maintenance operations of the Department;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Construct no more than 2 viewing platforms adjacent to trails for public observation of areas with value for education, research, and appreciation of natural resources; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Establish temporary access roads to the shoreline in Parcels 1 and 3 solely for the purpose of shoreline stabilization, provided that:<section prefix="1.">A comprehensive study, with opportunity for citizen input, is conducted on the necessity and methods for shoreline stabilization and that opportunities for nonstructural and offshore stabilization are considered the highest priority;</section><section prefix="2.">The use of any access road is demonstrated to be necessary to accomplish the required stabilization; and</section><section prefix="3.">After the completion of any shoreline stabilization, any access road shall be removed immediately and the area used for the access road shall be allowed to revert to its natural conditions.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, that property in Somerset County containing approximately 2,880 acres and described as follows is a Type 2 State wildland and shall be named the "Cedar Island Wildland":</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding any other provisions of this title, the Department may permit motorized boat access and use within the boundary of the Cedar Island Wildland.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section that property in St. Mary's County containing approximately 1,445 acres and described as follows is a Type 2 State wildland and shall be named the "St. Mary's River Wildland":</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Exempting from the above description a 100 foot wide right-of-way belonging to the Southern Maryland Electric Cooperative, Inc. as described in Liber 35, Folio 312, and Liber 35, Folio 292, of the land records of St. Mary's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The use of approximately 40 acres north of Indian Bridge Road for a shooting range operated by the St. Mary's County Sheriff's Department may continue until such time as an alternative site is established.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Within part of the St. Mary's River Wildland are thirty (30) acres of leased agricultural land located approximately 1,500 feet northeast of Indian Bridge Road. This use may continue until December 31, 1999.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Exempting from the above description that acreage subject to an existing or future easement agreed to between the Department of Natural Resources and St. Mary's County Government associated with improvements to Indian Bridge Road.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section that property in Charles County containing approximately 1,605 acres and described as follows is a Type 2 State wildland and shall be named the "Mattawoman Wildland":</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Exempting from this description a parcel of land containing 31 acres more or less, conveyed to Carlisle and Nettie Abell and recorded in Liber 1684, Folio 368 of the land records of Charles County.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Exempting a 6-acre tract of land located in the northeast corner of the above described Parcel of land, said Parcel is to be reserved for the use of the Charles County Board of Education, Lackey High School.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Notwithstanding any other provisions of this title, the Department may:<section prefix="(i)">Permit motorized boat access and use within the boundary of the Mattawoman Wildland; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Permit commercial fishing guide operations, provided the base of operations for the commercial activity is not located within the boundary of the Mattawoman Wildland.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(r)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, that property in Baltimore County containing approximately 1,526 acres and described as follows is a Type 2 State wildland and shall be named the "Soldiers Delight Wildland":</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Exempting the Baltimore Gas and Electric Company and Susquehanna Power Company rights-of-way.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Exempting the Baltimore Gas and Electric Company power line right-of-way.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Exempting from the above described Parcels the following described tracts:</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Soldiers Delight Wildland Area contains unique ecological features associated with serpentine soils. Active manipulation of the landscape may be required to maintain these features. Notwithstanding any other provisions of this title, the Department may:<section prefix="(i)">Remove, replace, or dispose of vegetation using mechanical or motorized equipment; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Erect fencing, gates, and signage associated with the protection and interpretation of unique natural or historical elements as called for in the management plan for the area.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(s)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, that property in Carroll County containing approximately 499 acres and described as follows is a Type 2 State wildland and shall be named the "Morgan Run Wildland":</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding any other provisions of this title, the Department may utilize mechanical or motorized equipment to create and maintain recreational trails as called for in the Morgan Run Natural Environment Area Master Plan.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(t)">Pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, that property in Baltimore County containing approximately 1,073 acres and described as follows is a Type 2 State wildland and shall be named the "Sweathouse Branch Wildland":</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">Pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, that property in Baltimore County containing approximately 735 acres and described as follows is a Type 2 State wildland and shall be named the "Panther Branch Wildland":</section>
    <section prefix="(v)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, that property in Washington and Allegany counties containing approximately 922 acres and described as follows is a Type 2 wildland and shall be named the "Sideling Hill Wildland":</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Exempting a tract of land described as beginning at a point, said point being north 30 degrees 00 east 1,450 feet from the end of the 16th line of the above described Parcel of land, said point being the center of a Parcel of land with a radius of 75.00 feet, this circular Parcel of land contains 0.405 acres.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Exempting a tract of land described as beginning at a point, said point being south 37 degrees 00 minutes 00 seconds west 275.00 feet from the beginning of the 44th line of the above described wildland and running south 56 degrees 00 minutes east 875.00 feet, then running south 17 degrees 00 minutes east 925.00 feet, then running north 65 degrees 30 minutes west 940.00 feet, then running south 54 degrees 00 minutes west 360.00 feet, then running north 30 degrees 00 minutes west 660.00 feet, then running north 37 degrees 00 minutes east 800.00 feet to the beginning.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(w)">Pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, that property in Allegany County containing approximately 2,760 acres and described as follows is a Type 1 State wildland and shall be named the "Maple Run Wildland":</section>
    <section prefix="(x)">Pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, that property in Allegany County containing approximately 1,260 acres and described as follows is a Type 2 State wildland and shall be named the "Deep Run Wildland":</section>
    <section prefix="(y)">Pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, that property in Garrett County containing approximately 1,517 acres and described as follows is a Type 1 State wildland and shall be named the "Bear Pen Wildland":</section>
    <section prefix="(z)">Pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, that property in Garrett County containing approximately 1,916 acres and described as follows is a Type 1 State wildland and shall be named the "Middle Fork Wildland":</section>
    <section prefix="(aa)">Pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, that property in Garrett County containing approximately 2,427 acres and described as follows is a Type 1 State wildland and shall be named the "Savage Ravines Wildland":</section>
    <section prefix="(bb)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Mineral" includes any gas, oil, coal, peat, clay, stone, or fossil fuel located under a wildland area.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Owner" includes any person that is:<section prefix="1.">A lessee or party in interest; and</section><section prefix="2.">Any successor or assign.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to review, permit, and approval actions required by law, an owner of mineral rights located in a wildland area shall have the right to access the minerals.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the failure of the Department to issue, extend, or renew a permit involves taking a property right without just compensation in violation of the Constitution of the United States or Constitution of Maryland and if the General Assembly has not appropriated sufficient funds to pay the compensation, the State may use available funds to purchase or otherwise pay for the property rights.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(cc)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, that property in Frederick and Montgomery counties containing approximately 670 acres and described as follows is a Type 2 State wildland and shall be named the "Islands of the Potomac Wildland":</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, the Department may permit motorized boat access and use within the boundaries of the islands of the Potomac Wildland.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(dd)">Pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, that property in Caroline County containing approximately 570 acres and described as follows is a Type 2 State wildland and shall be named the "Idylwild Wildland":</section>
    <section prefix="(ee)">Pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, that property in Baltimore County containing approximately 1272 acres and described as follows is a Type 2 State wildland and shall be named the "Mingo Branch/Bush Cabin Run Wildland":</section>
    <section prefix="(ff)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, that property in Garrett County containing approximately 1,934 acres and described as follows is a Type 2 State wildland and shall be named the "South Savage Wildland":</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The South Savage Wildland area provides a unique site for the study of environmental sciences and offers an outstanding value for education, research, and enhanced understanding of natural processes and related economic, sociological, and cultural benefits.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, the Department may allow research study in the South Savage Wildland area that involves some activities that are generally restricted or prohibited in State wildland areas, if the Department determines that the activities will not cause adverse impacts to the wildland resources and the ecological values of the site.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Department and the University System of Maryland, through its constituent institutions Frostburg State University and the University of Maryland Biotechnology Institute, shall develop a comprehensive plan for the site setting forth the timing, duration, and general scope of the research activities to be allowed, subject to public review and comment and subject to approval by the Secretary.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
