<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-710.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Department may design temporary certificates of boat number and furnish them to any licensed boa...</catch_line>
  <order_by>710.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department may design temporary certificates of boat number and furnish them to any licensed boat dealer.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For any vessel that is to be used principally in Maryland, a licensed dealer may issue 1 temporary certificate of boat number to the person who buys the vessel from the dealer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A dealer may not issue a temporary certificate of boat number unless:<section prefix="(i)">The taxes and other fees as required by this subtitle are paid to the dealer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">An application for Maryland certificate of boat title and number or a purchaser's application for transfer of a Maryland certificate of boat title is completed and signed by the purchaser of the vessel.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Before issuing a temporary certificate of boat number, the dealer shall complete the certificate by writing in the information required by the Department.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A temporary certificate of boat number is not valid unless the dealer completes the certificate as required by this subsection.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The dealer may not issue more than 1 temporary certificate for any vessel. If the temporary certificate is lost, stolen, or destroyed, the owner must apply to the Department for a certificate of boat number.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Within 30 days after a dealer issues a temporary certificate of boat number, the dealer shall mail a copy of the temporary certificate to the Department.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A temporary certificate of boat number expires when the first of either of the following occurs:<section prefix="(1)">A certificate of boat number for the vessel is issued by the Department; or</section><section prefix="(2)">90 days expire from the date the temporary certificate was issued by the dealer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition to any other sanction under this subtitle, on failure of a dealer to forward to the Department taxes and fees within 30 days of collection, the Department may declare forfeited the bond or other security filed by the dealer under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Department may require the return of all temporary certificates from any dealer who has not complied with any provision of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
