<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-731</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>731</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a person may not sell, offer for sale, or transport across a boundary of the State any striped bass, commonly known as rockfish, caught from the State waters of the Chesapeake Bay and its tributaries unless the person has in his possession one of the following:<section prefix="(i)">A valid commercial fishing license issued in his name;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A dated bill of sale signed by the licensed commercial fisherman who caught the fish; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A dated bill of sale signed by a dealer or wholesaler from whom the fish were purchased.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">However, a nonresident of the State who has caught striped bass from State waters by hook and line may transport across a boundary of the State not more than 100 pounds of striped bass on any day for any purpose other than sale.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not knowingly buy any striped bass caught from the State waters of the Chesapeake Bay and its tributaries from any person except the licensed commercial fisherman who caught the fish, or a wholesaler or retailer of fish.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any person who buys striped bass caught from State waters of the Chesapeake Bay and its tributaries for the purpose of resale shall maintain records showing every purchase made during the preceding 90 day period, the date and place of each purchase, the quantity purchased, and the name of the person from whom the fish were purchased.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Any person who violates any provision of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and upon conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $1,000, or imprisonment not exceeding six months, or both, with costs imposed in the discretion of the court.</section>
  </text>
</law>
