<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>Section 101. The Chesapeake Bay Commission, hereinafter designated as "Commission", is hereby create...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>Section 101. The Chesapeake Bay Commission, hereinafter designated as "Commission", is hereby created.<section prefix="(a)">The Commission members shall serve as the governing body of the Commission, and, except as hereinafter provided, shall exercise and discharge all powers, functions, and responsibilities assigned to the Commission. The Commission shall provide for the organization of internal procedures of the Commission and to this end shall adopt suitable bylaws. The Commission shall have a chairman and 2 vice chairmen, chosen by the respective delegations, whose offices shall rotate annually among the signatory states and may at no time be held by members from the same signatory. The Commission may maintain one or more offices for the transaction of its business. The Commission may, without regard to the civil service or the laws of any signatory relative to public officers and employees, create and abolish offices, employments, and positions as it deems necessary for the purposes of the Commission, affix and provide for the duties, conditions of employment, qualifications, appointment, removal, term, compensation, and other rights and benefits of the Commission's officers and employees, and shall appoint the principal officers of the Commission and allocate among them administrative functions, powers, and duties. The Commission may delegate to the officers and employees of the Commission any powers, functions, and responsibilities under this agreement as it deems suitable, except that it may not delegate its power to make recommendations to the respective legislatures, to issue reports or to adopt the annual expense budget.</section><section prefix="(b)">Full-time officers and employees of the Commission on a salary basis shall be considered employees of a participating governmental unit for the purposes of pension benefits under Division II of the State Personnel and Pensions Article and for the purposes of health insurance, Social Security, and other employee benefits.</section><section prefix="(1)">The Commission may collect, compile, analyze, interpret, coordinate, tabulate, summarize, and distribute technical and other data relative to the Chesapeake Bay and its environs. It may conduct or contract for studies, except those for primary scientific research, and may prepare reports on existing or potential problems within the Bay region.</section><section prefix="(2)">The Commission may prepare, publish, and disseminate information in reports related to the resources of the region.</section><section prefix="(3)">The Commission may serve as an advisory board to any requesting agency of the member states on matters of interstate concern.</section><section prefix="(4)">The Commission may make application for grants, services, or other aids as may be available from public or private sources to finance or assist in effectuating any purposes of this agreement; and receive and accept the same on such terms and conditions as may be required by the law of the respective signatory states.</section><section prefix="(5)">The Commission may purchase administrative supplies and may lease sufficient office space if such space is not otherwise made available for its use.</section><section prefix="(6)">The Commission may exercise such other powers as are granted by this agreement and take such actions as are necessary or appropriate for performing the duties set forth in this agreement.</section><section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">Identify specific Bay management concerns requiring intergovernmental coordination and cooperation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Recommend to the various federal, state, and local governments, which are involved in the Bay region, legislative and administrative actions necessary to effectuate coordinated and cooperative management for the Chesapeake Bay.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">In administering the provisions of this agreement the Commission shall consider the needs of the region for industrial and agricultural development and for gainful employment and maintenance for a high quality environment.</section><section prefix="(3)">The Commission shall respect and support the primary role of the respective signatory states and their administrative agencies in managing the resources of the region.</section><section prefix="(4)">The Commission shall collect, analyze, and disseminate information pertaining to the region and its resources for the respective legislative bodies. The Commission shall prepare an annual report indicating the status of environmental and economic issues involving the Chesapeake Bay and the progress of coordinative efforts by the member states.</section><section prefix="(5)">The Commission shall represent common interests of the signatories as they are affected by the activities of the federal government and shall assist in the monitoring of those activities in the Chesapeake Bay region.</section><section prefix="(6)">The Commission may provide a forum to serve as an advisory mediator for programmatic conflicts between or among the member states when such action is requested by the conflicting member states.</section></text>
</law>
