<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-2103</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>2103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall study and analyze the effectiveness of the cost sharing program in the Department that assists landowners in paying for the cost of the management and control of the spread of phragmites.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The analysis required in paragraph (1) of this subsection shall include information on how assistance under the cost sharing program is allocated.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department of Natural Resources shall ascertain on a per-acre basis the statewide extent of infestation of phragmites, when necessary data is available, and shall study and analyze the progress made in the management and control of the spread of phragmites on:<section prefix="(1)">Lands that the Department of Natural Resources owns or controls; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Any real property on which the Department of Natural Resources assists landowners with the control of phragmites.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall annually submit a report under subsections (a) and (b) of this section to:<section prefix="(i)">The Environmental Matters Committee of the House of Delegates of Maryland; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Education, Health, and Environmental Affairs Committee of the Senate of Maryland.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Beginning in 2000, the Department shall submit every 5 years a report on the extent of infestation of phragmites to:<section prefix="(i)">The Environmental Matters Committee of the House of Delegates of Maryland; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Education, Health, and Environmental Affairs Committee of the Senate of Maryland.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
