<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-10-410</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in paragraphs (2), (3), (4), and (6) of this subsection, a person may not hunt an...</catch_line>
  <order_by>410</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraphs (2), (3), (4), and (6) of this subsection, a person may not hunt any game bird or mammal on Sundays.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The following persons may hunt the specified game birds and mammals on Sundays:<section prefix="(i)">A person using State certified raptors to hunt game birds or mammals during open season;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An unarmed person participating in an organized fox chase to chase foxes;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Provided that the provisions of &#xA7; 10-906(b)(3) of this title are met, a person:<section prefix="1.">Using a regulated shooting ground under &#xA7; 10-906 of this title to hunt the following pen-reared game birds:</section><section prefix="2.">Having the written permission of the owner of the land or other person designated by the owner of the land, if the land is owned or leased by a person other than the person hunting on Sundays;</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">Subject to the provisions of &#xA7; 10-411 of this subtitle, in Allegany, Calvert, Caroline, Carroll, Charles, Dorchester, Frederick, Garrett, Harford, St. Mary's, Somerset, Talbot, Washington, Wicomico, and Worcester counties, a person hunting deer on private property with a bow and arrow or crossbow during open season on the last three Sundays in October and the second Sunday in November;</section><section prefix="(v)">Except on Easter Sunday, in Allegany County and Garrett County, a person hunting turkey on the last Sunday in April and the first Sunday in May; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">In Calvert County, Caroline County, Charles County, Dorchester County, and St. Mary's County, a person hunting turkey on private property on any Sunday during the spring turkey hunting season.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to the provisions of &#xA7; 10-415 of this subtitle, in Calvert County, Caroline County, Charles County, Harford County, St. Mary's County, Somerset County, and Worcester County, a person may hunt deer on private property on:<section prefix="(i)">The first Sunday of the bow hunting season in November; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Each Sunday in the deer firearms season.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Provided that the provisions of &#xA7; 10-415 of this subtitle are met and subject to paragraph (5) of this subsection, the Department may allow a person to hunt deer on private property on the first Sunday of:<section prefix="(i)">The bow hunting season in November; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The deer firearms season.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Sunday deer hunting provisions under paragraph (4) of this subsection do not apply:<section prefix="(i)">In Baltimore, Howard, and Prince George's counties; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">In Baltimore City.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A person who is 16 years of age or younger may hunt deer with a firearm on a Sunday through participation in the junior deer hunt established under &#xA7; 10-405(a) of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not hunt any game bird or mammal, except raccoon and opossum, at nighttime.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not shoot at any species of wildlife from an automobile or other vehicle or, except as provided in &#xA7; 4-203(b) of the Criminal Law Article and Title 5, Subtitle 3 of the Public Safety Article, possess in or on an automobile or other vehicle a loaded handgun or shotgun, or a rifle containing any ammunition in the magazine or chamber.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If this subsection is violated by an occupant of a vehicle which has 2 or more occupants and it cannot be determined which occupant is the violator, the owner of the vehicle, if present, shall be presumed to be responsible for the violation. In the absence of the owner of the vehicle, the operator of the vehicle shall be presumed to be responsible for the violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Provisions of this subsection do not apply to a disabled person who obtains a special permit under &#xA7; 10-307 of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">For the purposes of this subsection, "off-road vehicle" means a motorized vehicle designed for or capable of cross-country travel on land, water, snow, ice, marsh, swampland, or other natural terrain.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Off-road vehicle" includes four-wheel drive or low-pressure tire vehicles, automobiles, trucks, motorcycles and related two-wheel vehicles, amphibious machines, ground-effect or air-cushion vehicles, snowmobiles, boats, farm-type tractors, earth-moving or construction equipment, lawn mowers, snowblowers, garden or lawn tractors, or golf carts.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not pursue wildlife with an off-road vehicle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person or 2 or more persons together may not hunt or attempt to hunt at nighttime any species of wild bird or wild quadruped with a light, including the headlights of any vehicle, and a person may not cast the rays of any artificial light when the rays emanate from a vehicle on any woods, fields, orchards, livestock, wild animals or birds, dwellings, or buildings. The provisions of this paragraph do not apply to the normal use of headlights of a vehicle traveling on any public or private road in a normal manner, to any police, emergency or utility company vehicle using spotlights in the performance of their duties, or to any farmer or landowner on the farmer's or landowner's own or leased land using artificial lights to check on the farmer's or landowner's land, crops, livestock, or poultry. However, raccoons, fox, or opossum may be hunted on foot at nighttime during open season with the use of a dog or light, or both.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In Baltimore City and Montgomery and Prince George's counties only, a person may cast the rays of an artificial light from a vehicle on woods, fields, orchards, livestock, wild animals, or wild birds for the sole purpose of observing or photographing wildlife until 9:00 p.m.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a person casts the rays of any artificial light under this paragraph, the person has the burden of establishing that the person was doing so for the purposes of observing or photographing wildlife.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If a person casting artificial light under this paragraph or anyone with the person casting artificial light has a firearm or bow in the person's possession, the person shall be presumed to be in violation of paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person may not shoot at any species of wildlife on, from, or across any paved public highway or the shoulder of the highway. A person may not shoot from any public highway, whether paved or unpaved, in Kent County and Queen Anne's County or shoot from any public road, whether paved or unpaved, within the boundaries of the Hanover municipal waterworks property in Carroll County.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a person, other than the owner or occupant, while hunting for any wild bird or mammal may not shoot or discharge any firearm or other deadly weapon within 150 yards, known as the "safety zone," of a dwelling house, residence, church, or other building or camp occupied by human beings, or shoot at any wild bird or mammal while it is within this area, without the specific advance permission of the owner or occupant.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For archery hunters in Carroll County or Frederick County, the safety zone described in paragraph (1) of this subsection extends for 50 yards from a dwelling house, residence, church, or any other building or camp occupied by human beings.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">During any open hunting season, a person, other than the owner or occupant, may not hunt or chase willfully any wild bird or mammal within the safety zone without the specific advance permission of the owner or occupant.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A person may not dig in or drive a motor vehicle on any cleared field while hunting, except with the permission of the owner, tenant, or other person in charge of the land, or park or leave standing any motor vehicle so that the motor vehicle blocks the means of ingress or egress to any person's property, cattle ways, or fields.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A person may not carry a firearm to hunt any wild bird, mammal, amphibian, or reptile while intoxicated or under the influence of alcohol or any narcotic drug.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not hunt or attempt to hunt wild birds or mammals from an aircraft within the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any person who violates provisions of this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and upon conviction is subject to a fine of not more than $1,000 or imprisonment for not more than 6 months or both, with costs imposed in the discretion of the court.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">A person may not set any trap, except box traps for rabbits, net, or snare of any description to take any game birds or mammals, except fur-bearing mammals. A trap, net, or snare found in the possession of any person shall be prima facie evidence that the device was used to violate this subsection. A law enforcement officer of the State shall confiscate and destroy the device. A person may not place traps of any description on another person's property without the other person's written permission.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">A person may not hunt with any ferret or weasel.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">A person may not kill, attempt to kill, or injure by poison wildlife or domestic poultry.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">A person may not smoke, burn, injure, hunt, or molest any game birds or mammals in any den or damage or destroy the den of any game bird or mammal.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Anne Arundel, Baltimore, Howard, Montgomery, and Prince George's counties, a person may not use, set, place, or maintain any steel jaw leghold trap on land. The steel jaw leghold trap may be used for the capture of fur-bearing mammals in water only.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">Traps set on farmland by the owner of the farmland, by the owner's agent or tenant, owner's lessee, or by any member of the owner's or tenant's immediate family who resides on the farmland; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Traps set by an authorized agent of the Maryland Forest, Park and Wildlife Service who exercises the agent's duties for wildlife control under guidelines established by the Department.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Snare trap" means a device made of wire, synthetic cord, or other material that:<section prefix="1.">Is in the form of a noose with a slipknot, stop, swivel, or eyelet holes; and</section><section prefix="2.">Is designed or set with the intent of capturing an animal by the neck.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Snare trap" includes:<section prefix="1.">A pole snare;</section><section prefix="2.">A hanging snare; and</section><section prefix="3.">A neck snare.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, in Anne Arundel, Baltimore, Carroll, Cecil, Harford, Montgomery, and Prince George's counties, a person may not use, sell, possess, set, place, or maintain a snare trap.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In Anne Arundel County, from July 1, 1990 through June 30, 1992, a person may sell or possess a snare trap.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
