<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-11A-03.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>03.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is an Aquaculture Review Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Review Board shall consist of the following members, each of whom shall represent one of the following State departments charged with responsibility for an aspect of the State aquaculture permitting process or oversight of permit compliance:<section prefix="(i)">The Department of Natural Resources, to be represented by the Aquaculture Coordinator, who shall serve as chair;</section><section prefix="(ii)">One representative of the Department of the Environment, designated by the Secretary of the Environment;</section><section prefix="(iii)">One representative of the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene, designated by the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">One representative of the Department of Agriculture, designated by the Secretary of Agriculture.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The National Marine Fisheries Service shall be invited to designate a representative to the Review Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The United States Army Corps of Engineers shall be invited to designate a representative to the Review Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Aquaculture Coordinator shall be the single point of contact for an applicant for all permits and licenses necessary to conduct aquaculture in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Review Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">Coordinate the development of statewide aquaculture policy and, to the maximum extent feasible, the streamlining of the application process;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Track each application as it is processed; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Ensure full and meaningful departmental communication with an applicant during each stage of the application process.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
