<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-10-602</section_number>
  <catch_line>Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, "nighttime" means the time the Secretary of In...</catch_line>
  <order_by>602</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, "nighttime" means the time the Secretary of Interior of the United States adopts by rule or regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not hunt wild waterfowl in the State at nighttime in any manner whether from the shore or otherwise. A person may not possess at nighttime any gun or light used for hunting wild waterfowl in or near the vicinity of feeding and resting grounds. Any gun or light found in possession shall be prima facie evidence of intention of a violation of this section, and the light shall be confiscated and turned over to the Secretary.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not shoot a wild waterfowl resting on land or water.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who wounds and cripples a wild waterfowl may shoot the waterfowl.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person may not hunt wild waterfowl from a position located more than 10 feet in the air.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The only firearm that a person may use to hunt wild waterfowl is a shotgun fired from the shoulder.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A shotgun used to hunt wild waterfowl may not be larger than a 10 gauge or loaded with shot not approved by the United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">While hunting or attempting to hunt wild waterfowl, a person may not possess shotgun shells that are loaded with shot not approved by the United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to federal rule or regulation, the prohibition of this subsection does not apply to an automatic loading or hand-operated repeating shotgun with a magazine that is cut off or that is plugged with a one-piece filler incapable of removal through the loading end that reduces the capacity of the gun to hold no more than three shells at any one time in the magazine and chamber combined.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not hunt a wild waterfowl with an automatic loading or hand-operated repeating shotgun capable of holding more than three shells.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A person may not possess a rifle or pistol while hunting wild waterfowl.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may hunt wild waterfowl with any bow and arrow.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not hunt wild waterfowl with a crossbow.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may hunt wild waterfowl with the aid of a dog or with an artificial decoy.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not hunt wild waterfowl using a live decoy.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
