<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-1402" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-5-1402</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not, without express, prior, written permission of an owner, wilfully or knowingly:<section prefix="(i)">Break, break-off, crack, carve upon, write, burn, or otherwise mark upon, remove, or in any manner destroy, disturb, deface, mar, or harm the surfaces of any cave or any natural material which may be found therein whether attached or broken, including speleothems, speleogens, and sedimentary deposits;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Disturb or alter in any manner the natural condition of any cave; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Break, force, tamper with, or otherwise disturb a lock, gate, door, or other obstruction designed to control or prevent access to any cave, even though entrance thereto may not be gained.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">However, the entering or remaining in a cave by itself shall not constitute a violation of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not dispose of, dump, store, or otherwise introduce into any cave, sinkhole, or subterranean drainage system any litter, refuse, dead animals, sewage, trash, garbage, or any chemical or biological contaminant which is potentially dangerous to man or any form of cave life.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Unless otherwise established by the Secretary and clearly posted at the cave entrance, caves having access within the boundaries of public properties shall be open for recreational purposes.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Any person violating any provision of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon conviction thereof, shall be fined not more than $500, and in addition thereto, may be imprisoned for not less than ten days nor more than six months.</section>
  </text>
</law>
