<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-1802</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1802</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Atlantic Coastal Bays" means the Assawoman, Isle of Wight, Sinepuxent, Newport, and Chincoteague Bays.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Atlantic Coastal Bays Critical Area" means the initial planning area identified under &#xA7; 8-1807 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Buffer" means an existing, naturally vegetated area, or an area established in vegetation and managed to protect aquatic, wetlands, shoreline, and terrestrial environments from manmade disturbances.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Chesapeake Bay Critical Area" means the initial planning area identified under &#xA7; 8-1807 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Commission" means the Critical Area Commission for the Chesapeake and Atlantic Coastal Bays established in this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Critical Area" means the Chesapeake Bay Critical Area and the Atlantic Coastal Bays Critical Area.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Developer" means:<section prefix="(i)">A person who undertakes development as defined in this section; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A person who undertakes development activities as defined in the criteria of the Commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(9)">"Development" means any activity that materially affects the condition or use of dry land, land under water, or any structure.</section>
      <section prefix="(10)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Dwelling unit" means a single unit providing complete, independent living facilities for at least one person, including permanent provisions for sanitation, cooking, eating, sleeping, and other activities routinely associated with daily life.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Dwelling unit" includes a living quarters for a domestic or other employee or tenant, an in-law or accessory apartment, a guest house, or a caretaker residence.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(11)">"Growth allocation" means the number of acres of land in the Chesapeake Bay Critical Area or Atlantic Coastal Bays Critical Area that a local jurisdiction may use to create new intensely developed areas and new limited development areas.</section>
      <section prefix="(12)">"Includes" means includes or including by way of illustration and not by way of limitation.</section>
      <section prefix="(13)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Intensely developed area" means an area of at least 20 acres or the entire upland portion of the critical area within a municipal corporation, whichever is less, where:<section prefix="1.">Residential, commercial, institutional, or industrial developed land uses predominate; and</section><section prefix="2.">A relatively small amount of natural habitat occurs.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Intensely developed area" includes:<section prefix="1.">An area with a housing density of at least four dwelling units per acre;</section><section prefix="2.">An area with public water and sewer systems with a housing density of more than three dwelling units per acre; or</section><section prefix="3.">A commercial marina redesignated by a local jurisdiction from a resource conservation area or limited development area to an intensely developed area through a mapping correction that occurred before January 1, 2006.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(14)">"Land classification" means the designation of land in the Chesapeake Bay Critical Area or Atlantic Coastal Bays Critical Area in accordance with the criteria adopted by the Commission as an intensely developed area or district, a limited development area or district, or a resource conservation area or district.</section>
      <section prefix="(15)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Limited development area" means an area:<section prefix="1.">That is developed in low or moderate intensity uses and contains areas of natural plant and animal habitat; and</section><section prefix="2.">Where the quality of runoff has not been substantially altered or impaired.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Limited development area" includes an area:<section prefix="1.">With a housing density ranging from one dwelling unit per five acres up to four dwelling units per acre;</section><section prefix="2.">With a public water or sewer system;</section><section prefix="3.">That is not dominated by agricultural land, wetland, forests, barren land, surface water, or open space; or</section><section prefix="4.">That is less than 20 acres and otherwise qualifies as an intensely developed area under paragraph (13) of this subsection.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(16)">"Local jurisdiction" means a county, or a municipal corporation with planning and zoning powers, in which any part of the Chesapeake Bay Critical Area or the Atlantic Coastal Bays Critical Area, as defined in this subtitle, is located.</section>
      <section prefix="(17)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Lot coverage" means the percentage of a total lot or parcel that is:<section prefix="1.">Occupied by a structure, accessory structure, parking area, driveway, walkway, or roadway; or</section><section prefix="2.">Covered with gravel, stone, shell, impermeable decking, a paver, permeable pavement, or any manmade material.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Lot coverage" includes the ground area covered or occupied by a stairway or impermeable deck.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Lot coverage" does not include:<section prefix="1.">A fence or wall that is less than 1 foot in width that has not been constructed with a footer;</section><section prefix="2.">A walkway in the buffer or expanded buffer, including a stairway, that provides direct access to a community or private pier;</section><section prefix="3.">A wood mulch pathway; or</section><section prefix="4.">A deck with gaps to allow water to pass freely.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(18)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Program" means the critical area protection program of a local jurisdiction.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Program" includes any amendments to the program.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(19)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Program amendment" means any change or proposed change to an adopted program that is not determined by the Commission chairman to be a program refinement.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Program amendment" includes a change to a zoning map that is not consistent with the method for using the growth allocation contained in an adopted program.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(20)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Program refinement" means any change or proposed change to an adopted program that the Commission chairman determines will result in a use of land or water in the Chesapeake Bay Critical Area or the Atlantic Coastal Bays Critical Area in a manner consistent with the adopted program, or that will not significantly affect the use of land or water in the critical area.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Program refinement" may include:<section prefix="1.">A change to an adopted program that results from State law;</section><section prefix="2.">A change to an adopted program that affects local processes and procedures;</section><section prefix="3.">A change to a local ordinance or code that clarifies an existing provision; and</section><section prefix="4.">A minor change to an element of an adopted program that is clearly consistent with the provisions of this subtitle and all of the criteria of the Commission.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(21)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Project approval" means the approval of development, other than development by a State or local government agency, in the Chesapeake Bay Critical Area or the Atlantic Coastal Bays Critical Area by the appropriate local approval authority.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Project approval" includes:<section prefix="1.">Approval of subdivision plats and site plans;</section><section prefix="2.">Inclusion of areas within floating zones;</section><section prefix="3.">Issuance of variances, special exceptions, and conditional use permits; and</section><section prefix="4.">Approval of rezoning.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Project approval" does not include building permits.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(22)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Resource conservation area" means an area that is characterized by:<section prefix="1.">Nature dominated environments, such as wetlands, surface water, forests, and open space; and</section><section prefix="2.">Resource-based activities, such as agriculture, forestry, fisheries, or aquaculture.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Resource conservation area" includes an area with a housing density of less than one dwelling per five acres.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(23)">"Tributary stream" means a perennial stream or an intermittent stream within the critical area that has been identified by site inspection or in accordance with local program procedures approved by the Commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Wherever this subtitle requires Prince George's County to exercise any power or authority Prince George's County shares with the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission, the obligation imposed by this subtitle rests on both the county and the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission in accordance with their respective powers and authorities.</section>
  </text>
</law>
