<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-210" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-210</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except for a person employed to operate a vessel for a master fishing guide under &#xA7; 4-701(p) of this title or a person permitted to operate a charter boat under &#xA7; 4-210.2 of this subtitle, any person who desires to accept direct or indirect consideration for providing services as a fishing guide shall obtain a license.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to any license required by this section, a person may not furnish any service as a fishing guide that requires operating a boat or vessel as part of that service without first obtaining appropriate federal licenses to operate a vessel carrying passengers for hire.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person who is required to be licensed under this section must have all appropriate federal and State licenses in the person's possession whenever performing services as a fishing guide.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A commercial fishing guide shall be required to submit reports monthly on forms provided by the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary may establish by regulation first aid and safety requirements with which all licensed fishing guides shall comply.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department may suspend, revoke, or refuse to issue a license for failure to comply with the terms of the license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department may issue a tidal fish license under &#xA7; 4-701 of this title and a freshwater fishing guide license under &#xA7; 4-210.1 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department may issue a limited fishing guide license that is applicable in all waters of the State to allow a license holder to guide:<section prefix="(i)">Anglers in up to 3 boats or vessels that:</section><section prefix="(ii)"/></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not accept any consideration for services as a fishing guide licensed under this subsection unless the person and all persons being guided possess, as applicable, an angler's license issued under &#xA7; 4-604 of this title or a Chesapeake Bay and coastal sport fishing license issued under &#xA7; 4-745 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A recreational angler under the guidance of a limited fishing guide in tidal waters may not:<section prefix="(i)">Catch or possess the species of fish known as the striped bass or rockfish in the tidal waters designated in &#xA7; 4-210.1(f) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">From March 1 through May 31, catch or attempt to catch the species of fish known as the striped bass or rockfish in spawning areas and rivers, including all waters north of a line from Abbey Point to Worton Point, including the Sassafras River, Bohemia River, Elk River, Northeast River, Susquehanna River, Susquehanna Flats, and the Chesapeake and Delaware Canal.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The fee for a limited fishing guide license under subsection (g) of this section shall be:<section prefix="(i)">For a resident, $50; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">For a nonresident, $100.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">All fees collected by the Department under this subsection shall be used for monitoring the freshwater fishery.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department shall publicly report annually the amounts collected under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
