<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-1011</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person may not use patent tongs to catch oysters in any of the following waters: Wicomico, Queen A...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1011</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not use patent tongs to catch oysters in any of the following waters: Wicomico, Queen Anne's, Talbot, Dorchester, and Kent counties, except on the following natural oyster bars: 2-9, 2-10, 5-1, 5-2, also known as Huntingfield Bar 5-3, and 5-7, as defined on the charts of the Oyster Survey of 1906 to 1912, and its amendments.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may catch oysters by patent or hand tongs in Talbot County waters within the following bounds:</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not use patent tongs to catch oysters:<section prefix="(1)">In the Patuxent River above and north of a straight line joining Sotterly Wharf and the beacon at St. Leonard Creek; or</section><section prefix="(2)">In the tributaries of the Potomac River.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person may take or catch oysters by hand tong only in the waters of Holland Straits lying within the territorial limits of Somerset County. Holland Straits is that body of water bound by a line, on the north or Tangier Sound side, drawn from Lower Island Point to Sound Point and by a line, on the south or Kedges Straits side, drawn from Pry Island to the southern end of Holland Island.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person may not use patent tongs to catch oysters in the South River in Anne Arundel County above and west of a straight line drawn between Thomas Point and Saunders Point.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person may not use patent tongs to catch oysters in waters of Chesapeake Bay that are adjacent to Dorchester County and that lie generally eastward and northward of a line drawn in a southeasterly direction from the southernmost tip of Barren Island to Richland Point on Hooper Island.</section>
  </text>
</law>
