<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-1815" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-1815</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as otherwise authorized in a local jurisdiction, in accordance with the procedures set forth in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, a local authority may obtain access to and enter a property in order to identify or verify a suspected violation, restrain a development activity, or issue a citation if the local authority has probable cause to believe that a violation of this subtitle or the local program has occurred, is occurring, or will occur.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iii)"/>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A person who violates a provision of an order, permit, plan, local program, this subtitle, or regulations adopted, approved, or issued under the authority of this subtitle shall be:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A criminal prosecution or a suit for a civil penalty for violation of a provision of an order, permit, plan, local program, this subtitle, or regulations adopted, approved, or issued under the authority of this subtitle shall be instituted within 3 years after the Commission or the local authorities in fact knew or reasonably should have known of the violation.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A local authority may request:<section prefix="(i)">Assistance from the Commission in an enforcement action; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">That the chairman refer an enforcement action to the Attorney General.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Whenever the chairman has reason to believe that a local jurisdiction is failing to enforce the requirements of a program applicable to a particular development, the chairman shall serve notice upon the local enforcement authorities. If within 30 days after service of the notice, the local authorities have failed to initiate an action to remedy or punish the violation, the chairman may refer the matter to the Attorney General.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Upon referral of an alleged violation under subsection (a) or (b) of this section, the Attorney General may invoke any sanction or remedy available to local authorities, in any court of competent jurisdiction in which the local authorities would be authorized to prosecute or sue the violator.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition to any other sanction or remedy available, the Attorney General may bring an action in equity to compel compliance or restrain noncompliance with the requirements of approved project plans, and to compel restoration of lands or structures to their condition prior to any modification which was done in violation of approved project plans.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, whenever a development in the Critical Area is proceeding in violation of approved project plans and threatens to immediately and irreparably degrade the quality of tidal waters or fish, wildlife, or plant habitat, the Attorney General, upon request of the chairman, may bring an action to restrain the violation and, as appropriate, to compel restoration of any land or water areas affected by the development.</section>
  </text>
</law>
