<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-5-9A-05</section_number>
  <catch_line>A sponsor may file an application to designate a Rural Legacy Area in accordance with a schedule est...</catch_line>
  <order_by>05</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A sponsor may file an application to designate a Rural Legacy Area in accordance with a schedule established by the Board. A local government may not apply for or approve an application for a Rural Legacy Area designation inside another jurisdiction's boundaries without that jurisdiction's approval.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The application shall describe the proposed Rural Legacy Area, include a Rural Legacy Area Plan, identify existing protected lands, state the anticipated level of initial landowner participation in the Program and the amount of the grant requested, and comply with the criteria set forth below.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To qualify for additional funds appropriated above the level appropriated in fiscal year 2000 as provided for in &#xA7; 12-1007(d) of the Public Safety Article, an application shall include a certification that the local jurisdiction has not adopted any local amendments to the Maryland Building Rehabilitation Code.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board shall evaluate and compare applications in accordance with the following criteria in order to select those that best carry forward the goals and objectives of the Program set forth in &#xA7; 5-9A-01 of this subtitle:<section prefix="(1)">The significance of the agricultural, forestry, and natural resources proposed for protection, including:<section prefix="(i)">The degree to which proposed fee or easement purchases will protect the location, proximity, and size of contiguous blocks of lands, green belts or greenways, or agricultural, forestry, or natural resource corridors;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The nature, size, and importance of the land area to be protected, such as farmland, forests, wetlands, wildlife habitat and plant species, vegetative buffers, or bay or waterfront access; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The quality and public or economic value of the land;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The degree of threat to the resources and character of the area proposed for preservation, as reflected by patterns and trends of development and landscape modifications in and surrounding the proposed Rural Legacy Area;</section><section prefix="(3)">The significance and extent of the cultural resources proposed for protection through fee simple purchases, including the importance of historic sites and significant archaeological areas;</section><section prefix="(4)">The economic value of the resource-based industries or services proposed for protection through land conservation, such as agriculture, forestry, recreation, and tourism;</section><section prefix="(5)">The overall quality and completeness of the Rural Legacy Plan, including:<section prefix="(i)">The degree to which existing planning, zoning, and growth management policies contribute to land conservation and the protection of cultural resources;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The degree to which the proposed plan is consistent with the applicable local comprehensive plan, including protection of sensitive areas and mineral resources;</section><section prefix="(iii)">How well existing or new conservation programs are coordinated with the proposed acquisition plan;</section><section prefix="(iv)">How well the plan will maximize acquisition of real property interests in contiguous blocks of land within the Rural Legacy Area while providing for protection of isolated acquisitions important to the plan;</section><section prefix="(v)">Provisions for protection of resources, such as voluntarily granted or purchased easements, fee estate purchases, or gifts of lands;</section><section prefix="(vi)">How the sponsor plans to manage, prioritize, and sequence easement and land acquisitions;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Methodology for prioritizing and valuing or appraising easements;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Proposed titleholders for easement or fee estate acquisitions; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">The quality of the proposed stewardship program for holding and monitoring of easement restrictions in perpetuity;</section></section><section prefix="(6)">The strength and quality of partnerships created for land conservation among federal, State, and local governments and land trusts for implementing the plan, including:<section prefix="(i)">Financial support;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Dedication of staff and resources; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Commitment to and development of local land conservation policies, such as changes in zoning and use of transferable development rights;</section></section><section prefix="(7)">The extent to which federal or other grant programs will serve as a funding match; and</section><section prefix="(8)">A sponsor's ability to carry out the proposed Rural Legacy Plan and the goals and objectives of the Program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board:<section prefix="(1)">Shall review applications and may request additional information from a sponsor;</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall submit applications to appropriate State agencies and to the advisory committee established by this subtitle and consider any recommendations made regarding the applications; and</section><section prefix="(3)">May negotiate the terms of an application and proposed Rural Legacy Area and plan with a sponsor.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A sponsor shall assure adequate public participation in the development of an application and provide the Board with a summary of that participation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If an application proposes a Rural Legacy Area be located within 1 mile of the boundary of a municipal corporation, the municipal corporation shall have 45 days to review and comment on the application before the application is submitted to the Board.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The sponsor shall submit to the Board with the completed application a summary of the comments from the municipal corporation.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A land trust shall consult with a local government prior to filing an application.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may not approve or amend an application without local government approval.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The right of public access may not be required under a conservation easement.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A land trust may not hold exclusive title to real property interests acquired under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">An easement acquired under this subtitle is perpetual and may not be extinguished or released.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With the approval of a landowner, funds under this Program may be used to purchase a development right as part of an easement or fee estate acquisition. A development right shall be held by the titleholder and the Board and may be sold only within the same jurisdiction pursuant to local law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In a county with a locally adopted transferable development rights program and with the approval of the county, funds under this Program may be used to purchase transferable development rights in the county in accordance with the locally adopted transferable development rights program.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The right to resell the development right shall be stated in the instrument of purchase.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Rural Legacy Board shall maintain records concerning:<section prefix="(i)">Real property from which transferable development rights are purchased; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Real property to which rights are resold and transferred.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The county shall provide to the Board information relating to the records required in paragraph (4) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Transferable development rights may be resold only to owners or option purchasers of real property located in priority funding areas, including municipalities, within the county in which the rights were purchased.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The proceeds associated with the resale of transferable development rights shall be distributed only as described in this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Fifty percent of the proceeds shall be used by the local government in which the development using transferable development rights is located to fund capital projects in the county or municipal corporation which is receiving transferable development rights. Funds shall be distributed to the municipal corporation if the receiving area is within the corporate limits of a municipal corporation.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Fifty percent of the proceeds shall be returned to the Rural Legacy Program for use in the county in which the proceeds were generated.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Proceeds may not be used for operating expenses.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">All easement acquisitions must be recorded among the land records where the real property is located.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">State or local condemnation authority may not be used to acquire real property interests under this Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">Funds may be used for the protection of historic sites or significant archeological areas that otherwise meet the goals of this Program only if the sponsor is acquiring real property interests through a fee simple purchase.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">A land or mineral owner who participates in this Program may reserve mineral rights for extraction in accordance with applicable law and the terms of the easement or fee acquisition.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">In its determination under subsection (c) of this section, the Rural Legacy Board may not make its determination solely on the basis of whether a county has adopted a transferable development rights program authorizing Rural Legacy Board purchases and sales of transferable development rights.</section>
  </text>
</law>
