<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-1101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-1101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Chesapeake Bay" means the waters, commonly known as the Chesapeake Bay, as defined by the charts of the Oyster Survey of 1906 to 1912, and its amendments.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"County waters" means the waters lying within the territorial limits of any county in the State as defined by the charts of the Oyster Survey of 1906 to 1912, and its amendments.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Dredge" includes any dredge, scoop, handscrape, or similar device used in catching oysters and clams by dragging.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Hydraulic clam dredge" means any device used for dredging clams which consists of a manifold through which water is forced under pressure for the purpose of digging clams and working them into the mouth of the dredge where the clams then are brought up to boat level by means of an escalator. "Hydraulic clam dredge" includes the vessel on which the dredge is carried.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Leased oyster bottom" means any land lying beneath the waters of the State leased by the State to any person for the purpose of protecting, sowing, bedding, or cultivating oysters and other shellfish.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Marketable oyster" means an oyster measuring 3 inches or more from hinge to mouth.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Natural clam bar" means any area of submerged tidal bottom not classified as a natural oyster bar which has a population of clams of any species judged by the Secretary to have significant commercial value.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Natural oyster bar" means any submerged oyster bar, reef, rock, or area represented as an oyster bar on the charts of the Oyster Survey of 1906 to 1912 and its amendments.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Patent tongs" means any pincers, nippers, tongs, or similar device used to catch oysters or clams and raised with rope, cable, or other hoisting gear.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Shinnecock rake" means a hand tool used to catch hard-shell clams or oysters. It usually consists of a tooth bar with projecting long, outwardly and upwardly curving teeth which are progressively smaller toward the ends, form a basket, and are set transversely at the end of a long, usually wooden handle.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Tong" means any pincers, nippers, tongs, or similar device operated entirely by hand and consisting of two shafts or handles and a metal body composed of two opposable and complementary baskets used in catching oysters and clams.</section>
  </text>
</law>
