<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-308.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-10-308.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to any other requirement, a person hunting migratory game birds in the State first shall purchase a Maryland migratory game bird stamp.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may obtain a Maryland migratory game bird stamp for a fee of $9.00 from any person designated by the Department. The issuing person designated shall retain the sum of 75 cents as compensation for issuing each stamp. The balance of the fee is paid over and accounted for to the State Treasurer. The Treasurer shall credit all such fees received to the State Wildlife Management and Protection Fund, in accordance with &#xA7; 10-209 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department may sell expired stamps below face value to the general public for a period of 3 years, after which time the Department shall shred any unsold expired stamps. All revenues derived from the sale of these stamps shall revert back to the Game Management Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A printed receipt from the Department showing proof of purchase of the Maryland migratory game bird stamp must be carried on the person while hunting migratory game birds.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">All revenues accruing to the Wildlife Management and Protection Fund from sales of the migratory game bird stamps shall be expended solely for the following purposes:<section prefix="(i)">Migratory game bird projects included in an approved State program to create, develop, enhance, maintain, and manage nesting cover, winter foods, and other habitat components on public lands to satisfy the habitat requirements of a broad range of wintering migratory game birds and native migratory game bird species;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Migratory game bird research, management, and surveys; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Not more than 30% to adopt and implement a program to control the species Phragmites communis (phragmites) on private lands.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To encourage waterfowl habitat conservation on private lands, the Department shall implement a 10-year licensing agreement for approved projects on privately owned lands detailing the landowner's responsibilities. Expenditures by private landowners on private land for these waterfowl projects approved by the Department and covered by the licensing agreement shall be considered a contribution to the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Governor shall appoint a Migratory Game Bird Advisory Committee of 9 members who have a practical knowledge of migratory game bird habitat conservation, migratory game bird ecology, migratory game bird management, or migratory game bird hunting.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Committee shall advise the Department on:<section prefix="(i)">Matters relating to expenditures of funds derived from the sale of Maryland migratory game bird stamps;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Policy, regulations, and legislation related to migratory game birds; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Migratory game bird habitat conservation projects.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
