<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-721</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person may not fish with a hauling seine or stake net in the waters of Swan Creek from July 15 to ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>721</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not fish with a hauling seine or stake net in the waters of Swan Creek from July 15 to September 15, both dates inclusive, and in the waters of the Gunpowder River lying in Harford County from May 15 to September 15, both dates inclusive.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not fish at any time with a haul seine in the waters of Bush River or any of its tributaries in Harford County.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not fish a pound net in any part of the Gunpowder and Bush rivers lying in Harford County further than 1,500 feet from the shoreline of the Gunpowder River below Maxwell Point at mean low water tide and 750 feet from the shoreline of the Bush River at mean low water tide.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except within the boundaries of the Aberdeen Proving Grounds, a person may not set a fyke net in the Bush River within 300 feet of another fyke net or 750 feet of a pound net, measured at right angles to existing nets or line of nets for enforcement purposes.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An owner, tenant, or lessee of the riparian rights of any property bordering the Bush River may maintain a single fyke net that is closer than 300 feet to another fyke net or pound net set in front of an adjacent property.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person may not use a pound net or stake net in the waters of the Susquehanna River.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not set or maintain a commercial drift gill net, stake gill net, or anchor gill net so that any portion of the net is closer than 500 feet from any portion of any other commercial drift gill net, stake gill net, or anchor gill net in the designated striped bass spawning area of the Susquehanna River north of Concord Point and Stump Point.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">South of the line outlined, in paragraph (1) of this subsection, to Bears Point and Turkey Point, a person may set a commercial drift gill net only as provided in paragraph (1) of this subsection and may set and maintain a stake gill net or anchor gill net only as provided in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
