<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-5-908.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>908.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Commission" means the Somers Cove Marina Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Fund" means the Somers Cove Marina Improvement Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Unencumbered" means not pledged for use by the State for Somers Cove Marina before the creation of the Commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Somers Cove Marina Commission.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Commission is a body politic and corporate and an instrumentality of the State.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission consists of the following members:<section prefix="(i)">Two members from Somerset County, appointed by the Board of County Commissioners of Somerset County, one of whom shall be a member of the Somerset County business community;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Two members from the City of Crisfield, appointed by the Mayor of Crisfield, one of whom shall be a member of the Somerset County business community; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Three members appointed by the Secretary, one of whom shall be a current slip holder at Somers Cove Marina.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The term of a member is 4 years.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A member may not serve more than 2 consecutive terms.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member is not entitled to compensation except for reimbursement for expenses as provided in the budget of the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Commission shall elect a chair and a vice chair of the Commission from among its members.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Commission shall appoint a secretary-treasurer who need not be a member of the Commission.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A secretary-treasurer who is not a member of the Commission may not vote on matters before the Commission.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Commission shall meet at least every 2 months, as determined by the chair.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">At least 10 days before each meeting, written notice shall be given to each member of the Commission.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Five members of the Commission are a quorum.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">A majority vote of the members present at a meeting having a quorum is needed for the Commission to act.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Secretary may remove a member of the Commission for any reason upon a majority vote of the members of the Commission.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a member is removed, a new member shall promptly be appointed by the individual or body that appointed the removed member.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall:<section prefix="(i)">Appoint an Executive Director;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Consult with the Commission in conducting the annual performance evaluation of the Executive Director; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Review and make determinations on requests for approval of leases and contracts submitted to the Secretary by the Executive Director in accordance with subsection (d) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Executive Director:<section prefix="(i)">Shall administer the Fund;</section><section prefix="(ii)">On or before May 1 of each year, and after consulting with the Commission, shall prepare operating and capital budgets for the subsequent fiscal year and submit the budgets to the Commission for review and approval;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Shall supervise the marina manager;</section><section prefix="(iv)">May execute leases of land, buildings, or facilities at Somers Cove Marina and execute contracts for events or concessions at Somers Cove Marina in accordance with subsection (c) of this section;</section><section prefix="(v)">Subject to the approval of the Secretary, and in cooperation with the Commission, shall develop an annual master plan for the operations, maintenance, development, and improvement of Somers Cove Marina that improves services to the general boating public;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Shall administer, in cooperation with the Commission, all unencumbered grants;</section><section prefix="(vii)"><section prefix="1.">Shall employ a staff to operate and maintain Somers Cove Marina, and set the staff's compensation; and</section><section prefix="2.">Shall, except for the marina manager, employ staff as employees of the Commission; and</section></section><section prefix="(viii)">Shall be an employee of the State and serve at the pleasure of the Secretary.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The marina manager shall be an employee of the State.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The marina manager is responsible for the day-to-day operations of the marina.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On approval of and subject to the conditions that the Department may require, Commission staff who are not employees of the Department may use vehicles or equipment of the Department.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A lease of land, a building, or other facility at the Somers Cove Marina or a contract for an event or concession at the Somers Cove Marina shall conform to the annual master plan approved under subsection (c)(2)(v) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A lease of land, a building, or a facility or a contract for an event or concession that is executed by the Executive Director:<section prefix="(i)">May not be for a term of more than 5 years or be renewed for more than an additional 5 years; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall be reviewed and approved by the Commission and Office of the Attorney General.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A lease entered into before the creation of the Commission shall remain in effect for the duration of the term of the lease.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Executive Director may not execute a lease or contract for nonboating related improvements or goods at the marina without the approval of the Secretary.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Within 30 days after receiving a request for approval of a lease or contract, the Secretary shall provide the Executive Director with an initial response that may include a process or plan of action for addressing the merits of the request.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">On approval of and subject to the conditions that the Secretary may require, the Department may transfer any vehicle, equipment, or other inventory to the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (6) of this subsection, the Executive Director shall procure goods, services, and capital improvement, design, and maintenance projects in accordance with the requirements of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For goods, services, and capital improvement, design, and maintenance projects with an expected value of $1,000 to $5,000, the Executive Director shall:<section prefix="(i)">Make a written or telephone request for bids;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Evaluate the bids; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Award the contract to the responsible bidder that submits the responsive bid that is the lowest bid price.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For goods, services, and capital improvement, design, and maintenance projects with an expected value of $5,000 to $200,000, the Executive Director shall:<section prefix="(i)">Advertise the solicitation in a local newspaper and on the Somerset County website;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Issue invitations for bids to all known prospective vendors;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Tabulate and evaluate the bids;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Select for award the responsible bidder who submits the responsive bid that is the lowest bid price; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Submit the proposed award to the Commission for review and approval.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Executive Director shall procure goods, services, and capital improvement, design, and maintenance projects with an expected value exceeding $200,000 in accordance with Division II of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">For goods, services, and capital improvement, design, and maintenance projects funded by the proceeds from State bonds, the Executive Director shall submit the proposed award to the Board of Public Works for approval.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">For an emergency procurement that the Executive Director determines to be necessary to avoid or mitigate serious damage to public health, safety, or welfare, the Executive Director shall:<section prefix="(i)">Obtain as much competition as possible under the circumstances; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">After awarding the procurement contract, submit to the Commission and the Secretary a written report that gives the justification for the use of the emergency procurement procedure.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The Executive Director shall adopt a procurement policy that includes provisions for minority- and women-owned business participation.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">This subsection does not apply to procurement in support of enterprise activities for the purpose of direct resale or remanufacture and subsequent resale.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">Adopt an operating budget to use the Fund to implement the master plan;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Adopt a capital budget that may use funds from Somerset County, the City of Crisfield, the State, and other sources to implement the master plan;</section><section prefix="(iii)"><section prefix="1.">Apply for grants from the Waterway Improvement Fund in accordance with Title 8, Subtitle 7 of this article; and</section><section prefix="2.">Subject to the Secretary's approval, receive approved grant amounts at the time of acceptance of a bid or bids for waterway improvement work;</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">Assess slip and other fees and charges at Somers Cove Marina as necessary in order to implement the master plan;</section><section prefix="(v)">Set policy and provide general oversight of marina operations; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Adopt rules and regulations necessary for the conduct of its own affairs.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission may:<section prefix="(i)">Accept gifts, contributions, or loans of money, supplies, goods, and services, and accept appropriations, allotments, and loans of money from:<section prefix="1.">The State or federal government;</section><section prefix="2.">A federal corporation;</section><section prefix="3.">A unit or instrumentality of the federal government; or</section><section prefix="4.">A political subdivision or instrumentality of the State;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Exercise a power usually possessed by a private corporation in performing similar functions unless to do so would conflict with State law; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Do all things necessary to carry out the mandates and powers expressly provided by this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">There is a Somers Cove Marina Improvement Fund in the Commission, to be used for the operation, maintenance, development, and improvement of the Somers Cove Marina facilities in Crisfield, Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Any money obtained by the Commission from Somers Cove Marina shall be credited to the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">Maintain the Fund in a bank account separate from State funds;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Transfer any unencumbered moneys in the Fund run by the Department to the Commission's Fund; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Reimburse the State for the salary of the marina manager.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Moneys of the Fund are:<section prefix="(i)">Not moneys of the State within the meaning of Article VI of the Maryland Constitution; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Subject to audit by the State, including the Department and the Legislative Auditor.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Moneys pledged for use by the State for Somers Cove Marina before the creation of the Commission shall be used for the same purpose as originally pledged.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">On or before October 1 of each year, the Commission shall provide to the Department an accounting of revenues and expenses from Somers Cove Marina for the previous fiscal year.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On November 1, 2011, the Department and the Commission shall begin to evaluate the Commission's work so that the Department and the Commission may make findings and recommendations concerning the Commission's ability to:<section prefix="(i)">Operate, maintain, develop, and improve Somers Cove Marina in an effective manner; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Afford or assume the costs of operating, maintaining, developing, and improving Somers Cove Marina, including the salaries of:<section prefix="1.">The Executive Director; and</section><section prefix="2.">Employees of the State who remain working at Somers Cove Marina.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On November 1, 2013, based on the evaluation undertaken in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Department and the Commission shall report their findings and recommendations, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
