<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-703</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>703</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department shall administer the provisions of this subtitle. In addition, the Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">Develop plans, within the limits of available income, for the improvement and promotion of the waters of the State for recreational purposes;</section><section prefix="(2)">Promote safety of life and property through an educational program directed to boat owners, boat operators, and others concerning the inherent hazards to vessels and people on the waters, including precautions to be observed, and emergency action;</section><section prefix="(3)">Plan a regulatory program and its related cooperation with officials of other states, the federal government, and local governments;</section><section prefix="(4)">Improve the State's waterways by deepening channels, acquiring and developing access areas, clearing waterways by removing logs, debris, and other material obstructing or detrimental to navigation, building docks, and clearing waters of aquatic vegetation;</section><section prefix="(5)">Cooperate with federal, State, or local agencies which make funds available for the purposes of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(6)">In order to protect life and property, tow disabled vessels on any waters of the State to the nearest safe harbor or to a location where commercial towing facilities are available. The Department may not engage in towing in competition with commercial towing services;</section><section prefix="(7)">Designate and mark channels in the waters of the State; and</section><section prefix="(8)">By April 1, 1990, for any attended boat launching facility or marina that is owned or operated by the Department on July 1, 1989 or that is purchased, built, or otherwise acquired by the Department on or after July 1, 1989, install a pump-out station on-site at any attended boat launching facility or marina that is adequate to handle the sewage capacity from vessels expected to use the boat launching facility or marina.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department may take possession of any document the Department issues pursuant to this subtitle:<section prefix="(1)">After the document's expiration, revocation, cancellation, or suspension; or</section><section prefix="(2)">If the document is issued unlawfully or erroneously.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
