<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-11E-01" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-11E-01</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Seafood Marketing Advisory Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission consists of 13 members.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Of the 13 Commission members:<section prefix="(1)">1 shall be the Secretary of Agriculture or the designee of the Secretary of Agriculture, as an ex officio nonvoting member;</section><section prefix="(2)">1 shall be the Secretary of Natural Resources or the designee of the Secretary of Natural Resources, as an ex officio nonvoting member;</section><section prefix="(3)">5 shall represent the seafood packers in this State, at least 3 of whom shall be members of the Chesapeake Bay Seafood Industries Association;</section><section prefix="(4)">2 shall be licensed Maryland watermen;</section><section prefix="(5)">1 shall represent the retail food industry in this State;</section><section prefix="(6)">1 shall represent the aquaculture industry in this State; and</section><section prefix="(7)">2 shall be consumer members.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor shall appoint the 3 members representing the Chesapeake Bay Seafood Industries Association from a list of names submitted to the Governor by the Chesapeake Bay Seafood Industries Association. The names on the list shall be three times the number of vacancies;</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except for the ex officio members and the members representing the Chesapeake Bay Seafood Industries Association, the Governor shall appoint each member with the advice of the Secretary; and</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except for the ex officio members, each member appointed by the Governor shall be appointed with the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Before taking office, each appointee to the Commission shall take the oath required by Article I, --amp--sect; 9 of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The term of a member is 4 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A member may not serve more than 2 terms on the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The terms of the initial voting members of the Commission expire as follows:<section prefix="(1)">2 in 1988;</section><section prefix="(2)">3 in 1989;</section><section prefix="(3)">3 in 1990; and</section><section prefix="(4)">3 in 1991.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The Governor may remove a member for incompetence or misconduct.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">The Commission shall assist the Seafood Marketing and Aquaculture Development Program and the Division of Market Development in the Department of Agriculture in:<section prefix="(1)">Promoting increased consumption and distribution of Maryland seafood; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Seeking efficient methods to reduce cost and improve the quality and marketability of Maryland seafood.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
