<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-5-216</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>216</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Deep Creek Lake Policy and Review Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board consists of:<section prefix="(i)">Five members appointed by the Governor in accordance with paragraph (2) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Senator of the Maryland General Assembly who represents legislative district 1 or the Senator's designee;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Delegate of the Maryland General Assembly who represents delegate district 1A of legislative district 1 or the Delegate's designee;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A member of the Board of County Commissioners of Garrett County, selected by the Board of County Commissioners, or an alternative County Commissioner, serving as the member's designee;</section><section prefix="(v)">The president of the Deep Creek Lake property owner's association or the president's designee; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">The chairman of the Garrett County Chamber of Commerce or the chairman's designee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the five members appointed under paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">Two shall be residents of Garrett County;</section><section prefix="(ii)">One shall be a representative of the Maryland Bass Federation and a resident of Maryland; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Two shall be members at large.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each member of the Board appointed under paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection serves for a term concurrent with the term of the Board of County Commissioners of Garrett County.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">At the end of a term, the member continues to serve until a successor is appointed.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Each member of the Board or designee serving under paragraph (1)(ii) through (vi) of this section serves for a term concurrent with the member's office or position.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">From among the members appointed under subsection (b)(1)(i) of this section, the Governor shall name a chairman of the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A majority of the members then serving on the Board is a quorum.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member of the Maryland General Assembly, or a designee of the member, shall abstain from voting on:<section prefix="(i)">A proposed fee under &#xA7; 5-215(d) of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any other regulation submitted to the Board under &#xA7; 5-215.1(d)(2) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall meet at least four times a year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The chairman shall determine the time and place of the meetings of the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each meeting shall be conducted in Garrett County.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A member of the Board:<section prefix="(i)">May not receive compensation; but</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Expenses shall be paid from the Deep Creek Lake Recreation Maintenance and Management Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall review and advise the Secretary on matters that relate to the Deep Creek Lake Recreation Maintenance and Management Fund and the Deep Creek Lake management program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may review and make recommendations to the Secretary on budgetary matters that concern the management and maintenance of the lake and buffer area.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
