<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-5-903.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>903.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Fund" means the Program Open Space Contingency Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Program Open Space Contingency Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Fund is a continuing, nonlapsing, revolving fund not to exceed $1,000,000 that consists of the amount of appropriations for a capital project:<section prefix="(1)">In excess of the amount needed for the capital project; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Allocated to the Fund by the Governor.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Fund may be used to:<section prefix="(1)">Supplement an existing appropriation for a capital project; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Undertake critical maintenance projects.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall evaluate each request for an expenditure from the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department may request the Board of Public Works to authorize an expenditure from the Fund if:<section prefix="(i)">All reasonable attempts to reduce the cost of the capital project have been made;</section><section prefix="(ii)">No practical alternative exists for securing funding to complete the capital or critical maintenance project; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The requested funding does not increase the scope of the capital project.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Prior to seeking approval from the Board of Public Works, the Department of Natural Resources and the Department of Budget and Management shall:<section prefix="(i)">Provide written notice to the budget committees on the planned use of the funds; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Allow 45 days for review and comment by the budget committees unless the additional funds necessary do not exceed 20% of the original appropriation for any project and in the judgment of the Department of Natural Resources and the Department of Budget and Management that the additional funds are necessary to prevent a work stoppage on the project.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the Board of Public Works authorizes an expenditure from the Fund, the amount specified by the Board of Public Works may be transferred from the Fund to the Program Open Space account to supplement the specified authorization.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">On or before January 1 of each year, the Secretary of Natural Resources shall report to the General Assembly, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, on the moneys:<section prefix="(1)">Deposited in the Fund;</section><section prefix="(2)">Authorized for expenditure from the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Expended from the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Money in the Fund shall be deposited with the State Treasurer.</section>
  </text>
</law>
