<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-1-404</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>404</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Administrator" means the final authority in the decision making process for accepting land into a land conservation program in the Department of Natural Resources.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Conservation easement" means an easement held or co-held by the Department of Natural Resources or the Maryland Environmental Trust.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Land conservation program" includes the Maryland Environmental Trust, Program Open Space, and the Rural Legacy Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Project" means an acquisition or development project under Program Open Space, in accordance with Title 5, Subtitle 9 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Protected land" means land that is protected by a land conservation program.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Rural Legacy Area" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 5-9A-02 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to applications affecting land that is protected by a program within the Department of Natural Resources, including land that is:<section prefix="(1)">Subject to a conservation easement within a designated Rural Legacy Area;</section><section prefix="(2)">Subject to a conservation easement held by the Maryland Environmental Trust; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Subject to a conservation easement funded under Program Open Space.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the administrator of a land conservation program has not approved the use for the land for which an application is made, a county or municipal corporation may deny an application for:<section prefix="(1)">A subdivision plat or plan;</section><section prefix="(2)">A residential building permit; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Any other nonagricultural use or activity, including an access road.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section may not be construed to limit the authority of a county to grant or deny an application for a land use permit.</section>
  </text>
</law>
