<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-10-609</section_number>
  <catch_line>Offshore stationary blinds and offshore blind sites shall be at least 250 yards apart from each othe...</catch_line>
  <order_by>609</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Offshore stationary blinds and offshore blind sites shall be at least 250 yards apart from each other.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Offshore stationary blinds and offshore blind sites shall be located within 300 yards of the shoreline or one-third the distance to the opposite shore, whichever is less, except that in the Chesapeake Bay in Anne Arundel and Calvert counties, and in Prospect Bay in Queen Anne's County, all offshore stationary blinds and blind sites may be no more than 800 yards from the shoreline.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Offshore stationary blinds and blind sites may not be less than 150 yards from any dwelling house without the written permission of the owner of the house.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, offshore stationary blinds shall be marked with the licensee's name and license number and marked on each side with at least 100 square inches of clearly visible reflective material attached to the outside of the stationary blind at least 3 feet above the high water mark.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Reflective material is not required to be displayed or attached to the outside of a stationary blind while the stationary blind is occupied and is being used for hunting.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Offshore blind sites shall be marked by a stake showing the licensee's name and license number. Each stake shall be marked on all sides with reflective material at least 4 inches wide and located at least 3 feet above the high water mark. All stakes shall be removed within 30 days after the last wild waterfowl season closes.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the licensee of riparian shoreline shall have the sole right to establish offshore stationary blinds or blind sites within 300 yards of the licensed shoreline or one-third the distance to the opposite shore, whichever is less.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the Chesapeake Bay in Anne Arundel and Calvert counties, and in Prospect Bay in Queen Anne's County, the licensee of riparian shoreline shall have the sole right to establish offshore stationary blinds or blind sites within 800 yards of the licensed shoreline.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
