<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-1808" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-1808</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">It is the intent of this subtitle that each local jurisdiction shall have primary responsibility for developing and implementing a program, subject to review and approval by the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Governor shall include in the budget a sum of money to be used for grants to reimburse local jurisdictions for the reasonable costs of developing a program under this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Each local jurisdiction shall submit to the Governor a detailed request for funds that are equivalent to the additional costs incurred in developing the program under this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Governor shall include in the fiscal year 2003 budget a sum of money to be used for grants to reimburse local jurisdictions in the Atlantic Coastal Bays Critical Area for the reasonable costs of developing a program under this section.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Governor shall include in the budget annually a sum of money to be used for grants to assist local jurisdictions with the reasonable costs of implementing a program under this section. Each local jurisdiction shall submit to the Governor by May 1 of each year a detailed request for funds to assist in the implementation of a program under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A program shall consist of those elements which are necessary or appropriate:<section prefix="(1)">To minimize adverse impacts on water quality that result from pollutants that are discharged from structures or conveyances or that have run off from surrounding lands;</section><section prefix="(2)">To conserve fish, wildlife, and plant habitat; and</section><section prefix="(3)">To establish land use policies for development in the Chesapeake Bay Critical Area or the Atlantic Coastal Bays Critical Area which accommodate growth and also address the fact that, even if pollution is controlled, the number, movement, and activities of persons in that area can create adverse environmental impacts.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Notwithstanding any provision in a local law or ordinance, or the lack of a provision in a local law or ordinance, all of the requirements of this subtitle shall apply to, and be applied by, a local jurisdiction as minimum standards for a program sufficient to meet the goals of the Critical Area Program.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">With the approval of the Commission, a local jurisdiction may establish procedures for the granting of an administrative variance.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">At a minimum, a program shall contain all of the following elements, including:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In determining the amount of the penalty to be assessed under paragraph (1)(iii)14 of this subsection, a local jurisdiction shall consider:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In paragraph (1)(iii)14 of this subsection, "property owner" includes two or more persons holding title to the property under any form of joint ownership.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Regulations adopted under paragraph (1)(iii)15 of this subsection shall provide for the Commission's consideration of enforcement provisions submitted by a local jurisdiction that are at least as effective as enforcement requirements under this subtitle and regulations adopted under the authority of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A local jurisdiction may not issue a permit, approval, variance, or special exception unless the person seeking the permit, approval, variance, or special exception has:<section prefix="(i)">Fully paid all administrative, civil, and criminal penalties imposed under paragraph (1)(iii)15 of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Prepared a restoration or mitigation plan, approved by the local jurisdiction, to abate impacts to water quality or natural resources as a result of the violation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Performed the abatement measures in the approved plan in accordance with the local critical area program.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "unwarranted hardship" means that, without a variance, an applicant would be denied reasonable and significant use of the entire parcel or lot for which the variance is requested.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the provisions of this paragraph shall apply to a proceeding that involves a variance for a development activity in the buffer under the requirements of:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a person meets the threshold standing requirements under federal law, the person shall have standing to participate as a party in a local administrative proceeding.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A person that has standing under subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph may:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A local jurisdiction shall process an application for a variance regarding a parcel or lot that is subject to a current violation of this subtitle, a regulation adopted under the authority of this subtitle, or any provision of an order, permit, plan, or local program in accordance with subsection (c)(1)(iii)15 of this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In considering an application for a variance, a local jurisdiction shall presume that the specific development activity in the critical area that is subject to the application and for which a variance is required does not conform with the general purpose and intent of this subtitle, regulations adopted under this subtitle, and the requirements of the local jurisdiction's program.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If the variance request is based on conditions or circumstances that are the result of actions by the applicant, a local jurisdiction shall consider that fact.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An applicant has the burden of proof and the burden of persuasion to overcome the presumption established under paragraph (3)(ii) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A variance to a local jurisdiction's critical area program may not be granted unless:<section prefix="(i)">Due to special features of a site, or special conditions or circumstances peculiar to the applicant's land or structure, a literal enforcement of the critical area program would result in unwarranted hardship to the applicant;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The local jurisdiction finds that the applicant has satisfied each one of the variance provisions; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Without the variance, the applicant would be deprived of a use of land or a structure permitted to others in accordance with the provisions of the critical area program.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Within 10 working days after a written decision regarding a variance application is issued, the Commission shall receive a copy of the decision from a local jurisdiction.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A local jurisdiction may not issue a permit for the activity that was the subject of the variance application until the applicable 30-day appeal period has elapsed.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A development activity commenced without a required permit, approval, variance, or special exception is a violation of this subtitle.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A local jurisdiction may not accept an application for a variance to legalize a violation of this subtitle, including an unpermitted structure or development activity, unless the local jurisdiction first issues a notice of violation, including assessment of an administrative or civil penalty, for the violation.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If a final adjudication of a notice of violation results in a determination that a violation has occurred, the person shall be liable for a penalty that is twice the amount of the assessment in the notice of violation, in addition to the cost of the hearing and any applicable mitigation costs.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Application for a variance under this paragraph constitutes a waiver of the right to appeal the terms of a notice of violation and its final adjudication, including the payment of any penalties and costs assessed.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">If the local jurisdiction finds that the activity or structure for which a variance is requested commenced without permits or approvals and:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(8)">This subsection does not apply to building permits or activities that comply with a buffer exemption plan or buffer management plan of a local jurisdiction which has been approved by the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">Notwithstanding any provision of a local law or ordinance, or the lack of a provision in a local law or ordinance, all of the provisions of this subsection shall apply to, and shall be applied by, a local jurisdiction in the consideration, processing, and decision on an application for a variance.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall adopt by regulation on or before December 1, 1985 criteria for program development and approval, which are necessary or appropriate to achieve the standards stated in subsection (b) of this section. Prior to developing its criteria and also prior to adopting its criteria, the Commission shall hold at least 6 regional public hearings, 1 in each of the following areas:<section prefix="(i)">Harford, Cecil, and Kent counties;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Queen Anne's, Talbot, and Caroline counties;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Dorchester, Somerset, and Wicomico counties;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Baltimore City and Baltimore County;</section><section prefix="(v)">Charles, Calvert, and St. Mary's counties; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Anne Arundel and Prince George's counties.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">During the hearing process, the Commission shall consult with each affected local jurisdiction.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In accordance with its powers under &#xA7; 8-1806(a) of this subtitle, the Commission may amend the criteria for program development and approval adopted under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Nothing in this section shall impede or prevent the dredging of any waterway in a critical area. However, dredging in a critical area is subject to other applicable federal and State laws and regulations.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In adopting the initial land classification for the Atlantic Coastal Bays Critical Area, the local program:<section prefix="(1)">Of the Town of Ocean City shall classify as an intensely developed area that area that is within the municipal boundaries of Ocean City as of January 1, 2002; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Of Worcester County shall classify as an intensely developed area that area located on the western mainland that is east of Golf Course Road, south of Charles Street, and north of Route 707 (Old Bridge Road).</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The provisions of this subtitle and Title 27 of the Code of Maryland Regulations apply to the Atlantic Coastal Bays Critical Area.</section>
  </text>
</law>
