<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-5-426</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Department shall establish and administer an urban and community forestry program to provide Sta...</catch_line>
  <order_by>426</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall establish and administer an urban and community forestry program to provide State or federal financial assistance, on a matching basis, to:<section prefix="(i)">A county or municipal corporation that implements a local urban and community forestry program within its jurisdiction; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A nonprofit corporation that participates in the implementation of a local urban and community forestry program.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The county or municipal corporation may hire an individual to direct its program with the cooperation of the Department.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department's urban and community forestry program shall provide technical assistance to counties, municipal corporations, nonprofit corporations, and individuals for the retention and management of forests and trees. This technical assistance may include:<section prefix="(1)">Street tree inventories;</section><section prefix="(2)">Technical evaluation of site development plans;</section><section prefix="(3)">Management recommendations for the retention, protection, and utilization of forests and trees in developments;</section><section prefix="(4)">Assistance to planning and zoning departments;</section><section prefix="(5)">Advice on insect and disease control;</section><section prefix="(6)">Advice to counties and municipal corporations in implementing and conducting their own urban and community forestry program; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Advice to nonprofit corporations participating in the implementation of an urban and community forestry program.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
