<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-5-9A-08</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is an Advisory Committee to the Board in the Department of Natural Resources....</catch_line>
  <order_by>08</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is an Advisory Committee to the Board in the Department of Natural Resources.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Committee is established to review applications for Rural Legacy Areas, make recommendations for Rural Legacy Area designations to the Board, and consider such other matters as requested by the Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Committee has 11 members as follows:<section prefix="(1)">A trustee of the Maryland Agricultural Land Preservation Foundation;</section><section prefix="(2)">A trustee of the Maryland Environmental Trust;</section><section prefix="(3)">A representative of the agriculture industry;</section><section prefix="(4)">A representative of a nonprofit land conservation organization;</section><section prefix="(5)">A representative of a nonprofit environmental organization;</section><section prefix="(6)">A representative of the forest industry;</section><section prefix="(7)">A representative of a county government department of parks and recreation;</section><section prefix="(8)">A representative of a business organization;</section><section prefix="(9)">A private land owner;</section><section prefix="(10)">A representative of the mineral resources industry; and</section><section prefix="(11)">A representative of a municipal corporation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Committee members are appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Committee on July 1, 1997.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Governor shall solicit nominees from industries and groups which are represented on the Committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The members shall represent geographically and ethnically diverse areas.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of membership is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not serve more than two consecutive terms.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Governor shall designate the chairperson of the Committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department of Natural Resources, in cooperation with the Department of Agriculture and the Department of Planning, shall provide staff support for the Committee.</section>
  </text>
</law>
