<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-5-219</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>219</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Reforestation" means the stocking or restocking of an area with forest tree species.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Reforestation" includes:<section prefix="1.">Site preparation by mechanical operation, application of herbicides, or prescribed burning;</section><section prefix="2.">Tree planting;</section><section prefix="3.">Release of seedlings from competing vegetation;</section><section prefix="4.">Animal damage control of seedlings; and</section><section prefix="5.">Other activities that the Secretary requires.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Reforestation" does not include the growing of Christmas or ornamental trees.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Timber stand improvement" means any precommercial cultural operation made to improve the composition, constitution, condition, and increment of a timber stand.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Timber stand improvement" includes tree removal, girdling, poisoning, and pruning activities that:<section prefix="1.">Are not done only to help regeneration; and</section><section prefix="2.">Do not result in immediately salable forest products.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person who owns or leases 10 to 500 acres of land may apply for reforestation or timber stand improvement certification under this section if the land is:<section prefix="(1)">Capable of growing more than 20 cubic feet of wood per acre per year; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Available for the application of scientific forest management practices for the primary purpose of growing and harvesting forest tree species.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department shall issue an initial certification of reforestation or timber stand improvement to an applicant who owns or leases 10 to 500 acres of land that is used as commercial forest land or that is being restored and is capable of growing a commercial forest, if there is:<section prefix="(1)">A successful planting of the required minimum number of seedlings with acceptable species; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Timber stand improvement activities in accordance with a forest management plan developed by a licensed forester.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 2 years after the date of initial certification, the Department shall issue a final certification of reforestation or timber stand improvement to an applicant who received an initial certification if:<section prefix="(i)">Seedlings are living without other vegetation growing around or over the seedling; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Successful timber stand improvements have been made in accordance with regulations of the Secretary.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the reforestation or timber stand improvement activities do not meet the requirements for final certification when the application is made, the applicant may replant or conduct additional timber stand improvement activities.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If an application for final certification is not filed within 2 years after the date of initial certification, the applicant shall submit a plan to continue the reforestation or timber stand improvement project to the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department shall decertify land if:<section prefix="(1)">Reforestation or timber stand improvement activity on the land is discontinued before issuance of a final certificate;</section><section prefix="(2)">A final certificate application or a plan of continuation is not filed within 2 years after the date on which the initial certificate is issued; or</section><section prefix="(3)">The land does not continue to be used as commercial forest land for 15 years after final certification is issued.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Secretary shall:<section prefix="(1)">Adopt regulations to carry out this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide to a certified person notice of initial and final certification that the person may file with the Comptroller as evidence of the eligibility of the person for the income tax subtraction modification for reforestation and timberland expense allowed under &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-208 and 10-308 of the Tax - General Article; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Send a copy of a decertification notice to the Comptroller for purposes of the income tax addition modification for reforestation and timberland expense required under &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-205 and 10-306 of the Tax - General Article.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
