<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-701" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-701</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to any person who is required under Subtitle 2, 7, 8, 9, or 10 of this title to be licensed to guide fishing parties or to catch, sell, buy, process, transport, export, or otherwise deal in fish caught in tidal waters.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall utilize a single, commercial license, to be known and designated as a tidal fish license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A tidal fish license authorizes a licensee:<section prefix="(i)">To engage in each activity indicated on the license; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">For catching crabs, to utilize the number of crew members indicated on the license.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except for a person receiving a license as a beneficiary of a deceased licensee under subsection (j)(4)(i) of this section, the Department may not issue a tidal fish license to an individual who is younger than 14 years of age.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A person may not guide fishing parties or catch, sell, buy, process, transport, export, or otherwise deal in fish caught in tidal waters unless licensed under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The license year for every tidal fish license shall be 12 months from September 1 through August 31 of the following year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A licensee and crew members may engage only in those activities for which the annual fees for that license year have been paid.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department may issue no more than one authorization to a person to engage in each activity under paragraph (2)(ii)1 and 2 of this subsection during a license year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">On a tidal fish license, the Department may issue an authorization for any of the following activities for which the indicated fee has been paid.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The following annual fees for an authorization shall apply regardless of when the license is issued or an activity is authorized:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To catch striped bass for sale:<section prefix="(i)">A licensee authorized under subsection (d)(2)(ii)2A of this section shall pay an annual surcharge of $200; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A licensee authorized under subsection (d)(2)(ii)2F of this section shall pay with the license fee an annual surcharge of $100.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A person may not catch oysters for sale without:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Department shall use the surcharges collected under this paragraph only for oyster repletion activities.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In addition to the normal license fees imposed under subsection (d)(2)(ii)2 and 4 of this section, a licensee shall pay to the Department an annual surcharge of $10 to be credited to the Seafood Marketing Office of the Department to fund seafood marketing programs which have been approved by the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)"/>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Department shall assess annually on every nonresident license applicant for the applicant's fishing activities under Subtitles 7, 8, and 9 of this title, in addition to the normal license fees imposed by this subsection, a surcharge which cumulatively for the license year, shall be the greater of:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department may assess annually on every person licensed under subsection (d)(2)(ii)2 of this section a surcharge for the costs incurred by the Department for:<section prefix="(1)">Fish tags issued to the licensee; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The use by a licensee of a hailing system.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">An applicant for a license to provide services as a commercial fishing guide in tidal waters of the State shall supply as part of the application verifiable references to any federal license that is issued by the U.S. Coast Guard to operate a vessel carrying passengers for hire in the applicant's name, as a condition precedent to engaging as a commercial fishing guide in tidal waters.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the Department may issue an apprenticeship permit for any activity under subsection (d)(2)(ii)1 or 2 of this section to a person who currently resides and has resided for at least 5 years on an island in the State that is at least 3 miles from the mainland.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department may set by regulation targets for the number of tidal fish license authorizations under subsection (d)(2)(ii) of this section to be the number issued between September 1, 1998 and March 31, 1999. The Department may modify by regulation the target number of authorizations based on:<section prefix="(i)">Recommendations of the Tidal Fisheries Advisory Commission;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Recommendations of fishery management plans adopted by the Department, the Chesapeake Bay Program, the Atlantic States Marine Fisheries Commission, the Mid-Atlantic Fisheries Management Council, or any other appropriate management body;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The number of people historically participating;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Target species, size, number, weight, incidental catch, total biomass, annual harvest, mortality rates, and other factors which are necessary and appropriate; and</section><section prefix="(v)">The number of authorizations relinquished to the Department under subsection (k) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Department shall by regulation limit the total number of commercial authorizations to fish for striped bass not to exceed 1,231 participants in the commercial fishery and 499 participants in the charter boat fishery.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Department shall provide in its regulations for reallocation of any authorizations that may be revoked or voluntarily relinquished to the Department.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Department shall provide in its regulations for the allocation of any available quota on a monthly basis to assure that all areas of the State have ample opportunity to attain an equitable portion of the available quota.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Department shall issue a license authorizing participation in a particular fishing activity to a person who has completed the requirements of an apprenticeship under &#xA7; 4-701.1 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A license or authorization may be transferred only under the provisions of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who desires to obtain a license or authorization by transfer under this subsection shall, for each license or authorization applied for:<section prefix="(i)">Pay a $50 application fee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Submit a completed application to the Department.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department shall review and may approve the permanent transfer of a license or an authorization to a person who is the licensee's spouse, daughter, son, stepchild, grandchild, stepgrandchild, parent, sister, brother, grandparent, aunt, uncle, niece, nephew, father-in-law, mother-in-law, son-in-law, daughter-in-law, sister-in-law, or brother-in-law.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">On the death of a licensee, the Department shall review and may approve the permanent transfer of a license or authorization to the person indicated on the beneficiary form submitted by the deceased licensee at the time of issuance on the license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The personal representative of the estate of the deceased licensee may retain the license or authorization for 2 years from the date of appointment as personal representative if:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">On appointment, the personal representative shall notify the Department of the appointment and the intent to retain the license or authorization.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">A license or authorization retained under this paragraph may be renewed annually as required by this title.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">Before the end of the 2-year period, the personal representative may submit a completed transfer application to transfer the license or authorization to a qualified individual.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">If a license or authorization is not transferred under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, and a transfer application is not submitted under subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the license or authorization is void.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">A person may not operate under the license or authorization of the deceased licensee without approval of the application by the Department.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Twice per license year, the Department may approve a temporary transfer of a license or authorization for not more than the remainder of the license year.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A temporary transferee who is convicted or receives an accepted plea of nolo contendere for a violation of federal or State fisheries law that results in a license suspension or revocation may not engage in that fishing activity or receive a transfer of a tidal fish license during the period of suspension or revocation.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Department may approve the permanent transfer of a license or authorization under this subsection from a person who has held a valid tidal fish license for at least 2 years to a person who provides a notarized bill of sale for the license or authorization being transferred.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except for a fishing guide licensee or a master fishing guide licensee, a licensee may allow one individual to use the licensee's commercial fishing vessel to engage in activities authorized under the license if:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A licensee may change the assignment once per license year.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If a licensee allows an individual to utilize a vessel under this paragraph, the individual and the licensee shall be held responsible for any violations committed by the individual using the vessel.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding the qualification criteria for a license and authorization to engage in an activity under this section, licensees may renew any valid existing authorizations on their licenses annually.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Application to renew a tidal fish license shall be made not later than August 31, or the next business day in the instance that the Department is not open, for the following license year.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Department may not accept application for renewal after that date, as stated in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph unless:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before September 1, 2012, at the time of license renewal, a licensee who possesses three or more authorizations under subsection (d)(2)(ii)1 and 2A through E of this section, one of which is a crabbing authorization, may relinquish each authorization and receive an authorization under subsection (d)(2)(ii)2F of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A licensee who possesses an unlimited tidal fish license under subsection (d)(2)(ii)2F of this section may relinquish the unlimited tidal fish license and receive one or more authorizations under subsection (d)(2)(ii)1A through E of this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the fee for an unlimited tidal fish license is less than the total of the fees for authorizations received by a licensee under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the licensee shall pay to the Department an amount equal to the difference between the fee for the unlimited tidal fish license and the total of the fees for the authorizations received.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department shall adjust the number of authorizations under subsection (d)(2)(ii) of this section to reflect the number of license conversions under paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to any other penalty provided in this title, the Department may suspend or revoke a person's entitlement to engage in a particular activity or activities under a tidal fish license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">During a period of suspension or revocation imposed by the Department, the person penalized is not and shall not be authorized under any existing, renewed, transferred, or new tidal fish license to engage in the particular activity or activities for which the suspension is imposed.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The following are grounds for suspension or revocation of a tidal fish license:<section prefix="(i)">Making any false statement in an application for a tidal fish license;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A serious violation of a State or federal commercial fisheries law that results in a conviction or an accepted plea of nolo contendere;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Failure to submit reports required by the provisions of this title or by the Department pursuant to provisions of this title; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Failure for a nonresident of the State to appear in court pursuant to a citation issued by a Natural Resources police officer, or to any other process issued by any court of Maryland, for violation of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A penalty imposed in accordance with this subtitle shall be in addition to any other penalty authorized under &#xA7; 4-1201 of this title regarding striped bass.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Department, in consultation with the Tidal Fisheries Advisory Commission and the Sport Fisheries Advisory Commission, shall adopt regulations relating to the suspension and revocation of licenses and authorizations issued under this title, including:<section prefix="(i)">A schedule of points assigned to various offenses under this title;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A schedule of the maximum number of days that a license may be suspended according to the number of points accumulated;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Suspension or revocation of a license or authorization for a serious violation of a State or federal commercial fisheries law that results in an individual receiving a conviction or an accepted plea of nolo contendere;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Enhanced penalties for repeated violations of this title; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Enhanced penalties for violations of provisions of this title that regulate species deemed by the Department to be in need of special protection, including striped bass, crabs, oysters, and menhaden.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Before the suspension or revocation of a tidal fish license under this section, the Department shall notify the licensee in writing of the licensee's right to a hearing on request.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a licensee submits a written request for a hearing to the Department within 30 days after the date that the notice required under this paragraph is mailed, the Department shall:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Department may suspend a commercial license issued under this title without a hearing if:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a person is engaged in an activity for which a license or authorization is required under this section, the person shall possess:<section prefix="(i)">Any required license, authorization, or permit; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">For a person to whom a license or authorization has been temporarily transferred, documentation indicating the Department's approval of the temporary transfer application.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph does not limit the Department's authority to inspect books, statements, and accounts under &#xA7; 4-206(b) of this title.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The licensee or any person to whom a licensee has transferred a license under subsection (j) of this section shall allow any police officer, at reasonable times, including when the licensee or person is engaged in an activity that requires a license under this section, to inspect:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Inspections of vessels, vehicles, and businesses authorized under this paragraph shall be restricted to inspections of fishing gear and places where fish may be stored.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Inspections of businesses authorized under this paragraph may be conducted in any building other than a dwelling house.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An inspector may seize fishing gear or fish found during an inspection under this subsection that is used or possessed in connection with a violation of this title or a regulation adopted under this title.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Fishing gear seized under this paragraph shall be held by the Department pending disposition of court proceedings, and on conviction the property seized or proceeds from the seizure shall be forfeited to the State for destruction or disposition as the Department may deem appropriate.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Department may dispose of fish seized under this paragraph at its discretion.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">The Department shall assign a permanent identification number to each licensee. A licensee shall display the identification number on every vessel, vehicle, gear, or place of business, as the Department may require by regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">Deposit to the credit of the Fisheries Research and Development Fund all fees received for tidal fish licenses, authorizations, and permits under this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Use the funds received from the sale of striped bass surcharges for striped bass management and enforcement purposes.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only to a person who, on April 1, 1997:<section prefix="(i)">Held a valid fishing guide license; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Either:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who meets the requirements of paragraph (1) of this subsection may obtain an annual master fishing guide license by:<section prefix="(i)">Filing an application on a form provided by the Department;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Supplying with the application proofs of ownership of the required vessels; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Paying the master fishing guide license fee set forth in subsection (d)(2)(ii)1 of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A person holding a master fishing guide license may:<section prefix="(i)">Employ other persons to guide fishing parties on vessels owned by the master fishing guide; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Allow a person who holds a valid Coast Guard license to operate a vessel to carry passengers for fishing from the marina owned or operated by the master guide license holder authorized under paragraph (1)(ii)3 of this subsection as follows:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Department shall issue a number of copies of the master fishing guide license corresponding to the number of vessels owned or operated by the master fishing guide, with each copy bearing the registration number of one of the vessels.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The master fishing guide shall ensure that when a vessel is operated, the appropriate copy of the license is on board.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If a master fishing guide employs another person to operate a vessel to carry passengers for fishing, for purposes of the license suspension criteria in subsection (m) of this section, the master fishing guide shall be held responsible for any violations committed by the person employed to operate the vessel.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
