<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-604" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-604</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section provides a fund to pay the expense of protecting and managing game and freshwater fish and preventing unauthorized persons from fishing or attempting to fish for any game and freshwater fish without first procuring an angler's license.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Any person 16 years old or older shall secure an angler's license to fish in the nontidal waters of the State. An angler's license entitles the holder to fish in the nontidal waters of the State only during the open season.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An angler's license is not required of the following:<section prefix="(1)">The owner or tenant of land bordering on nontidal water, his spouse and children, or the spouse of any child who resides on the land with the owner or tenant when he fishes in nontidal water adjoining his land;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any resident serving in the armed forces of the United States, while on leave in the State, during his leave period, if, while angling, he possesses a copy of his official leave orders;</section><section prefix="(3)">A person who fishes in nontidal waters of the State on free fishing days designated by the Secretary;</section><section prefix="(4)">A person holding a current resident consolidated senior sport fishing license issued under &#xA7; 4-216 of this title;</section><section prefix="(5)">A person fishing in a free fishing area established under &#xA7; 4-214(b)(2) of this title; or</section><section prefix="(6)">A person authorized by a disability exemption issued under &#xA7; 4-217 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person may apply for an angler's license to any person designated by the Department. The application shall be on a form the Department prepares and supplies. The applicant shall fill out, sign and submit the application to the person designated to issue an angler's license. A person may apply by mail.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An applicant for a license issued under this section shall provide all the information requested by the Department on forms issued by the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The following annual license fees shall apply:<section prefix="(i)">Resident$20.50</section><section prefix="(ii)">Subject to paragraph (2)(ii) of this subsection, short-term license valid for 7 consecutive days from date of issuance$7.50</section><section prefix="(iii)">Resident and nonresident blind personsNo fee</section><section prefix="(iv)">Complimentary licenseNo fee</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For a nonresident:<section prefix="(i)">The fee for an annual angler's license is the greater of:</section><section prefix="(ii)">The fee for a short-term license valid for 7 consecutive days from the date of issuance is the greater of:</section><section prefix="(iii)">The fee for a short-term license valid for 3 consecutive days from the date of issuance is the greater of:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">All fees collected by the Department under this section may only be used in accordance with &#xA7; 4-208 of this title.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Department shall publicly report annually the amounts collected and the expenditures under this section.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A person designated to sell an angler's license shall issue the license and collect the fee prescribed in subsection (f) of this section. The Department shall furnish the licenses to the designated persons. An angler's license shall bear the Secretary's facsimile signature and the countersignature of the issuing person. The person who issues the license shall enter the name and address of the licensee. The collected money shall be transmitted to the Department as prescribed by the Department. As compensation, the agent shall retain $1 for each license issued.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Every angler's license shall expire on December 31 of each year following the date of issuance.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The licensee shall sign his name in ink on the license at the time of purchase.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The license may not be transferred to another person, nor used or presented by any person other than the person to whom it was issued.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
