<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-728" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-728</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "connected line of nets" means a series of connected nets set in single file.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, a person may not set:<section prefix="(i)">A fish pot, fyke net, or connected line of fyke nets within 500 feet in any direction of any other net or connected line of nets;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A fyke net or connected line of fyke nets that exceeds 1,500 feet in length, including the net's leaders, hedges, or wings; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A fish pot, fyke net, or connected line of fyke nets at a distance greater than one-fourth the distance across the bay, measured from the low water mark.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In the waters in the part of the Chesapeake Bay which lies between a straight line drawn from Drum Point Lighthouse in Calvert County to Hog Point in St. Mary's County, and a straight line drawn from Cove Point Lighthouse in Calvert County to Cedar Point Lighthouse in St. Mary's County, a person may not set any kind of net:<section prefix="(i)">Nearer than 500 yards in every direction from any other net;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Of a total length of more than 550 yards including the net's leaders, hedges, or wings; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">At a greater distance than one-fourth the distance across these waters measured from the low water mark on either side.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not set any pound net or stake net in the headwaters of the Chesapeake Bay, except those areas within 2,400 feet from the natural shoreline in Cecil County, the bay shore of Kent County up to Howell Point, and those areas within 2,400 feet from the shore on the west side of the bay from Pooles Island north to one-half mile north of Spesutie Island. For the purpose of this subsection the headwaters of the Chesapeake Bay are defined as the waters embraced in the area marked by the following line:</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not set an anchored gill net in the area of Chesapeake Bay bounded on the north by a line drawn from Turkey Point on the eastern shore to Sandy Point in Harford County, and on the south by a line drawn from Abbey Point to channel buoy Number 29, following the channel northward to buoy Number 1, off Grove Point, thence to Grove Point. This paragraph does not apply to the commercial fishing area within the Aberdeen Proving Grounds as specified by the Proving Ground.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not set or fish with any gill net within 1,200 feet of any pier that supports either span of the William Preston Lane, Jr. Memorial Bridge between May 1 and October 31, inclusive.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A person may not set or fish with any gill net in the Chesapeake Bay, excluding its tributaries, south of a line drawn from Howell Point to Taylor Island Point in the upper bay to a line drawn from Kent Point to Curtis Point in the mouth of West River between June 1 and October 31, inclusive.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
