<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-5-302</section_number>
  <catch_line>The General Assembly declares that it is in the general public interest of the State to foster and e...</catch_line>
  <order_by>302</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The General Assembly declares that it is in the general public interest of the State to foster and encourage the development, management, and protection of the nonindustrial private woodlands of the State as these lands provide:<section prefix="(1)">Significant environmental, aesthetic, and wildlife benefits; and</section><section prefix="(2)">For the production of timber and forest resources essential to commerce and industry in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The General Assembly finds that:<section prefix="(1)">The growing demands on woodlands and related land resources cannot be met by intensive management of public lands and industrial forests alone;</section><section prefix="(2)">Nonindustrial private woodlands of the State are a significant source of the production of timber and other forest resources; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Unless measures are instituted to encourage landowners to apply practices to ensure the development, management, and protection of nonindustrial private woodlands, this natural resource will not be sustained with a consequent detriment to the citizens of the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">It is the intention of the General Assembly to provide incentives to eligible landowners:<section prefix="(1)">To apply practices that provide for:<section prefix="(i)">Afforestation of suitable open lands;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Reforestation of cutover or other nonstocked or overstocked woodlands;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Timber stand improvement practices, including thinning, prescribed burning, and other silvicultural treatments; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Forest resources management and protection; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">To provide for the nonindustrial private woodland production of timber and other related forest resources.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
