<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-215</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>215</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Conservation and management measures" means 1 or more techniques through which the objectives of a fishery management plan are achieved.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Fishery" or "fishery resource" means:<section prefix="(i)">One or more stocks of fish which can be treated as a unit for purposes of conservation and management and which are identified on the basis of geographic, scientific, technical, recreational, and economic characteristics; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The group or industry harvesting those stocks.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Fishery management" means the system used to conserve and allocate the fishery resource, including research and data collection, determination of objectives and management measures, and establishment, enforcement, and periodic evaluation of regulations.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Fishery management plan" means a document or report that contains a systematic description of a given fishery and the objectives and conservation and management measures for the fishery.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department shall prepare fishery management plans for the following species:<section prefix="(1)">Striped bass or rockfish;</section><section prefix="(2)">White perch;</section><section prefix="(3)">Yellow perch;</section><section prefix="(4)">American shad;</section><section prefix="(5)">Hickory shad;</section><section prefix="(6)">Oysters;</section><section prefix="(7)">Blue crabs;</section><section prefix="(8)">Bluefish;</section><section prefix="(9)">Herring;</section><section prefix="(10)">Weakfish;</section><section prefix="(11)">Croaker;</section><section prefix="(12)">Spot;</section><section prefix="(13)">Summer flounder;</section><section prefix="(14)">American eel;</section><section prefix="(15)">Red drum;</section><section prefix="(16)">Black drum;</section><section prefix="(17)">Spotted sea trout;</section><section prefix="(18)">Horseshoe crabs;</section><section prefix="(19)">Menhaden;</section><section prefix="(20)">Tautog;</section><section prefix="(21)">Black sea bass;</section><section prefix="(22)">Scup;</section><section prefix="(23)">Hard shell clams; and</section><section prefix="(24)">Catfish.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department may prepare fishery management plans for any species of fish if, after consultation with the Tidal Fisheries Advisory Commission and the Sport Fisheries Advisory Commission, the Department determines that the plans are necessary based on:<section prefix="(1)">The population of the species;</section><section prefix="(2)">The distribution of the species;</section><section prefix="(3)">The habitat needs of the species; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Other biological, ecological, or socioeconomic factors concerning the species.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Conservation and management measures adopted under a fishery management plan, to the extent possible:<section prefix="(i)">Shall prevent overfishing while attempting to achieve the best and most efficient utilization of the State's fishery resources;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall be based on the best information available;</section><section prefix="(iii)">May not discriminate unfairly among groups of fishermen or have economic allocation as its sole purpose;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Shall take into account and allow for variations among, and contingencies in, fisheries, fishery resources, and catches; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Shall avoid duplication of regulatory efforts and unnecessary costs to the State and to any other person.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If it becomes necessary to allocate or assign fishing privileges among various groups of individuals under paragraph (1)(iii) of this subsection, or under any fishery management plan, that allocation shall be:<section prefix="(i)">Fair and equitable to all individuals;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Reasonably calculated to promote conservation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Carried out in such a manner that no particular individual, corporation, or other entity acquires an excessive share of such privileges.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a fishery management plan may apply separately or jointly to the waters of the Chesapeake Bay and its tidal tributaries, the coastal bays and their tributaries, and the Maryland waters of the Atlantic Ocean and shall include:<section prefix="(i)">The best available estimates of sustainable harvest rates;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Indicators that would trigger any tightening or loosening of harvest restrictions;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A description of the fishery, including:<section prefix="1.">The history of the fishery, and its current condition relative to historic populations;</section><section prefix="2.">The numbers of potential commercial and recreational fishermen projected to participate in the fishery;</section><section prefix="3.">The type and quantity of fishing gear used commercially;</section><section prefix="4.">Where practicable, the cost likely to be incurred in the management of the fishery; and</section><section prefix="5.">The actual and potential revenues from the recreational and commercial fishery;</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">If the Department determines that a fishery has been, or is currently, overfished:<section prefix="1.">A species-specific time period for:</section><section prefix="2.">A description of:</section></section><section prefix="(v)">Other pertinent data that will assist the Secretary in determining conservation and management measures reasonably necessary to ensure that the fishery resources will be sustained.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department may waive the requirements in paragraph (1)(iv) of this subsection for a species of fish if the Department determines that meeting the requirements is not practicable or biologically appropriate based on:<section prefix="(i)">The specific biology of the species;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The management of the species under a federal or multi-state fishery management plan;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The designation of the species as a nuisance;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Environmental conditions; or</section><section prefix="(v)">Other ecological factors.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A fishery management plan may include:<section prefix="(1)">Proposed limitations on the catch of fish, based on area, species, size, number, weight, sex, incidental catch, total biomass, or other factors, which are necessary and appropriate for conservation and management of a fishery;</section><section prefix="(2)">Incorporation of relevant fishery conservation and management measures proposed or adopted by interstate bodies of which Maryland is a member; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Other proposed measures, requirements, or conditions and restrictions which are necessary and appropriate for fishery management.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Department shall present the management plans under this section in the form of an annual report, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to:<section prefix="(1)">The Legislative Policy Committee;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Education, Health, and Environmental Affairs Committee; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The Environmental Matters Committee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Secretary shall adopt the proposed management plans and any proposed conservation and management measures by regulation.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Secretary may adopt conservation and management measures in separate proceedings and by separate regulations. Conservation and management measures adopted separately may include changes to those proposed or adopted in a fishery management plan and any additional measures necessary to carry out the adopted plan.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Secretary may not prohibit the use of pound net sites in the coastal bays that are registered with the Department as of January 1, 2000.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The regulations of the Department to implement a fisheries management plan for the coastal bays may not become effective under this section until the Department first holds public hearings in Worcester County.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">All notices of public hearings required for the adoption of regulations under this section shall be printed in the Maryland Register and further publicized so as to provide reasonable notice to the affected communities of fishermen and the public.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, except &#xA7; 4-1002 of this title, once a fishery management plan has been adopted by regulation, the State's fishery resources shall be harvested in accordance with the conservation and management measures in the fishery management plan and any regulations implementing or amending that plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The provisions of this section do not apply to aquaculture activities in nontidal ponds, lakes, or impoundments in the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
