<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-1901" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-5-1901</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Fund" means the Calvert County Youth Recreational Opportunities Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Calvert County Youth Recreational Opportunities Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The purpose of the Fund is to increase youth recreational opportunities in Calvert County.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary shall administer the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Treasurer shall hold the Fund separately, and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">Revenue distributed to the Fund under &#xA7; 2-202(b)(1)(ii) of the Tax - General Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">Money appropriated in the State budget to the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Any other money from any other source accepted for the benefit of the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Fund may be used only for projects that are approved by the Secretary to advance youth recreational opportunities in Calvert County and that receive contributions from the county for the projects.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Treasurer shall invest the money of the Fund in the same manner as other State money may be invested.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any investment earnings of the Fund shall be credited to the General Fund of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Expenditures from the Fund may be made only in accordance with the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">Money expended from the Fund for youth recreational opportunities in Calvert County is supplemental to and is not intended to take the place of funding that otherwise would be appropriated for youth recreational opportunities in Calvert County.</section>
  </text>
</law>
