<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-723</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>723</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Fund" means the State Boat Act Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a State Boat Act Fund in the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary shall administer the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Treasurer shall hold the Fund separately and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Fund shall be invested and reinvested in the same manner as other State funds.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Unless otherwise provided, the Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">Moneys received from any fee and other revenue the Department collects under authority of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Moneys appropriated in the State budget to the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Any moneys received and accepted as gifts, contributions, or grants.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department shall use the Fund:<section prefix="(1)">For the administration of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">To cover the costs of fulfilling the duties and responsibilities of the Department under this title; and</section><section prefix="(3)">For administrative costs calculated in accordance with &#xA7; 1-103(b)(2) of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Any investment earnings of the Fund shall be credited to the General Fund of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Within the limits of funds available, the Department may enter into any agreement with the federal government, any municipality or other political subdivision of the State, or any private agency to share the cost of any development, construction, or improvement of waterways or of facilities determined to have beneficial value to the boating public.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Expenditures from the Fund may be made only in accordance with the State budget.</section>
  </text>
</law>
