<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-210.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "permit" means a Maryland Provisional Chesapeake Bay Charter Boat Permit....</catch_line>
  <order_by>210.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "permit" means a Maryland Provisional Chesapeake Bay Charter Boat Permit.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department shall establish a Maryland Provisional Chesapeake Bay Charter Boat Permit.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department may issue a permit if the person:<section prefix="(1)">Is licensed by Virginia to operate a charter boat in its jurisdictional tidal waters; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Provides the Department with documentation of fishing activity for 2001 and 2002 based upon licensing and reporting requirements of the Virginia Marine Resources Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A permit issued by the Department:<section prefix="(1)">Is valid only for an authorized person operating a vessel for charter fishing trips originating from the tidal waters of Virginia; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is nontransferable.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person in possession of a permit is not required to possess a Maryland commercial fishing guide license under &#xA7; 4-210 of this subtitle to operate a charter boat in tidal waters of the Chesapeake Bay in Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person operating a charter boat under the provisions of this section shall have all appropriate federal and State licenses and the required permit in possession whenever operating a charter boat.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The holder of a permit issued under this section is subject to the penalties under Subtitle 12 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Department may adopt regulations necessary to implement this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
