<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-3-3A-02</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Director of the Power Plant Siting and Research Program shall be responsible for the direction a...</catch_line>
  <order_by>02</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Director of the Power Plant Siting and Research Program shall be responsible for the direction and coordination of the activities required under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To the extent funds are provided in the State budget, the departments, in cooperation with the participating agencies, shall conduct a comprehensive evaluation of:<section prefix="(i)">The sources of acid deposition received in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The impact of acid deposition on the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any available effective methods to alleviate any significant adverse impact on the State; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The costs of the available effective methods to alleviate any significant adverse impact on the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The departments shall utilize the results of studies conducted by other organizations where applicable and shall conduct independent research and monitoring studies where necessary.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The departments, in cooperation with the participating agencies, shall consult with and involve interested parties, including affected private sector industries and resource conservationists, in the comprehensive evaluation in subsection (b)(1) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The interested parties shall participate in the planning of the research program and monitoring activities, the design of specific projects, the review of the results of studies, and the production of final reports.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
