<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-5-1603</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1603</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A unit of local government having planning and zoning authority shall develop a local forest conservation program, consistent with the intent, requirements, and standards of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">By April 30, 1992 all units of government with planning and zoning authority shall submit a proposed forest conservation program, which meets or is more stringent than the requirements and standards of this subtitle, to the Department for its review and approval.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A unit of local government which has an existing program of forest conservation, or subsequently adopts such a program prior to December 31, 1992, may continue to administer its program prior to approval by the Department of the local forest conservation program.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A municipality which has planning and zoning authority may, with the concurrence of the county and the Department, assign its obligations under this subtitle to the county.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By July 1, 1992 the Department shall either approve a proposed local forest conservation program as submitted by the local authority or provide a written notice of program elements needing revision.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Local forest conservation programs requiring revisions shall be resubmitted to the Department within 2 months of the date the Department notified the local authority of the need for revisions.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">All units of local government with planning and zoning authority shall submit to the Department, by December 31, 1992, their adopted forest conservation program which meets or is more stringent than the requirements and standards of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A local forest conservation program, which has been approved by the Department, shall include:<section prefix="(i)">A policy document and all applicable new and amended local ordinances relating to implementation of the regulated activities, exemptions, the review, approval and appeal processes, incentives, legal instruments for protection, enforcement program, and penalties; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A technical manual which outlines submittal requirements for forest stand delineations, required information for the approval of a forest conservation plan, specific forest conservation criteria and protection techniques.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A local authority shall review and amend, as appropriate, all current local ordinances, policies and procedures that are inconsistent with the intent and requirements of this subtitle such as parking, road width, setback, curb and gutter, grading, and sidewalk requirements.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A local forest conservation program, when approved by the Department, may allow clustering and other innovative land use techniques that protect and establish forests where open space is preserved, sensitive areas are protected, and development is physically concentrated.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Failure to submit a proposed local forest conservation program under subsection (a) of this section or failure to adopt a program approved by the Department prior to December 31, 1992 under subsection (b) of this section shall result in the Department's assumption of review and approval of all forest conservation plans within the jurisdiction of that local authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Department shall conduct a review of each local authority's program at least once every 2 years from the date of initial departmental approval.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In its biennial review, the Department shall evaluate the level of compliance with the performance standards and required forest conservation.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a local authority's program is found to be deficient by the Department, then the Department shall give notice and allow the local authority 90 days for compliance, after which the Department may assume review and approval of all forest conservation plans within the jurisdiction of the local authority until the deficiencies are corrected.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">After December 31, 1992, the Public Service Commission shall give due consideration to the need to minimize the loss of forest and the provisions for afforestation and reforestation set forth in this subtitle together with all applicable electrical safety codes, when reviewing applications for a certificate of public convenience and necessity issued pursuant to &#xA7; 7-204, &#xA7; 7-205, &#xA7; 7-207, or &#xA7; 7-208 of the Public Utilities Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A local authority or the Department in its administration of a State forest conservation program in jurisdictions which do not have an approved local program in effect may establish reasonable and appropriate procedures for the recovery of all costs incurred in the development, implementation, administration, and enforcement of the local forest conservation program or the State forest conservation program for jurisdictions without an approved forest conservation program.</section>
  </text>
</law>
