<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-4A-01" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-4A-01</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>The Governor is hereby authorized and directed to execute a Compact on behalf of the State of Maryland with the State of West Virginia, with participation through concurrence by the United States Army Corps of Engineers legally joining in the form substantially as follows:<section prefix=""><section prefix="1.">The Congress, under Public Law 87-874, authorized the development of the Jennings Randolph Lake Project for the North Branch of the Potomac River substantially in accordance with House Document Number 469, 87th Congress, 2nd Session for flood control, water supply, water quality, and recreation; and</section><section prefix="2.">Section 4 of the Flood Control Act of 1944 (CH 665, 58 Stat. 534) provides that the Chief of Engineers, under the supervision of the Secretary of War (now Secretary of the Army), is authorized to construct, maintain and operate public park and recreational facilities in reservoir areas under control of such Secretary for the purpose of boating, swimming, bathing, fishing, and other recreational purposes, so long as the same is not inconsistent with the laws for the protection of fish and wildlife of the State(s) in which such area is situated; and</section><section prefix="3.">Pursuant to the authorities cited above, the U.S. Army Engineer District (Baltimore), hereinafter "District", did construct and now maintains and operates the Jennings Randolph Lake Project; and</section><section prefix="4.">The National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (P.L. 91-190) encourages productive and enjoyable harmony between man and his environment, promotes efforts which will stimulate the health and welfare of man, and encourages cooperation with State and local governments to achieve these ends; and</section><section prefix="5.">The Fish and Wildlife Coordination Act (16 U.S.C. 661-666c) provides for the consideration and coordination with other features of water-resource development programs through the effectual and harmonious planning, development, maintenance, and coordination of wildlife conservation and rehabilitation; and</section><section prefix="6.">The District has Fisheries and Wildlife Plans as part of the District's project Operational Plan Management; and</section><section prefix="7.">In the respective States, the Maryland Department of Natural Resources (hereinafter referred to as Maryland DNR) and the West Virginia Division of Natural Resources (hereinafter referred to as West Virginia DNR) are primarily responsible for providing a system of control, propagation, management, protection, and regulation of natural resources, criminal activities, and boating in Maryland and West Virginia and the enforcement of laws and regulations pertaining to those resources as provided in Annotated Code of Maryland Natural Resources Article and West Virginia Chapter 20, respectively, and the successors thereof; and</section><section prefix="8.">The District, the Maryland DNR, and the West Virginia DNR are desirous of conserving, perpetuating and improving fish and wildlife resources and recreational benefits of the Jennings Randolph Lake Project; and</section><section prefix="9.">The District and the States of Maryland and West Virginia wish to implement the aforesaid acts and responsibilities through this Compact and they each recognize that consistent enforcement of the natural resources, criminal, and boating laws and regulations can best be achieved by entering this Compact;</section><section prefix="1.1">This compact shall be known and may be cited as the Jennings Randolph Lake Project Compact.</section><section prefix="1.2">The legislative bodies of the respective signatory parties, with the concurrence of the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, hereby find and declare:</section><section prefix="1.">The water resources and project lands of the Jennings Randolph Lake Project are affected with local, state, regional, and national interest, and the planning, conservation, utilization, protection and management of these resources, under appropriate arrangements for inter-governmental cooperation, are public purposes of the respective signatory parties.</section><section prefix="2.">The lands and waters of the Jennings Randolph Lake Project are subject to the sovereign rights and responsibilities of the signatory parties, and it is the purpose of this compact that, notwithstanding any boundary between Maryland and West Virginia that preexisted the creation of Jennings Randolph Lake, the parties will have and exercise concurrent jurisdiction over any lands and waters of the Jennings Randolph Lake Project concerning natural resources, criminal, and boating laws and regulations in the common interest of the people of the region.</section><section prefix="2.1">Acknowledges that the Maryland DNR and West Virginia DNR have authorities and responsibilities in the establishment, administration and enforcement of the natural resources, criminal, and boating laws and regulations applicable to this project, provided that the laws and regulations promulgated by the States support and implement, where applicable, the intent of the Rules and Regulations Governing Public Use of Water Resources Development Projects administered by the Chief of Engineers in Title 36, Chapter III, Part 327, Code of Federal Regulations,</section><section prefix="2.2">Agrees to practice those forms of resource management as determined jointly by the District, Maryland DNR and West Virginia DNR to be beneficial to natural resources and which will enhance public recreational opportunities compatible with other authorized purposes of the project,</section><section prefix="2.3">Agrees to consult with the Maryland DNR and West Virginia DNR prior to the issuance of any permits for activities or special events which would include, but not necessarily be limited to: fishing tournaments, training exercises, regattas, marine parades, placement of ski ramps, slalom water ski courses and the establishment of private markers and/or lighting. All such permits issued by the District will require the permittee to comply with all State laws and regulations,</section><section prefix="2.4">Agrees to consult with the Maryland DNR and West Virginia DNR regarding any recommendations for regulations affecting natural resources including, but not limited to, hunting, trapping, fishing or boating at the Jennings Randolph Lake Project which the District believes might be desirable for reasons of public safety, administration, or public use and enjoyment,</section><section prefix="2.5">Agrees to consult with the Maryland DNR and West Virginia DNR relative to the marking of the lake with buoys, aids to navigation, regulatory markers and establishing and posting of speed limits, no wake zones, restricted or other control areas and to provide, install and maintain such buoys, aids to navigation and regulatory markers as are necessary for the implementation of the District's Operational Management Plan. All buoys, aids to navigation and regulatory markers to be used shall be marked in conformance with the Uniform State Waterway Marking System,</section><section prefix="2.6">Agrees to allow hunting, trapping, boating and fishing by the public in accordance with the laws and regulations relating to the Jennings Randolph Lake Project,</section><section prefix="2.7">Agrees to provide, install and maintain public ramps, parking areas, courtesy docks, etc., as provided for by the approved Corps of Engineers Master Plan, and</section><section prefix="2.8">Agrees to notify the Maryland DNR and the West Virginia DNR of each reservoir drawdown prior thereto excepting drawdown for the reestablishment of normal lake levels following flood control operations and drawdown resulting from routine water control management operations described in the reservoir regulation manual including releases requested by water supply owners and normal water quality releases. In case of emergency releases or emergency flow curtailments, telephone or oral notification will be provided. The District reserves the right, following issuance of the above notice, to make operational and other tests which may be necessary to insure the safe and efficient operation of the dam, for inspection and maintenance purposes, and for the gathering of water quality data both within the impoundment and in the Potomac River downstream from the dam.</section><section prefix="3.1">That each State will have and exercise concurrent jurisdiction with the District and the other State for the purpose of enforcing the civil and criminal laws of the respective States pertaining to natural resources and boating laws and regulations, and criminal activities over any lands and waters of the Jennings Randolph Lake Project;</section><section prefix="3.2">That existing natural resources, criminal, and boating laws and regulations already in effect in each State shall remain in force on the Jennings Randolph Lake Project until either State amends, modifies or rescinds its laws and regulations;</section><section prefix="3.3">That the Agreement for Fishing Privileges dated June 24, 1985 between the State of Maryland and the State of West Virginia, as amended, remains in full force and effect;</section><section prefix="3.4">To enforce the natural resources, criminal, and boating laws and regulations applicable to the Jennings Randolph Lake Project;</section><section prefix="3.5">To supply the District with the name, address and telephone number of the person(s) to be contacted when any drawdown except those resulting from normal regulation procedures occurs;</section><section prefix="3.6">To inform the Reservoir Manager of all emergencies or unusual activities occurring on the Jennings Randolph Lake Project;</section><section prefix="3.7">To provide training to District employees in order to familiarize them with natural resources, criminal, and boating laws and regulations as they apply to the Jennings Randolph Lake Project; and</section><section prefix="3.8">To recognize that the District and other Federal Agencies have the right and responsibility to enforce, within the boundaries of the Jennings Randolph Lake Project, all applicable Federal laws, rules and regulations so as to provide the public with safe and healthful recreational opportunities and to provide protection to all federal property within the project.</section><section prefix="4.1">Pursuant to the aims and purposes of this Compact, the State of Maryland, the State of West Virginia and the District mutually agree that representatives of their natural resource management and enforcement agencies will cooperate to further the purposes of this Compact. This cooperation includes, but is not limited to, the following:</section><section prefix="4.2">Meeting jointly at least once annually, and providing for other meetings as deemed necessary for discussion of matters relating to the management of natural resources and visitor use on lands and waters within the Jennings Randolph Lake Project;</section><section prefix="4.3">Evaluating natural resources and boating, to develop natural resource and boating management plans and to initiate and carry out management programs;</section><section prefix="4.4">Encouraging the dissemination of joint publications, press releases or other public information and the interchange between parties of all pertinent agency policies and objectives for the use and perpetuation of natural resources of Jennings Randolph Lake Project; and</section><section prefix="4.5">Entering into working arrangements as occasion demands for the use of lands, waters, construction and use of buildings and other facilities at the project.</section><section prefix="5.1">Each and every provision of this Compact is subject to the laws of the States of Maryland and West Virginia and the laws of the United States, and the delegated authority in each instance.</section><section prefix="5.2">The enforcement and applicability of natural resources, criminal, and boating laws and regulations referenced in this Compact shall be limited to the lands and waters of the Jennings Randolph Lake Project, including but not limited to the prevailing reciprocal fishing laws and regulations between the States of Maryland and West Virginia.</section><section prefix="5.3">Nothing in this Compact shall be construed as obligating any party hereto to the expenditure of funds or the future payment of money in excess of appropriations authorized by law.</section><section prefix="5.4">The provisions of this Compact shall be severable, and if any phrase, clause, sentence or provision of the Jennings Randolph Lake Project Compact is declared to be unconstitutional or inapplicable to any signatory party or agency of any party, the constitutionality and applicability of the Compact shall not be otherwise affected as to any other provision, party, or agency. It is the legislative intent that the provisions of this Compact be reasonably and liberally construed to effectuate the stated purposes of the Compact.</section><section prefix="5.5">No member of or delegate to Congress, or signatory shall be admitted to any share or part of this Compact, or to any benefit that may arise therefrom; but this provision shall not be construed to extend to this agreement if made with a corporation for its general benefit.</section><section prefix="5.6">When this Compact has been ratified by the legislature of each respective State, when the Governor of West Virginia and the Governor of Maryland have executed this Compact on behalf of their respective States and have caused a verified copy thereof to be filed with the Secretary of State of each respective State, when the Baltimore District Engineer of the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers has executed its concurrence with this Compact, and when this Compact has been consented to by the Congress of the United States, then this Compact shall become operative and effective.</section><section prefix="5.7">Either State may, by legislative act, after one year's written notice to the other, withdraw from this Compact. The U.S. Army Corps of Engineers may withdraw its concurrence with this Compact upon one year's written notice from the Baltimore District Engineer to the Governor of each State.</section><section prefix="5.8">This Compact may be amended from time to time.</section></section></text>
</law>
