<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-2A-04</section_number>
  <catch_line>The BayStat Program shall direct the administration of the Trust Fund in accordance with this sectio...</catch_line>
  <order_by>04</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The BayStat Program shall direct the administration of the Trust Fund in accordance with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The BayStat Program shall implement nonpoint source pollution reduction measures to achieve the tributary strategies by targeting funds, geographically and by practice, to proven, scientifically based projects that provide the most cost-effective and measurable water quality benefits to the Chesapeake and Atlantic Coastal Bays.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To the maximum extent practicable, the BayStat Program shall distribute the Trust Fund moneys on a competitive basis.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The BayStat Program shall distribute funds from the Trust Fund to the BayStat Subcabinet agencies in accordance with the final work and expenditure plans.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The BayStat Subcabinet agencies shall administer the funds in accordance with the final work and expenditure plans, including the distribution of funds:<section prefix="(i)">Through grants to:<section prefix="1.">Counties;</section><section prefix="2.">Bicounty agencies;</section><section prefix="3.">Municipalities;</section><section prefix="4.">Forest conservancy district boards;</section><section prefix="5.">Soil conservation districts;</section><section prefix="6.">Academic institutions; and</section><section prefix="7.">Nonprofit organizations having a demonstrated ability to implement nonpoint source pollution control projects;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">To the Chesapeake and Atlantic Coastal Bays Nonpoint Source Fund established under &#xA7; 9-1605.3 of the Environment Article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">To the Maryland Agricultural Cost-Share Program established under Title 8, Subtitle 7 of the Agriculture Article for nonpoint source pollution control projects; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">To the Mel Noland Woodland Incentives Fund established under &#xA7; 5-307 of this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The BayStat Program shall develop solicitations, guidelines, and applications for Trust Fund grants that shall include consideration of the extent to which a proposed project, both geographically and by practice, will deliver the greatest, most cost-effective, and measurable nonpoint source pollution reduction per Trust Fund dollar.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The BayStat Program shall encourage and consider multi-year, multi-partner proposals, local match or cost-share agreements, or similar actions proposed by a grant applicant in evaluating a Trust Fund grant application.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Any grant agreement regarding funds from the Trust Fund shall:<section prefix="(1)">Specify the use of the funds provided under the grant, accountability measures, and performance requirements;</section><section prefix="(2)">Take into account the need for efficient, multi-year funding and administration; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Include provisions for verification that practices are being implemented.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A recipient of funds from the Trust Fund in any fiscal year shall submit an annual report to the BayStat Program by November 1 of the next fiscal year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The report required under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall include:<section prefix="(i)">For agencies receiving moneys from the Trust Fund:<section prefix="1.">A description of how the funds were allocated, including:</section><section prefix="2.">How funding was leveraged; and</section><section prefix="3.">Estimated or calculated nutrient reductions associated with Trust Fund expenditures.</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">For recipients of competitive grants from the Trust Fund, a description of funded projects, including:<section prefix="1.">Project location;</section><section prefix="2.">Description of practices implemented;</section><section prefix="3.">Timeframes for project completion;</section><section prefix="4.">Estimated or calculated nutrient reductions; and</section><section prefix="5.">Provisions for long-term maintenance of practices.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Funds from the Trust Fund may not be used to enable an individual cited for noncompliance with a nonpoint source pollution control law or regulation to achieve compliance.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a BayStat Program Scientific Advisory Panel.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Governor shall appoint the chair and members of the BayStat Program Scientific Advisory Panel.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The BayStat Program Scientific Advisory Panel shall include scientists and other technical experts with demonstrated expertise in the disciplines related to protection and restoration of the Chesapeake and Atlantic Coastal Bays.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The BayStat Program Scientific Advisory Panel shall:<section prefix="(i)">On or before August 1, annually provide recommendations to the BayStat Subcabinet on the use of funds of the Trust Fund for the following fiscal year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Monitor the distribution of funds from the Trust Fund;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Review the categories of grants made in the previous year to assess nutrient loading reduction estimates and cost efficiencies and the effectiveness of any innovative nonpoint source pollution reduction measure;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Review the proposed annual work plan and advise the BayStat Subcabinet of any recommended changes;</section><section prefix="(v)">On request by the BayStat Subcabinet, review individual grant applications; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Annually review any Trust Fund moneys that are not distributed on a competitive basis to assess whether those moneys may be distributed on a competitive basis.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The BayStat Subcabinet agencies may distribute to an administrative cost account the amount that is necessary to administer grant programs, not to exceed 1.5% of the allocations to the BayStat Subcabinet agencies.</section>
  </text>
</law>
