<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-206</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Department shall audit the books of any person who packs or deals in fish resources within the j...</catch_line>
  <order_by>206</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department shall audit the books of any person who packs or deals in fish resources within the jurisdiction of the Department including anyone who catches and ships directly to market. The Department audit shall be conducted to determine the quantity of resources caught and any other data needed for reporting and accounting to State officials.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Every person engaged in the business of packing or dealing in any fish resource within the Department's jurisdiction shall keep accurate books, statements, and accounts showing every detail of the business. Every book, statement, and account shall be open for the Department to inspect at reasonable hours. Every person engaged in the business of packing or dealing in any fish resource within the Department's jurisdiction shall make any report the Department requires on forms the Department prescribes.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Every person the Department licenses to catch the fish resource shall make any report the Department requires on forms the Department provides.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An officer or employee of any department or unit of the Executive Branch of State government may not divulge or use in any manner information contained in any report submitted pursuant to the provisions of this section that would reveal the income of any person submitting the report. This section does not prohibit the publication of statistics classified to prevent the identification of particular reports and items of them or prohibit inspection of reports and records by any official or employee of the Executive Branch having a proper interest in them.</section>
  </text>
</law>
