<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-710</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>710</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A manufacturer or dealer may not conduct his business in the State unless licensed as a manufacturer or dealer pursuant to regulations the Department adopts.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An out-of-state or foreign manufacturer or dealer shall be exempted from licensing solely for purposes of displaying and selling vessels at a boat show, boat exposition, or outdoor recreation show if the show or exposition is 14 consecutive days or less duration, admission taxes are paid on charges for admission to the show or exposition, and the manufacturer or dealer does not principally own, control, or manage the show or exposition.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Application for a manufacturer's or dealer's license is made on the form the Department prescribes and contains the name and address of the applicant. If the applicant is a partnership, the application shall include the name and address of each partner. If the applicant is a corporation, the application shall contain the names of the principal officers of the corporation, the state of incorporation, the addresses of every place where the business is conducted, the nature of the business, and any other information the Department requires. Every application shall be verified by oath or affirmation of the applicant if an individual, or by the partner or officer if the applicant is a partnership or corporation. A license fee fixed by the Department not to exceed $25 shall accompany every application.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">After receiving the required application and fee, the Department issues a license certificate to the applicant which entitles him to conduct business as a manufacturer or dealer during the calendar year in which the license is issued. Every license expires on December 31 of each year in which issued. The license may be renewed upon annual application and payment of the required fee.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department may refuse to issue a license or, after written notice to the licensee and a hearing, may cancel a license when the Department determines that the applicant or licensee has failed to comply with the provisions of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On petition of the Consumer Protection Division of the Office of the Attorney General, and after written notice to a licensee and a hearing, the Department may revoke or suspend the license of a dealer if the Department determines that the licensee has violated &#xA7; 13-301 or &#xA7; 13-303 of the Commercial Law Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If, during the period for which a dealer's or manufacturer's license is issued, there is any change in the factual information furnished to the Department by the licensee in connection with obtaining or retaining the license or a renewal of the license, the change shall be truly, fully, and promptly communicated to the Department in writing on forms provided by the Department. The applicant shall sign the form and certify that the information given is true and correct.</section>
  </text>
</law>
