<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Tidal Fisheries Advisory Commission in the Department....</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Tidal Fisheries Advisory Commission in the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission is composed of up to 15 members appointed and serving in accordance with the procedures adopted under &#xA7; 1-102(c) of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Up to 14 commercial watermen and one member of the Sport Fisheries Advisory Commission shall comprise the Commission.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The composition of the Commission shall reflect the geographic regions of the State where the commercial fishing industry is operating.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The term of a member is 2 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The terms of members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Commission on July 1, 2010.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Sport Fisheries Advisory Commission in the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall provide the Department advice on recreational fisheries matters.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission is composed of 15 members appointed and serving in accordance with the provisions of &#xA7; 1-102(c) of this article. The experience and backgrounds of Commission members shall represent the diversified angling interests and waters of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The term of a member is 4 years and a member may be reappointed.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The terms of members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Commission on July 1, 2010.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is an Oyster Advisory Commission in the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission consists of members appointed by the Secretary.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">Provide the Department with advice on matters related to oysters in the Chesapeake Bay;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Review the best possible science and recommend changes to the framework and strategies for rebuilding and managing the oyster population in the Chesapeake Bay under the Chesapeake Bay Oyster Management Plan;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Review the latest findings relevant to the Environmental Impact Statement evaluating oyster restoration alternatives for the Chesapeake Bay;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Review any other scientific, economic, or cultural information relevant to oysters in the Chesapeake Bay; and</section><section prefix="(v)">By December 31, 2007 and to the extent reasonably appropriate, report to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly on:<section prefix="1.">Strategies to minimize the impact of oyster disease, including the State repletion program and bar cleaning;</section><section prefix="2.">The framework and effectiveness of the oyster sanctuary, harvest reserve, and repletion programs, and the overall management of natural oyster bars, after performing a cost-benefit analysis that considers biological, ecological, economic, and cultural issues;</section><section prefix="3.">Strategies to maximize the ecological benefits of natural oyster bars; and</section><section prefix="4.">Strategies to improve enforcement of closed oyster areas.</section></section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
