<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-3-105</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Service is responsible for carrying out the following general activities subject to the limitati...</catch_line>
  <order_by>105</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Service is responsible for carrying out the following general activities subject to the limitations stated in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Planning, integrating, and establishing geographic service regions and districts, in cooperation with affected municipalities and based upon approved State-county master plans for water and sewerage, and solid waste disposal as provided in the Environment Article, as well as other plans and studies permitted by this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Research and developmental studies and investigations into improved methods and techniques of water supply, liquid wastes, solid wastes, and energy generation, acquisition, transportation, processing, recycling, purification, disposal and management, and technical consultation and assistance to design, management, and operation personnel of the Service and, pursuant to an order or request, to appropriate municipalities or persons possessing similar responsibilities.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">To the extent appropriate in each instance, acquisition, design, construction, reconstruction, rehabilitation, improvement, operation, maintenance, and repair of a water supply project, wastewater purification project, and solid waste disposal project, pursuant to an order of the Secretary of the Environment as further provided in &#xA7;&#xA7; 3-109 and 3-110 of this subtitle; or pursuant to a mandatory agreement to provide requested services, as provided in &#xA7; 3-107 of this subtitle; or pursuant to an approved five-year plan, as provided in &#xA7; 3-106 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except upon request of a municipality and pursuant to a contract between the Service and the municipality, the Service may not acquire, construct, operate, or establish a wastewater purification project or solid waste disposal project, as the case may be, for (1) any area or district which, in the determination of the Secretary of the Environment, is receiving adequate service from a project owned by a municipality and operated in compliance with applicable laws and regulations; (2) any area or district which, in the determination of that Secretary, will receive, within a reasonable time, adequate service from a project owned by a municipality and operated in compliance with applicable laws and regulations; or (3) dredging or dredged material disposal projects.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Execute the powers and perform the duties set forth in Title 7, Subtitle 4 of the Environment Article, including the financing, acquisition, leasing, and operation of hazardous waste disposal facilities.</section>
  </text>
</law>
