<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-10-415</section_number>
  <catch_line>There are the following 3 seasons to hunt deer:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>415</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There are the following 3 seasons to hunt deer:<section prefix="(1)">Deer bow hunting season;</section><section prefix="(2)">Deer firearms season; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Deer muzzle loader season.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Every person killing a deer shall report with the deer to a designated checking station within 24 hours after killing the deer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding any requirement of law, if the designated checking stations are closed in the county where a person kills a deer, a Natural Resources police officer shall authorize the person to report with the deer to a designated checking station in another county.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person with a hunting license also may purchase bonus deer stamps from the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A bonus deer stamp allows a person with the hunting license to hunt 1 deer for each stamp purchased in any of the following hunting seasons for deer in the State:<section prefix="(i)">Deer bow hunting season;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Deer muzzle loader season; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Deer firearms season.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An individual who purchases a bonus antlered deer stamp but does not use it during a particular season may use that stamp during any subsequent season in that hunting license year.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The fee for each bonus antlered deer stamp issued in accordance with this subsection shall be $10.00 for residents and $25.00 for nonresidents.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Department may establish by regulation the type and number of deer stamps issued under this subsection if necessary to control the deer harvest in various areas of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Repealed.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person may not remove the head or hide or any part from any deer, except internal organs, or cut the meat into parts until the deer has been checked by the Department or 1 of the Department's agents at a designated checking station. Removal of the head or the hide of any deer not checked at a designated checking station shall be prima facie evidence that the deer was hunted illegally. Each separate deer or part of any deer taken illegally or found in possession shall be considered a separate offense.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Any person who, while operating a motor vehicle on any highway in the State, accidentally strikes and kills a deer on the highway may have the deer if the person produces visible evidence of collision with the deer to any Natural Resources police officer, State law enforcement officer, or other designated representative of the Secretary. The provisions of this subsection shall be applicable to deer killed by collision with a motor vehicle at any time whether during the open season for killing deer or during the legally closed season.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A person may not hunt a deer while the deer is taking refuge in or swimming through the waters of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Abrogated.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Upon written request from a federal facility for a variance from the established deer hunting season, the Department shall review the request and may:<section prefix="(1)">Approve the request;</section><section prefix="(2)">Deny the request; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Approve the request with conditions.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
