<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-208" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-208</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Fund" means the State Fisheries Management and Protection Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a State Fisheries Management and Protection Fund in the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The purpose of the Fund is to finance the scientific investigation, protection, propagation, and management of nontidal finfish.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department shall administer the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Treasurer shall hold the Fund separately and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">Any money received for a fish and fisheries license, stamp, permit, or application fee under this title, unless otherwise provided;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any investment earnings of the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Money appropriated from the General Fund of the State in accordance with subsection (j) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Fund may be used only for:<section prefix="(1)">The scientific investigation, protection, propagation, and management of nontidal finfish; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Administrative costs calculated in accordance with &#xA7; 1-103(b)(2) of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Treasurer shall invest the money of the Fund in the same manner as other State money may be invested.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any investment earnings of the Fund may not be transferred or revert to the General Fund of the State, but shall remain in the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Expenditures from the Fund may be made only in accordance with the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">Beginning with fiscal year 2009 and each fiscal year thereafter, the Governor may include in the budget bill an appropriation from the General Fund for the Fund.</section>
  </text>
</law>
