<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-406" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-10-406</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except during the hunting and trapping season or as allowed under subsection (b) of this section, a person may not hunt or trap any fur-bearing mammal or possess the meat or pelt of any fur-bearing mammal, whether hunted or trapped within the State or any other state, territory, or country.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A person may possess any green pelt of any fur-bearing mammal until March 25 for purposes of curing the skins.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">However, in Frederick, Garrett, Allegany, Carroll, Howard, and Washington counties, a person may hunt or trap mink or muskrat between November 15 and February 15, of the year following, and a person may possess any green mink and muskrat pelt until February 25 for purposes of curing the skin.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The Department may extend any muskrat season set by this subsection for a period of 1 week, if the Department considers it necessary for any reason, including weather conditions.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may possess the meat of muskrat or otter no more than 10 days after the close of open season for these mammals in order to dispose of the meat for food. However, a person may apply for a permit to store the meat during the closed season if the meat was hunted lawfully.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A muskrat damaging any embankment or impoundment may be destroyed by the owner at any time.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A person may hunt or trap and possess the pelt or meat of raccoon or opossum during those periods and under the restrictions, including bag limits, the Department may establish by regulation.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In Charles and Dorchester counties, a person may hunt or trap a fox or possess the pelt of a fox at any time of year.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A person may hunt or trap on the person's land a coyote, fox or skunk that is damaging or destroying the personal or real property of the landowner.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">A person may:<section prefix="(i)">Trap a coyote during the trapping season established by the Department; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Hunt a coyote:</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
