<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-709" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-709</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department shall include in its annual budget request an itemized list of requests for the use of any available money from the Waterway Improvement Fund for the projects under &#xA7; 8-707 of this subtitle. The Department's list shall include a brief description of each project, an estimate of its cost, and the benefits to be derived from it. The list shall designate which projects are financed solely by the Waterway Improvement Fund, which are matching fund projects, and which are interest-free loan projects.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, in any fiscal year the Department may expend from the Waterway Improvement Fund without legislative approval a total sum of not more than $225,000. Of this amount, a sum of not more than $125,000 may be expended for small projects under &#xA7; 8-707(a)(3) and (4) of this subtitle, subject to the limitation that a single project of this kind may not exceed $5,000 in cost to the Waterway Improvement Fund, and a sum of not more than $100,000 may be expended for boating safety and education.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, the Department may propose an appropriation from the Waterway Improvement Fund to support marine operations of the Natural Resources Police not exceeding:<section prefix="(1)">$1,700,000 in the Department's fiscal year 2006 budget; and</section><section prefix="(2)">$2,000,000 in the Department's fiscal year 2007 budget, and every year thereafter.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">For fiscal year 2006 through fiscal year 2009, as provided in the State budget, the Department may use up to the following percentage of the moneys in the Waterway Improvement Fund for administrative expenses directly relating to implementing the purposes of the Waterway Improvement Fund:<section prefix="(i)">In fiscal year 2006, 8%;</section><section prefix="(ii)">In fiscal year 2007, 6%;</section><section prefix="(iii)">In fiscal year 2008, 4%; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">In fiscal year 2009, 2%; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">For fiscal years after fiscal year 2009, the Department may use up to $750,000 in the Waterway Improvement Fund for administrative expenses directly relating to implementing the purposes of the Waterway Improvement Fund.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
