<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-1915</section_number>
  <catch_line>The purpose of the Corps Board is to advise the Trust in the development and implementation of the C...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1915</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The purpose of the Corps Board is to advise the Trust in the development and implementation of the Corps Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Corps Board consists of the following 11 members:<section prefix="(i)">One member of the Senate of Maryland, appointed by the President of the Senate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">One member of the House of Delegates, appointed by the Speaker of the House;</section><section prefix="(iii)">One member appointed by the Chancellor of the University System of Maryland with the advice and consent of the Senate, to serve as a liaison between the Corps Board, the Chancellor, and the Board of Regents;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Three members of the Board of Trustees of the Chesapeake Bay Trust, appointed by the Chair of the Board; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Five members appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate, including at least one individual from the not-for-profit sector with a background in education and student service and one with a background in workforce development.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a regulated lobbyist is appointed to serve as a member of the Corps Board, the lobbyist is not subject to:<section prefix="(i)">&#xA7; 15-504(d) of the State Government Article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">&#xA7; 15-703(f)(3) of the State Government Article as a result of that service.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A member of the Corps Board shall reside in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In making appointments to the Corps Board, the Governor shall consider:<section prefix="(1)">Diversity; and</section><section prefix="(2)">All geographic regions of the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A member of the Corps Board:<section prefix="(1)">May not receive compensation as a member of the Corps Board; but</section><section prefix="(2)">Is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of the members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members on July 1, 2010.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The appointing authority may remove a member for incompetence, misconduct, or failure to perform the duties of the position.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Corps Board shall determine the times and places of its meetings.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Corps Board may act with an affirmative vote of six members.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
