<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-712.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>712.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in paragraphs (3), (4), and (5) of this subsection, a person born on or after July 1, 1972 may not operate on the waters of the State a vessel for pleasure that is required to be numbered in accordance with this subtitle or a vessel for pleasure that is required to be numbered in accordance with the Federal Boat Safety Act of 1971 without first obtaining a certificate of boating safety education.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who is subject to the provisions of paragraph (1) of this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">Possess the certificate of boating safety education when operating a vessel on waters of the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Show the certificate on the demand of a Natural Resources police officer or other law enforcement officer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The following persons are exempt from the requirements of this section:<section prefix="(i)">A person who is operating a vessel in connection with commercial purposes;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A person who is a resident of another state and who is visiting the State for 60 days or less in a vessel that is numbered in another state if:<section prefix="1.">The person is 16 years old or older; or</section><section prefix="2.">The person has been issued a boating safety certificate in accordance with the provisions of subsection (c)(6) of this section;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">A person who is visiting the State for 90 days or less in a vessel from a country other than the United States;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A person operating a vessel on a body of water located on private property; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Any other person exempted by regulation of the Department.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">When a vessel numbered in accordance with this subtitle or in accordance with the Federal Boat Safety Act of 1971 is operated for pleasure on waters of the State, at least 1 person on the vessel must:<section prefix="(i)">Possess the certificate of boating safety education; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be exempt from the certification requirements of paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A person who is under the age of 16 and who operates a vessel numbered in accordance with this subtitle or in accordance with the Federal Boat Safety Act of 1971 must:<section prefix="(i)">Possess a certificate of boating safety education;</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">If operating a vessel under 11 feet in length, be under the supervision of a person who has obtained a certificate of boating safety education and is aboard the vessel; or</section><section prefix="2.">If operating a vessel 11 feet in length or greater, be under the supervision of a person who is 18 years or older and has obtained a certificate of boating safety education and is aboard the vessel; or</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">Be under the supervision of a person who was born before July 1, 1972 and is aboard the vessel.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(i)">Adopt regulations that establish criteria for a course of instruction in boating safety education;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Administer a verbal test when appropriate;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Coordinate a statewide program of boating safety instruction and certification and ensure that a course of boating safety education is available within each county; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Ensure that a course of boating safety education is available at the earliest practicable age for children in boating communities.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any course of boating safety education that is offered through a public school is not required to be more than 6 classes, or exceed a total of 8 hours.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The following persons may offer the course of instruction in boating safety education if approved by the Department:<section prefix="(i)">The Department;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The U.S. Coast Guard Auxiliary;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The U.S. Power Squadron;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A political subdivision;</section><section prefix="(v)">A municipal corporation;</section><section prefix="(vi)">An agency;</section><section prefix="(vii)">A public or nonpublic school;</section><section prefix="(viii)">A group;</section><section prefix="(ix)">A firm;</section><section prefix="(x)">An association; or</section><section prefix="(xi)">Any other person.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department or the Department's designee shall issue a certificate of boating safety education to a person who:<section prefix="(i)">Passes the course prescribed by the Department in boating safety education; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Passes a boating safety equivalency examination administered by persons authorized to offer the course on boating safety education.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Upon request, the Department shall provide, without charge, boating safety education materials to persons who plan to take the boating safety equivalency examination.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Once issued, the certificate of boating safety education:<section prefix="1.">Is valid for the lifetime of the person to whom the certificate was issued; and</section><section prefix="2.">May not be revoked by the Department or a court of law.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Department shall replace, without charge, a lost or destroyed certificate if the Department issued the certificate or has a record that the certificate was issued by the U.S. Coast Guard or the U.S. Power Squadron.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Department or the Department's designee may issue a 30-day temporary certificate of boating safety education to a person who signs an affidavit stating that the person has read and understood the boating safety education materials provided by the Department.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The 30-day temporary certificate of boating safety education issued in accordance with subparagraph (i) of this paragraph may be renewed for 1 additional 30-day period.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In lieu of a certificate of boating safety education issued by the Department, a license issued by the U.S. Coast Guard, or a boating safety certificate issued by a unit of the U.S. Coast Guard Auxiliary, the U.S. Power Squadron, or a local board of education, is sufficient to comply with the requirements of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">In lieu of a certificate of boating safety education issued by the Department, a boating safety certificate issued in another state in accordance with criteria of the National Association of State Boating Law Administrators is sufficient to comply with the requirements of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">On or after July 1, 1988 a person who is subject to the provisions of subsection (a)(1) of this section and who operates on waters of the State a vessel for pleasure that is required to be numbered in accordance with this subtitle or a vessel for pleasure that is required to be numbered in accordance with the Federal Boat Safety Act of 1971, in violation of any requirement of this section, is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to:<section prefix="(1)">For a first offense, a fine not exceeding $25; and</section><section prefix="(2)">For any subsequent offense that occurs within 2 years of a prior conviction under this section, a fine not exceeding $500.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A juvenile charged with any violation under this section shall be charged as provided in Title 3, Subtitle 8A of the Courts Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A Natural Resources police officer or other law enforcement officer may enforce the provisions of this section only as a secondary action when the officer detains an operator of a vessel for a suspected violation of another provision of the Code or regulations adopted in accordance with another provision of the Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may be cited but not apprehended solely for a violation of this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
