<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-5-720</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>720</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Burning ban" means a complete ban on all open air burning that is declared by the Secretary or the Governor as a result of prolonged or unusual conditions conducive to the easy starting and spread of fire.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Open air burning" means a fire where any material is burned in the open or in a receptacle other than a furnace, incinerator, or other equipment connected to a stack or chimney.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Public officer" means:<section prefix="(i)">The authorized agents of the Department; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any police officer who is authorized to enforce the laws of the State or of a political subdivision of the State.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, a person may not start or allow open air burning in an area in which a burning ban imposed by the Secretary or the Governor is in effect.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">The supervised burning of buildings or solid, liquid, or gaseous fuels conducted under the direct control and supervision of qualified instructors at a training center operated by a fire department; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any other supervised burning conducted under the direct control and supervision of:<section prefix="1.">Qualified fire instructors; or</section><section prefix="2.">In Wicomico County, Worcester County, or Somerset County, a fire chief, captain, or fire line officer of a fire department that has jurisdiction over the area where the supervised burning occurs.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">On reasonable suspicion of open air burning on privately owned property in an area in which a burning ban is in effect, a public officer may enter on the privately owned property of any person to extinguish the fire or to enforce the provisions of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
