<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-11A-03.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>03.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is an Aquaculture Coordinating Council.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Coordinating Council shall consist of the following 17 members:<section prefix="(1)">1 member of the Maryland Senate designated by the President of the Senate;</section><section prefix="(2)">1 member of the Maryland House of Delegates designated by the Speaker of the House;</section><section prefix="(3)">1 representative of the Department of Agriculture designated by the Secretary of Agriculture;</section><section prefix="(4)">1 representative of the Department of Natural Resources Police designated by the Secretary of Natural Resources;</section><section prefix="(5)">1 representative of the Department of Natural Resources, Fisheries Service, designated by the Secretary of Natural Resources;</section><section prefix="(6)">2 representatives of the University of Maryland designated by the President of the University of Maryland, College Park:<section prefix="(i)">1 with expertise in aquaculture research; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">1 representing the Maryland Cooperative Extension;</section></section><section prefix="(7)">1 representative of the Department of Business and Economic Development designated by the Secretary of Business and Economic Development;</section><section prefix="(8)">1 representative of the Department of the Environment designated by the Secretary of the Environment;</section><section prefix="(9)">1 representative of the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene designated by the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene;</section><section prefix="(10)">3 representatives of the aquaculture industry designated by the Governor;</section><section prefix="(11)">3 tidal fisheries licensed harvesters, including at least one who is a member of the Maryland Watermen's Association designated by the Governor; and</section><section prefix="(12)">1 representative designated by the President of the University of Maryland Center for Environmental Science.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Coordinating Council shall:<section prefix="(i)">Formulate and make proposals to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the Senate Education, Health, and Environmental Affairs Committee and the House Environmental Matters Committee on or before October 1 of each year for advancing Maryland aquaculture, including recommendations for a fee structure on aquaculture operations in order to reduce State expenditures on aquaculture programs;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Establish and monitor a grant program for the implementation of appropriate projects that support the economic health of the State aquaculture industry;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Conduct applied studies of projects and products that will expand the aquaculture industry in the State;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Conduct market tests to determine acceptability and potential demand for new aquaculture products;</section><section prefix="(v)">As appropriate, implement pilot projects and small commercial demonstrations to resolve any outstanding quality or production issues and to educate industry representatives, regulators, and other partners;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Support the aquaculture industry in its efforts to implement innovative procedures and to comply with associated regulations;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Enhance the awareness of innovative aquaculture products and programs among commercial buyers and the general public;</section><section prefix="(viii)">On or before December 31, 2006, develop best management practices that:<section prefix="1.">Provide guidance for freshwater and marine aquaculture permitting and compliance; and</section><section prefix="2.">Serve as the basis for the adoption of State regulations regarding tidal and nontidal aquaculture;</section></section><section prefix="(ix)">Investigate and, to the extent feasible, enhance the area of State waters that is available to private lease for purposes related to the aquaculture and seafood industries;</section><section prefix="(x)">Provide for the establishment of Aquaculture Enterprise Zones in the Chesapeake and coastal bays, so as to:<section prefix="1.">Streamline the permitting process in these zones;</section><section prefix="2.">Provide incentives for private investment in leasing operations; and</section><section prefix="3.">Encourage individuals with historical records in the commercial fishery to adapt their expertise to the raising and harvesting of seafood by aquaculture; and</section></section><section prefix="(xi)">On a regular basis, review State regulations impacting aquaculture and make recommendations to the Aquaculture Review Board regarding any necessary or advisable regulatory changes.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Coordinating Council may establish subcommittees to provide technical assistance to the Council, with subcommittee topics and membership as the Council determines to be appropriate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member appointed by the Governor is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of the members appointed by the Governor serving on July 1, 2006 expire as follows:<section prefix="(i)">2 members in 2007;</section><section prefix="(ii)">2 members in 2008; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">2 members in 2009.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term begins serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">An appointed member may not serve more than 2 consecutive terms.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Governor may remove a member for incompetence or misconduct.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Coordinating Council may elect from among its members a chairman, vice-chairman, secretary and other officers it deems appropriate.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Coordinating Council shall determine the time and place of its meetings.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The members of the Coordinating Council may not receive a salary, but shall be reimbursed for reasonable expenses incurred in attending meetings and other Council business, as provided under the Standard State Travel Regulations.</section>
  </text>
</law>
