<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-1006" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-1006</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not catch oysters or clams within 400 yards of the Federal Research Laboratory at Oxford.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not catch oysters or clams on any area closed by the Department of the Environment due to pollution.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">However, oysters may be transplanted from areas deemed polluted during the closed season in accordance with the provisions of &#xA7; 4-1009 of this subtitle and &#xA7; 4-1106 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the Department of the Environment closes any area to the catching of oysters or clams under this subsection, in addition to the notice required in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the Department of Natural Resources shall mark the area so that the area can be seen from the water.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Department of Natural Resources shall adopt rules and regulations to provide for the marking in a plain and visibly obvious fashion of any area that is closed to the catching of oysters or clams because of pollution. Even in the absence of such marking devices, a person may not catch oysters or clams in a restricted area as designated by the Department of the Environment if notice has been given to the appropriate governing body and the committee of watermen of any county affected by the restriction.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">During the open season for migratory wild waterfowl, a person may not catch oysters in Charles County within 500 yards of any stationary blind or blind site which is occupied and is being used for hunting migratory wild waterfowl.</section>
  </text>
</law>
