<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-1807" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-1807</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The initial planning area for determination of the Chesapeake Bay Critical Area consists of the following areas, as indicated on the Statewide Base Map:<section prefix="(1)">All waters of and lands under the Chesapeake Bay and its tributaries to the head of tide;</section><section prefix="(2)">All State and private wetlands designated under Title 16 of the Environment Article; and</section><section prefix="(3)">All land and water areas within 1,000 feet beyond the landward boundaries of the resources identified under paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The initial planning area for determination of the Atlantic Coastal Bays Critical Area consists of the following areas, as indicated on the Statewide Base Map:<section prefix="(1)">All waters of and lands under the coastal bays and their tributaries to the head of tide;</section><section prefix="(2)">All State and private wetlands designated under Title 16 of the Environment Article; and</section><section prefix="(3)">All land and water areas within 1,000 feet beyond the landward boundaries of the resources identified under paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In determining the Chesapeake Bay Critical Area or the Atlantic Coastal Bays Critical Area within its boundaries, a local jurisdiction may exclude those portions of the planning area designated in subsection (a) or (b) of this section which the local jurisdiction finds to be:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A portion of urban area to be excluded shall be at least 50% developed and may not be less than 2,640,000 square feet in contiguous area or the entire initial planning area located within the boundaries of a municipality, whichever is less.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A local jurisdiction shall include in any program submitted to the Commission under &#xA7; 8-1809 of this subtitle a designation of those portions of the Chesapeake Bay Critical Area or Atlantic Coastal Bays Critical Area proposed for exclusion under paragraph (1) of this subsection, together with all factual information and expert opinion supporting its findings under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission shall approve a local jurisdiction's designation of portions to be excluded unless the Commission finds, based on stated reasons, that the decision of the local jurisdiction was:<section prefix="(i)">Not supported by competent and material evidence; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Arbitrary or capricious.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the Commission develops the program to be applied in a local jurisdiction, the Commission shall exclude areas as appropriate to meet the intent of paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Chesapeake Bay Critical Area shall consist of:<section prefix="(1)">Those areas designated in subsection (a) of this section, except any areas excluded in accordance with subsection (c) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Additional areas proposed for inclusion by local jurisdictions and approved by the Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Atlantic Coastal Bays Critical Area shall consist of:<section prefix="(1)">Those areas designated in subsection (b) of this section, except any areas excluded in accordance with subsection (c) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Additional areas proposed for inclusion by local jurisdictions and approved by the Commission.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
