<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-215.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-215.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The provisions of this section do not apply if:<section prefix="(1)">The Department of the Environment has determined that it is necessary to close an area of State waters to finfishing for the protection of the public health and safety;</section><section prefix="(2)">An abatement or a summary abatement of a state of nuisance is necessary under &#xA7; 4-205.1 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(3)">The Department closes an area of State waters:<section prefix="(i)">For the stocking of coldwater trout; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">In order to provide a security zone adjacent to a production hatchery.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department may completely close an area of State waters to all finfishing if the Department:<section prefix="(1)">In a written report made available to the general public:<section prefix="(i)">Makes a finding that the closure is necessary, after due consideration of:</section><section prefix="(ii)">Develops protocols and a reporting timeline to monitor and evaluate the effectiveness of the closure; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Holds at least one public hearing in accordance with the requirements under subsection (d) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The reporting timeline required under subsection (b)(1)(ii) of this section shall provide for a written report as often as appropriate under the circumstances but at least as often as every 3 years from the date of closure.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For 2 successive weeks in advance of a public hearing required under subsection (b)(2) of this section, the Department shall:<section prefix="(i)">Post a notice of the date, time, place, and purpose of the hearing in a prominent position on the Department's official Internet website; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Advertise the date, time, place, and purpose of the hearing in at least:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At least 15 days before the public hearing, the Department shall make available to the general public the report required under subsection (b)(1) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Following a closure of State waters under this section, in a written report made available to the general public and in accordance with the reporting timeline established under subsection (b)(1)(ii) of this section, the Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">Based on the protocols adopted under subsection (b)(1)(ii) of this section, evaluate the effectiveness of the closure in accomplishing its overall management objectives; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Determine what, if any, management modifications would be appropriate, including the reopening of the closed area.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
