<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-5-1405</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person may not excavate, remove, destroy, injure, deface, or in any manner disturb any paleontolog...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1405</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not excavate, remove, destroy, injure, deface, or in any manner disturb any paleontological site or any part thereof, including saltpeter workings, fossils, bones, or any other paleontological features which may be found in any cave.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, a permit to excavate or remove paleontological features may be obtained from the Secretary. The permit shall be issued for a period of two years and may be renewed at expiration. It is not transferable but this does not preclude persons from working under the direct supervision of the person holding the permit.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person applying for a permit shall:<section prefix="(1)">Have knowledge of paleontology.</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide a detailed statement to the Secretary giving the reasons and objectives for excavation or removal and the benefits expected to be obtained from the contemplated work.</section><section prefix="(3)">Provide data and results of any completed excavation, study, or collection at the first of each calendar year.</section><section prefix="(4)">Obtain the prior written permission of the Secretary if the site of the proposed excavation is on State-owned lands and prior written permission of the owner if the site of the proposed excavation is on privately owned land.</section><section prefix="(5)">Carry the permit while exercising the privileges granted.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person who violates any provision of subsection (a) of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon conviction shall be fined not less than $100 nor more than $500, and may be imprisoned for not less than ten days nor more than six months. A person who violates any of the provisions of subsection (b) of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor, and, upon conviction, shall be fined not less than $100 nor more than $500, and the permit shall be revoked.</section>
  </text>
</law>
