<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-10-2A-06</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>06</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary shall establish programs, including acquisition of land or aquatic habitat or interests in the land or aquatic habitats, necessary for the conservation of nongame, threatened, or endangered species of wildlife or plants. The Secretary shall use all vested authority to carry out the provisions of this subsection.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In carrying out programs authorized by this section, the Secretary shall consult with the State Secretary of Agriculture and other states having a common interest in particular species of nongame, endangered, or threatened species of wildlife or plants. The Secretary may enter into agreements with federal agencies, other states, political subdivisions of the State, or with individuals with respect to programs designed to conserve nongame, endangered, or threatened species of wildlife or plants, including agreements for administration and management established under this section or utilized for conservation of nongame, endangered, or threatened species of wildlife or plants.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Governor shall review other programs administered by the Governor and utilize these programs in furtherance of the purposes of this subtitle. All State departments and agencies, in consultation with and with the assistance of the Secretary, shall utilize their authorities in furtherance of the purposes of this subtitle by carrying out programs for the conservation of endangered species and threatened species listed pursuant to &#xA7; 10-2A-04(f) of this subtitle, and by taking any action necessary to insure that actions authorized, funded, or carried out by them do not jeopardize the continued existence of the endangered species or threatened species or result in the destruction or modification of habitat of the species which is deemed by the Secretary to be critical.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary shall adopt regulations necessary to implement this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
