<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-11A-10</section_number>
  <catch_line>A leaseholder shall:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>10</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A leaseholder shall:<section prefix="(1)">Subject to subsection (b) of this section, actively use the lease and comply with any standards for planting, harvesting, and use of the leased area established by the Department;</section><section prefix="(2)">Mark each lease area with an 8-inch by 12-inch marker displaying the initials of the leaseholder and posted on a minimum of four poles;</section><section prefix="(3)">Comply with any other marking requirements established by the Department for the protection of navigation;</section><section prefix="(4)">Comply with the regulations established by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene in consultation with the Department of the Environment to carry out the mandate of the National Shellfish Sanitation Program; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Pay the rent and the aquaculture development surcharge for the lease at the time established by the Department.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department may waive the requirements for active use of a lease on a showing that conditions not present at the time of execution of the lease, including the unavailability of shellfish seed, prevent active use of the leased area.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A leaseholder may not:<section prefix="(1)">Place shellfish, bags, nets, or structures on submerged aquatic vegetation;</section><section prefix="(2)">Plant or harvest shellfish within 500 yards of any stationary blind or blind site that is occupied and being used for hunting migratory waterfowl;</section><section prefix="(3)">Sublease a lease;</section><section prefix="(4)">Transfer a lease without the approval of the Department;</section><section prefix="(5)">Harvest shellfish between the hours of sunset and sunrise; or</section><section prefix="(6)">Place unlawfully harvested oysters on a lease.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Shellfish planted or harvested in accordance with a lease issued under this subtitle are subject to inspection by the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who wishes to renew a lease issued under this subtitle or an existing shellfish lease or oyster lease shall submit an application that meets the requirements for an initial application in &#xA7; 4-11A-09 or &#xA7; 4-11A-11 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before the termination or expiration of a lease issued under this subtitle, the leaseholder shall have the right of first refusal with respect to future leases of the leased area.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department may terminate a lease issued under this subtitle for failure to comply with the requirements of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall notify a leaseholder by registered mail of its intention and proposed decision to terminate a lease for failure to comply with the requirements of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A leaseholder who wishes to contest the Department's proposed decision may request a review of the decision by the Secretary, which shall be filed not later than 30 days after receipt of the Department's decision.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Failure of a leaseholder to respond to the Department's proposed decision within 30 days of the date of the decision shall cause the leasehold to revert to the State.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
