<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-1917</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Trust, in consultation with the Corps Board, shall make grants to qualified organizations for th...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1917</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Trust, in consultation with the Corps Board, shall make grants to qualified organizations for the creation or expansion of full- and part-time Chesapeake Conservation Corps Programs, that involve citizens of all ages throughout the State, to carry out this part.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Corps programs shall engage and develop volunteers and stipend volunteers in environmental and energy conservation projects.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Eligible Corps Program expenses include personnel costs, stipends, supplies, and other materials for projects undertaken by Corps Program volunteers.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Trust, in consultation with the Corps Board, shall develop guidelines for evaluating applications from qualified organizations.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The guidelines developed in accordance with subsection (b) of this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">Consider the capability of the qualified organization to carry out Corps programs or projects;</section><section prefix="(2)">Encourage and consider multiyear, multipartner proposals, local match, cost-sharing agreements, and in-kind match as factors in evaluating Corps Program grant applications; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Require grant applications to describe how the qualifying organization intends to:<section prefix="(i)">Assess the skills of Corps Program volunteers;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provide life skills and work skills training;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Provide training and education, in addition to the training provided as a part of the main Corps Program;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Develop, where relevant, agreements for academic study with:<section prefix="1.">Local education agencies;</section><section prefix="2.">Community colleges;</section><section prefix="3.">4-year colleges;</section><section prefix="4.">Area charter high schools and vocational-technical schools; and</section><section prefix="5.">Community-based organizations;</section></section><section prefix="(v)">Provide career and educational guidance;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Recruit participants without high school diplomas; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">Recruit retired and semi-retired seniors and other qualified individuals with relevant experience to train Corps Program volunteers and participate in Corps projects by volunteering their experience and skills.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A grant agreement regarding funds from the Trust shall:<section prefix="(1)">Specify the allowed use of the funds provided under the grant, including accountability measures and performance requirements;</section><section prefix="(2)">Take into account the need for efficient multiyear funding and administration of the funds; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Include provisions for verification that Corps programs and projects are being implemented as planned.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
