<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-904" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-3-904</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">As used in this subtitle, the words and terms listed in this section have the meaning given, unless the context clearly indicates another or different meaning.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Bonds" means all bonds, bond anticipation notes, revenue anticipation notes, grant anticipation notes, or other evidences of indebtedness of the Authority, whether general or limited obligations of the Authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Cost" shall include the purchase price of any project or the cost of acquiring all or any portion of the right, title, or interest of a project and the amount to be paid to discharge all obligations necessary or desirable to vest title to the project or any part thereof in the Authority or other owner; the cost of any reconstruction, extension, enlargement, alteration, repair or improvement; the cost of all lands, properties, rights, easements, franchises, and permits; the cost of all labor, machinery, and equipment; financing charges; interest prior to and during construction and if, deemed desirable by the Authority, for a limited period after the completion of construction; reserves for principal and interest and for extensions, enlargements, additions and improvements; the cost of revenue estimates, engineering and legal services, plans, designs, specifications, surveys, investigations, demonstrations, studies, estimates of cost, other expenses necessary or incident to determining the feasibility or practicability of any such acquisition, improvement, repair or construction; administrative expenses, and other expenses as necessary or incident to the financings herein authorized, and to the acquisition, operation, maintenance, improvement, construction of a project and the placing of the same in operation by the Authority, including reasonable provision for working capital. Any obligation or expense incurred prior to the issuance of bonds under the provisions of this subtitle in connection with the foregoing items of cost may be regarded as a part of such cost.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The word "county" includes the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore unless otherwise indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Person" means any natural person, corporation, firm, partnership, cooperative, or other entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Project" means the facilities and properties used or useful or having present capacity for future use in connection with:<section prefix="(i)">The transporting, transferring, compacting, burying, incinerating, reduction, composting, collection, storage, treatment, utilization, processing, or final disposal of waste;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The conversion of waste to fuel, steam, electricity, energy, or other resources or the generation of steam, electricity, or other forms of energy from fuel which is derived from, or is otherwise related to, waste;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The reconstruction, converting or otherwise recycling of waste into material which is not waste or which is useful or is marketable; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any combination of the foregoing (whether or not such facilities are located on a single site). The term "project" also includes but shall not be limited to:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The term "project" includes (without limitation) land, buildings, structures, machinery, equipment, rail or motor vehicles, barges, boats, and all properties and rights therein and appurtenances thereof, rights-of-way, franchises, easements and other interests in land, all land and facilities which are functionally related and subordinate to the project and all patents, licenses and other rights necessary or useful in the construction or operation of a project.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Resolution of participation" means the resolution filed by a county with the Secretary of State and the Department of Legislative Services in order to evidence the consent of the county to participate in the activities of the Authority in accordance with the provisions of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Revenues" means, but is not necessarily limited to, all moneys received by the Authority from or in connection with any project, including (without limitation) grants, rentals, rates, fees, charges for the use of the services furnished or available and all other income inuring to the Authority; provided that the Authority, from time to time, may further define or limit the term "revenues" as applied to a particular project, financing, or other matter.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Subdivision" means any county, municipal corporation, sanitary district, State or local agency, or other public body or agency created or established by or pursuant to State or local law, ordinance, or resolution.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Wastes" means all waste materials, whether solid, liquid or gas, including but not limited to garbage, refuse, and other discarded materials, waste materials resulting from industrial, commercial and agricultural operations and from community activities, rubbish, ashes, incinerator residue, wastewater treatment residue, street cleanings, dead animals, demolition and construction debris, discarded household appliances, automobile bodies, offal and paunch manure.</section>
  </text>
</law>
