<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Scenic and Wild Rivers Review Board. The Board consists of the Secretaries of Natural Res...</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Scenic and Wild Rivers Review Board. The Board consists of the Secretaries of Natural Resources, Agriculture, and the Environment and the Director of Planning and a member of the Garrett County Commissioners, who shall be a voting member of the Board only on matters pertaining to the wild portion of the Youghiogheny River.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The members of the Board shall select the chairperson.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member of the Board:<section prefix="(i)">May not receive any compensation for the member's services; but</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall be reimbursed for necessary travel expenses and disbursements made in order to attend any meeting or perform any other official duty.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to the duties set forth elsewhere in this subtitle, the Scenic and Wild Rivers Review Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">Review:<section prefix="(i)">Any inventory, study, plan, and regulation that is prepared under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The recommendations on the inventory, study, plan, and regulation of the Secretary, any local governing body, or any local advisory board;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Meet regularly; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Appoint, with the advice and consent of the appropriate local governing body, a local scenic and wild river advisory board for each river that is included in the Scenic and Wild Rivers Program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each local scenic and wild river advisory board consists of at least 7 members, except for the Youghiogheny local Scenic and Wild River Advisory Board that consists of at least 8 members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each member of a local scenic and wild river advisory board shall reside in the county through which the scenic and wild river flows.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Scenic and Wild Rivers Review Board shall select the members of each local advisory board as follows:<section prefix="(i)">At least 2 members shall own land contiguous to the scenic or wild river, except for the Youghiogheny River where at least 3 members shall own land contiguous to that portion of the river designated by &#xA7; 8-408(a) of this subtitle as a wild river;</section><section prefix="(ii)">At least 2 members who own land that is not contiguous to the scenic or wild river;</section><section prefix="(iii)">1 member shall represent the local governing body; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">2 members from the county soil conservation district.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a scenic or wild river flows through more than 1 county, the local advisory board shall consist of no more than the following members:<section prefix="(1)">2 residents of each county through which the scenic or wild river flows who own land contiguous to the scenic or wild river;</section><section prefix="(2)">2 residents of each county through which the scenic or wild river flows who do not own land contiguous to the scenic or wild river;</section><section prefix="(3)">2 representatives of the local governing body of each county through which the scenic or wild river flows; and</section><section prefix="(4)">1 representative of each soil conservation district through which the scenic or wild river flows.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each local scenic and wild river advisory board shall:<section prefix="(1)">Review any inventory, study, plan, and regulation that is proposed under this subtitle and is applicable to any river in its jurisdiction;</section><section prefix="(2)">Make recommendations on the inventory, study, plan, and regulation to its local governing body and to the Scenic and Wild Rivers Review Board;</section><section prefix="(3)">Select its own chairperson; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Adopt its own administrative regulations for the operation of the local advisory board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each member of a local advisory board may not:<section prefix="(i)">Receive compensation for service; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be reimbursed for expenses incurred in travel or for attending meetings or performing any official duty.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary shall schedule meetings for each local advisory board. However, in the event of emergencies, the chairperson of a local advisory board may schedule meetings for the local advisory board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Upon completion of an approved management plan, the local governing body may establish a scenic river advisory board for each designated scenic or wild river within its jurisdiction. Each board, as constituted by the local authority, may recommend policies, laws, and regulations in furtherance of the aims of this subtitle to the appropriate local governing body. If a scenic or wild river flows through more than 1 county, the scenic river advisory board may consist of an equal number of members from each county.</section>
  </text>
</law>
