<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-712.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>712.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An owner of a vessel that has a valid document issued by the United States Coast Guard and that is used principally on the waters of the State for pleasure shall apply to the Department for a Maryland use sticker.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall issue a Maryland use sticker to any person who submits an application and pays a fee as required by subsection (b) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Maryland use sticker issued under this section shall be valid for a period not to exceed 2 years expiring on December 31 of the calendar year following the year the sticker is issued.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The owner of the vessel shall:<section prefix="(1)">Submit an application to the Department on the form that the Department requires and be signed by every owner of the vessel; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Pay to the Department an application fee of $10 for the 2-year sticker.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Within 30 days after the sale or other transfer of a vessel that is displaying or should display a sticker under this section:<section prefix="(1)">The transferor shall give notice of the transfer to the Department on a form that the Department requires; and</section><section prefix="(2)">If the transferee intends to continue to use the vessel principally on the waters of the State, the transferee shall submit an application for a Maryland use sticker and pay the fee as required by subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Maryland use sticker shall be displayed on or about the forward half of the vessel.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Unless the vessel that is subject to the requirement of this section displays a current sticker:<section prefix="(1)">A person may not operate the vessel on the waters of the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The owner may not knowingly permit the vessel to be operated on the waters of the State.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
