<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-2003</section_number>
  <catch_line>Whenever a person is halted by a regular or special police officer for an offense on publicly owned ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>2003</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Whenever a person is halted by a regular or special police officer for an offense on publicly owned watershed property punishable as a misdemeanor and which is either a violation of law or a violation of watershed regulations, and is not taken before a District Court commissioner as would otherwise be required or is permitted by law, the officer may prepare a written or electronic citation containing:<section prefix="(1)">A notice to appear in court;</section><section prefix="(2)">The name and address of the person charged;</section><section prefix="(3)">The offense charged;</section><section prefix="(4)">The time and place the person shall appear in court;</section><section prefix="(5)">An acknowledgment of receipt of the citation by the person charged made in a manner determined by the Department; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Other pertinent information as necessary.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The time specified in the notice to appear shall be at least five days after the alleged violation unless the person charged with the violation demands an earlier hearing.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The place specified in the notice to appear shall be before a judge of the appropriate District Court.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The person charged with the violation may promise to appear in court by acknowledging receipt of at least one copy of the citation prepared by the officer in a manner determined by the Department, in which event the officer shall deliver a copy of the citation to the person. Then, the officer may not take the person into physical custody for the violation.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Failure to comply with the notice to appear is punishable as contempt or as otherwise provided by law in such cases.</section>
  </text>
</law>
