<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-107" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-3-107</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Any municipality or person may request the Service to provide the water supply, wastewater purification, solid waste disposal, or energy projects, or any other services, authorized by this subtitle. The request shall set forth the type of proposed project or services to be furnished and the proposed boundaries of the area within which a project or services are requested.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notwithstanding any limitations or other provisions to the contrary of Article 23A, Article 25A, or Article 25B of the Code, or of any charter or local law regulating the procurement or awarding of public contracts, a municipality may enter into contracts with the Service for the purpose of the Service providing any of the projects or services requested by the municipality. As soon as possible after receipt of a duly authorized request from a municipality or person, the Service shall draft a proposed contract with the municipality or person in accordance with the provisions of this subtitle specifying the type of project or services to be provided, whether or not a service district will be established, the boundaries and effective date of any service district, and the terms, conditions, and costs under which the project or services will be provided. Upon execution of the contract, the Service as soon as possible shall establish any service district provided for in the contract and provide, maintain, and operate the necessary project. For the purposes of this subsection, the express powers contained and enumerated in Articles 23A, 25A, and 25B of the Code and in the Charter of the City of Baltimore are deemed to incorporate and include the power and authority contained in this subsection.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The charges levied against a service district shall be reduced by the full amount of federal and State grants which the Service receives and is entitled to retain to defray the cost of any project within the service district.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Existing facilities providing service of the type requested, including all rights, easements, laboratory facilities, vehicles, records, and all other property, equipment, and furnishings necessary and normally associated with the operation of the facility, shall be transferred to the sole ownership of the Service on the date a service district comes into existence unless the Service determines that it not be so transferred. Compensation for existing projects may be based on the original cost of the project minus an allowance for depreciation, or on other terms and conditions satisfactory to the municipality or person transferring the project. All costs and obligations assumed by the Service incidental to the transfer of ownership shall be included in the charge levied against the service district.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">At the request of any person or municipality having the responsibility for the collection of liquid waste or solid waste, the Service may enter into a contract to provide management and operation of waste collection services in any service district as an adjunct to the mandatory provision of projects as set forth in subsections (a) through (d) of this section, if (1) as a condition to the provision of management and operation of waste collection services, the municipality or person enters into a contract upon terms the Service determines reasonable; and (2) the Service and the municipality or person requesting collection services determines by agreement from time to time the charges including the amount and frequency of payments to the Service.</section>
  </text>
</law>
