<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-1001</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1001</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Benefited property" means land immediately abutting the waters of the State that is protected by an erosion control project constructed under the provisions of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Benefited property" includes land in the vicinity of the waters of the State that is protected by the erosion control project when:<section prefix="(i)">The owner of the land has rights of access to land immediately abutting the waters; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The owner is a party to the application for assistance in the project.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Fund" means the Shore Erosion Control Construction Loan Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Net project construction cost" means the construction cost paid from the Fund, equal to the project construction cost, plus any excess costs, less the property owner's cash contribution.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Project construction cost" means the estimated cost to design and construct a shore erosion control project, exclusive of supervision, inspection, and maintenance costs.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Property owner's cash contribution" means the sum an owner of property benefited by a shore erosion control project is required to pay in a lump sum prior to construction of the project.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Shore erosion control project" means a competently designed work project, which may include but is not limited to erection or placement of bulkheads, groins, or other erosion control devices, and measures required to stabilize waterside, shorelines, and banks, and to change drainage patterns, all in order to halt or retard erosion of shorelines and deposit of eroded sediments in the waters of the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
