<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-5-215</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>215</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Fund" means the Deep Creek Lake Recreation Maintenance and Management Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Deep Creek Lake Recreation Maintenance and Management Fund in the Department for the maintenance and management of the land, recreational facilities, and services that are related to Deep Creek Lake in Garrett County.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (4) of this subsection, the Department shall pay all fees collected for boat launching at Deep Creek Lake State Park, all funds collected from lake and buffer use permits, contracts, grants, and gifts as a result of the Deep Creek Lake management program, and any investment earnings of the Fund, into the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the end of each quarter of the fiscal year, the Department shall pay 25% of the total revenue collected during the quarter under paragraph (1) of this subsection to the Board of County Commissioners of Garrett County.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Any investment earnings of the Fund may not be transferred or revert to the General Fund of the State, but shall remain in the Fund.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Moneys in the Fund may be used for administrative costs calculated in accordance with &#xA7; 1-103(b)(2) of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Unless there is an agreement between the Secretary and the Deep Creek Lake Policy and Review Board as to a proposed change, the fee for issuance and processing of any permit covered under subsection (c) of this section may not be changed.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before the Department and the Deep Creek Lake Policy and Review Board may change any fee for the issuance and processing of any permit covered under subsection (c) of this section, the Secretary shall hold a public hearing in Garrett County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notice of the public hearing shall be published in two newspapers of general circulation in Garrett County at least 30 days before the hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The notice shall include the proposed change in the fee and the reason for the fee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may apply to the Department for a lake and buffer use permit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who is aggrieved by a decision of the Department to issue or deny a lake and buffer use permit may seek judicial review of the decision in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
