<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-720</section_number>
  <catch_line>If ownership of a vessel is transferred by operation of law, such as by inheritance, order in bankru...</catch_line>
  <order_by>720</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If ownership of a vessel is transferred by operation of law, such as by inheritance, order in bankruptcy, insolvency, replevin, or execution sale, the transferee, within 30 days after the transferee has acquired the right to possession of the vessel by operation of law, shall mail or deliver to the Department satisfactory proof of the transferee's ownership as the Department requires, together with his application for a new certificate of title, and the required fee. A title tax is not required on these transactions.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department may transfer on its records the ownership of a vessel that has been repossessed by a secured party, if the secured party pays the fee required for transfer of a title and submits to the Department a certification that states:<section prefix="(i)">That the secured party has a security interest in the vessel;</section><section prefix="(ii)">That, on the basis of the security agreement or other lawful basis, the secured party has a right to the possession of and title to the vessel;</section><section prefix="(iii)">That the secured party has possession of the vessel; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any other information that the Department requires.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A secured party that repossesses a vessel is not required to pay the title tax.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On submission of the certification to it, the Department may issue a new certificate of title if it is satisfied that the secured party is entitled to one.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
