<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-506" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-10-506</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the exceptions of subsection (f) of this section, any person who desires to buy, acquire, sell, transport, ship, or store at any time any fur or pelt of any wild quadruped taken within or outside the State first shall obtain a fur dealer's license from the Secretary.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person who has resided permanently in the State for a period of not less than 6 months immediately preceding the time of application may obtain a resident State fur dealer's license upon payment of a $50 fee.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A nonresident may obtain a nonresident fur dealer's license upon payment of a $100 fee.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Every application for a license shall contain information the Secretary requires.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Every fur dealer's license issued shall expire on June 30 following the date of issuance.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department may not require the following persons to obtain a fur dealer's license:<section prefix="(1)">A person who buys or otherwise acquires any fur or pelt of any wild quadruped for the personal use of the person and not for barter, exchange, or sale;</section><section prefix="(2)">A person who can substantiate the fact that any fur or pelt the person possesses is bought from a licensed fur dealer or lawfully is obtained from a dealer in another state and is dressed, altered, trimmed, repaired, or manufactured into a finished product but not resold as a fur or pelt;</section><section prefix="(3)">A tanner or taxidermist who possesses any fur or pelt legally owned by another person and which the tanner or taxidermist temporarily is holding solely for the purpose of processing;</section><section prefix="(4)">A person who sells or possesses to sell the meat, pelt, carcass, or mounted specimen of any beaver, coyote, fisher, fox, mink, muskrat, nutria, opossum, otter, raccoon, skunk, or long-tailed weasel legally taken by that person;</section><section prefix="(5)">Any person who butchers a deer for another person and who retains the hide or fur of the deer because the other person did not want or take the hide or fur; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Any person who sells or possesses to sell the hide, hair, tail, or feet, excluding a mounted specimen of deer, squirrel, or rabbit legally acquired.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The licensee shall allow any Natural Resources police officer or any law enforcement officer to enter the premises and holding facilities where operations are being carried on at all reasonable hours for the following purposes:<section prefix="(1)">To inspect the premises and holding facilities where operations are being carried on;</section><section prefix="(2)">To inspect wildlife; and</section><section prefix="(3)">To inspect records.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
