<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-10-2A-07</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>07</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Any person who violates the provisions of &#xA7; 10-2A-05 of this subtitle, fails to procure any permit required by &#xA7; 10-2A-05 of this subtitle, or violates the terms of any permit shall be fined not more than $1,000 or be imprisoned not more than 1 year, or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Any Natural Resources police officer or any law enforcement officer may conduct searches as provided by law, and execute a warrant to search for and seize any equipment, business records, merchandise, wildlife, or plants taken, used, or possessed in connection with a violation of any subsection. Any Natural Resources police officer or law enforcement officer, without a warrant, may arrest any person who the officer has probable cause to believe is violating, in the officer's presence or view, this subtitle or any regulation or permit provided for by this subtitle. Any Natural Resources police officer or law enforcement officer who has made an arrest of a person in connection with any violation may search the person, premises, or business records at the time of arrest and may seize any wildlife, plants, records, or property taken, or used in connection with any violation.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Equipment, merchandise, wildlife, plants or records seized under the provisions of subsection (b) of this section shall be held by any Natural Resources police officer or law enforcement officer pending disposition of court proceedings, and after disposition of court proceedings shall be forfeited to the State for destruction or disposition as the Secretary may deem appropriate. Prior to forfeiture the Secretary may direct the transfer of wildlife or plants so seized to a qualified zoological, botanical, educational, or scientific institution for safekeeping, costs to be assessable to the defendant. The Secretary may issue regulations to implement this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
