<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-10-2A-06.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>06.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Birdwatcher" means a person who engages in birdwatching.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Birdwatching" means identifying, studying, and recording the presence of wild birds in their natural surroundings.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Birdwatching" does not include incidental sightings of wild birds in their natural surroundings.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The purpose of this section is to provide a special fund that shall be expended for the preservation of nongame wildlife species and threatened and endangered species.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">There is a Birdwatcher's Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">All revenue that the Department derives from the issuance of birdwatcher's stamps and decals shall be credited to the Birdwatcher's Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary shall administer the Birdwatcher's Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Money in the Birdwatcher's Fund shall be expended only for the preservation of nongame wildlife species and threatened and endangered species.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The fee for a birdwatcher's stamp or decal is $5.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Private contributions, grants and donations may be made to the Birdwatcher's Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any person engaged in a retail business who desires to sell birdwatcher's stamps and decals as an agent under the Department's control and supervision shall apply on forms prepared and prescribed by the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An agent may retain 25 cents out of the birdwatcher's stamp or decal fee for each birdwatcher's stamp or decal the agent sells.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Department, by regulation, shall provide procedures and forms for the sale of birdwatcher's stamps and decals.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The purpose of this Fund is:<section prefix="(1)">Dissemination of information pertaining to nongame wildlife species and threatened and endangered species conservation, management, and values;</section><section prefix="(2)">Scientific investigation and survey of nongame wildlife species and threatened and endangered species for better protection and conservation;</section><section prefix="(3)">Propagation, distribution, protection, and restoration of nongame wildlife species and threatened and endangered species;</section><section prefix="(4)">Research and management of nongame wildlife species and threatened and endangered species;</section><section prefix="(5)">Development of habitats for nongame wildlife species and threatened and endangered species;</section><section prefix="(6)">Acquisition of habitats for nongame wildlife species and threatened and endangered species; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Matching of funds available to the Department under federal programs for projects and activities authorized under this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
