<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="1-102" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-1-102</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department shall include all units, programs, boards, commissions, and advisory boards and commissions referenced in this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The following units are also included in this Department:<section prefix="(1)">The Maryland Membership Unit of the Interstate Commission of the Potomac River Basin;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Maryland Membership Unit of the Susquehanna River Basin Commission;</section><section prefix="(3)">The Maryland Membership Unit of the Atlantic States Marine Fisheries Commission;</section><section prefix="(4)">The Maryland Membership Unit of the Potomac River Fisheries Commission;</section><section prefix="(5)">The Maryland Membership Unit of the Interstate Oil and Gas Compact Commission; and</section><section prefix="(6)">The Maryland Membership Unit of the Interstate Mining Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless otherwise provided by this article, each advisory commission created by law consists of five members appointed by the Governor, with the advice of the Secretary, to serve at the pleasure of the Governor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Wildlife Advisory Commission is composed of nine members appointed by the Governor.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The term of a member is 4 years.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">A member may not serve more than 2 terms on the Commission.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The terms of members are staggered so that:</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member shall be knowledgeable in the area of interest of the advisory commission on which he serves.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Each advisory commission shall advise the Secretary or the administration of the appropriate Department unit, pursuant to rules and regulations the Secretary adopts.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The members of each advisory commission annually shall elect a chairman of the commission and may adopt procedures to conduct its meetings.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">An advisory commission member receives the compensation provided in the Department budget. Every member shall be reimbursed for necessary travel expenses incurred in performing any official duty, pursuant to rules and regulations the Secretary adopts.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition to any advisory body established by law, the Secretary, with the Governor's approval, may create administratively any advisory unit of a size and tenure the Secretary deems appropriate.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If any provision of this article as it affects the Maryland membership unit of any interstate agency is inconsistent with any interstate compact to which Maryland is a party, the provision of this article does not apply to that unit to the extent of the inconsistency.</section>
  </text>
</law>
