<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-611</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>611</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Any person engaged in a retail business who desires to sell angler's licenses as an agent under the Department's control and supervision shall apply to the Department on forms prepared and prescribed by the Department. The Department may furnish angler's licenses on consignment to any agent who provides a bond or other security deemed sufficient and adequate by the Department to insure payment for the licenses.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The agent shall fill out every license and duplicate stub in a legible and proper manner and submit any necessary report of sales together with the duplicate stubs after the first day of each month as long as he sells these licenses in accordance with &#xA7; 4-604 of this subtitle. The report and stubs shall reach the Department by the seventh day of each succeeding month. The Department shall reimburse any agent who does not dispose of every angler's license purchased from the Department and who presents the unused licenses intact in their original books to the Department for a refund before March 31 of each year, for the amount of licenses returned and after they are checked and found correct. Every angler's license not returned by March 31 shall be deemed sold and is not reimbursable, unless accompanied by a notarized statement stating why the license is returned late. The Department, after review, may reimburse the agent.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An agent may not make any false statement concerning any date of issuance or other license data. Every license book or stub shall be available for any law enforcement officer to inspect at any time during the regular business day. An agent may not issue any license without receiving the license fees required by law. A receipt may not be issued in lieu of an angler's license.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition to any other penalty provided for in this title, any agent convicted of violating the provisions of this section shall have his angler's license-issuing privilege rescinded.</section>
  </text>
</law>
