<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-1808.4" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-1808.4</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to any project involving the construction of a dwelling unit or other non-water dependent structure on a pier located on State or private wetlands within the Critical Area in Prince George's County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section, "pier" means any pier, wharf, dock, walkway, bulkhead, breakwater, piles, or other similar structure.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Pier" does not include any structure on pilings or stilts that was originally constructed beyond the landward boundaries of State or private wetlands.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section applies notwithstanding:<section prefix="(1)">Any other provision of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Any criteria or regulation adopted by the Commission under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section preempts any other requirement concerning piers in the Critical Area.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) of this subsection, a local jurisdiction may not issue a building permit for any project involving the construction of a dwelling unit or other non-water dependent structure on a pier located on State or private wetlands within the Critical Area.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not prohibit or restrict a local jurisdiction from issuing a building permit for a project involving the construction of a dwelling unit or other non-water dependent structure on a pier located on State or private wetlands within the Critical Area that was issued a permit by the Secretary on or before January 1, 1989.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A local jurisdiction may issue a building permit for a project involving the construction of a dwelling unit or other non-water dependent structure on a pier located on State or private wetlands within the Critical Area if:<section prefix="(i)">The project is constructed on a pier in existence as of December 1, 1985 that can be verified by a Department of Natural Resources aerial photograph dated 1985, accompanied by a map of the area;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The project does not require an expansion of the pier greater than 25% of the area of piers or dry docks removed on the same property; however, additional expansion may be allowed in the amount of 10% of the water coverage eliminated by removing complete piers from the same or other properties. If the horizontal surface area of a pier to be removed is not intact but the remaining pilings identify its previous size, that area may be used in determining the additional expansion permitted. The project expansion based on water coverage eliminated can be considered only if all nonfunctional piers on the property are removed except for the project pier. The total expansion may not exceed 35% of the original size of the piers and dry docks removed;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The project is approved by local planning and zoning authorities; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The project is located in an intensely developed area, as designated in programs adopted or approved by the Critical Area Commission under this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A local jurisdiction may issue a building permit for the repair of an existing dwelling unit or other non-water dependent structure on a pier located on State or private wetlands within the Critical Area.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Except for projects under paragraph (2) of this subsection, and in addition to all other provisions of this section, all projects involving the construction of a dwelling unit or other non-water dependent facility on a pier located on State or private wetlands within the Critical Area may not be issued a building permit unless:<section prefix="(i)">The applicant demonstrates that the construction and operation of the project will not have a long term adverse effect on the water quality of the adjacent body of water in accordance with standards established by the local jurisdiction's critical areas program;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The applicant is required to improve the water quality of existing stormwater runoff from the project site into adjoining waters in accordance with standards established by the local jurisdiction's critical areas program; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The applicant demonstrates that any sewer lines or other utility lines extended for the pier will not adversely affect the water quality of adjoining waters in accordance with standards established by the local jurisdiction's critical areas program.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
