<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-1808.5</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "community pier" means a boat docking facility associated with a subdivision or sim...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1808.5</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section, "community pier" means a boat docking facility associated with a subdivision or similar residential area, or with condominiums, apartments, or other multiple-family dwelling units.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Community pier" does not include a private pier or a mooring.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies notwithstanding:<section prefix="(1)">Any other provision of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Any criteria or regulation adopted by the Commission under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subject to the requirements under subsection (d) of this section, a new or expanded community pier or other noncommercial boat docking or storage facility may be permitted in the buffer if:<section prefix="(1)">The facility:<section prefix="(i)">Is water dependent;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Meets a recognized private right or public need;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is community-owned and established and operated for the benefit of the residents of a platted and recorded riparian subdivision; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Is associated with a residential development approved by the local jurisdiction for the Critical Area and is consistent with all criteria and local regulations for the Critical Area;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Adverse effects on water quality and fish, plant, and wildlife habitat are minimized;</section><section prefix="(3)">Insofar as possible, nonwater dependent structures or operations associated with water dependent projects or activities are located outside the buffer;</section><section prefix="(4)">Disturbance to the buffer is the minimum necessary to provide a single point of access to the facility;</section><section prefix="(5)">Food, fuel, or other goods and services are not offered for sale, and adequate and clean sanitary facilities are provided; and</section><section prefix="(6)">When a community pier with slips is provided as part of a new development project, private piers are not permitted in the development area.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The number of slips permitted at a facility shall be the lesser of the following:<section prefix="(1)">One slip for each 50 feet of shoreline in a subdivision located in an intense or limited development area, and one slip for each 300 feet of shoreline in a subdivision located in a resource conservation area; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A density of slips to platted lots or dwellings within a subdivision in the critical area in accordance with the following schedule:</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A local jurisdiction may grant a variance from the provisions of this section in accordance with regulations adopted by the Commission concerning variances as part of local program development set forth in COMAR 27.01.11 and notification of project applications set forth in COMAR 27.03.01.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">On or before December 31, 1994, a local jurisdiction shall amend its local critical area protection program to meet the provisions of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
