<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-215.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-5-215.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The General Assembly declares that:<section prefix="(1)">Deep Creek Lake and the land under and around it possess unique and valuable scenic, ecologic, historic, recreational, fish, wildlife, and other natural resource values; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A Deep Creek Lake recreation and land use plan will:<section prefix="(i)">Protect the resources and natural value of the lake and surrounding land;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provide for the ongoing recreation, use, and enjoyment of these resources; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Fulfill vital conservation purposes by wise, sustainable use of these resources.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary and the Deep Creek Lake Policy and Review Board shall prepare a plan that provides for the wise use, protection, and management of the natural and recreational resources of Deep Creek Lake.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The plan shall:<section prefix="(i)">Evaluate the lake, shoreline, and buffer area as a recreational, water, natural, and scenic resource, considering land use, carrying capacity, zoning, visitor access, recreation areas, commercial and private use, and related activities; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Reflect activities such as fishing, boating, docking, hiking, water sports, scenic appreciation, natural interpretation, and other programs which provide the public with opportunities to appreciate and enjoy the value of the lake and buffer area.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department may consult with the Department of the Environment and the Department of Business and Economic Development:<section prefix="(1)">In preparing the Deep Creek Lake recreation and land use plan; and</section><section prefix="(2)">On any other matter relating to Deep Creek Lake.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Secretary may adopt regulations relating to Deep Creek Lake that are  necessary to:<section prefix="(i)">Protect the public health and safety, natural resources, and the environment; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Implement the Deep Creek Lake recreation and land use plan.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before the Secretary proposes or adopts a regulation, the Secretary shall submit a draft of the regulation to the Deep Creek Lake Policy and Review Board for its review and consent if the regulation relates to:<section prefix="(i)">The content or the adoption and implementation of a Deep Creek Lake recreation and land use plan, as described under subsections (a) and (b) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any fee proposed under &#xA7; 5-215 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
