<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-727</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>727</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Elude" means to evade a police officer's visual or audible signal to stop by:<section prefix="(i)">Willfully failing to stop the vessel;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Fleeing on foot; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any other means.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Police officer" means an officer who is:<section prefix="(i)">In uniform, prominently displaying the officer's badge or other insignia of office; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">In a vessel that is appropriately marked as an official law enforcement vessel, whether or not the officer is in uniform.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Visual or audible signal" means a warning or command by hand, voice, emergency light, signal device, or siren.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A Natural Resources police officer or any law enforcement officer enforcing the provisions of this subtitle may stop, board, or inspect any vessel subject to this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, an individual who is on a vessel may not display or operate a flashing blue light or signal device.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A police officer who is on a vessel of a county, municipal, State, or federal law enforcement agency may display and operate flashing blue lights or signal devices while responding to or at the scene of an emergency or pursuing a violator or suspected violator of the law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">On the immediate approach of a law enforcement vessel lawfully using a flashing blue light or signal device, an operator of another vessel, unless otherwise directed by a police officer, shall:<section prefix="(1)">Yield the right-of-way; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Stop the vessel and stay in that position until the law enforcement vessel has passed.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An operator of a vessel may not elude or attempt to elude a police officer who gives a visual or audible signal to the operator to stop.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who violates subsection (c) or (d) of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $500.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who violates subsection (e) of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction:<section prefix="(i)">For a first offense, is subject to a fine not exceeding $1,000 or imprisonment not exceeding 1 year or both; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">For a subsequent offense, is subject to a fine not exceeding $1,000 or imprisonment not exceeding 2 years or both.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
