<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-1810</section_number>
  <catch_line>If a local jurisdiction fails to notify the Commission that the local jurisdiction will develop a pr...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1810</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If a local jurisdiction fails to notify the Commission that the local jurisdiction will develop a program, fails to submit a proposed program or changed proposal on time, or fails to obtain Commission approval of a proposed program or changed proposal that is submitted, the Commission shall prepare and adopt a program that satisfies the criteria adopted under &#xA7; 8-1808 of this subtitle for the part of the Chesapeake Bay Critical Area or Atlantic Coastal Bays Critical Area in that local jurisdiction.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Where a local jurisdiction failed to adopt or obtain Commission approval of a program, the Commission shall adopt a program for that jurisdiction by adopting regulations in accordance with Title 2, Subtitle 5 (Joint Committee on Administrative, Executive, and Legislative Review) and Title 10, Subtitle 1 (Administrative Procedure Act) of the State Government Article. Before the full Commission adopts a program under this subsection, the Commission shall appoint a panel of 3 of the Commission's members to conduct in the affected jurisdiction at least 2 public hearings at least 10 days apart on the proposed program, for which 2 weeks' notice shall be published in a newspaper of general circulation in the local jurisdiction. A program adopted by the Commission under this subsection shall supersede any inconsistent local laws, ordinances, or plans.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the Commission adopts a program for a local jurisdiction, the program shall be implemented and enforced by local authorities in the same manner as if the program had been adopted by the local jurisdiction itself.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If, at any time after the Commission has adopted a program for a local jurisdiction, the local jurisdiction submits an alternative program of its own that satisfies the criteria adopted under &#xA7; 8-1808 of this subtitle and is approved by the Commission, the alternative program supersedes the program adopted by the Commission.</section>
  </text>
</law>
