<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-5-1606</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1606</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For the following land use categories, tracts having less than 20% of the net tract area in forest cover shall be afforested up to 20% of the net tract area:<section prefix="(i)">Agriculture and resource areas; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Medium density residential areas.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For the following land use categories, tracts having less than 15% of the net tract area in forest cover shall be afforested up to 15% of the net tract area:<section prefix="(i)">Institutional development areas;</section><section prefix="(ii)">High density residential areas;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Mixed use and planned unit development areas; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Commercial and industrial use areas.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Afforestation requirements must conform to the conditions in &#xA7;&#xA7; 5-1607 and 5-1610 of this subtitle, including payment into the Forest Conservation Fund, if afforestation on-site or off-site cannot be reasonably accomplished.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The afforestation requirements under this subsection shall be accomplished within 1 year or 2 growing seasons after the completion of the development project.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If afforestation cannot be reasonably accomplished on-site or off-site, the requirement to contribute money to a Forest Conservation Fund under &#xA7; 5-1610 of this subtitle shall be met within 90 days after the completion of the development project.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Linear projects that involve no change in land use may not be subject to afforestation requirements.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a forest conservation threshold established for all land use categories as provided in subsection (c) of this section. The forest conservation threshold means the percentage of the net tract area at which the reforestation requirement changes from a ratio of 1/4 acre planted for every 1 acre removed to a ratio of 2 acres planted for every 1 acre removed.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">After every reasonable effort to minimize the cutting or clearing of trees and other woody plants is exhausted in the development of a subdivision plan and grading and sediment control activities and implementation of the forest conservation plan, the forest conservation plan shall provide for reforestation, or payment into the Forest Conservation Fund, according to the formula set forth in subsection (b) of this section and consistent with the following forest conservation thresholds for the applicable land use category:<section prefix="(1)">Agricultural and resource areas: 50% of net tract area;</section><section prefix="(2)">Medium density residential areas: 25% of net tract area;</section><section prefix="(3)">Institutional development areas: 20% of net tract area;</section><section prefix="(4)">High density residential areas: 20% of net tract area;</section><section prefix="(5)">Mixed use and planned unit development areas: 15% of net tract area; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Commercial and industrial use areas: 15% of net tract area.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, for all existing forest cover measured to the nearest 1/10 acre cleared on the net tract area above the applicable forest conservation threshold, the area of forest removed shall be reforested at a ratio of 1/4 acre planted for every 1 acre removed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each acre of forest retained on the net tract area above the applicable forest conservation threshold shall be credited against the total number of acres required to be reforested under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">For all existing forest cover measured to the nearest 1/10 acre cleared on the net tract area below the applicable forest conservation threshold, the area of forest removed shall be reforested at a ratio of 2 acres planted for every 1 acre removed.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The reforestation requirements under this section shall be accomplished within 1 year or 2 growing seasons after completion of the development project.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If reforestation cannot be reasonably accomplished on-site or off-site, the requirement to contribute money to a Forest Conservation Fund under &#xA7; 5-1610 of this subtitle shall be met within 90 days after completion of the development project.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
