<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-212" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-5-212</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Fund" means the Forest or Park Reserve Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Forest or Park Reserve Fund in the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The purpose of the Fund is to enable the Department to purchase and manage in the name of the State lands suitable for forest culture, reserves, watershed protection, State parks, scenic preserves, historic monuments, parkways, and State recreational reserves.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department shall administer the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Treasurer shall hold the Fund separately and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 5-307(f)(4) of this title, any money obtained from the State forest reserves, State parks, scenic reserves, parkways, historic monuments, and recreation areas;</section><section prefix="(2)">Revenue distributed to the Fund from fines collected under &#xA7; 5-1302 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Revenue received by the Fund under &#xA7; 5-207(b) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund may be used only for:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, payments to counties in the amount of:</section><section prefix="(iii)">Administrative costs calculated in accordance with &#xA7; 1-103(b)(2) of this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For fiscal years 2012 and 2013 only, the payments under paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection shall be based only on the revenue derived from sales of timber.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Treasurer shall invest the money of the Fund in the same manner as other State money may be invested.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any investment earnings of the Fund shall be credited to the General Fund of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Expenditures from the Fund may be made only in accordance with the State budget.</section>
  </text>
</law>
