<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-10-507</section_number>
  <catch_line>Each fur dealer shall keep a ledger on a form provided by the Department which includes the name, ad...</catch_line>
  <order_by>507</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each fur dealer shall keep a ledger on a form provided by the Department which includes the name, address, and current hunting, trapping, fur dealer's, taxidermist and fur tanner's, or game husbandry license number of each person from whom any fur was purchased or received within or outside the State, the date of purchase or receipt, the quantity of each species of furs purchased, and the country, state, and county or political subdivision where the furs were taken, and identifies any appropriate official game or fur possession tag number or bill of sale. The ledger must state the final disposition of the furs and the date disposed of. Disposition includes selling, transporting, shipping, storing, or otherwise using or possessing the furs. The licensee also shall include the same information with regard to any wildlife taken from the wild by the licensee. The ledger shall cover every transaction from date of issuance of the fur dealer's license until date of expiration and shall be kept up-to-date. In addition to any other penalty provided by this subtitle, any person convicted of failing to maintain and keep up-to-date a ledger as required by this subsection or of making false entries shall have the license revoked for a period of at least 1 year and not exceeding 5 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Between July 1 and July 10, every fur dealer shall submit the ledger to the Secretary along with a statement under oath that the information in the ledger is correct on forms furnished by the Secretary, indicating the number or quantity and species of furs possessed, and the county or place of origin where furs were taken, possessed, bought, sold, transported, shipped, stored, tanned, or used by him during the period covered by the previous license. Every fur dealer also shall include in the report the name, address, and current license number of each person from whom any fur was purchased within or outside the State, the date of purchase, the quantity of each species of furs purchased, and the county where the furs were taken, if purchased in the State. Each report shall cover every transaction from date of issuance of the fur dealer's license until expiration. Application for renewal of a fur dealer's license shall accompany the ledger.</section>
  </text>
</law>
