<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-11A-11</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>11</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to demonstration leases.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department may issue a demonstration lease to a public high school, an incorporated college or university within the State, a 4-H club, or a nonstock, nonprofit corporation organized under the laws of the State exclusively for educational, conservation, or ecological purposes.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An application for a demonstration lease shall include a declaration that the applicant intends to actively use the leased area for demonstration purposes and a proposed plan for active use of the lease.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The size of the lease may not exceed 5 acres.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The proposed lease area may not be located:<section prefix="(1)">Within a minimum of 50 feet of shoreline or any pier without the written permission of the riparian owner at the time of application for the lease;</section><section prefix="(2)">Within 150 feet of the public shellfish fishery or a registered pound net site;</section><section prefix="(3)">Within 150 feet of an oyster reserve or any Yates Bar located in an oyster sanctuary;</section><section prefix="(4)">Within 150 feet of a federal navigational channel;</section><section prefix="(5)">In any creek, cove, bay, or inlet less than 300 feet wide at its mouth at mean low tide;</section><section prefix="(6)">In an SAV Protection Zone; or</section><section prefix="(7)">In a setback or buffer from the Assateague Island National Seashore established by the Department.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A demonstration lease may not be assigned or transferred.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any transfer or assignment or attempt to transfer or assign a lease shall be void and the interest in submerged land shall revert to the State without the necessity of any action by the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A demonstration leaseholder shall actively use the lease for the purpose of demonstrating the ecological benefits of growing shellfish or for research or education.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Failure to actively use the lease may result in termination of the lease.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not harvest shellfish for commercial or consumption purposes from an area that is subject to a demonstration lease.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
