<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-745</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in subsections (c) and (d) of this section and &#xA7; 4-217 of this title, a person m...</catch_line>
  <order_by>745</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsections (c) and (d) of this section and &#xA7; 4-217 of this title, a person may not fish for finfish in the Chesapeake Bay or in its tributaries up to tidal boundaries or in State waters of the Atlantic Ocean and the Atlantic coastal bays and their tributaries without first obtaining a Chesapeake Bay and coastal sport fishing license or registration issued under subsection (d)(3) of this section and possessing evidence of the license or registration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The license may be obtained from the Department or from any authorized agent of the Department. The following annual license fees shall apply:<section prefix="(i)">Resident $15</section><section prefix="(ii)">Short-term resident license valid for 7 consecutive days from date of issue ..............................................................................................................$6</section><section prefix="(iii)">For a short-term nonresident license valid for 7 consecutive days from date of issue ...................................................................................................$12</section><section prefix="(iv)">Nonresident $22.50</section><section prefix="(v)">Resident and nonresident blind persons No fee</section><section prefix="(vi)">Complimentary license under subsection (e) of this      section .........................................................................................................................No fee</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Every Chesapeake Bay and coastal sport fishing license and registration shall be valid for not more than 1 year and shall expire on December 31.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An applicant for a license issued under this section shall provide all the information requested by the Department on forms issued by the Department.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department may designate a person engaged in a commercial enterprise to sell the Chesapeake Bay and coastal sport fishing license or issue a registration under subsection (d) of this section as an agent under the Department's control and supervision.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">As compensation, the agent shall retain $1 for each license issued.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">There is no agent compensation for each registration issued.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Chesapeake Bay and coastal sport fishing license shall be furnished to an agent upon satisfactory payment or upon consignment and only if the Department is given adequate security to insure ultimate payment by an agent to the Department for the licenses.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, all fees collected on behalf of the Department pursuant to this section shall be remitted to the Department in accordance with its rules and regulations for deposit with the State Treasurer to the credit of the Fisheries Research and Development Fund to be used for the replenishment, protection, and conservation of fish stocks caught by recreational fishermen, for enhancement of recreational fishing opportunities, and for research concerning tidal fishery resources. The Department shall publicly report annually the amounts collected and the expenditures.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In fiscal year 1999 and in each subsequent fiscal year, the Department, for the purposes set forth in subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph, shall use:<section prefix="1.">$2 from the sale of each license under subsection (a) of this section;</section><section prefix="2.">$20 from the sale of each license under subsection (d)(2) of this section; and</section><section prefix="3.">$225 of the special charter boat license under subsection (d)(1) of this section.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Department shall use the moneys specified in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph for:<section prefix="1.">Achieving the maximum federal fund apportionments;</section><section prefix="2.">Management assessment and sport fishing surveys; and</section><section prefix="3.">Angler outreach and public fishing information.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In the preparation of plans for the expenditure of license receipts, the Secretary annually shall solicit the advice and opinions of the Department's Sport Fisheries Advisory Commission, representative fishing and boating associations, and other interested parties.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may fish for finfish in the Chesapeake Bay or its tidal tributaries or in State waters of the Atlantic Ocean and coastal bays and their tributaries without a Chesapeake Bay and coastal sport fishing license if the person:<section prefix="(1)">Is under the age of 16;</section><section prefix="(2)">Possesses a valid commercial license;</section><section prefix="(3)">Holds a valid tidal water sport fishing license issued by the State of Virginia, Potomac River Fisheries Commission, or District of Columbia, provided that this exemption shall not take effect until the Secretary has published notice in the Maryland Register of the Secretary's determination that the Virginia, Potomac River Fisheries Commission, or District of Columbia requirements for a tidal water sport fishing license are substantially similar to and reciprocal with the Chesapeake Bay and coastal sport fishing license requirements of this section;</section><section prefix="(4)">Is fishing pursuant to any special charter boat license issued under subsection (d)(1) of this section;</section><section prefix="(5)"><section prefix="(i)">Is on active duty with the armed forces of the United States;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is a resident of this State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is on leave from the armed forces; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Has, while fishing, a copy of the person's official leave orders;</section></section><section prefix="(6)">Fishes on a free fishing day designated by the Secretary;</section><section prefix="(7)">Holds a current resident consolidated senior sport fishing license issued under &#xA7; 4-216 of this title;</section><section prefix="(8)">Holds a current registration issued under subsection (d)(3) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(9)">Is fishing on a commercial fishing pier licensed under subsection (d)(4) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department may provide by regulation for issuance of a special charter boat license that would be valid for all individuals on a charter boat operated by a licensed fishing guide in tidal waters of the State. The fee shall be:<section prefix="(i)">For 6 fishermen or less $240.</section><section prefix="(ii)">For 7 or more fishermen $290.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Department may provide by regulation for issuance of an annual special Chesapeake Bay and coastal sport fishing license, which when permanently affixed to a boat registered in any state shall authorize any person on the boat to fish for finfish in the Chesapeake Bay or in its tributaries up to tidal boundaries or in State waters of the Atlantic Ocean and the Atlantic coastal bays and their tributaries, except that such a license may not be used on a boat that has been hired to take such persons fishing.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual fee for this special license shall be $50.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If a boat owner purchases the special license under this paragraph, the boat owner may fish anywhere in the Chesapeake Bay and its tributaries or the State waters of the Atlantic Ocean and the Atlantic coastal bays and their tributaries, whether the boat owner is fishing in the owner's boat, in another person's boat, on land, or elsewhere. The Department shall issue a complimentary Chesapeake Bay and coastal sport fishing license to the boat owner who purchases a special license under this paragraph. If a boat to which the special license is affixed has more than one owner, then only the individual applicant who signs the application for the special license shall be entitled to a complimentary Chesapeake Bay and coastal sport fishing license under this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An individual shall register with the Department before fishing in any of the following areas that do not require a Chesapeake Bay and coastal sport fishing license:<section prefix="1.">A free fishing area established under &#xA7; 4-214(b)(1) of this title with hook and line;</section><section prefix="2.">On private real property bordering on tidal water as an owner or tenant of the property, or a spouse or an immediate family member who resides on the property with the owner or tenant; and</section><section prefix="3.">On a boat licensed under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">There is no fee for registration under this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">An individual required to register under this paragraph shall provide all the information requested by the Department on forms issued by the Department.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">
          <section prefix="1.">The Department may provide by regulation for the issuance of a special commercial fishing pier license that is valid for all individuals fishing from the pier in tidal waters of the State.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The annual fee for the special commercial fishing pier license shall be $290.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Individuals fishing from a licensed commercial fishing pier are exempt from purchasing a Chesapeake Bay and coastal sport fishing license.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">
          <section prefix="1.">The owner or operator of a licensed commercial fishing pier shall maintain a log of the contact information of the persons fishing from that structure each day.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The logs required under subsubparagraph 1 of this subparagraph must be submitted electronically as prescribed or approved by the Department.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "former prisoner of war" means a person who, while serving in the active military, naval, or air service of the United States, was forcibly detained or interned in the line of duty by an enemy government or its agents, or a hostile force, during a period of armed conflict.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department may issue a lifetime complimentary Chesapeake Bay and coastal sport fishing license to any Maryland resident who certifies that the resident is a former prisoner of war or a 100% service connected disabled American veteran.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A complimentary license is not transferable and shall be issued on forms the Department designates.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
