<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-1808.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section is intended to establish conditions for development in the Chesapeake Bay Critical Area...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1808.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section is intended to establish conditions for development in the Chesapeake Bay Critical Area and the Atlantic Coastal Bays Critical Area in addition to those established in criteria of the Commission. However, in the event of any inconsistency between the criteria and the provisions of this section, this section shall control.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The growth allocation for a local jurisdiction shall be calculated based on 5 percent of the total resource conservation area in a local jurisdiction:<section prefix="(1)">In the Chesapeake Bay Critical Area at the time of the original approval of the local jurisdiction's program by the Commission, not including tidal wetlands or land owned by the federal government; or</section><section prefix="(2)">In the Atlantic Coastal Bays Critical Area at the time of the original approval of the local jurisdiction's program by the Commission, not including tidal wetlands or land owned by the federal government.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In paragraphs (3)(i) and (4)(i) of this subsection, "consistent with" or "consistency with" a jurisdiction's comprehensive plan means that a standard or factor will further, and not be contrary to, the following items in the plan:<section prefix="(i)">Policies;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Timing of the implementation of the plan;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Timing of development;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Timing of rezoning;</section><section prefix="(v)">Development patterns;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Land uses; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">Densities or intensities.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When locating new intensely developed or limited development areas, local jurisdictions shall use the following standards:<section prefix="(i)">Locate a new intensely developed area in a limited development area or adjacent to an existing intensely developed area;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Locate a new limited development area adjacent to an existing limited development area or an intensely developed area;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Locate a new limited development area or an intensely developed area in a manner that minimizes impacts to a habitat protection area as defined in COMAR 27.01.09, and in an area and manner that optimizes benefits to water quality;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Locate a new intensely developed area or a limited development area in a resource conservation area at least 300 feet beyond the landward edge of tidal wetlands or tidal waters, unless the local jurisdiction proposes, and the Commission approves, alternative measures for enhancement of water quality and habitat that provide greater benefits to the resources;</section><section prefix="(v)">Locate new intensely developed areas and limited development areas in a manner that minimizes their impacts to the defined land uses of the resource conservation area;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Except as provided in item (viii) of this paragraph, no more than one-half of the expansion allocated in the criteria of the Commission may be located in resource conservation areas;</section><section prefix="(vii)">New intensely developed or limited development areas involving the use of growth allocation shall conform to all criteria of the Commission and shall be designated on the comprehensive zoning map submitted by the local jurisdiction as part of its application to the Commission for program approval or at a later date in compliance with &#xA7; 8-1809(g) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">In Calvert, Caroline, Cecil, Charles, Dorchester, Kent, Queen Anne's, St. Mary's, Somerset, Talbot, Wicomico, and Worcester counties, if the county is unable to utilize a portion of the growth allocated to the county in items (i) and (ii) of this paragraph within or adjacent to existing intensely developed or limited development areas as demonstrated in the local plan approved by the Commission, then that portion of the allocated expansion which cannot be so located may be located in the resource conservation area in addition to the expansion allocated in item (vi) of this paragraph. A developer shall be required to cluster any development in an area of expansion authorized under this paragraph.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A local jurisdiction may use a standard that varies from the standards required under paragraph (2)(i) and (ii) of this subsection if:<section prefix="(i)">The alternative standard is consistent with the jurisdiction's adopted comprehensive plan; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Commission has approved the alternative standard as part of the local program.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In reviewing map amendments or refinements involving the use of growth allocation, the Commission shall consider the following factors:<section prefix="(i)">Consistency with the jurisdiction's adopted comprehensive plan and whether the growth allocation would implement the goals and objectives of the adopted plan;</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">For a map amendment or refinement involving a new intensely developed area, whether the development is:</section><section prefix="2.">For a map amendment or refinement involving a new limited development area, whether the development is:</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">The use of existing public infrastructure, where practical;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Consistency with State and regional environmental protection policies concerning the protection of threatened and endangered species and species in need of conservation that may be located on- or off-site;</section><section prefix="(v)">Impacts on a priority preservation area, as defined under &#xA7; 2-518 of the Agriculture Article;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Environmental impacts associated with wastewater and stormwater management practices and wastewater and stormwater discharges to tidal waters, tidal wetlands, and tributary streams; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">Environmental impacts associated with location in a coastal hazard area or an increased risk of severe flooding attributable to the proposed development.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Commission shall ensure that the standards and factors in paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) of this subsection have been applied in a manner that is consistent with the purposes, policies, goals, and provisions of this subtitle, and all criteria of the Commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the conditions under paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, if a jurisdiction has within its territorial limits an area that is subject to the Chesapeake Bay Critical Area program and an area that is subject to the Atlantic Coastal Bays Critical Area program, the growth allocation for that jurisdiction may be utilized within either critical area, as the jurisdiction's local program considers appropriate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A local jurisdiction's program may not utilize the growth allocation from another critical area unless the growth allocation remaining in either critical area is insufficient to allow approval of a growth allocation proposal associated with a program amendment for which the local program seeks Commission approval.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A local jurisdiction's program may not transfer more than 150 acres of growth allocation to another critical area.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as authorized under paragraph (2) of this subsection, in calculating the 1-in-20 acre density of development that is permitted on a parcel located within the resource conservation area, a local jurisdiction:<section prefix="(i)">Shall count each dwelling unit; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May permit the area of any private wetlands located on the property to be included, under the following conditions:<section prefix="1.">The density of development on the upland portion of the parcel may not exceed one dwelling unit per 8 acres; and</section><section prefix="2.">The area of private wetlands shall be estimated on the basis of vegetative information as designated on the State wetlands maps.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Within a resource conservation area, a local jurisdiction may consider one additional dwelling unit per lot or parcel as part of a primary dwelling unit for the purpose of the density calculation under this subsection if the additional dwelling unit:<section prefix="1."/><section prefix="2."/></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The provisions of this paragraph may not be construed to require a local jurisdiction to consider an additional dwelling unit as part of a primary dwelling unit for the purpose of the density calculation under this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">An additional dwelling unit meeting all the criteria under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph that is separate from the primary dwelling unit may not be subdivided or conveyed separately from the primary dwelling unit.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each local jurisdiction shall:<section prefix="1.">Maintain records of all building permits issued under this subsection for additional dwelling units considered part of a primary dwelling unit; and</section><section prefix="2.">Provide this information on a quarterly basis to the Commission.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Beginning on November 1, 2004 and annually thereafter, the Commission shall report, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the Senate Education, Health, and Environmental Affairs Committee, the House Environmental Matters Committee, and the Joint Committee on the Chesapeake and Atlantic Coastal Bays Critical Area regarding the construction of additional dwelling units considered part of a primary dwelling unit under this subsection.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The provisions of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">Apply to density calculations only; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May not be construed to authorize a local jurisdiction to grant a variance, unless the variance is granted in accordance with the requirements of &#xA7; 8-1808(d) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
