<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-209</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>209</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Fund" means the Fisheries Research and Development Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Fisheries Research and Development Fund in the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The purpose of the Fund is to:<section prefix="(1)">Finance the replenishment of fisheries resources and related research; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Match federal funds available for research and development of fisheries resources.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department shall administer the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Treasurer shall hold the Fund separately and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">Any money received under this title for:<section prefix="(i)">Commercial licenses and permits;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Service fees, taxes, and royalties paid to the State for oyster shells and clam shells removed from the bottom beneath the tidal waters of the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The sale of seed oysters under &#xA7; 4-1103 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any fine or forfeiture collected under &#xA7; 4-1202 of this title;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Any investment earnings of the Fund;</section><section prefix="(3)">Money received from any other source; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Money appropriated from the General Fund of the State in accordance with subsection (j) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Subject to &#xA7;&#xA7; 4-701(o), 4-1020, 4-1028, and 4-1035 of this title, the Fund may be used for:<section prefix="(1)">Replenishing fisheries resources and related research;</section><section prefix="(2)">Matching federal funds available for research and development of fisheries resources; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Administrative costs calculated in accordance with &#xA7; 1-103(b)(2) of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Treasurer shall invest the money of the Fund in the same manner as other State money may be invested.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any investment earnings of the Fund may not be transferred or revert to the General Fund of the State, but shall remain in the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Expenditures from the Fund may be made only in accordance with the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">Beginning with fiscal year 2009 and each fiscal year thereafter, the Governor may include in the budget bill an appropriation from the General Fund for the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The Governor shall include in the budget bill for each fiscal year a General Fund appropriation to the Fisheries Research and Development Fund of not less than $1,794,000.</section>
  </text>
</law>
