<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-210.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person providing fishing guide services for compensation to a person fishing in nontidal freshwate...</catch_line>
  <order_by>210.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person providing fishing guide services for compensation to a person fishing in nontidal freshwater or areas of tidal water designated in subsection (f) of this section for game and freshwater fish shall obtain a freshwater fishing guide license.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An applicant for a license shall:<section prefix="(1)">Submit to the Department an application on the form that the Department requires;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pay to the Department an application fee of:<section prefix="(i)">$20 for residents or $50 for nonresidents to operate in nontidal freshwater; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">$50 for residents or $100 for nonresidents to operate in nontidal freshwater and the areas of tidal water designated in subsection (f) of this section; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Possess any necessary fishing licenses and stamps.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before a freshwater fishing guide license expires, the licensee may renew the license for an additional 1 year term. The licensee may renew a freshwater fishing guide permit if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">Otherwise is entitled to hold the license;</section><section prefix="(2)">Submits to the Department a renewal application on the form that the Department requires; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Submits to the Department the annual license application fee under subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">All fees collected by the Department pursuant to this section shall be used for monitoring the freshwater fishery, including the capture and tagging of black bass in order to develop information and methods to sustain a healthy black bass population.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall publicly report annually the amounts collected and the expenditures under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Beginning January 1, 2000 the Department may issue a freshwater fishing guide license which shall be valid for not more than 1 year and shall expire on December 31 of each year following the date of issuance.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The freshwater fishing guide license is not valid in tidal waters except for the following designated areas:<section prefix="(1)">In the upper Chesapeake Bay upstream of a line from Sandy Point to Turkey Point;</section><section prefix="(2)">In the Elk River upstream of a line from Turkey Point to the State launching ramp at Pearce Creek;</section><section prefix="(3)">In the Pond Creek upstream of a line connecting the two unnamed points at the entrance to the creek;</section><section prefix="(4)">In the Sassafras River upstream of a line from Grove Point to Howell Point;</section><section prefix="(5)">In the Still Pond Creek upstream of a line from Meeks Point to Rocky Point;</section><section prefix="(6)">In the Worton Creek upstream of a line from the point at Copeland to Handys Point;</section><section prefix="(7)">In the Fairlee Creek upstream of a line across the entrance of the creek;</section><section prefix="(8)"><section prefix="(i)">In the Chester River upstream of a line from Spaniard Point to Nichols Point;</section><section prefix="(ii)">In the Corsica River, a tributary of the Chester River, upstream of a line from Spaniard Point to Holton Point;</section><section prefix="(iii)">In the Langford Creek, a tributary of the Chester River, upstream of a line from Nichols Point to Grays Inn Point;</section><section prefix="(iv)">In the Grays Inn Creek, a tributary of the Chester River upstream from Grays Inn Point to Little Gum Point;</section></section><section prefix="(9)">In the Choptank River upstream of the Dover Bridge on Route 331;</section><section prefix="(10)">In the Blackwater River upstream of a line from the lower point of Snake Island to the southernmost point on the opposite shore;</section><section prefix="(11)">In the Transquaking River upstream of a line from Alabaster Point running magnetic north to the opposite shore;</section><section prefix="(12)">In the Nanticoke River upstream of a line from Long Point to Runaway Point;</section><section prefix="(13)">In the Wicomico River upstream of the Whitehaven ferry crossing;</section><section prefix="(14)">In the Pocomoke River upstream of the landing at Rehobeth;</section><section prefix="(15)"><section prefix="(i)">In the Maryland tributaries of the Potomac River above the Route 301 bridge; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">In the Wicomico River, a tributary of the Potomac River, upstream of a line from Mills Point in a westerly direction to the northernmost point at the entrance to Dolly Boarmans Creek;</section></section><section prefix="(16)"><section prefix="(i)">In the Patuxent River upstream of the overhead power lines north of Gods Grace Point;</section><section prefix="(ii)">In the Swanson Creek, a tributary of the Patuxent River, upstream of a line from Teague Point to Chalk Point;</section></section><section prefix="(17)">In the Patapsco River upstream of the Hanover Street crossing parallel to the Potee Street crossing;</section><section prefix="(18)">In the Back River upstream of a line from Cuckhold Point to Rocky Point;</section><section prefix="(19)">In the Middle River upstream of a line from Booby Point to Bowley Bar Point;</section><section prefix="(20)">In the Seneca Creek upstream of a line from Bowley Bar Point to Lowen Point;</section><section prefix="(21)">In the Gunpowder River upstream of a line from Weir Point to Rickett Point; and</section><section prefix="(22)">In the Bush River upstream of a line from Abbey Point to Sandy Point.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A recreational angler under the guidance of a freshwater fishing guide in tidal waters may not:<section prefix="(i)">Possess the species of fish known as striped bass or rockfish; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">From March 1 through May 31, catch or attempt to catch striped bass in spawning areas and rivers.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For the purposes of item (1)(ii) of this subsection, spawning areas and rivers include everything north of a line from Abbey Point to Worton Point, including the Sassafras River, Bohemia River, Elk River, Northeast River, Susquehanna River, Susquehanna Flats, and the Chesapeake and Delaware Canal.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">An applicant for a freshwater fishing license that will be used in tidal waters must demonstrate to the Department that the applicant has obtained the appropriate federal licenses.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Department shall adopt regulations necessary to implement this section including regulations that:<section prefix="(1)">Prohibit a person from furnishing any service as a fishing guide that requires operating a boat or vessel as part of that service without complying with appropriate federal regulations governing the operation of a vessel carrying passengers for hire;</section><section prefix="(2)">Limit to 150 the number of freshwater fishing guide licenses that will be issued annually that allow a person to operate in nontidal freshwater and tidal water areas designated in subsection (f) of this section;</section><section prefix="(3)">Allocate not more than 20% to nonresidents of the 150 freshwater fishing guide licenses that allow a person to operate in nontidal freshwater and tidal areas designated in subsection (f) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Establish provisions for maintaining a waiting list for applicants in excess of the maximum number of fishing guide licenses that allow a person to operate in nontidal freshwater and tidal areas designated in subsection (f) of this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
