<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-716" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-716</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Commissioning procedures" means the initial outfitting of a vessel immediately after the purchase of the vessel, including the installation of rigging, electronic gear, propulsion machinery, generators, or other related gear.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Fair market value" means:<section prefix="(i)">As to the sale of any vessel by a licensed dealer or a dealer licensed by another state or a foreign country, the total purchase price, as certified by the dealer on a form acceptable to the Department, less the value of any vessel that is traded in as part of the consideration for the sale, which trade-in value may not exceed the value for the trade-in vessel as shown in a national publication of used vessel values adopted by the Department;</section><section prefix="(ii)">As to any other vessel that is sold by any person other than a licensed dealer, the greater of:</section><section prefix="(iii)">As to any other vessel that is sold by any person other than a licensed dealer, either:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Sea trial" means a period of on-the-water operations, not to exceed 1 day, that is conducted:<section prefix="(i)">For the purpose of testing the effectiveness of specific maintenance, repairs, or commissioning procedures; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">For a vessel held for resale by a licensed dealer under this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Total purchase price" means the price of a vessel, including simultaneously purchased motors, spars, sails, and accessories exclusive of trailer, agreed on by the buyer and seller, with no deduction for trade-in or other nonmonetary consideration.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Used principally in this State" means that this State is the state of principal use as defined in &#xA7; 8-701(p) of this subtitle, except that in calculating where the vessel is used or used most, a vessel is not considered to be in use for any period of time that it is held for maintenance, repair, or commissioning for 30 consecutive days or more.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Vessel" has the meaning indicated in &#xA7; 8-701(s) of this subtitle.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Vessel" does not include a ship's lifeboat, a vessel propelled only by sail, or vessel manually propelled.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department shall charge a $2 fee to issue a certificate of title, a transfer of title, or a duplicate or corrected certificate of title.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 8-715(d) of this subtitle and in subsections (e) and (f) of this section, and in addition to the fees prescribed in subsection (b) of this section, an excise tax is levied at the rate of 5% of the fair market value of the vessel on:<section prefix="(i)">The issuance of every original certificate of title required for a vessel under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The issuance of every subsequent certificate of title for the sale, resale, or transfer of the vessel;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The sale within the State of every other vessel; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The possession within the State of a vessel used or to be used principally in the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding the provisions of this subsection, no tax is paid on issuance of any certificate of title if the owner of the vessel for which a certificate of title is sought was the owner of the vessel prior to June 1, 1965, or paid Maryland sales and use tax on the vessel as required by law at the time of acquisition. The Department may require the applicant for titling to submit satisfactory proof that the applicant owned the vessel prior to June 1, 1965.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the tax is not collected by a licensed dealer pursuant to &#xA7; 8-716.1 of this subtitle, the owner, whether or not applying for the issuance of a title, shall remit the tax directly to the Department within 30 days of the date of sale or, in the case of a vessel purchased outside the State, within 30 days of the date upon which the possession within the State became subject to the tax.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person is not required to pay the tax provided for in subsection (c) of this section resulting from:<section prefix="(1)">A transfer between members of the immediate family as determined by Department regulations;</section><section prefix="(2)">A transfer between members of the immediate family as determined by Department regulations of a documented vessel for which the transferor applied for and was issued a valid use sticker under &#xA7; 8-712.1 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">A transfer to a licensed dealer of a vessel for resale, rental, or leasing purposes;</section><section prefix="(4)">The holding of a vessel that is titled or numbered in another state or is federally documented, provided:<section prefix="(i)">The vessel is held for resale or listed for resale by a licensed dealer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The vessel owner signs an affidavit that there will be no use of the vessel on the waters of the State other than for a sea trial;</section></section><section prefix="(5)">Purchase of a vessel by the State or any political subdivision;</section><section prefix="(6)">Purchase of a vessel by an eleemosynary organization which the Secretary has approved;</section><section prefix="(7)">The purchase within the State of a vessel if the owner paid or incurred a liability for the Maryland sales and use tax on the vessel prior to July 1, 1986;</section><section prefix="(8)">The possession within the State of a vessel which was purchased outside the State if the owner paid or incurred a liability for the Maryland use tax on the vessel prior to July 1, 1986;</section><section prefix="(9)">The possession of a vessel in the State that is not used or to be used principally on the waters of the State and for which the issuance of a title is not sought or required under this subtitle, except that:<section prefix="(i)">A vessel is not deemed used on the waters of the State if the vessel is used for 90 days or less of a calendar year; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">If a vessel is used for more days than 90 days in a calendar year, the period of 90 days shall be counted in the determination of principal use under this subtitle;</section></section><section prefix="(10)">The possession within the State of a vessel if the current owner, before July 1, 1986:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)"/></section><section prefix="(11)">The possession within the State of a vessel that:<section prefix="(i)">Is owned by a nonprofit organization that:</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is used for the purposes of the organization;</section></section><section prefix="(12)">The possession within the State of a vessel for a period of not more than one year if the current owner is a member of the armed services and is serving on active duty in this State; or</section><section prefix="(13)">The sale of a vessel within the State if:<section prefix="(i)">The vessel is purchased from a licensed dealer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The issuance of a title is not sought or required;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The vessel is not used or to be used principally on the waters of this State;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The vessel is duly registered in another jurisdiction within 30 days of the date of purchase; and</section><section prefix="(v)">The dealer and the purchaser execute an agreement certifying the state of principal use for the vessel which is filed with the Department within 30 days of the date of purchase.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to possession within the State of a vessel if:<section prefix="(i)">The vessel was formerly:</section><section prefix="(ii)">The present owner has paid a sales or excise tax on the vessel to the other jurisdiction; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The jurisdiction to which the tax was paid would allow an exemption or credit under its sales or excise tax for excise tax on a vessel formerly paid to the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For a vessel described in paragraph (1) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">If the rate of the tax paid to the other jurisdiction is not less than the rate under subsection (c) of this section, the tax imposed under subsection (c) of this section does not apply to possession of the vessel within the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the rate of the tax paid to the other jurisdiction is less than the rate under subsection (c) of this section, the rate of the tax imposed under subsection (c) of this section on possession of the vessel within the State is the difference between the tax rate paid to the other jurisdiction and the rate under subsection (c) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Department may require the taxpayer to submit satisfactory proof of the payment of a tax to another jurisdiction and the rate of tax paid and, where applicable, evidence of principal use of a federally documented vessel in another jurisdiction.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This subsection is applicable to any vessel incurring a liability for Maryland boat excise tax on or after July 1, 1986.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may claim a credit against any tax imposed under subsection (c) of this section on a vessel for sales tax the person has paid to the State, to another state, or to the District of Columbia on materials and equipment that are incorporated into the vessel, if:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)"/></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department may require a person claiming the credit allowed under this subsection to submit satisfactory proof of payment of the sales tax and that the materials or equipment have been incorporated into the vessel.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">If the Department determines there has been an overpayment of the tax on a vessel, or an overpayment has resulted for any other reason, the Department may submit the overpayment and supporting data whether accompanied by a written claim or not to the State Comptroller for refund to the appropriate person.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For purposes of subsection (a)(4) of this section, a vessel is deemed to be held for maintenance, repair, or commissioning if:<section prefix="(i)">The maintenance, repair, or commissioning work is provided in exchange for compensation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The maintenance, repair, or commissioning work is performed pursuant to a schedule preestablished with one or more marine contractors; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The total cost of the maintenance, repair, or commissioning work is at least two times the reasonable current market cost of docking or storing the vessel.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Time spent conducting sea trials shall be included when calculating the period of time a vessel is held for maintenance, repair, or commissioning under subsection (a)(4) of this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
