<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-617</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except when fishing through ice, a person may not angle with more than three rods and lines with two...</catch_line>
  <order_by>617</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except when fishing through ice, a person may not angle with more than three rods and lines with two hooks to each line. Artificial lures or plugs with multiple or gang hooks are considered one unit.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A slat basket, commonly known as the Chesapeake Bay eel pot, may not be used to catch eels.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A State resident who has secured a resident angler's license may fish by use of a dip net only from January 1 through April 15 only in the following nontidal waters:<section prefix="(1)">The Susquehanna River in Cecil and Harford counties;</section><section prefix="(2)">In Allegany and Washington counties; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The Monocacy and Potomac rivers in Carroll and Frederick counties. However, dip nets may not be used within 50 yards of the mouth of any tributary or the breast of any dam of these rivers. A dip net may not be used in any of the waters of the State which are stocked with trout.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Only a person with a resident angler's license may use a bush-bob or bank pole;</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Bush-bobs or bank poles not exceeding a total of 25 in all and not exceeding one hook to a pole or bob may be used only in the waters of the Potomac or Monocacy River within Carroll, Washington, and Frederick counties.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Bush-bobs or bank poles may not be used on any streams stocked with trout.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A bush-bob or bank pole which has been baited with scale bait or live bait may not be used to catch suckers, catfish, carp, eels, gudgeons and every species of sunfish, including bluegills and rock bass, commonly known as redeye.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A bush-bob or bank pole may not be used except between sunset and sunrise.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Department may regulate, supervise, and control ice-fishing.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">White shad, hickory shad, and herring may be caught or taken only by angling, unless otherwise provided.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A person may catch large or small mouth black bass from nontidal waters of the State only by angling. An artificial lure is legal.</section>
  </text>
</law>
