<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-5-1101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Charge" means price or fee asked for services, entertainment, recreation performed, or products offered for sale on land or in return for invitation or permission to enter or go upon land.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Charge" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">The sharing of game, fish, or other products of recreational use;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Benefits to the land arising from the recreational use; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Contributions in kind or services to promote the management or conservation of resources on the land.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Educational purpose" includes:<section prefix="(1)">Nature study;</section><section prefix="(2)">Farm visitations for purposes of learning about the farming operation;</section><section prefix="(3)">Practice judging of livestock, dairy cattle, poultry, other animals, agronomy crops, horticultural crops, or other farm products;</section><section prefix="(4)">Organized visits to farms by school children, 4-H clubs, FFA clubs, and others as part of their educational programs;</section><section prefix="(5)">Organized visits for purposes of participating in or observing historical reenactments as part of an educational or cultural program; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Observation of historical, archaeological, or scientific sites.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Land" means land, roads, paths, trails, water, watercourses, private ways and buildings, structures, and machinery or equipment when attached to realty.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Land" does not include any structure or equipment provided by a unit of local government for the purpose of public recreation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Owner" means the owner of any estate or other interest in real property, whether possessory or nonpossessory, including the grantee of an easement.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Recreational purpose" means any recreational pursuit.</section>
  </text>
</law>
