<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-11A-09</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>09</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person who wishes to obtain an aquaculture, water column, or submerged land lease shall pay a nonrefundable application fee established by the Department, in consultation with the Aquaculture Coordinating Council, and complete and submit an application to the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An application for an aquaculture lease, water column lease, or submerged land lease shall include:<section prefix="(1)">A declaration that the applicant intends to actively use the leased area for commercial purposes; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A proposed plan for active use of the lease that shall include:<section prefix="(i)">The lessee's source and quantity of shellfish seed;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The methods and means the applicant will use to grow shellfish;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The quantity of shellfish that the lessee expects to plant and harvest, and the time for planting and harvesting, during the initial 3 years of the lease; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">A description of the labor, materials, and equipment to be used by the lessee.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The requirements for active use of a lease shall include:<section prefix="(1)">Annually planting at least one-fourth of the leased area at a minimum density of 1,000,000 shellfish seed per acre; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Complying with any other requirements established by the Department.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a lease is 20 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except for a demonstration lease under &#xA7; 4-11A-11 of this subtitle, a lease may be of any size provided that the leaseholder actively uses the area.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department shall establish, in consultation with the Aquaculture Coordinating Council, an annual amount of rent and an aquaculture development surcharge for an aquaculture, water column, or submerged land lease.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Department, as it considers necessary to protect the public health, safety, and welfare, may:<section prefix="(i)">Deny a lease application for reasonable cause; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Include any conditions in a lease.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If an application for an aquaculture lease meets the requirements of this subtitle, the Department shall survey the leased area and issue a lease to the applicant.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If an application for a submerged land lease in an area preapproved for leasing in the Atlantic Coastal Bays meets the requirements of this subtitle, the Department shall survey the leased area and issue a submerged land lease to the applicant.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an application for a submerged land or water column lease in the Chesapeake Bay or in the Atlantic Coastal Bays meets the requirements of this subtitle:<section prefix="(i)">The applicant for the lease shall mark the proposed area with a stake; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Department shall:<section prefix="1.">Advertise the application on the website of the Department and once a week for 2 weeks in a newspaper published in the county or counties where the proposed lease is to be located;</section><section prefix="2.">Notify the owners of property directly in front of the proposed activity;</section><section prefix="3.">Notify each Chair of an Oyster Committee in the county in which the proposed activity is located; and</section><section prefix="4.">Notify other interested parties that the Department deems appropriate.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Within 30 days of publication of the last advertisement under paragraph (1) of this subsection, any person who has a specific right, duty, privilege, or interest that is different from that held by the general public and may be adversely affected by the proposed lease may file a petition with the Department protesting the issuance of the lease.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The protest shall be heard in accordance with the requirements of the Administrative Procedure Act under Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Department shall hold a public informational meeting on the issuance of a lease on the request of any person.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Immediately after termination of the period prescribed in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph for filing a petition or after a final decision dismissing a protest, the Department shall survey the proposed leased area and issue a lease to the applicant.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
