<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-5-501</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>501</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following terms have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Cutting operation" means the cutting of timber for commercial purposes from five acres or more of land on which loblolly pine (Pinus taeda), shortleaf pine (Pinus echinata), or pond pine (Pinus serotina), singly or together occur and constitute 25 percent or more of the live trees on each acre.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Diameter" means the distance through the tree at the point of average thickness as measured from outside the bark to outside of bark at a point on the trunk eight inches above the general ground level.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Landowner" means the person holding title to the land or possessing the right to contract for the cutting operation thereon.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Operator" means any person, including a "landowner", who conducts any cutting operation.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Person" includes the State, any county, municipal corporation or other political subdivision of the State, or any of their units, or an individual, receiver, trustee, guardian, executor, administrator, fiduciary, or representative of any kind, or any partnership, firm, association, public or private corporation or any other entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Pine" means any loblolly (Pinus taeda), shortleaf pine (Pinus echinata), or pond pine (Pinus serotina).</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Seedling" means a young loblolly, shortleaf, or pond pine plant less than six inches in diameter.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Tree" or "timber" means any tree of a currently commercially valuable species which is six inches or more in diameter.</section>
  </text>
</law>
