<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-608" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-10-608</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A Maryland resident who possesses a current year or prior year hunting license may apply to the Department to license riparian shoreline for the purpose of establishing an offshore blind site.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An applicant for a license shall:<section prefix="(1)">Submit to the Department:<section prefix="(i)">An application on a form provided by the Department; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A signed statement that:</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Pay to the Department an application fee of $20 for each license requested.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The completed application shall be submitted to Department regional service centers or other designated local sites on days designated by the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall establish and adequately staff a site in each county where licensing occurs.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department shall provide public notice of the licensing process through the media, Internet, and other sources.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Licensing shall begin on or before the first Tuesday in August of each year on dates set by the Department.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each designated site or regional service center shall have maps available by July 15 of each year that show the location of all shoreline licensed by riparian landowners.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except for riparian landowners licensing their own property, a person may not obtain more than two licenses per day.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Each license shall apply to 250 yards of shoreline. Blind sites shall be located equidistant from the boundaries described by the license.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In Kent County and Queen Anne's County and on the nontidal waters of the Potomac River and its nontidal tributaries, only a riparian landowner owning the amount of shoreline required under &#xA7; 10-607(d) of this subtitle or a landowner's lessee, licensee, or assignee may erect and maintain a stationary blind or blind site.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Licenses are valid until June 30 of the following year and shall be issued in the order the applications are received in person.</section>
  </text>
</law>
