<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-905" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-10-905</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On payment of a reasonable fee, the Secretary may issue a game husbandry license to any person who desires to raise, breed, protect, or sell game birds or mammals.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The license shall expire on December 31 after the date of issuance and may be revoked at any time for noncompliance with the license's terms and conditions.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The license shall specify:<section prefix="(i)">The species of game birds and mammals which may be bred, raised, protected, or sold and for what purpose;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The type of fencing or other requirements necessary to prevent undesirable mixing of native wildlife and the captive game birds or mammals; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any other condition necessary to ensure adequate protection of native wildlife.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If any game bird or mammal raised in captivity is shipped or removed from the licensee's premises, the game bird or mammal must be properly identified until prepared for final consumption or disposition.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any game bird or mammal moved within the State shall be accompanied by an itemized bill of sale from the licensee.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any game bird or mammal shipped out-of-state shall have a bill of lading attached to the shipping carton, crate, or other container.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each licensee shall keep a ledger of any game bird or mammal raised, the number killed, and the number sold dead or alive. The licensee shall allow the Department:<section prefix="(1)">To enter and inspect at any reasonable hour the premises where operations are carried on; and</section><section prefix="(2)">To inspect the records.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary may prescribe, by regulation, the conditions under which a person may possess and sell game birds and mammals intended for human consumption which have been purchased from a licensed game breeder.</section>
  </text>
</law>
