<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-10-604</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person may hunt wild waterfowl while standing in water on the natural bottom only in the waters of...</catch_line>
  <order_by>604</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may hunt wild waterfowl while standing in water on the natural bottom only in the waters of the Susquehanna Flats, the nontidal waters of the Potomac River, the waters of Tangier Sound, Fishing Bay, Monie Bay, Manokin River, Big Annemessex River, Pocomoke Sound, and Kedges Straits in the waters of Dorchester, Somerset, and Wicomico counties, and in other waters of the State in areas and on days the Department prescribes by regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may hunt wild waterfowl while standing in water on the natural bottom at a licensed offshore stationary blind or blind site.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person hunting wild waterfowl while standing in water on the natural bottom shall remain at least 250 yards from all offshore stationary blinds or blind sites or another person hunting wild waterfowl offshore.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person hunting wild waterfowl while standing in water on the natural bottom shall be at least 800 yards from shore including shore emerging at mean low water except in the waters of the Potomac River, in the waters of the Susquehanna Flats, in the waters of Harford, Baltimore, and St. Mary's counties, in the waters of Tangier Sound, Fishing Bay, Monie Bay, Manokin River, Big Annemessex River, Pocomoke Sound, and Kedges Straits in the waters of Dorchester, Somerset, and Wicomico counties, or while hunting at a licensed stationary blind or blind site.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person hunting wild waterfowl while standing in water on the natural bottom shall be at least 400 yards from shore, including shore emerging at mean low water, in the following areas:<section prefix="(i)">The waters of the Susquehanna Flats;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The tidal waters of the Potomac River that the Department by regulation prescribes for hunting under subsection (a) of this section;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The waters of Harford, Baltimore, and St. Mary's counties that the Department by regulation prescribes for hunting under subsection (a) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The waters of Tangier Sound, Fishing Bay, Monie Bay, Manokin River, Big Annemessex River, Pocomoke Sound, and Kedges Straits in the waters of Dorchester, Somerset, and Wicomico counties that the Department by regulation prescribes for hunting under subsection (a) of this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person may not hunt wild waterfowl while standing in State waters on the natural bottom when the natural bottom is privately owned, unless the hunter has the written permission of the landowner.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Except at a licensed stationary blind or blind site, a nonresident may not hunt wild waterfowl while standing in water on the natural bottom unless accompanied by a Maryland resident.</section>
  </text>
</law>
