<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-1018</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1018</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Every oyster in the shell and every oyster shell sold in the State shall be measured either in a half bushel tub, a bushel tub, a bushel and a half tub, or a 3 bushel tub. A person shall measure oysters in the shell or oyster shells only with an iron circular tub having straight sides and a straight solid bottom, with holes in the bottom for draining which are no larger than 1 inch in diameter. The Department may set standards and allow other bulk containers it deems proper. Every measurement shall be taken from inside to inside. The dimensions shall be as follows:<section prefix="(i)">Half bushel tub - 15 inches across the top, 13 inches across the bottom, and 17 inches diagonally from the inside chime to the top;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Bushel tub - sixteen and one-half inches across the bottom, 18 inches across the top, and 21 inches diagonally from the inside chime to the top;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Bushel and a half tub - 18 inches across the bottom, 19 inches across the top, and 24 inches diagonally from the inside chime to the top; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Three bushel tub - 22 inches across the bottom, 24 inches across the top, and 29.26 inches diagonally from the inside chime to the top.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">All oysters measured in the shell as required by this section shall be even measure to the top of the tub only.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Due to the quantity of water contained in measures of newly shucked oysters, any proprietor or manager of a plant, house, or establishment shall measure oysters as received from the shuckers in a special gallon cup which contains no more than 9 pints. Any device other than this 9 pint gallon cup may not be used to measure any oysters received from shuckers. A Natural Resources police officer shall stamp every 9 pint gallon measure used in measuring newly shucked oysters. A proprietor or manager of any house, plant, or establishment which shucks oysters shall have every 9 pint gallon measure stamped.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Every shucked oyster sold in the State shall be sold by the standard United States one-half pint, pint, quart, or gallon liquid measure, or by fractions or multiples of these liquid measures.</section>
  </text>
</law>
