<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-5-307</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>307</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Fund" means the Mel Noland Woodland Incentives Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Mel Noland Woodland Incentives Fund in the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The purpose of the Fund is to finance the Woodland Incentives Program and the cost-share assistance established under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department shall administer the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Treasurer shall hold the Fund separately and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">As provided in &#xA7; 13-306 of the Tax - Property Article, up to $200,000 annually of the proceeds of the tax imposed by &#xA7; 13-302 of the Tax - Property Article that are attributable to the taxation of instruments of writing that transfer title to parcels of land that are entirely woodland;</section><section prefix="(2)">Revenues collected by the Department from the payment of charges imposed for Department assistance in implementation of an approved practice;</section><section prefix="(3)">Money distributed from the Chesapeake and Atlantic Coastal Bays 2010 Trust Fund under &#xA7; 8-2A-04 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Subject to approval by the Secretary and the Board of Public Works, a portion of the revenues derived from the forestry practices on designated lands owned and managed by the Department, that are conducted in accordance with applicable State law and regulation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Department shall use the Fund:<section prefix="(1)">To help fund the Woodland Incentives Program and the cost-share assistance established under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">For administrative costs calculated in accordance with &#xA7; 1-103(b)(2) of this article;</section><section prefix="(3)">To offset the costs of the Forest and Park Service for developing and approving forest stewardship plans on privately owned forest lands;</section><section prefix="(4)">To provide annual grants to the forest conservancy district boards under &#xA7; 5-605 of this title, to help facilitate their respective outreach efforts to encourage forest land owners to develop forest stewardship and other forest conservation management plans;</section><section prefix="(5)">To establish a forest health emergency contingency program to help:<section prefix="(i)">Maintain the health and vitality of publicly owned and privately owned forest lands; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Prevent or control large degradation caused by natural threats;</section></section><section prefix="(6)">To provide financial assistance, as provided in the State budget, for the administration of an urban and community forestry program established under &#xA7; 5-426 of this title, including:<section prefix="(i)">Increasing the number of communities with tree canopy goals;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Facilitating compliance with the Chesapeake Bay Program's forestry targets;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Supporting the use of urban tree canopy expansion for air quality improvement purposes; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Helping achieve implementation of Regional Greenhouse Gas Initiative offset opportunities in urban areas;</section></section><section prefix="(7)">To help fund a forest marketing and utilization program in the Department to provide financial assistance to help support, stimulate, and market innovative and creative ways to enhance the production of value-added wood products;</section><section prefix="(8)">To help the Department, in cooperation with appropriate public and private sector entities, develop and expand:<section prefix="(i)">A forest mitigation banking system;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A carbon credit or carbon sequestration program;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A clean water credit trading system;</section><section prefix="(iv)">An environmental services credit trading program; and</section><section prefix="(v)">A renewable energy credit trading system; and</section></section><section prefix="(9)">To help offset administrative costs for providing staff assistance to the Sustainable Forestry Council established under &#xA7; 5-204 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The amount of revenues collected under subsection (f)(1) of this section shall be included in the report required under Article 24, &#xA7; 2-101 of the Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The amount of the grants under subsection (g)(4) of this section shall be determined by the Department and eligibility for the grants shall be contingent on each board providing an in-kind match as certified by the Secretary.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">On or before June 30 of each year, the Department shall report to the Senate Education, Health, and Environmental Affairs Committee and the House Environmental Matters Committee, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, on the use of funds credited to the Fund, including an identification of and the reasons for those revenues derived from forestry practices on designated lands owned and managed by the Department that were not credited to the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Treasurer shall invest the money of the Fund in the same manner as other State money may be invested.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any investment earnings of the Fund shall be credited to the General Fund of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">Expenditures from the Fund may be made only in accordance with the State budget.</section>
  </text>
</law>
