<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-10-405</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>405</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Pursuant to &#xA7; 10-205 of this title, the Department shall establish by regulation and publish by July 1 each year the open season to hunt forest and upland game birds and mammals.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided under &#xA7; 10-410 of this subtitle, the Department may not authorize hunting on a Sunday.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">
          <section prefix="1.">Subject to subsubparagraph 2 of this subparagraph, the Department shall establish by regulation by July 1 of each year a junior deer hunt to occur on a Saturday and Sunday on the same weekend during a deer hunting season.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The regulations adopted under this subparagraph may not authorize the junior deer hunt to occur on a Sunday in a county in which deer hunting is not authorized for that Sunday.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A person may participate in the junior deer hunt if the person:<section prefix="1.">Is 16 years of age or younger;</section><section prefix="2.">Possesses a valid hunting license or is exempt from hunting license requirements; and</section><section prefix="3.">Is accompanied by a person who:</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A person who participates in the junior deer hunt may use a firearm to hunt deer on the days of the hunt.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the Department by regulation pursuant to &#xA7; 10-205 of this title restricts or reduces the number of days normally allowed to hunt, possess, sell, purchase, ship, transport, carry, or export any game bird or mammal because of an emergency situation, the Department may extend the open season to provide a comparable number of days in any given season.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department shall establish by regulation the maximum open season for hunting crows which is permissible under federal law, and shall include in its regulations such provisions as are permitted under federal law for control of crows at any time they are found to be committing or about to commit depredation upon ornamental or shade trees, agricultural crops, livestock or wildlife, or when concentrated in such numbers and manner as to constitute a health hazard or other nuisance.</section>
  </text>
</law>
