<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-725.7</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>725.7</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Marine gathering" means an intentional congregation of at least 100 vessels in the waters of the State that, by its nature, circumstances, or location, creates extra or unusual hazards to life or property.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)"> "Marine gathering" does not include:<section prefix="1.">A race, a regatta, a parade, an exhibition, or other marine event for which a permit is required by the United States Coast Guard;</section><section prefix="2.">A docking competition; or</section><section prefix="3.">Vessels docked or moored at a marina.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Permit" means a marine gathering permit issued in accordance with this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not sponsor or hold a marine gathering without obtaining a written permit from the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The organizer or sponsor of the marine gathering shall submit a permit application to the Department and pay an application fee established by the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The application fee may not exceed the cost of processing the permit.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department may not require the application to be submitted more than 45 days before the marine gathering.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall adopt regulations governing the application and issuance of the permit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a permit is needed to ensure public safety, the Department shall issue a permit in accordance with paragraphs (3) and (4) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department may require in the terms of a permit one or more of the following requirements:<section prefix="(i)">The presence of security officers at the marine gathering;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The presence of rescue personnel or lifeguards at the marine gathering;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The placement of buoys at the marine gathering; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Limitations on the duration of the marine gathering.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Department may:<section prefix="(i)">Recommend additional actions to an applicant to further safeguard the participants of the marine gathering; but</section><section prefix="(ii)">Not require any additional terms or conditions in a permit beyond what may be required under paragraph (3) of this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Before issuing a marine gathering permit, the Department shall notify the local law enforcement unit of the county in which the marine gathering will occur and public safety organizations that the Department considers necessary.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A police officer may terminate and disband a marine gathering:<section prefix="(1)">Held without the necessary permit; or</section><section prefix="(2)">In violation of the terms of a permit.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who violates this section or a regulation adopted under this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $1,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who commits a second or subsequent violation of this section or a regulation adopted under this section is:<section prefix="(i)">Guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $5,000; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Liable to the State for the cost of disbanding the marine gathering.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
