<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-11C-01</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Seafood Program Management Team to be administered by the Maryland Cooperative Extension....</catch_line>
  <order_by>01</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Seafood Program Management Team to be administered by the Maryland Cooperative Extension.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Team shall:<section prefix="(1)">Establish and monitor a grant program for the implementation of appropriate projects that support the economic health of the Maryland seafood industry;</section><section prefix="(2)">Prioritize, select for funding, and oversee seafood industry projects under a rapid response structure; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Examine new technologies, equipment, raw and value-added products, feasibility studies, and market development and cost control strategies.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Team shall consist of the following 18 individuals appointed by the Department:<section prefix="(1)">12 members including:<section prefix="(i)">1 holder of a tidal fisheries license;</section><section prefix="(ii)">1 crab processor;</section><section prefix="(iii)">1 oyster packer;</section><section prefix="(iv)">1 surf clam processor;</section><section prefix="(v)">1 finfish processor;</section><section prefix="(vi)">1 value-added processor;</section><section prefix="(vii)">1 wholesale distributor;</section><section prefix="(viii)">1 seafood distributor;</section><section prefix="(ix)">1 aquafarmer;</section><section prefix="(x)">1 representative of the Chesapeake Bay Seafood Industries Association;</section><section prefix="(xi)">1 representative of the Maryland Watermen's Association; and</section><section prefix="(xii)">1 representative of the Seafood Marketing Advisory Commission; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">6 advisors, including 1 representative each from:<section prefix="(i)">The University of Maryland, College Park;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The University of Maryland Eastern Shore;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Department;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The Department of the Environment;</section><section prefix="(v)">The Department of Natural Resources; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">The Department of Health and Mental Hygiene.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Team members shall select the chair from among the Team members.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Only Team members may vote in the selection of projects to be funded.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the invitation of the members, Team advisors may assist with project design, proposal preparation, and project-related research.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a project is funded by the Team, the Team shall make public the project's design and results on the Department's website and by other methods determined by the Team or as required by law.</section>
  </text>
</law>
