<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-425" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-10-425</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not conduct a waterfowl processing operation unless the person has a waterfowl processing operation license issued by the Department under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department may not charge a fee for any license issued under the provisions of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person desiring a waterfowl processing operation license shall apply on a form the Department supplies.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Upon receipt of a completed application, the Department shall issue a license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A waterfowl processing operation license:<section prefix="(1)">Shall expire on June 30 following the date of issuance; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May be renewed by providing a completed renewal application.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A waterfowl processing operation may not receive or have in custody any wild waterfowl unless the wild waterfowl is properly tagged as required by State and federal laws and regulations.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A waterfowl processing operation shall keep on forms provided by the Department a record of:<section prefix="(1)">The number of each species of wild waterfowl processed, received by, or in the custody of the operation;</section><section prefix="(2)">The location (county and state) where each wild waterfowl received by the operation was taken;</section><section prefix="(3)">The date each wild waterfowl was received by the operation;</section><section prefix="(4)">The name and address of the person from whom each wild waterfowl was received;</section><section prefix="(5)">The date each wild waterfowl was disposed of by the operation; and</section><section prefix="(6)">The name and address of the person to whom each wild waterfowl was delivered.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A licensee shall submit a copy of the records required by subsection (e) of this section to the Department annually prior to the March 1 immediately following the date of the issuance of the license.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">At any reasonable hour, a licensee shall allow any Natural Resources police officer or any law enforcement officer to enter and inspect the premises where the operation is conducted and to inspect records.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">In addition to any other penalty under this title, the Department may suspend or revoke the license of a licensee who is convicted of violating a provision of this title, a regulation issued under this title, or a federal game law or regulation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
