<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-2A-07</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>07</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Any person who violates the provisions of &#xA7; 4-2A-05 of this subtitle, or fails to procure any permit required by &#xA7; 4-2A-05 of this subtitle, or who violates the terms of any permit shall be fined not more than $1,000 or be imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Any Natural Resources police officer or any law enforcement officer may conduct searches as provided by law, and execute a warrant to search for and seize any equipment, business records, merchandise, fish taken, used or possessed in connection with a violation of any subsection. Any Natural Resources police officer or law enforcement officer, without a warrant, may arrest any person who the officer has probable cause to believe is violating, in his presence or view, this subtitle, any rule or regulation, or permit provided for by this subtitle. Any Natural Resources police officer or law enforcement officer who has made an arrest of a person in connection with any violation may search the person, premises, or business records at the time of arrest and may seize any fish, records, or property taken, or used in connection with any violation.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Equipment, merchandise, fish or records seized under the provisions of subsection (b) of this section shall be held by any Natural Resources police officer or law enforcement officer pending disposition of court proceedings, and thereafter shall be forfeited to the State for destruction or disposition as the Secretary may deem appropriate. Prior to forfeiture the Secretary may direct the transfer of fish so seized to a qualified zoological, educational, or scientific institution for safekeeping, costs to be assessable to the defendant. The Secretary may issue rules and regulations to implement this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
