<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-743" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-8-743</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Child" means an individual who is under the age of 13 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Personal flotation device" means a Type I, II, III, or V U.S. Coast Guard approved personal flotation device that is:<section prefix="(i)">The proper size for the child; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">In good and serviceable condition.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Vessel" means:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Vessel" does not include a vessel carrying passengers for hire under the command of an individual licensed by the U.S. Coast Guard to carry passengers for hire, or a vessel displaying a valid seafood harvester's license number while engaged in the harvesting of seafood for sale.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not operate or permit the operation of a vessel under 21 feet in length while there is present in the vessel a child not wearing a personal flotation device which is securely and properly attached to the child.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the child is under the age of 4 years, the personal flotation device shall feature additional safety precautions, as appropriate for an infant, toddler, or young child, so as to:<section prefix="(i)">Hold the child securely within the personal flotation device, including a strap that is secured between the child's legs to fasten together the front and back of the personal flotation device;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Maintain the buoyancy of the child, including an inflatable headrest or high collar; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Ensure the ready accessibility of the child from the vessel, including a web handle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subsection (b) does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">A vessel that is moored or anchored; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A child who is below deck or in an enclosed cabin.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
