<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-2A-06</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>06</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary shall establish programs, including acquisition of land or aquatic habitat or interests therein, necessary for the conservation of threatened or endangered species of fish. The Secretary shall use all vested authority to carry out the provisions of this subsection.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In carrying out programs authorized by this section, the Secretary shall consult with other states having a common interest in particular species of endangered or threatened species of fish and may enter into agreements with federal agencies, other states, political subdivisions of this State, or with individuals with respect to programs designed to conserve endangered or threatened species of fish including agreements for administration and management of any that are established under this section or utilized for conservation of endangered or threatened species of fish.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Governor shall review other programs administered by him and utilize these programs in furtherance of the purposes of this subtitle. All State departments and agencies, in consultation with and with the assistance of the Secretary, shall utilize their authorities in furtherance of the purposes of this subtitle by carrying out programs for the conservation of endangered species and threatened species listed pursuant to &#xA7; 4-2A-04(f) of this subtitle and by taking any action necessary to insure that actions authorized, funded, or carried out by them do not jeopardize the continued existence of the endangered species or threatened species or result in the destruction or modification of habitat of the species which is deemed by the Secretary to be critical.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary shall adopt rules and regulations necessary to implement this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
