<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="gnr" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-5-1612</section_number>
  <catch_line>The enforcement provisions in this section and &#xA7; 5-1608 of this subtitle are in lieu of any other p...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1612</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The enforcement provisions in this section and &#xA7; 5-1608 of this subtitle are in lieu of any other provision in this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to the enforcement authority granted the Department, the enforcement provisions of this section may be exercised by any local authority that has adopted a forest conservation program, in addition to any enforcement provisions available to the local authority.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department or a local authority may revoke an approved forest conservation plan for cause, including violation of conditions of the plan, obtaining a plan approval by misrepresentation, failing to disclose a relevant or material fact, or change in conditions. The Department or a local authority shall notify the violator in writing and provide an opportunity for a hearing.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department or a local authority may issue a stop work order against any person who violates any provision of this subtitle or any regulation, order, approved plan, or management agreement.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who violates any provision of this subtitle or any regulation, order, plan, or management agreement under this subtitle is liable for a penalty not exceeding $1,000 which may be recovered in a civil action brought by the Department or a local authority. Each day a violation continues is a separate violation under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court may issue an injunction requiring the person to cease the violation and take corrective action to restore or reforest an area.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A local authority conducting enforcement activity in accordance with this section or &#xA7; 5-1608(c) of this subtitle shall give notice to the Department within 15 days after the commencement of the enforcement activity.</section>
  </text>
</law>
