<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-5-801</section_number>
  <catch_line>The purpose of this compact is to promote effective prevention and control of forest fires in the Mi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>801</order_by>
  <text>The purpose of this compact is to promote effective prevention and control of forest fires in the Middle Atlantic region of the United States by the development of integrated forest fire plans, by the maintenance of adequate forest fire fighting services by the member states, and by providing for mutual aid in fighting forest fires among the compacting states of the region and with states which are party to other regional forest fire protection compacts or agreements.<section prefix="(a)">The Governor, on behalf of the State, may execute a compact in substantially the following form, with one or more of the states of Delaware, New Jersey, Ohio, Pennsylvania, Virginia, and West Virginia. The General Assembly signifies in advance its approval and ratification of this compact:</section><section prefix="(b)">When the Governor has executed the compact on behalf of the State and caused a verified copy to be filed with the Secretary of State, and when it has been ratified by one or more of the states named in subsection (a) of this section, then the compact becomes operative and effective as between this State and the other state. The Governor may take the necessary action to complete the exchange of official documents between this State and any other state which ratifies the compact.</section><section prefix="(c)">The Secretary, or someone designated by him, shall act as compact administrator for the State and perform the functions required under subsection (a) of this section.</section><section prefix="(d)">The Department shall take the necessary action to integrate the State forest fire plan with the regional forest fire plan formulated by the compact administrators, and adjust and expand the plan as necessary to comply with subsection (a) of this section.</section></text>
</law>
