<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-412" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-10-412</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Baiting" means the placing, exposing, depositing, distributing, or scattering of shelled, shucked, or unshucked corn, wheat or other grain, salt, or other feed so as to constitute for birds a lure, attraction, or enticement to, on, or over any areas where persons are attempting to hunt them.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Baited area" means any area where shelled, shucked, or unshucked corn, wheat or other grain, salt, or other feed capable of luring, attracting, or enticing birds is directly or indirectly placed, exposed, deposited, distributed, or scattered, and this area remains a baited area for 10 days following complete removal of all corn, wheat or other grain, salt, or other feed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not hunt wetland game birds or upland game birds, except quail and pheasant, by the aid of baiting, or on or over any baited area.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section does not prohibit:<section prefix="(1)">The hunting of wetland and upland game birds on or over standing crops, flooded standing crops (including aquatics), flooded harvested croplands, grain crops properly shocked on the field where grown, or grains found scattered solely as the result of normal agricultural planting or harvesting; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The hunting of all upland game birds on or over any lands where shelled, shucked, or unshucked corn, wheat or other grain, salt, or other feed has been distributed or scattered as the result of bona fide agricultural operations or procedures, or as a result of manipulation of a crop or other feed on the land where grown for wildlife purposes. Manipulation for wildlife management purposes does not include the distributing or scattering of grain or other feed once it has been removed from or stored on the field where grown.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">By rule or regulation, the Department may exempt from this section captive raised mallard ducks which are released on a regulated shooting ground to be shot at immediately after release.</section>
  </text>
</law>
