<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-10-910</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>910</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Captive Wildlife Advisory Committee. It shall be composed of 7 members appointed by the Director of the Forest, Park and Wildlife Service.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Of the 7 Committee members:<section prefix="(1)">1 shall be a representative of the pet industry;</section><section prefix="(2)">1 shall be a falconer;</section><section prefix="(3)">1 shall be a representative of the shooting preserve industry;</section><section prefix="(4)">1 shall be a representative of the game breeding industry;</section><section prefix="(5)">1 shall be a representative of a humane society or like organization; and</section><section prefix="(6)">2 shall be members of the general public.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The term of a member is 3 years. The terms of the members are staggered. The terms of the initial appointees expire as follows:<section prefix="(1)">1 member representing the general public, the member representing the pet industry, and the falconry member after 3 years;</section><section prefix="(2)">1 member representing the general public, the member representing the game breeding industry, and the member representing a humane society or like organization after 2 years; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The member representing the shooting preserve industry after 1 year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">From among its members, the Director shall designate a chairman and a vice chairman of the Committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Committee shall meet at the times and places that the Committee determines.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A member of the Committee:<section prefix="(1)">May not receive compensation; but</section><section prefix="(2)">Is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Committee shall:<section prefix="(1)">Review pertinent proposed regulations and give recommendations and comments to the Director; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Advise the Director on other matters relating to captive wildlife.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
