<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gnr" order_by="" level="1">Natural Resources</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gnr-4-1001</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1001</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Buy boat" means any boat engaged or used in buying, selling, or transporting oysters caught by other boats.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Chesapeake Bay" means the waters, commonly known as the Chesapeake Bay as defined by the charts of the Oyster Survey of 1906 to 1912, and its amendments.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"County waters" means the waters lying within the territorial limits of any county in the State as defined by the charts of the Oyster Survey of 1906 to 1912, and its amendments.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Diving apparatus" means any diving equipment that is supplied with air from the surface through a hose, or diving equipment generally referred to as scuba, the use of which allows a person to catch oysters by hand beneath the water.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Dredge" includes any dredge, scoop, scrape, or similar device used in catching oysters or clams by dragging.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Dredge boat" means any sailboat which does not have a screw, propeller, engine, turbine, or other device for self-propulsion, used in catching oysters or clams by dredge.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Dunnaged boat" means any boat having a false bottom, partition, ceiling, or deck, designed to diminish or having the effect of diminishing visible cargo space.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Handscrape" means any dredge cast and hauled by hand and without any winch, winder, or spool.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Hard-shell clams" mean mollusks of the species Mercenaria mercenaria.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Harvest" means to take, kill, trap, gather, catch or in any manner reduce any hard-shell clam, soft-shell clam, or oyster to personal possession or to attempt to engage in this conduct.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Harvest reserve area" means an area designated by the Department for the restoration and harvesting of oysters on a rotational basis.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Hydraulic clam dredge" means any device used for dredging clams which consists of a manifold through which water is forced under pressure for the purpose of digging clams and working them into the mouth of the dredge where the clams then are brought up to boat level by means of an escalator. "Hydraulic clam dredge" includes the vessel on which the dredge is carried.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Marketable oyster" means any oyster measuring 3 inches or more from hinge to mouth.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Natural oyster bar" means any submerged oyster bar, reef, rock, or area represented as an oyster bar on the charts of the Oyster Survey of 1906 to 1912 and its amendments.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Packer" means any person having a fixed place of business and buying, selling, packing, shucking, or preparing oysters for sale, trade, barter, or shipment to any dealer, merchant, or retailer.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Patent tongs" means any pincers, nippers, tongs, or similar device used to catch oysters and clams raised with rope, cable, or other hoisting gear.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Shinnecock rake" means a hand tool used to catch hard-shell clams or oysters. It usually consists of a tooth bar with projecting long, outwardly, and upwardly curving teeth which are progressively smaller towards the ends, form a basket, and are set transversely at the end of a long, usually wooden handle.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Soft-shell clams" means mollusks of the species Mya arenaria and of the species Genus Tagelus.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Tong" means any pincers, nippers, tongs, or similar device used in catching oysters and clams and consisting of 2 shafts or handles and a metal body composed of 2 opposable and complementary baskets that:<section prefix="(i)">Are opened, closed, and emptied entirely by hand; and</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">Are lifted by hand; or</section><section prefix="2.">May use power to assist lifting the tongs with a single lifting cable or rope attached at only a single point on 1 shaft of the tongs.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Tong" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Shaft tongs; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Hand tongs.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Tong" does not include a patent tong.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(u)">"Tong boat" means any boat on or from which tongs or patent tongs are used in catching oysters.</section>
  </text>
</law>
