<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Department" means the Department of Housing and Community Development.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"First user" means a person who initially installs an industrialized building or manufactured home in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"First user" does not include a person who subsequently buys a building that consists wholly or partly of an industrialized building.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Industrialized building" means a building assembly or system of building subassemblies manufactured in its entirety, or in substantial part, off site and transported to a site for installation or erection, with or without other specified components, as a finished building or as part of a finished building that comprises two or more industrialized building units.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Industrialized building" includes the electrical, plumbing, heating, ventilating, insulation, and other service systems of the building assembly or system of building subassemblies if the service systems are installed at the off site manufacture or assembly point.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Industrialized building" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">open frame construction that can be completely inspected on site;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a manufactured home; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a building 8 body feet or less in width and 40 body feet or less in length that is:<section prefix="1.">used for business purposes, mobile offices, or storage; and</section><section prefix="2.">not open to the general public.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Install" means to assemble an industrialized building or manufactured home on site and to affix the industrialized building or manufactured home to land, a foundation, footings, or an existing building.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Local enforcement agency" means an agency of the governing body of a county or municipal corporation that enforces laws that govern the construction of buildings.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Manufactured home" means a structure that:<section prefix="(i)">is transportable in one or more sections;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is 8 body feet or more in width and 30 body feet or more in length;</section><section prefix="(iii)">is built on a permanent chassis; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">is designed to be used as a dwelling, with or without a permanent foundation, when connected to the required utilities.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Manufactured home" includes the plumbing, heating, air-conditioning, and electrical systems contained in the structure.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Manufactured Home Construction and Safety Standards Act" means the National Manufactured Home Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1974, 42 U.S.C. &#xA7; 5401 et seq.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Site" means the entire tract, subdivision, or parcel of land on which an industrialized building or manufactured home is installed.</section>
  </text>
</law>
