<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-14-305</section_number>
  <catch_line>If the Governor proclaims that a state of emergency exists, each law enforcement agency, fire compan...</catch_line>
  <order_by>305</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If the Governor proclaims that a state of emergency exists, each law enforcement agency, fire company, or rescue squad of the State, a county, or municipal corporation shall:<section prefix="(1)">cooperate in any manner requested by the Governor or the Governor's designated representative; and</section><section prefix="(2)">subject to subsection (b) of this section, allow the use of its equipment, facilities, and personnel if the use is required by the Governor or the Governor's designated representative.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The use of equipment, facilities, and personnel under subsection (a)(2) of this section may not substantially interfere with the normal duties of a law enforcement agency, fire company, or rescue squad located outside an area designated by the Governor as an emergency area.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, if the Governor proclaims that a state of emergency exists, the Department of State Police may take any action it considers necessary to assist local law enforcement agencies.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any action that the Department of State Police takes under this subsection shall be reasonably calculated effectively to control and terminate the public emergency.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A law enforcement agency of a county or municipal corporation shall notify the Secretary of State Police if the local law enforcement agency receives notice of a threatened or actual disturbance that indicates the possibility of serious domestic violence.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 14-306 of this subtitle, each law enforcement agency, fire company, or rescue squad of the State, a county, or municipal corporation within an emergency area shall operate under the direction of the person designated by order of the Governor.</section>
  </text>
</law>
