<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-506" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-13-506</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c) of this section, the Maryland Defense Force may not be required to serve outside the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not apply to any instance in which the Maryland Defense Force as part of the organized militia of the State is ordered into service of the United States by the President pursuant to the Constitution and laws of the United States.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On request of the governor of another state, the Governor of this State may order the Maryland Defense Force to serve outside the State to assist the military or other public safety forces of the requesting state.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Governor of this State may recall the Maryland Defense Force from the other state.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If fresh pursuit is authorized by law of another state, any organization, unit, or detachment of the Maryland Defense Force, on the order of the commanding officer of the organization, unit, or detachment, may continue in fresh pursuit of insurrectionists, saboteurs, or enemies outside of this State into the other state until:<section prefix="(1)">the insurrectionists, saboteurs, or enemies are apprehended; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the military or law enforcement forces of the other state or forces of the United States have had a reasonable opportunity to pursue or apprehend the insurrectionists, saboteurs, or enemies.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An organization, unit, or detachment of the Maryland Defense Force shall surrender without unnecessary delay an individual apprehended in another state to the military or law enforcement force of:<section prefix="(i)">the state of apprehension; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the United States.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The surrender of an individual apprehended under paragraph (1) of this subsection to the military or law enforcement forces of another state is not a waiver by this State of the right to extradite or prosecute the individual for a crime committed in this State.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
