<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-405" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-13-405</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Institution" means:<section prefix="(i)">any campus of the University System of Maryland, any community college established under Title 16 of the Education Article, Morgan State University, or St. Mary's College;</section><section prefix="(ii)">any private institution of higher education that grants a member a tuition waiver of at least 50%;</section><section prefix="(iii)">any public postsecondary vocational-technical or trade school; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">any private postsecondary vocational-technical or trade school that grants a member a tuition waiver of at least 50%.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Member" means an individual who:<section prefix="(i)">is regularly enlisted in the National Guard; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">holds a commission in the National Guard as:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Tuition" means the basic instructional charge for undergraduate graduate, professional, vocational-technical, and trade school credit courses and related fees at an institution.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Tuition" does not include charges for self-supporting programs.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To the extent that funds are provided in the State budget, the Department may provide assistance equal to 50% of the cost of in-State tuition for any regularly scheduled undergraduate credit course, graduate credit course, professional credit course, vocational-technical course, or trade course for any active member attending an institution who is certified as eligible by the Adjutant General.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member who receives assistance under paragraph (1) of this subsection for an undergraduate credit, vocational-technical, or trade course shall remain an active member for at least 2 years following the completion of the course.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member who receives assistance under paragraph (1) of this subsection for a graduate or professional credit course shall remain an active member for at least 4 years following the completion of the course.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Adjutant General may not certify a member as eligible unless the member is:<section prefix="(i)">enlisted and has at least 24 months remaining to serve on the current enlistment of the member; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an officer or warrant officer and agrees in writing to serve for a minimum of 24 months.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The 24-month requirement runs from the first day of classes for the semester.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a recipient of tuition assistance under this section is discharged from the National Guard for a reason designated by the Adjutant General, the assistance terminates and the member shall reimburse the Department the amount of tuition assistance received for that semester within 30 days of discharge.</section>
  </text>
</law>
