<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-14-907</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>907</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An individual may not fail to register under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An individual who violates subsection (a) of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $50.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">After the Governor issues a proclamation under this subtitle, the county sheriffs, the police department of Baltimore City, and any other officer of the State, a county, or municipal corporation charged with enforcing the law shall:<section prefix="(1)">seek diligently the names and addresses of able-bodied individuals within their respective jurisdictions who are between 18 and 50 years old, inclusive, and not regularly or continuously employed or engaged in a lawful and useful occupation and who have failed to register under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">obtain criminal summonses or warrants from a District Court commissioner for the arrest of individuals described in item (1) of this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The District Court shall send the name of each individual convicted of failing to register and the information specified in subsection (c)(1) of this section to the clerk of the circuit court of the county in which the individual resides.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The circuit court clerks shall register each individual convicted of failing to register under this subtitle and report the registration to the Governor in accordance with &#xA7; 14-903 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Governor shall assign each individual registered under subsection (e) of this section to work as provided in &#xA7; 14-904 of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
