<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-202" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-4-202</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a School Bus Safety Enforcement Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The purpose of the Fund is to assist law enforcement agencies in addressing the problem of drivers illegally failing to stop for school vehicles.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Executive Director shall administer the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Executive Director shall receive from the Fund each fiscal year the amount, not exceeding $50,000 in a fiscal year, necessary to offset its costs in administering this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Treasurer shall hold the Fund separately and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund in conjunction with the Executive Director.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">money credited to the Fund under &#xA7; 17-106(e) of the Transportation Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">money from any other source accepted for the benefit of the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(3)">investment earnings of the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Treasurer shall invest the money of the Fund in the same manner as other State money may be invested.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Expenditures from the Fund may only be made:<section prefix="(1)">in accordance with the State budget; or</section><section prefix="(2)">by the budget amendment procedure as provided in &#xA7; 7-209 of the State Finance and Procurement Article, if at least 45 days have passed since the budget amendment and supporting information were submitted to the budget committees for their review and comment.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
