<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-905" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-905</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board shall formulate regulations for the safe construction, use, installation, maintenance, repair, and inspection of boilers and pressure vessels in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The regulations formulated by the Board shall conform as nearly as possible to the requirements of:<section prefix="(1)">this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the following codes as amended and interpreted:<section prefix="(i)">the Boiler and Pressure Vessel Code of the American Society of Mechanical Engineers;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Inspection Code of the National Board of Boiler and Pressure Vessel Inspectors;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Code for Power Piping, B31.1 of the American Society of Mechanical Engineers;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Code for Controls and Safety Devices for Automatically Fired Boilers, CSD-1 of the American Society of Mechanical Engineers;</section><section prefix="(v)">NFPA 85 Boiler and Combustion Systems Hazards Code; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">the Code for Chemical Plant and Petroleum Refinery Piping, B31.3 of the American Society of Mechanical Engineers.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The regulations formulated by the Board may be adopted by the Commissioner subject to the approval of the Secretary.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board and the Commissioner shall submit proposed amendments to regulations adopted under this subtitle to be consistent with the Maryland Building Rehabilitation Code within 90 days after any amendments to the Maryland Building Rehabilitation Code are adopted by the Department of Housing and Community Development under Subtitle 10 of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
