<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-702</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>702</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Commission" means the State Fire Prevention Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"NFPA 70" means the most recent edition of the National Electrical Code adopted by the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"NFPA 101" means the most recent edition of the National Life Safety Code adopted by the Commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other provisions of this article, this section applies in Baltimore City.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Baltimore City, the Baltimore City Fire Department shall enforce this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In Baltimore City, appeals concerning this section shall be made to the Baltimore City fire board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to:<section prefix="(i)">a public building or structure owned by the State or a subdivision of the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a hotel, apartment building, lodging house, hospital, nursing home, dormitory, or educational building with:<section prefix="1.">a potential evening occupancy of more than 25 individuals; and</section><section prefix="2.">at least 4 stories, excluding attics and basements.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each building or structure subject to this subsection shall be equipped with adequate emergency power and lighting in accordance with NFPA 101.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The emergency electrical power supply system required by this section may be powered by generators, battery packs, or other similar devices at the discretion of the owner of the building or structure.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall administer this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall adopt regulations to enforce this section, including regulations that require:<section prefix="(i)">emergency electrical systems in accordance with NFPA 101, to provide sufficient light in halls, corridors, and stairways during outages or blockages of regular services to facilitate the movement of individuals in the event of an emergency;</section><section prefix="(ii)">sufficient exit signs that are adequately lighted to guide individuals on the premises;</section><section prefix="(iii)">sufficient emergency electrical power to operate elevators, electrical facilities in hospital operating rooms, hospital X-ray equipment, and other emergency equipment that are necessary to the proper operation of medical services in hospitals and nursing homes;</section><section prefix="(iv)">adequate emergency electric lighting in accordance with NFPA 101 in each building for commercial, mercantile, industrial, storage, office, or similar purposes if the building is at least 4 stories, excluding attics and basements, and evening occupancy is more than 25 individuals; and</section><section prefix="(v)">installation and operation of emergency power and lighting in accordance with NFPA 101 and NFPA 70.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">For purposes of paragraph (2)(iii) of this subsection, the Commission shall consult with the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene to evaluate the requirements to be adopted for the operation of hospitals and nursing homes.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In making this evaluation, the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene shall consider the size and nature of the particular hospital or nursing home operation.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, the State Fire Marshal shall enforce this section and the regulations adopted by the Commission so that individuals on the premises are reasonably protected in the event of an emergency.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to the penalties of &#xA7; 6-601 of this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
