<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-903</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>903</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, this subtitle applies to all boilers and pressure vessels.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This subtitle does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">a boiler or pressure vessel that is under federal control or regulation;</section><section prefix="(2)">a pressure vessel that:<section prefix="(i)">is used to transport or store compressed gases;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is constructed in compliance with specifications of the U.S. Department of Transportation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">when charged with gas, is marked, maintained, and periodically requalified for use, as required by the regulations of the U.S. Department of Transportation;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">an air tank that is located on a vehicle that is operating under the rules of other State authorities and is used for carrying passengers or freight;</section><section prefix="(4)">an air tank that is installed on the right-of-way of a railroad and is used directly in the operation of trains;</section><section prefix="(5)">a pressure vessel that does not exceed:<section prefix="(i)">5 cubic feet in volume and 250 psig pressure;</section><section prefix="(ii)">1 1/2 cubic feet in volume and 600 psig pressure; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">an inside diameter of 6 inches with no limitation on pressure;</section></section><section prefix="(6)">a pressure vessel that operates at a working pressure not exceeding 15 psig;</section><section prefix="(7)">subject to subsection (c) of this section, a vessel that contains water under pressure, including a vessel that contains air, the compression of which serves only as a cushion, if neither of the following limitations is exceeded:<section prefix="(i)">a design pressure of 300 psig; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a design temperature of 210 degrees Fahrenheit;</section></section><section prefix="(8)">a hot water supply boiler that is equipped with a safety relief valve and is directly fired with oil, gas, or electricity if none of the following limitations is exceeded:<section prefix="(i)">heat input of 200,000 BTU/hour;</section><section prefix="(ii)">water temperature of 210 degrees Fahrenheit; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">nominal water capacity of 120 gallons;</section></section><section prefix="(9)">a mechanical device of any of the following types:<section prefix="(i)">a pump;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a compressor;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a turbine;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a generator; or</section><section prefix="(v)">a hydraulic or pneumatic cylinder; or</section></section><section prefix="(10)">the water-containing part of an air-conditioning or refrigeration system condenser or evaporator:<section prefix="(i)">that uses halocarbon refrigerant;</section><section prefix="(ii)">that is constructed in accordance with the requirements of ANSI/ASHRAE Standard 15 (the Safety Code for Mechanical Refrigeration) in effect at the time of construction; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">if neither of the following limitations is exceeded:<section prefix="1.">a design pressure of 300 psig; and</section><section prefix="2.">a design temperature of 210 degrees Fahrenheit.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For purposes of subsection (b)(7) of this section, water may contain additives if the ASTM flash point of the aqueous solution at atmospheric pressure is 185 degrees Fahrenheit or higher.</section>
  </text>
</law>
