<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-4-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Executive Director may make grants to law enforcement agencies from the Fund....</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Executive Director may make grants to law enforcement agencies from the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Executive Director shall establish procedures for law enforcement agencies to apply for grants from the Fund and for the evaluation of progress in addressing the problem of drivers illegally failing to stop for school vehicles.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">When making grants from the Fund, the Executive Director shall consider:<section prefix="(1)">the extent of the problem of drivers illegally failing to stop for school vehicles in the area identified by the law enforcement agency applying for a grant;</section><section prefix="(2)">the law enforcement agency's goals and plans with respect to enhanced enforcement efforts that relate to &#xA7; 21-706 of the Transportation Article; and</section><section prefix="(3)">other factors that the Executive Director considers appropriate that relate to drivers illegally failing to stop for school vehicles.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Executive Director may not make a grant from the Fund exceeding $35,000 in a fiscal year for use in a single county.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If money remains available in the Fund after grants are initially awarded in a fiscal year, the Executive Director may make supplemental grants to law enforcement agencies in accordance with procedures established by the Executive Director.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A law enforcement agency that receives a grant under this subtitle:<section prefix="(1)">may use the grant only in accordance with the terms of the grant for efforts that relate to the enforcement of &#xA7; 21-706 of the Transportation Article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">shall comply with reporting requirements established by the Executive Director to evaluate:<section prefix="(i)">the law enforcement agency's enforcement efforts under the grant; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">statewide enforcement efforts under this subtitle.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
