<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-401" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-401</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"ANSI Standard" means the American National Standards Institute Standard ANSI z 97.1 - 1984, as adopted most recently by the Department in the Maryland Building Performance Standards.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Department" means the Department of Housing and Community Development.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Fixed glazed panel immediately adjacent to an entrance or exit door" means the first fixed glazed panel that:<section prefix="(1)">is beside an entrance or exit door;</section><section prefix="(2)">has a glazing less than 18 inches from the finished floor or the least dimension of which is 18 inches or more; and</section><section prefix="(3)">may be mistaken as a means of egress or ingress.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Hazardous location" means a place for a door, panel, enclosure, or other element, that is glazed or to be glazed, in a residential, industrial, commercial, institutional, or public building where the use of material other than safety glazing material constitutes an unreasonable hazard.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Hazardous location" includes a place for a framed or unframed exit door, a storm door except an operating vent on a jalousie door, a fixed or moving sliding door, a shower door, a tub enclosure, a fixed glazed panel immediately adjacent to an entrance or exit door, and any other element, that is glazed or to be glazed, whether or not the glazing is transparent.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Safety glazing material" means glazing material that:<section prefix="(i)">is constructed, treated, or combined with other materials to minimize the likelihood of cutting and piercing injuries resulting from human contact with the glazing material; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">meets the test requirements of the ANSI Standard.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Safety glazing material" includes tempered glass, laminated glass, wire glass, or rigid plastic.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
