<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-14-110.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "human service facility" means a facility licensed by the State that is:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>110.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "human service facility" means a facility licensed by the State that is:<section prefix="(1)">a nursing home, as defined in &#xA7; 19-1401 of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">an assisted living facility, as defined in &#xA7; 19-1801 of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="(3)">a hospital, as defined in &#xA7; 19-301 of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="(4)">a related institution as defined in &#xA7; 19-301 of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="(5)">a State-operated institution for mental disease;</section><section prefix="(6)">a group home as defined in &#xA7; 7-101 of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="(7)">an alternative living unit as defined in &#xA7; 7-101 of the Health - General Article; and</section><section prefix="(8)">a State residential center as defined in &#xA7; 7-101 of the Health - General Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A human service facility shall develop an emergency plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An emergency plan shall include procedures that will be followed before, during, and after an emergency to address:<section prefix="(1)">the evacuation, transportation, or shelter-in-place of individuals served by the human service facility;</section><section prefix="(2)">the notification to families, staff, and licensing authorities regarding the action that will be taken concerning the safety and well-being of the individuals served by the human service facility;</section><section prefix="(3)">staff coverage, organization, and assignment of responsibilities; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the continuity of operations, including:<section prefix="(i)">procuring essential goods, equipment, and services; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">relocation to alternate facilities.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not prohibit a human service facility from applying for and receiving reimbursement:<section prefix="(i)">under any applicable insurance policy; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">from any State or federal funds that may be available due to a declared State or federal emergency.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A human service facility is solely responsible for any financial obligation arising from voluntary or mandatory activation of any aspect of the emergency plan developed by the human service facility under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before November 30, 2007, a State agency that is responsible for the licensing of a human service facility shall adopt regulations governing the development of emergency plans under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Regulations adopted under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be developed in consultation with representatives of:<section prefix="(i)">the Maryland Emergency Management Agency;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Maryland Institute for Emergency Medical Services Systems;</section><section prefix="(iii)">local organizations for emergency management; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">human service facilities.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">For purposes of coordinating local emergency planning efforts, a human service facility shall provide access to the emergency plans developed under this section to local organizations for emergency management.</section>
  </text>
</law>
