<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-604" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-3-604</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Caregiver" means a parent, spouse, guardian, legal custodian, or person responsible for the supervision of another adult.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Law enforcement agency" means a State, county, or municipal police department or agency, or a sheriff's department.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Missing person" means an individual:<section prefix="(i)">whose whereabouts are unknown;</section><section prefix="(ii)">who suffers a cognitive impairment including a diagnosis of Alzheimer's disease or dementia to the extent that the individual requires assistance from a caregiver; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">whose disappearance poses a credible threat to the health and safety of the individual due to age, health, mental or physical disability, environment, or weather conditions, as determined by a law enforcement agency.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department of State Police shall establish a Silver Alert Program to provide a system for rapid dissemination of information to assist in locating a missing person.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department of State Police shall:<section prefix="(i)">adopt guidelines and develop procedures for issuing a Silver Alert for a missing person;</section><section prefix="(ii)">provide training to local law enforcement agencies on the guidelines and procedures to be used to handle a report of a missing person;</section><section prefix="(iii)">provide assistance to a local law enforcement agency, as necessary, to assist in the safe recovery of a missing person;</section><section prefix="(iv)">recruit public and commercial television and radio broadcasters, local volunteer groups, and other members of the public to assist in developing and implementing a Silver Alert;</section><section prefix="(v)">consult with the State Highway Administration to establish a plan for providing information relevant to a Silver Alert to the public through the dynamic message sign system located across the State; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">consult with the State Department of Education to develop a program that:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A caregiver or person filing a report regarding a missing person immediately shall notify the local law enforcement agency with which the report was filed and the Department of State Police if:<section prefix="(1)">the missing person who was the subject of the report is located; and</section><section prefix="(2)">it is unlikely that the local law enforcement agency or the Department of State Police has knowledge that the missing person has been located.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
