<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-130" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-5-130</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "gun show" means any organized gathering open to the public at which any firearm is displayed.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subsections (c) through (h) of this section do not apply to a licensee.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person must obtain a temporary transfer permit issued by the Secretary before the person displays a regulated firearm for sale or transfer from a table or fixed display at a gun show.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant for a temporary transfer permit shall:<section prefix="(i)">submit to the Secretary an application on the form that the Secretary provides; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">pay to the Secretary a fee of $10 for each calendar year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each additional temporary transfer permit during the same calendar year shall be issued without charge.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The application for a temporary transfer permit shall contain any information that is necessary for the Secretary to conduct a computer background investigation.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Each application for a temporary transfer permit shall contain the following statement: "Any false information supplied or statement made in this application is a crime which may be punished by imprisonment for a period of not more than 3 years or a fine not more than $5,000 or both.".</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall conduct an investigation to determine the truth or falsity of the information supplied and the statements made in the application for a temporary transfer permit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If there is no reason to disapprove the application for a temporary transfer permit, the Secretary shall issue the permit within 7 days after the date of application.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary shall disapprove an application for a temporary transfer permit if the Secretary determines that:<section prefix="(i)">the applicant supplied false information or made a false statement; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the application is not properly completed.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the Secretary disapproves an application for a temporary transfer permit, the Secretary shall notify the applicant in writing of the disapproval.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A temporary transfer permit shall be clearly labeled "temporary" and shall include the statement: "This is not a license to engage in the business of selling firearms.".</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The temporary transfer permit shall be placed in public view as part of any display of a regulated firearm.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not receive more than five temporary transfer permits during a single calendar year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To display a regulated firearm for sale, trade, or transfer at more than five gun shows in a calendar year, a person shall obtain a dealer's license under this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">A sale or transfer of a regulated firearm from a table or fixed display at a gun show is governed by &#xA7;&#xA7; 5-103, 5-104, 5-117 through 5-129, and 5-136 of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
