<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-827</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>827</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An applicant for an elevator mechanic license shall:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">have an acceptable combination of documented experience and education credits, with at least 3 years of recent and active work experience in the elevator industry, in construction, maintenance, and service or repair, as verified by current and previous employers; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">pass a written examination administered by the Board on the Safety Code;</section></section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">have completed at least 3 years of recent and active work experience in the elevator industry, in construction, maintenance, and service or repair, as verified by current and previous employers; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">have a certificate of completion of the mechanic examination of a nationally recognized training program for the elevator industry such as the National Elevator Industry Educational Program or its equivalent; or</section></section><section prefix="(3)">have a certificate of completion of an apprenticeship program for elevator mechanics that has standards substantially equivalent to those of Part III of this subtitle and is registered with the Bureau of Apprenticeship and Training of the U.S. Department of Labor or a state apprenticeship council.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An applicant for an elevator contractor license shall have at least 5 years of work experience in the elevator industry in construction, maintenance, service, or repair.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board shall adopt regulations governing:<section prefix="(1)">the qualifications of an applicant for an elevator renovator contractor license and an applicant for an elevator renovator mechanic license; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the scope of practice of a licensed elevator renovator contractor and a licensed elevator renovator mechanic.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant for an accessibility lift mechanic license shall:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">have an acceptable combination of documented experience and education credits, with at least 3 years of recent and active experience in the accessibility lift industry, in construction, maintenance, and service or repair, as verified by current and previous employers; and</section><section prefix="2.">pass a written examination administered by the Board on the Safety Code;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">have an acceptable combination of documented experience and education credits, with at least 3 years of recent and active experience in the accessibility lift industry, in construction, maintenance, and service or repair, as verified by current and previous employers; and</section><section prefix="2.">have a certificate from an organization providing an education program for the accessibility industry, such as the Certified Accessibility Technician Program or an equivalent program; or</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">have a certificate of completion of an apprenticeship program for accessibility mechanics that has standards substantially equivalent to those of Part III of this subtitle and is registered with the Bureau of Apprenticeship and Training of the U.S. Department of Labor or a state apprenticeship council.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may issue a conditional license under this subsection that is effective until January 1, 2017, to a candidate actively completing the educational requirements described in paragraph (1)(ii)2 of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
