<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-1-304</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each county shall have in operation an enhanced 9-1-1 system.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If implementation is preceded by cooperative planning, the enhanced 9-1-1 system required under subsection (a) of this section may operate as part of a multicounty system.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Services available through a 9-1-1 system shall include police, fire fighting, and emergency ambulance services.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Other emergency and civil defense services may be incorporated into the 9-1-1 system at the discretion of the county or counties served by the 9-1-1 system.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The digits 9-1-1 are the primary emergency telephone number in the 9-1-1 system.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A public safety agency whose services are available through the 9-1-1 system:<section prefix="(i)">may maintain a separate secondary backup telephone number for emergency calls; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall maintain a separate telephone number for nonemergency calls.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Educational information that relates to emergency services made available by the State or a county:<section prefix="(1)">shall designate the number 9-1-1 as the primary emergency telephone number; and</section><section prefix="(2)">may include a separate secondary backup telephone number for emergency calls.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each public safety answering point shall notify the public safety agencies in a county 9-1-1 system of calls for assistance in the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Written guidelines shall be developed to govern the referral of calls for assistance to the appropriate public safety agency.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">State, county, and local public safety agencies with concurrent jurisdiction shall have written agreements to ensure a clear understanding of which specific calls for assistance will be referred to which public safety agency.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Counties, other units of local government, public safety agencies, and public safety answering points may enter into cooperative agreements for the allocation of maintenance, operational, and capital costs attributable to the 9-1-1 system.</section>
  </text>
</law>
