<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="1-311" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-1-311</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to the 9-1-1 fee, the governing body of each county, by ordinance or resolution enacted or adopted after a public hearing, may impose an additional charge to be added to all current bills rendered for switched local exchange access service or CMRS or other 9-1-1-accessible service in the county.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The additional charge imposed by a county may not exceed 75 cents per month per bill.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The amount of the additional charges may not exceed a level necessary to cover the total eligible maintenance and operation costs of the county.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The additional charge continues in effect until repealed or modified by a subsequent county ordinance or resolution.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">After imposing, repealing, or modifying an additional charge, the county shall certify the amount of the additional charge to the Public Service Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Public Service Commission shall direct each telephone company that provides service in a county that imposed an additional charge to add, within 60 days, the full amount of the additional charge to all current bills rendered for switched local exchange access service in the county.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Within 60 days after a county enacts or adopts an ordinance or resolution that imposes, repeals, or modifies an additional charge, each 9-1-1 service carrier that provides service in the county shall add the full amount of the additional charge to all current bills rendered for CMRS or other 9-1-1-accessible service in the county.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each telephone company and each 9-1-1 service carrier shall:<section prefix="(i)">act as a collection agent for the 9-1-1 Trust Fund with respect to the additional charge imposed by each county;</section><section prefix="(ii)">collect the money from the additional charge on a county basis; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">remit all money collected to the Comptroller on a monthly basis.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Comptroller shall deposit the money remitted in the 9-1-1 Trust Fund account maintained for the county that imposed the additional charge.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
