<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-824.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "Fund" means the Elevator Safety Review Board Fund....</catch_line>
  <order_by>824.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Fund" means the Elevator Safety Review Board Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is an Elevator Safety Review Board Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The purpose of the Fund is to cover the actual documented direct and indirect costs of fulfilling the statutory and regulatory duties of the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commissioner shall administer the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Treasurer shall hold the Fund separately and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">revenue distributed to the Fund under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">money appropriated in the State budget to the Fund;</section><section prefix="(3)">investment earnings of the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(4)">any other money from any other source accepted for the benefit of the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Fund may be used only to cover the actual documented direct and indirect costs of fulfilling the statutory and regulatory duties of the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Treasurer shall invest the money of the Fund in the same manner as other State money may be invested.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any investment earnings of the Fund shall be paid into the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Expenditures from the Fund may be made only in accordance with the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">Any balance in the Fund at the end of June 30 of each fiscal year in excess of 10% of the actual expenses of operating the Elevator Safety Review Board shall revert to the General Fund of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The Legislative Auditor shall audit the accounts and transactions of the Fund as provided in &#xA7; 2-1220 of the State Government Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">On or before October 1, 2009, and each year thereafter, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the Board shall report to the Senate Budget and Taxation Committee, the Senate Finance Committee, the House Appropriations Committee, and the House Economic Matters Committee on the implementation of the Fund.</section>
  </text>
</law>
