<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-907" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-907</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The following entities may request the Commissioner to issue special inspector commissions:<section prefix="(i)">an authorized insurer that insures boilers and pressure vessels in the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an authorized inspection agency.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On request of an entity described in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Commissioner may issue a special inspector commission to an individual employed by the entity to serve as a special inspector if the entity and the individual satisfy the requirements of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant for a special inspector commission shall be employed by the entity that requests the special inspector commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An applicant for a special inspector commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">hold a commission as an inspector of boilers and pressure vessels issued by the National Board of Boiler and Pressure Vessel Inspectors; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">pass the examination given by the Board under subsection (e) of this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The employer of an applicant for a special inspector commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">submit to the Commissioner an application on the form that the Commissioner requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">pay to the Commissioner a fee of $50.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The application shall include:<section prefix="(i)">the name and qualifications of the individual who will serve as a special inspector; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">evidence that the individual satisfies the requirements of subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">By regulation, the Commissioner shall establish insurance requirements that an authorized inspection agency must satisfy before a special inspector commission may be issued to an inspector employed by the authorized inspection agency.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may give examinations to applicants for special inspector commissions as provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The examination:<section prefix="(i)">shall be in writing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall be limited to questions the answers to which will help to determine the fitness and competency of the individual for the intended service; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">may consist of questions prepared by the National Board of Boiler and Pressure Vessel Inspectors.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An applicant who fails the examination may appeal to the Board for a reexamination.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The reexamination shall be given by the Board within 90 days.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The record of an applicant's examination shall be available to the applicant and the applicant's employer.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The fee for an examination or reexamination is $50.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commissioner shall issue a special inspector commission to each applicant who meets the requirements of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">An inspection by a special inspector of a boiler or pressure vessel insured or pressure vessel operated by the employer of the special inspector, or an inspection by a special inspector employed by an authorized inspection agency, exempts the owner or user of the boiler or pressure vessel from the payment to the State of inspection fees required by this subtitle for the boiler or pressure vessel.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A special inspector may not receive a salary from or have any expenses paid by the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A special inspector commission expires 2 years after its effective date.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before a special inspector commission expires, the employer of the special inspector may renew the commission if the employer:<section prefix="(i)">pays to the Commissioner a renewal fee of $50; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">submits evidence to the Commissioner that the special inspector:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">Within 30 days after the termination of the employment of a special inspector, the employer shall return the special inspector commission to the Chief Boiler Inspector.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an identification card of a special inspector is lost or destroyed, the Commissioner shall issue a new identification card in its place without another examination.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The fee for replacement of an identification card is $50.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After investigation and recommendation by the Board, the Commissioner may suspend the special inspector commission for:<section prefix="(i)">incompetence of the special inspector;</section><section prefix="(ii)">untrustworthiness of the special inspector;</section><section prefix="(iii)">willful falsification of any matter or statement contained in the application for the special inspector commission; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">willful falsification of any matter or statement contained in a report of an inspection made by the special inspector.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 10 days after suspending a special inspector commission, the Commissioner shall give written notice of the suspension to the special inspector and the employer of the special inspector.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An individual whose special inspector commission has been suspended may appeal to the Board.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">At the hearing on the appeal, the individual may be present and represented by counsel.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An individual whose special inspector commission has been suspended may apply for reinstatement of the commission after 90 days following the date of the suspension.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Board has reason to believe that a special inspector is no longer qualified to hold a commission, the Board shall hold a hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall give at least 10 days' written notice of the hearing to the special inspector and to the employer of the special inspector.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the hearing, the special inspector and the employer shall have an opportunity to be heard.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If after the hearing the Board finds that the special inspector is no longer qualified to hold a commission:<section prefix="(i)">the Board shall recommend to the Commissioner that the special inspector commission be revoked; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Commissioner shall revoke the special inspector commission immediately.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
