<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-9-102</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>102</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each sleeping area within each occupancy classified residential, as defined in the most recent edition of the National Fire Protection Association Life Safety Code adopted by the State Fire Prevention Commission, shall be equipped with at least one approved smoke detector that:<section prefix="(i)">senses visible or invisible particles of combustion; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is installed in a manner and location approved by the State Fire Prevention Commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When activated, the smoke detector shall provide an alarm suitable to warn the occupants.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The landlord shall install smoke detectors as required under subsection (a) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On written notification by certified mail by the tenant or on notification in person by the tenant, the landlord shall repair or replace the smoke detector.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the tenant personally notifies the landlord of the failure of a smoke detector, the landlord shall provide a written receipt acknowledging the notification.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A tenant may not remove a smoke detector or render a smoke detector inoperative.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Except for hotels or motels, a landlord may require a refundable deposit for a smoke detector not exceeding the value of the smoke detector.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">On written request of a tenant who is deaf or hearing impaired, the landlord shall provide a smoke detector that, when activated, provides a signal that:<section prefix="(i)">is approved by a nationally recognized testing laboratory for electrical appliances; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is sufficient to warn the deaf or hearing impaired tenant.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Regardless of the number of units, each hotel or motel shall have available at least one smoke detector for the deaf or hearing impaired for each 50 units or fraction of 50 units.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The hotel or motel may require a refundable deposit for a portable smoke detector not exceeding the value of the smoke detector.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The hotel or motel shall post in a conspicuous place at the registration desk a permanent sign that states the availability of smoke detectors for the deaf or hearing impaired.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">On or before July 1, 1982, an occupant of a one, two, or three family residential dwelling constructed before July 1, 1975, shall:<section prefix="(1)">equip each occupant's living unit with at least one approved battery or alternating current (AC) primary electric powered smoke detector; and</section><section prefix="(2)">maintain the smoke detector.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
