<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-3A-03" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-14-3A-03</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">After the Governor issues a proclamation under this subtitle, the Governor may issue the orders authorized in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor may order the Secretary or other designated official to:<section prefix="(i)">seize immediately anything needed to respond to the medical consequences of the catastrophic health emergency; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">work collaboratively, to the extent feasible, with health care providers to designate and gain access to a facility needed to respond to the catastrophic health emergency.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Governor may order the Secretary or other designated official to control, restrict, or regulate the use, sale, dispensing, distribution, or transportation of anything needed to respond to the medical consequences of the catastrophic health emergency by:<section prefix="(i)">rationing or using quotas;</section><section prefix="(ii)">creating and distributing stockpiles;</section><section prefix="(iii)">prohibiting shipments;</section><section prefix="(iv)">setting prices; or</section><section prefix="(v)">taking other appropriate actions.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If medically necessary and reasonable to treat, prevent, or reduce the spread of the disease or outbreak believed to have been caused by the exposure to a deadly agent, the Governor may order the Secretary or other designated official to:<section prefix="(i)">require individuals to submit to medical examination or testing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">require individuals to submit to vaccination or medical treatment unless the vaccination or treatment likely will cause serious harm to the individual;</section><section prefix="(iii)">establish places of treatment, isolation, and quarantine; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">require individuals to go to and remain in places of isolation or quarantine until the Secretary or other designated official determines that the individuals no longer pose a substantial risk of transmitting the disease or condition to the public.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Governor may order any health care provider, who does not voluntarily participate, to participate in disease surveillance, treatment, and suppression efforts or otherwise comply with the directives of the Secretary or other designated official.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor may order the evacuation, closing, or decontamination of any facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If necessary and reasonable to save lives or prevent exposure to a deadly agent, the Governor may order individuals to remain indoors or refrain from congregating.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
