<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-6-315</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>315</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The State Fire Marshal, a designee of the State Fire Marshal, a full-time fire investigator who is a member of a fire department, or a police officer may apply to a judge of the District Court or a circuit court for an administrative search warrant to enter a vehicle, building, or premises where a fire has occurred to conduct a search to determine the cause and origin of the fire.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An application under subsection (a) of this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">be in writing;</section><section prefix="(2)">be signed and sworn to by the applicant; and</section><section prefix="(3)">particularly describe the vehicle, building, or premises to be searched and the nature, scope, and purpose of the search to be performed by the applicant.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A judge of the District Court or a circuit court may issue the warrant on finding that:<section prefix="(1)">a fire of undetermined origin has occurred;</section><section prefix="(2)">the scope of the proposed search is reasonable and will not intrude unnecessarily on the fire victim's privacy;</section><section prefix="(3)">the search will be executed at a reasonable and convenient time; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the owner, tenant, or other individual in charge of the property has denied access to the property, or after making a reasonable effort, the applicant has been unable to locate any of these individuals.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An administrative search warrant issued under this section shall specify the vehicle, building, or premises to be searched.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The search conducted may not exceed the limits specified in the warrant.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An administrative search warrant issued under this section shall be executed and returned to the judge who issued it within:<section prefix="(1)">the time specified in the warrant, not exceeding 30 days; or</section><section prefix="(2)">if no time period is specified in the warrant, 15 days after its issuance.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
