<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-107" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-14-107</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Governor finds that an emergency has developed or is impending due to any cause, the Governor shall declare a state of emergency by executive order or proclamation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The state of emergency continues until the Governor:<section prefix="(i)">finds that the threat or danger has passed or the emergency has been dealt with to the extent that emergency conditions no longer exist; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">terminates the state of emergency by executive order or proclamation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A state of emergency may not continue for longer than 30 days unless the Governor renews the state of emergency.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The General Assembly by joint resolution may terminate a state of emergency at any time.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">After the General Assembly terminates a state of emergency, the Governor shall issue an executive order or proclamation that terminates the state of emergency.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each executive order or proclamation that declares or terminates a state of emergency shall indicate:<section prefix="(i)">the nature of the emergency;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the area threatened; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the conditions that have brought about the state of emergency or that make possible the termination of the state of emergency.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each executive order or proclamation shall be:<section prefix="(i)">disseminated promptly by means calculated to publicize its contents; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">unless prevented or impeded by the circumstances of the emergency, filed promptly with:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After the Governor declares a state of emergency, the Director shall coordinate the activities of the agencies of the State and of those political subdivisions included in the declaration in all actions that serve to prevent or alleviate the ill effects of the imminent or actual emergency.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An executive order or proclamation that declares a state of emergency:<section prefix="(i)">activates the emergency response and recovery aspects of the State and local emergency plans applicable to the political subdivision or area covered by the declaration; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is authority for:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After declaring a state of emergency, the Governor, if the Governor finds it necessary in order to protect the public health, welfare, or safety, may:<section prefix="(i)">suspend the effect of any statute or rule or regulation of an agency of the State or a political subdivision;</section><section prefix="(ii)">direct and compel the evacuation of all or part of the population from a stricken or threatened area in the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">set evacuation routes and the modes of transportation to be used during an emergency;</section><section prefix="(iv)">direct the control of ingress to and egress from an emergency area, the movement of individuals in the area, and the occupancy of premises in the area;</section><section prefix="(v)">authorize the use of private property, in which event the owner of the property shall be compensated for its use and for any damage to the property;</section><section prefix="(vi)">provide for temporary housing; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">authorize the clearance and removal of debris and wreckage.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The powers of the Governor under this subsection are in addition to any other authority vested in the Governor by law.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
