<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-3-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, a law enforcement officer has the same rights to engage in political activity as a State employee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This right to engage in political activity does not apply when the law enforcement officer is on duty or acting in an official capacity.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A law enforcement agency:<section prefix="(1)">may not prohibit secondary employment by law enforcement officers; but</section><section prefix="(2)">may adopt reasonable regulations that relate to secondary employment by law enforcement officers.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A law enforcement officer may not be required or requested to disclose an item of the law enforcement officer's property, income, assets, source of income, debts, or personal or domestic expenditures, including those of a member of the law enforcement officer's family or household, unless:<section prefix="(1)">the information is necessary to investigate a possible conflict of interest with respect to the performance of the law enforcement officer's official duties; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the disclosure is required by federal or State law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A law enforcement officer may not be discharged, disciplined, demoted, or denied promotion, transfer, or reassignment, or otherwise discriminated against in regard to the law enforcement officer's employment or be threatened with that treatment because the law enforcement officer:<section prefix="(1)">has exercised or demanded the rights granted by this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">has lawfully exercised constitutional rights.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A statute may not abridge and a law enforcement agency may not adopt a regulation that prohibits the right of a law enforcement officer to bring suit that arises out of the law enforcement officer's duties as a law enforcement officer.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A law enforcement officer may waive in writing any or all rights granted by this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
