<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-1-309</section_number>
  <catch_line>On recommendation of the Board, each year the Secretary shall request an appropriation from the 9-1-...</catch_line>
  <order_by>309</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">On recommendation of the Board, each year the Secretary shall request an appropriation from the 9-1-1 Trust Fund in an amount sufficient to:<section prefix="(1)">carry out the purposes of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">pay the administrative costs chargeable to the 9-1-1 Trust Fund; and</section><section prefix="(3)">reimburse counties for the cost of enhancing a 9-1-1 system.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the limitations under subsection (e) of this section, the Comptroller shall disburse the money in the 9-1-1 Trust Fund as provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each July 1, the Comptroller shall allocate sufficient money from the 9-1-1 fee to pay the costs of administering the 9-1-1 Trust Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">As directed by the Secretary and in accordance with the State budget, the Comptroller, from the appropriate account, shall:<section prefix="(i)">reimburse counties for the cost of enhancing a 9-1-1 system; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">pay contractors in accordance with &#xA7; 1-306(b)(12) of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Comptroller shall pay to each county from its account the money requested by the county to pay the maintenance and operation costs of the county's 9-1-1 system in accordance with the State budget.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Comptroller shall pay the money for maintenance and operation costs on September 30, December 31, March 31, and June 30 of each year.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Money accruing to the 9-1-1 Trust Fund may be used as provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Money collected from the 9-1-1 fee may be used to:<section prefix="(i)">reimburse counties for the cost of enhancing a 9-1-1 system; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">pay contractors in accordance with &#xA7; 1-306(b)(12) of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Money collected from the additional charge may be used by the counties for the maintenance and operation costs of the 9-1-1 system.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Reimbursement may be made only to the extent that county money was used to enhance the 9-1-1 system.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Reimbursement for the enhancement of 9-1-1 systems shall include the installation of equipment for automatic number identification, automatic location identification, and other technological advancements that the Board requires.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Reimbursement from money collected from the 9-1-1 fee may be used only for 9-1-1 system enhancements approved by the Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may direct the Comptroller to withhold from a county money for 9-1-1 system expenditures if the county violates this subtitle or a regulation of the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board shall state publicly in writing its reason for withholding money from a county and shall record its reason in the minutes of the Board.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">On reaching its decision to withhold money, the Board shall notify the county.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The county has 30 days after the date of notification to respond in writing to the Board.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">On notification by the Board, the Comptroller shall hold money for the county in the county's account in the 9-1-1 Trust Fund.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Money held by the Comptroller under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph does not accrue interest for the county.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Interest income earned on money held by the Comptroller under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph accrues to the 9-1-1 Trust Fund.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">County money withheld by the Comptroller shall be withheld until the Board directs the Comptroller to release the money.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Legislative Auditor shall conduct fiscal/compliance audits of the 9-1-1 Trust Fund and of the appropriations and disbursements made for purposes of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The cost of the fiscal portion of the audits shall be paid from the 9-1-1 Trust Fund as an administrative cost.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
