<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-129" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-5-129</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Notwithstanding &#xA7; 5-128(b) of this subtitle, a person may purchase more than one regulated firearm in a 30-day period if:<section prefix="(1)">the person applies for and the Secretary approves a multiple purchase; and</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">the purchase of the regulated firearms is for a private collection or a collector series;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the purchase of the regulated firearms is a bulk purchase from an estate sale;</section><section prefix="(iii)"/><section prefix="(iv)">the purchase is for other purposes similar to items (i) through (iii) of this item.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The application for a multiple purchase shall:<section prefix="(i)">list the regulated firearms to be purchased;</section><section prefix="(ii)">state the purpose of the purchase of more than one regulated firearm in a 30-day period;</section><section prefix="(iii)">be witnessed by a licensee or designated law enforcement agency; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">be signed under the penalty of perjury by the firearm applicant.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The application for a multiple purchase of regulated firearms shall be attached to a completed firearm application and forwarded to the Secretary by a licensee or designated law enforcement agency.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">On receipt of the firearm application and the application for a multiple purchase, the Secretary shall conduct a background investigation as required in &#xA7; 5-121 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 3 years or a fine not exceeding $5,000 or both.</section>
  </text>
</law>
