<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-1-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Additional charge" means the charge imposed by a county in accordance with &#xA7; 1-311 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Board" means the Emergency Number Systems Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Commercial mobile radio service" or "CMRS" means mobile telecommunications service that is:<section prefix="(1)">provided for profit with the intent of receiving compensation or monetary gain;</section><section prefix="(2)">an interconnected, two-way voice service; and</section><section prefix="(3)">available to the public.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Commercial mobile radio service provider" or "CMRS provider" means a person authorized by the Federal Communications Commission to provide CMRS in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"County plan" means a plan for a 9-1-1 system or enhanced 9-1-1 system, or an amendment to the plan, developed by a county or several counties together under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Customer" means:<section prefix="(i)">the person that contracts with a home service provider for CMRS; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the end user of the CMRS if the end user of the CMRS is not the contracting party.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Customer" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">a reseller of CMRS; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a serving carrier under an arrangement to serve the customer outside the home service provider's licensed service area.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Enhanced 9-1-1 system" means a 9-1-1 system that provides:<section prefix="(1)">automatic number identification;</section><section prefix="(2)">automatic location identification; and</section><section prefix="(3)">any other technological advancements that the Board requires.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"FCC order" means an order issued by the Federal Communications Commission under proceedings regarding the compatibility of enhanced 9-1-1 systems and delivery of wireless enhanced 9-1-1 service.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Home service provider" means the facilities-based carrier or reseller that contracts with a customer to provide CMRS.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Next generation 9-1-1 services" means an Internet Protocol (IP)-based system, comprised of hardware, software, data, and operational policies and procedures, that:<section prefix="(1)">provides standardized interfaces from emergency call and message services to support emergency communications;</section><section prefix="(2)">processes all types of emergency calls, including voice, text, data, and multimedia information;</section><section prefix="(3)">acquires and integrates additional emergency call data useful to call routing and handling;</section><section prefix="(4)">delivers the emergency calls, messages, and data to the appropriate public safety answering point and other appropriate emergency entities;</section><section prefix="(5)">supports data or video communications needs for coordinated incident response and management; and</section><section prefix="(6)">provides broadband service to public safety answering points or other first responder entities.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"9-1-1-accessible service" means telephone service or another communications service that connects an individual dialing the digits 9-1-1 to an established public safety answering point.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"9-1-1 fee" means the fee imposed in accordance with &#xA7; 1-310 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"9-1-1 service carrier" means a provider of CMRS or other 9-1-1-accessible service.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"9-1-1 service carrier" does not include a telephone company.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"9-1-1 system" means telephone service that:<section prefix="(i)">meets the planning guidelines established under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">automatically connects an individual dialing the digits 9-1-1 to an established public safety answering point.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"9-1-1 system" includes:<section prefix="(i)">equipment for connecting and outswitching 9-1-1 calls within a telephone central office;</section><section prefix="(ii)">trunking facilities from a telephone central office to a public safety answering point; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">equipment to connect 9-1-1 calls to the appropriate public safety agency.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"9-1-1 Trust Fund" means the fund established under &#xA7; 1-308 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Public safety agency" means:<section prefix="(1)">a functional division of a public agency that provides fire fighting, police, medical, or other emergency services; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a private entity that provides fire fighting, police, medical, or other emergency services on a voluntary basis.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Public safety answering point" means a communications facility that:<section prefix="(1)">is operated on a 24-hour basis;</section><section prefix="(2)">first receives 9-1-1 calls in a 9-1-1 service area; and</section><section prefix="(3)">as appropriate, dispatches public safety services directly, or transfers 9-1-1 calls to appropriate public safety agencies.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Secretary" means the Secretary of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Wireless enhanced 9-1-1 service" means enhanced 9-1-1 service under an FCC order.</section>
  </text>
</law>
