<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-403" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-14-403</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "executive officer" means the mayor or comparable official of the legislative body of a municipal corporation of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The powers in this section may be exercised only during the effective period of an official proclamation by the Governor that declares all or part of the municipal corporation to be in an actual or threatened emergency area.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an executive officer is killed or is sick, incapacitated, missing, or otherwise unavailable for a temporary or indefinite period because of a military or warlike catastrophe, and the municipal corporation is unable to fill that vacancy for a temporary or indefinite period, the local governing body of the county in which the municipal corporation is located may appoint an individual to fill the vacancy for a temporary or indefinite period.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the vacancy is in a municipal corporation that is located in more than one county:<section prefix="(i)">the local governing body of any of the counties in which part of the municipal corporation is located may appoint an individual to fill the vacancy; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the local governing bodies of the counties may agree to appoint an individual to fill the vacancy.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">To the extent possible, each appointee shall have the qualifications required for the particular office to which appointed.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each appointee may exercise the powers and prerogatives of an officer elected to the position.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Each appointee shall hold office until:<section prefix="(1)">the executive officer originally holding the position returns to the position; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the position is filled by the regular election and qualification of a successor.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Under the circumstances described in this section, the Governor may exercise the executive and administrative powers of the municipal government until the number of individuals sufficient to operate the municipal government are appointed and qualified as executive officers.</section>
  </text>
</law>
