<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-6-206</section_number>
  <catch_line>To protect life and property from the hazards of fire and explosion, the Commission shall adopt comp...</catch_line>
  <order_by>206</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">To protect life and property from the hazards of fire and explosion, the Commission shall adopt comprehensive regulations as a State Fire Prevention Code.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The State Fire Prevention Code shall comply with standard safe practice as embodied in widely recognized standards of good practice for fire prevention and fire protection.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The State Fire Prevention Code has the force and effect of law in the political subdivisions of the State.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the regulations adopted under this subsection do not apply to existing installations, plants, or equipment.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the Commission determines that an installation, plant, or equipment is a hazard so inimicable to the public safety as to require correction, the regulations adopted under this subsection apply to the installation, plant, or equipment.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall adopt regulations to establish and administer a fee schedule for:<section prefix="(i)">reviewing building plans to ensure compliance with the State Fire Prevention Code; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">conducting inspections in accordance with Subtitle 3 of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall review the fee schedule annually to ensure that the money collected at least covers the costs of administering plan review and conducting inspections.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This subsection does not limit the authority of a local authority to establish a fee schedule for plan review and inspections conducted by the local authority.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before adopting a regulation, the Commission shall hold at least one public hearing on the proposed regulation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Commission shall publish notice of the hearing at least 15 days before the hearing in a newspaper of general circulation in the State.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">At the same time, the Commission shall send a copy of the notice to each person who has filed a request for notification with the Commission.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The notice shall contain the time, place, and subject of the hearing and the place and times to examine the proposed regulation.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Fire Prevention Code establishes the minimum requirements to protect life and property from the hazards of fire and explosion.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a State or local law or regulation is more stringent than the State Fire Prevention Code, the more stringent law or regulation governs if the more stringent law or regulation is:<section prefix="(i)">not inconsistent with the State Fire Prevention Code; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">not contrary to recognized standards and good engineering practices.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If there is a question whether a State or local law or regulation governs, the decision of the Commission determines:<section prefix="(i)">which law or regulation governs; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">whether State and local officials have complied with the State Fire Prevention Code.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commission shall make available for public information a copy of the State Fire Prevention Code, and any amendments to the State Fire Prevention Code, in each county courthouse in the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
