<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-13-510</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>510</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor shall appoint and commission each commissioned officer or appoint each warrant officer of the organized militia on recommendation of the Adjutant General.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The appointments under paragraph (1) of this subsection do not require confirmation by the Senate of Maryland.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each individual commissioned or appointed as an officer or warrant officer shall be:<section prefix="(i)">an officer, warrant officer, or enlisted individual of the National Guard;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a retired or former officer or warrant officer of the United States Army, Navy, Marine Corps, Air Force, or Coast Guard or any auxiliary thereof;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an individual with prior enlisted service in the United States Army, Navy, Marine Corps, Air Force, or Coast Guard, or any auxiliary thereof;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a graduate of the United States Military Academy, Naval Academy, Coast Guard Academy, Merchant Marine Academy, or Air Force Academy;</section><section prefix="(v)">a graduate of a school, college, university, or officers' training school who received military instruction under the supervision of an officer of the United States Army, Navy, Marine Corps, Air Force, or Coast Guard who certified the graduate's fitness for appointment as a commissioned officer; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">an individual not otherwise identified in items (i) through (v) of this paragraph who is specially qualified for service by achievement in any professional, technical, or public service capacity or otherwise displays extraordinary qualifications for commissioning as an officer of the Maryland Defense Force.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before taking office, each member of the National Guard shall take the oath prescribed in &#xA7; 13-407 of this title and each member of the Maryland Defense Force shall take the oath prescribed in &#xA7; 13-509 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">When initially appointed, a general officer or colonel of the organized militia must:<section prefix="(1)">be an officer in the National Guard of a grade of O-4 or higher; or</section><section prefix="(2)">have served in any component or auxiliary of the United States Army, Navy, Marine Corps, Air Force, or Coast Guard or National Guard with the grade of O-4 or higher.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">When initially appointed, a lieutenant-colonel or major of the line must have had  service as an officer for at least 2 years in any component or auxiliary of the United States Army, Navy, Marine Corps, Air Force, or Coast Guard or National Guard.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Subsections (c) and (d) of this section do not apply in the case of:<section prefix="(1)">officers promoted to the grade of major or above from within the Maryland Defense Force; or</section><section prefix="(2)">officers qualified under subsection (b)(1)(vi) of this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
