<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-2-703</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Vehicle Theft Prevention Fund....</catch_line>
  <order_by>703</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Vehicle Theft Prevention Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Treasurer shall hold the Fund separately and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">money received by the Fund under &#xA7; 17-106 of the Transportation Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">money received by the Council or the Fund from any source; and</section><section prefix="(3)">investment earnings of the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The money of the Fund shall be invested in the same manner as other State money.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Council shall spend money in the Fund in the following order of priority:<section prefix="(1)">to pay the expenses of the Council; and</section><section prefix="(2)">to carry out the purposes of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">When making grants from the Fund, the Council shall consider and prioritize the following entities and programs:<section prefix="(1)">State and local law enforcement agencies:<section prefix="(i)">to enhance vehicle theft enforcement and prevention teams or efforts; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">for programs designed to reduce the incidence of vehicle theft;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">local prosecutors and judicial agencies, for enhanced prosecution and adjudication of vehicle theft crime;</section><section prefix="(3)">neighborhood, community, or business organizations, for programs designed to reduce the incidence of vehicle theft;</section><section prefix="(4)">educational programs designed to inform motor vehicle owners of methods to prevent motor vehicle theft and to provide equipment, for experimental purposes, to enable motor vehicle owners to prevent motor vehicle theft;</section><section prefix="(5)">programs designed to reduce the incidence of vehicle theft and recidivism by juveniles; and</section><section prefix="(6)">programs designed to reduce or deter damage or vandalism to vehicles in connection with vehicle theft or theft of property from vehicles.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">To the extent practicable, the Council shall allocate grants made under this subtitle among the subdivisions of the State on a pro rata basis determined by the total number of vehicles registered in each subdivision divided by the total number of vehicles registered in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Expenditures from the Fund may be made only:<section prefix="(i)">in accordance with the State budget; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">by the budget amendment procedure as provided in &#xA7; 7-209 of the State Finance and Procurement Article, if at least 45 days have passed since the budget amendment and supporting information were submitted to the budget committees for their review and comment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The proposed budget and any budget amendment submitted to the General Assembly shall include an itemized list of each grant and other expenditure from the Fund to be made in the fiscal year.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
