<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-13-302</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>302</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Adjutant General may appoint:<section prefix="(i)">a chief of State operations;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an executive officer;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an administrative officer;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the directors of military installations, procurement, military support to civil authorities, State personnel, finance, and veterans affairs;</section><section prefix="(v)">the site managers for military reservations; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">a grants administrator.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The executive officer and directors appointed under paragraph (1) of this subsection serve at the pleasure of the Adjutant General.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Adjutant General shall keep all records required to be kept and filed with the Adjutant General's office.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On or before each October 15, the Adjutant General shall submit to the Governor a detailed statement of all the receipts and expenditures for military purposes during the year ending the previous September 30.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On request, the Adjutant General or the Adjutant General's designee shall assist the spouse of a member of the military who resides in the State or is transferred to the State in finding employment in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The assistance provided under paragraph (1) of this subsection may include providing:<section prefix="(i)">the informational form developed by the State Department of Education under &#xA7; 6-201.1 of the Education Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">information relating to health occupations in the State that permit reciprocal licensure; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">information relating to business occupations in the State that permit reciprocal licensure.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Adjutant General is responsible for:<section prefix="(i)">each armory that the State owns; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">each building or other property purchased, occupied, or leased by or on behalf of the State military forces.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Adjutant General rejects an application to use an armory for nonmilitary purposes, the application is subject to review and approval by the Board of Public Works, the Adjutant General, and the commanding officer of the unit occupying that armory.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Adjutant General may adopt regulations to enforce this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Adjutant General is the custodian of battle flags and war records and is responsible for their proper care and preservation.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Adjutant General may employ employees as required.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Adjutant General shall carry out the Governor's policies concerning matters specified in this title and Title 14, Subtitles 1, 2, and 4 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The seal of the Adjutant General's office shall be delivered by the Adjutant General to the Adjutant General's successor.</section>
  </text>
</law>
