<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-508" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-2-508</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On written or electronic request after verification by the Director that a match has been made in the population data base, the typing results and personal identification information of the DNA profile of an individual in the statewide DNA data base system may be made available to:<section prefix="(i)">federal, State, or local law enforcement agencies;</section><section prefix="(ii)">crime laboratories that have been approved by the Director and that serve federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a State's Attorney's office or other prosecutorial office; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">a person participating in a judicial proceeding in which the data base information may be offered as evidence.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A request for DNA information under paragraph (1) of this subsection must be in furtherance of a purpose set forth in &#xA7; 2-505 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The typing results and personal identification information of the DNA profile of an individual in the statewide DNA data base system shall be made available to a defendant or defendant's counsel on written order of the court in which the case is pending.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A search of the data base to determine the existence of a match to DNA obtained from crime scene evidence taken in relation to the crime for which a defendant is charged shall be conducted if:<section prefix="(i)">the defendant requests the search; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a court issues a written order for the search.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This subtitle does not limit a court from ordering discovery of a DNA record or other related material in a criminal case.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Director shall maintain a file of all orders issued under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
