<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-510</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>510</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Hotel" means an establishment that offers sleeping accommodations for compensation.  </section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Hotel" does not include a bed and breakfast establishment.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Master control device" means:<section prefix="(i)">a control that is activated when a person enters the room through the primary room-access method; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an occupancy sensor control that is activated by a person's presence in the room.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only to the new construction of hotels.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each hotel guest room shall be equipped with a master control device that automatically turns off the power to all of the lighting fixtures in the guest room no more than 30 minutes after the room has been vacated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A master control device may also control the heating, ventilation, or air conditioning default settings in hotel guest rooms 30 minutes after a room has been vacated by:<section prefix="(i)">increasing the set temperature by at least 3 degrees Fahrenheit when in the air conditioning mode; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">decreasing the set temperature by at least 3 degrees Fahrenheit when in the heating mode.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department shall adopt the provisions of this section as a part of the Maryland Building Performance Standards.</section>
  </text>
</law>
