<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-8-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A volunteer company shall submit each request for a grant or loan from the Fund to the Association for approval by a board of review in accordance with the Association's bylaws.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each request for a grant or loan shall include:<section prefix="(i)">financial statements for the 2 fiscal years immediately preceding the fiscal year in which the request is made;</section><section prefix="(ii)">any available audit of the financial statements; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">a detailed explanation of the reasons for the request.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For each request for a grant or loan from the Fund, the volunteer company shall certify that the volunteer company applied for money from its local government and was denied, either wholly or partly.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Association disapproves a request or does not take action within 90 days after the request for any reason other than because funds are not available, the volunteer company requesting a grant or loan may appeal to a panel composed of the president of the Association, the State Fire Marshal, and the chairman of the Fire and Rescue Education and Training Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The decision of the panel is final and is not subject to further review.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">On approval of a request for a grant or loan, the Association or the panel shall transmit its recommendation to the Board of Public Works.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">As authorized by the Board of Public Works, the Treasurer shall disburse money from the Fund to the Association in the name of a volunteer company for the purposes of this subtitle on warrant of the Comptroller.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Baltimore City Fire Department may submit a request for a grant or loan from the Fund for the purposes set forth in &#xA7; 8-203(b) of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
