<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-3-307</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>307</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each special police officer shall protect and preserve peace and good order on the property described in the application for the commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A special police officer may:<section prefix="(1)">arrest individuals who trespass or commit offenses on the property described in the application for the commission;</section><section prefix="(2)">exercise the powers of a police officer on the property described in the application for the commission;</section><section prefix="(3)">exercise the powers of a police officer in a county or municipal corporation of the State in connection with the care, custody, and protection of other property of the entity that requested the appointment of the special police officer or other property, real or personal, for which the entity has assumed an obligation to maintain or protect; and</section><section prefix="(4)">direct and control traffic on public highways and roads in the immediate vicinity of the property described in the application for the commission in order to facilitate the orderly movement of traffic to and from the property, if the Secretary approves of this activity in advance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A special police officer may make an arrest or issue a traffic citation for a violation of the Maryland Vehicle Law or any other State or local traffic law or regulation only if the special police officer:<section prefix="(i)">has a probationary or permanent appointment as a security officer or is a member of an industrial police force; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">has completed the basic training course for police officers as established by the Police Training Commission in accordance with Subtitle 2 of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A special police officer may exercise the power described in paragraph (1) of this subsection only on the property of the special police officer's employer as described in the application for the commission, unless the special police officer is in active pursuit for the purpose of immediate apprehension.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
