<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-5-306</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>306</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to subsection (b) of this section, the Secretary shall issue a permit within a reasonable time to a person who the Secretary finds:<section prefix="(1)">is an adult;</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">has not been convicted of a felony or of a misdemeanor for which a sentence of imprisonment for more than 1 year has been imposed; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if convicted of a crime described in item (i) of this item, has been pardoned or has been granted relief under 18 U.S.C. &#xA7; 925(c);</section></section><section prefix="(3)">has not been convicted of a crime involving the possession, use, or distribution of a controlled dangerous substance;</section><section prefix="(4)">is not presently an alcoholic, addict, or habitual user of a controlled dangerous substance unless the habitual use of the controlled dangerous substance is under legitimate medical direction; and</section><section prefix="(5)">based on an investigation:<section prefix="(i)">has not exhibited a propensity for violence or instability that may reasonably render the person's possession of a handgun a danger to the person or to another; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">has good and substantial reason to wear, carry, or transport a handgun, such as a finding that the permit is necessary as a reasonable precaution against apprehended danger.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An applicant under the age of 30 years is qualified only if the Secretary finds that the applicant has not been:<section prefix="(1)">committed to a detention, training, or correctional institution for juveniles for longer than 1 year after an adjudication of delinquency by a juvenile court; or</section><section prefix="(2)">adjudicated delinquent by a juvenile court for:<section prefix="(i)">an act that would be a crime of violence if committed by an adult;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an act that would be a felony in this State if committed by an adult; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">an act that would be a misdemeanor in this State that carries a statutory penalty of more than 2 years if committed by an adult.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
