<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-8-206</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>206</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">On or before August 30 of each fiscal year, the Association shall submit to the Department, the Legislative Auditor, and to the Board of Public Works an annual report that includes:<section prefix="(1)">the number and total amount of grants and the number and total amount of loans made in the previous fiscal year;</section><section prefix="(2)">for each grant or loan made:<section prefix="(i)">the volunteer company that received the grant or loan;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the amount of the grant or loan; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the specific purpose of making the grant or loan;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">for each volunteer company that received a grant or loan:<section prefix="(i)">the financial statement of the volunteer company for the previous fiscal year or the year in which the grant or loan was received, whichever is available; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">documentation of the volunteer company's actual expenditures from the grant or loan;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">for each loan made, the terms of the loan, including origination date, loan term, payment terms, payment amount, payments made to date, outstanding balance, and loan status; and</section><section prefix="(5)">summary listings of grants and loans made during the previous fiscal year and outstanding loans, by county.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">review the documentation submitted in accordance with subsection (a) of this section on an annual basis to determine if each grant or loan was spent in accordance with this subtitle and the request approved by the Board of Public Works; and</section><section prefix="(2)">report the findings to the Senate Budget and Taxation Committee and the House Appropriations Committee on an annual basis.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Legislative Auditor may:<section prefix="(1)">review the documentation submitted in accordance with subsection (a) of this section to determine if each grant or loan was spent in accordance with this subtitle and the requests approved by the Board of Public Works; and</section><section prefix="(2)">report the findings to the Department and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the Joint Audit Committee of the General Assembly.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Comptroller may audit the financial affairs of the Association to ensure compliance with this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
