<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-801" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-801</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Accessibility lift mechanic" means a person who is engaged in erecting, constructing, wiring, altering, replacing, maintaining, repairing, dismantling, or servicing commercial stairway chairlifts, vertical platform lifts, or incline platform lifts.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Accessibility lift mechanic specialist" means a person who is licensed as an accessibility lift mechanic and has been certified by the Board to erect, construct, wire, alter, replace, maintain, repair, dismantle, or service private residential elevators.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Board" means the Elevator Safety Review Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Certificate" means a certificate of registration and inspection issued by the Commissioner to operate an elevator unit.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Labor and Industry or an authorized representative of the Commissioner of Labor and Industry.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Dumbwaiter" means a hoisting and lowering machine equipped with a car of limited capacity and size that moves in guides in a substantially vertical direction and is used exclusively for carrying material.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Elevator" means a hoisting and lowering machine equipped with a car or platform that moves in guides in a substantially vertical direction and serves two or more floors of a building or structure.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Elevator contractor" means a person who is engaged in the business of erecting, constructing, wiring, altering, replacing, maintaining, repairing, dismantling, or servicing elevator or accessibility lift units.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Elevator mechanic" means a person who is engaged in erecting, constructing, wiring, altering, replacing, maintaining, repairing, dismantling, or servicing elevator or accessibility lift units.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Elevator refinisher" means a person who is engaged in the refinishing of existing metal and wood elements in elevator cabs, including the stripping of old lacquer on wood and bronze items, staining wood to match existing finishes, cleaning, polishing, oxidizing, painting, lacquering, and the removing of scratches to maintain existing finishes.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Elevator renovator contractor" means a person who is engaged in the business of performing work:<section prefix="(1)">on the interior of an elevator involving the removal or installation of the nonstructural surface of the elevator's wall, ceiling, floor, rail, or handle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">that does not affect the elevator's moving operation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Elevator renovator mechanic" means a person who performs work:<section prefix="(1)">on the interior of an elevator involving the removal or installation of the nonstructural surface of the elevator's wall, ceiling, floor, rail, or handle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">that does not affect the elevator's moving operation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Elevator unit" includes an elevator, escalator, dumbwaiter, and moving walk.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Escalator" means a power driven, inclined, continuous stairway used for raising and lowering passengers.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"License" includes:<section prefix="(1)">an accessibility lift mechanic license;</section><section prefix="(2)">an elevator contractor license;</section><section prefix="(3)">an elevator mechanic license;</section><section prefix="(4)">an elevator renovator contractor license; and</section><section prefix="(5)">an elevator renovator mechanic license.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Moving walk" means a type of passenger-carrying device on which passengers stand or walk and in which the passenger-carrying surface remains parallel to its direction of motion and is uninterrupted.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Safety Code" means the American National Standard/American Society of Mechanical Engineers Safety Code for Elevators, Dumbwaiters, Escalators, and Moving Walks, known as ANSI A17.1-1971, and all subsequent amendments and revisions to it, as adopted by the Commissioner.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Secretary" means the Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Third-party qualified elevator inspector" means an inspector who:<section prefix="(1)">meets the qualifications, insurance requirements, and procedures established by the Commissioner; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is certified by an organization accredited by the American Society of Mechanical Engineers in accordance with the American National Standard/American Society of Mechanical Engineers Safety Code for Elevators, Dumbwaiters, Escalators, and Moving Walks, known as ANSI A17.1-1971, and all subsequent amendments, and any related consensus standards.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
