<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-809</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>809</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A State inspector shall make the following inspections:<section prefix="(1)">final acceptance inspection of all new elevator units prior to issuance of first certificate;</section><section prefix="(2)">investigation of accidents and complaints;</section><section prefix="(3)">follow-up inspections to confirm corrective action;</section><section prefix="(4)">final acceptance inspection of the modernization or alteration of an elevator unit;</section><section prefix="(5)">a comprehensive 5-year inspection as defined by regulation;</section><section prefix="(6)">except as provided by &#xA7; 12-807(b) of this subtitle, inspections of elevator units owned by the State or a political subdivision; and</section><section prefix="(7)">quality control monitoring of inspections conducted by third-party qualified elevator inspectors.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A contractor, owner, or lessee shall provide the Commissioner with at least 60 days' notice of a requested inspection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a contractor, owner, or lessee provides the Commissioner with less than 60 days' notice of a requested inspection that will be conducted by a State inspector, the Commissioner shall schedule the inspection at the convenience of the State subject to the availability of State resources.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For all inspections conducted by a State inspector, the contractor, owner, or lessee of an elevator unit shall pay a fee for an inspection under &#xA7; 12-810(d) or &#xA7; 12-812(d)(3) of this subtitle at the following rate:<section prefix="(i)">half day (up to 4 hours), not to exceed $250; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">full day (up to 8 hours), not to exceed $500.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each fee collected under this subsection shall be paid into the Elevator Safety Review Board Fund established under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A contractor, owner, or lessee who notifies the Commissioner at least 24 hours in advance of a scheduled inspection that the elevator unit does not comply with the requirements of Part II of this subtitle may not be charged a fee under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An owner shall hire a third-party qualified elevator inspector to conduct all periodic annual inspections that are required by the Safety Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An inspection by a third-party qualified elevator inspector shall ensure that the elevator unit complies with the Safety Code and other regulations adopted by the Commissioner under Part II of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commissioner shall establish qualifications, insurance requirements, and procedures based on nationally accepted standards that the Commissioner considers necessary to register third-party qualified elevator inspectors under Part II of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Any fees collected by the Commissioner to register third-party qualified elevator inspectors shall be paid into the Elevator Safety Review Board Fund established under this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
