<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-14-3A-01</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>01</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Catastrophic health emergency" means a situation in which extensive loss of life or serious disability is threatened imminently because of exposure to a deadly agent.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Deadly agent" means:<section prefix="(1)">anthrax, ebola, plague, smallpox, tularemia, or other bacterial, fungal, rickettsial, or viral agent, biological toxin, or other biological agent capable of causing extensive loss of life or serious disability;</section><section prefix="(2)">mustard gas, nerve gas, or other chemical agent capable of causing extensive loss of life or serious disability; or</section><section prefix="(3)">radiation at levels capable of causing extensive loss of life or serious disability.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Exposure to a deadly agent" means a threat to human health caused by the release, distribution, or transmission of a deadly agent in:<section prefix="(1)">this State; or</section><section prefix="(2)">another jurisdiction because of movement into the State of the deadly agent or of individuals exposed to the deadly agent.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Health care provider" means:<section prefix="(1)">a health care facility as defined in &#xA7; 19-114(d)(1) of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">a health care practitioner as defined in &#xA7; 19-114(e) of the Health - General Article; and</section><section prefix="(3)">an individual licensed or certified as an emergency medical services provider under &#xA7; 13-516 of the Education Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Secretary" means the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene.</section>
  </text>
</law>
