<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-305" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-305</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department:<section prefix="(1)">shall adopt regulations that set standards to which industrialized buildings shall comply to protect against the hazards of industrialized buildings to safety, health, and property;</section><section prefix="(2)">may adopt regulations that govern the enforcement, inspection, and certification programs authorized by this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(3)">with respect to industrialized buildings, shall adopt the Maryland Building Performance Standards with exceptions or modifications that, after adequate public notice and public hearing, the Department considers appropriate to meet the needs and judgments of the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If practical, the regulations that set standards for industrialized buildings shall be stated in terms of required levels of performance to facilitate the prompt approval of acceptable new building materials and methods.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If generally recognized standards of performance are not available, the regulations shall provide for acceptance of materials and methods whose performance has been determined by the Department, on the basis of reliable test and evaluation data presented by the proponent, to be substantially equal in safety to the materials and methods specified when used for the purpose and in the manner recommended.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall have printed and keep in pamphlet form the regulations that set standards for industrialized buildings.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The pamphlets shall be provided at cost to the public on request.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department may adopt regulations that relate to issues of construction or safety of manufactured homes for which a federal standard has not been established and which are not reserved to a local government under &#xA7; 12-303 of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
