<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-5-110</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Secretary shall disapprove an application for a dealer's license if:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>110</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary shall disapprove an application for a dealer's license if:<section prefix="(1)">the Secretary determines that the applicant supplied false information or made a false statement;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Secretary determines that the application is not properly completed; or</section><section prefix="(3)">the Secretary receives a written notification from the applicant's licensed attending physician that the applicant suffers from a mental disorder and is a danger to the applicant or to another.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the Secretary disapproves an application for a dealer's license, the Secretary shall notify the applicant in writing of the disapproval.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person whose application for a dealer's license has been disapproved may not engage in the business of selling, renting, or transferring regulated firearms, unless the disapproval has been subsequently withdrawn by the Secretary or overruled by a court in accordance with subsection (d) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant who is aggrieved because the Secretary has disapproved the application for a dealer's license may appeal to the circuit court of the county where the applicant's place of business is to be located.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The appeal must be filed not later than 30 days after the Secretary mails notification of disapproval to the applicant.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the appeal is properly and timely filed, the court shall affirm or reverse the disapproval of the Secretary depending on whether the court finds that:<section prefix="(i)">the applicant supplied false information or made a false statement; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the application was not properly completed.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Secretary or the applicant may appeal the decision of the circuit court to the Court of Special Appeals.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
