<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-6-302</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>302</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary shall appoint a State Fire Marshal from a list of three names submitted by the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The State Fire Marshal shall:<section prefix="(1)">be a graduate of an accredited college or university; and</section><section prefix="(2)">have 5 years of recent progressively responsible experience, at least 3 years of which shall have been at the administrative level, in fire prevention inspection, fire investigation, fire safety promotion, fire protection engineering, fire fighting, or teaching fire safety engineering.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The State Fire Marshal serves for a term of 6 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The State Fire Marshal is in the executive service of the State Personnel Management System.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At any time, the Secretary may remove the State Fire Marshal for neglect of duty or other conduct unbecoming the office.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission may recommend to the Secretary that the State Fire Marshal be removed for cause.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Before removing the State Fire Marshal, the Secretary shall give the State Fire Marshal:<section prefix="1.">timely notice with a statement of the charges; and</section><section prefix="2.">an opportunity for a public hearing on the charges.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The State Fire Marshal may be represented at the hearing by counsel.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The State Fire Marshal is entitled to the salary provided in the State budget.</section>
  </text>
</law>
