<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-5-114</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Secretary shall suspend a dealer's license if the licensee:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>114</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary shall suspend a dealer's license if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">is under indictment for a crime of violence; or</section><section prefix="(2)">is arrested for a violation of this subtitle that prohibits the purchase or possession of a regulated firearm.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Secretary shall revoke a dealer's license if:<section prefix="(1)">it is discovered that false information has been supplied or false statements have been made in an application required by this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the licensee:<section prefix="(i)">is convicted of a disqualifying crime;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is convicted of a violation classified as a common law crime and receives a term of imprisonment of more than 2 years;</section><section prefix="(iii)">is a fugitive from justice;</section><section prefix="(iv)">is a habitual drunkard;</section><section prefix="(v)">is addicted to a controlled dangerous substance or is a habitual user;</section><section prefix="(vi)">has spent more than 30 consecutive days in a medical institution for treatment of a mental disorder, unless the licensee produces a physician's certificate, issued after the last institutionalization and certifying that the licensee is capable of possessing a regulated firearm without undue danger to the licensee or to another;</section><section prefix="(vii)">has knowingly or willfully manufactured, offered to sell, or sold a handgun not on the handgun roster in violation of &#xA7; 5-406 of this title; or</section><section prefix="(viii)">has knowingly or willfully participated in a straw purchase of a regulated firearm.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the Secretary suspends or revokes a dealer's license, the Secretary shall notify the licensee in writing of the suspension or revocation.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person whose dealer's license is suspended or revoked may not engage in the business of selling, renting, or transferring regulated firearms, unless the suspension or revocation has been subsequently withdrawn by the Secretary or overruled by a court in accordance with &#xA7; 5-116 of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
