<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-10-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each building in a fireworks plant shall be constructed as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to a building that is constructed or improved after July 1, 1970, or to which an addition is made after July 1, 1970.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The following buildings in a fireworks plant shall have exterior walls and roofs that are constructed of noncombustible material and shall be constructed to be frangible:<section prefix="(i)">a finishing and assembling building;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a press building; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">a mixing building.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A building in a fireworks plant may not contain a basement or exceed one story.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The interior wall surfaces and ceilings of a building in a fireworks plant shall:<section prefix="(i)">be smooth, free from cracks and crevices, and fire resistant; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">contain a minimum number of horizontal ledges on which dust may accumulate.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A floor or work surface in a building in a fireworks plant may not have cracks or crevices in which explosives may lodge.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A wall joint or opening for wiring or plumbing in a building in a fireworks plant shall be sealed to prevent entry of dust.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A mixing building or press building in a fireworks plant shall contain conductive flooring that is properly grounded.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A building in a fireworks plant shall be heated by:<section prefix="(1)">steam;</section><section prefix="(2)">indirectly radiating hot air;</section><section prefix="(3)">hot water; or</section><section prefix="(4)">any other means approved by the State Fire Prevention Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">All electric wiring in a fireworks plant shall be permanent and installed in approved conduits.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">All electrical service shall comply with applicable electrical codes.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Temporary or loose electric wiring or extension lights may not be used except:<section prefix="(i)">during repair operations while using approved temporary extensions; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">after the area has been cleared of all explosive composition and washed of dust.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Each fireworks plant shall have a master switch that:<section prefix="(i)">is located at the point where electric current enters the fireworks plant; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">on being opened, immediately cuts off all electric current to the fireworks plant.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Other than in a warehouse, an open knife switch may not be used inside a building of a fireworks plant.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Artificial lighting in a fireworks plant shall be provided by electric, vapor-proof, keyless lamps.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, each building shall contain:<section prefix="(i)">at least two exits for each work area; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">at least two exits from the building.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each small building with a designated capacity of one individual may have only one exit.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each exit shall be at least 30 inches wide.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Exits shall be located:<section prefix="(i)">so that the path of travel from the work area is unobstructed; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">at opposite ends of the work area.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">An exit door shall:<section prefix="(i)">open outward;</section><section prefix="(ii)">remain unlocked during the hours that the work area or building is occupied; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">remain unobstructed.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
