<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Department" means the Department of Housing and Community Development.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall adopt by regulation a State building code to make buildings and facilities accessible and usable by individuals with physical disabilities to the extent feasible.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The regulations shall be developed in conjunction with:<section prefix="(i)">the Governor's Committee on Employment of People with Disabilities;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Maryland Rehabilitation Association; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Maryland Society of Architects.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Maryland Accessibility Code shall be enforced by local jurisdictions or any other governmental units with authority over buildings or facilities.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department:<section prefix="(1)">shall decide questions of interpretation of the Maryland Accessibility Code; and</section><section prefix="(2)">may authorize waivers or exemptions under the Maryland Accessibility Code.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In addition to any other penalty for a violation of the Maryland Accessibility Code, the Department shall investigate to determine if a violation exists.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Department determines that a violation of the Maryland Accessibility Code exists, the Department may resolve any issue related to the violation by mediation and conciliation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition, the Department may bring an action for equitable or other appropriate relief in a court in the jurisdiction in which the violation occurred, including an action to enjoin the construction, renovation, or occupancy of a building or facility that violates the Maryland Accessibility Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Department may not seek an injunction until 5 working days after the Department has sought to resolve the violation through mediation and conciliation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Attorney General may prosecute civil cases that arise under this section that are referred to the Attorney General by the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall cooperate with and provide technical assistance to the Commission on Civil Rights concerning an action brought by the Commission on Civil Rights to enforce &#xA7; 20-705 or &#xA7; 20-706 of the State Government Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not limit the authority of the Commission on Civil Rights to enforce &#xA7;&#xA7; 20-705 and 20-706 of the State Government Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not willfully violate the Maryland Accessibility Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who violates this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject for each violation to imprisonment not exceeding 3 months or a fine not exceeding $500 for each day the violation exists or both.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A penalty imposed under this subsection is in addition to and not a substitute for any other penalty imposed under federal, State, or local law.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
