<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-6-318</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>318</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The State Fire Marshal may issue a reasonable abatement order if the State Fire Marshal:<section prefix="(1)">determines that a building or structure has been constructed, altered, or repaired in a manner that violates a regulation adopted by the Commission before the construction, alteration, or repairs began;</section><section prefix="(2)">determines that a building or structure:<section prefix="(i)">is a fire hazard because of disrepair, age, dilapidated or abandoned condition, or for any other reason; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">endangers other buildings and property; or</section></section><section prefix="(3)">finds in a building or on premises a combustible, flammable, or explosive substance or material, or other condition dangerous to the safety of individuals who occupy the building or premises and adjacent premises or property.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An abatement order under this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">be in writing;</section><section prefix="(2)">be directed to the owner or occupant of the building, structure, or premises; and</section><section prefix="(3)">contain a notice that:<section prefix="(i)">compliance with the order is required within the time specified in the notice; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any person aggrieved by the order may file an appeal from the order in accordance with Subtitle 5 of this title.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The abatement order may order:<section prefix="(1)">the repair or demolition of the building or structure or the removal of the combustible, flammable, or explosive substance or material; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the remedying of any condition found to be in violation of a regulation adopted by the Commission or to be dangerous to the safety of individuals or property.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
