<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-304" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-6-304</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A county or municipal corporation of the State may designate a fire marshal or appropriate fire official to serve as assistant State fire marshal to carry out this title, including issuing orders, in that county or municipal corporation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An assistant State fire marshal may not receive compensation from the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The State Fire Marshal shall carry out this title in a county or municipal corporation that has not designated an assistant State fire marshal.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An assistant State fire marshal shall have at least completed National Fire Protection Association (NFPA) Standard 1031 - Fire Inspector I, or the equivalent, as determined by the State Fire Marshal.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Fire Marshal may administer an examination based on NFPA Standard 1031 before designating an individual as an assistant State fire marshal.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Fire Marshal may designate as a special assistant State fire marshal:<section prefix="(i)">a law enforcement officer involved in arson investigations;</section><section prefix="(ii)">any other suitable individual who meets the standards established under this section; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">on the advice of an assistant State fire marshal, a member of a fire department if:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A special assistant State fire marshal serves at the pleasure of the State Fire Marshal.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A special assistant State fire marshal may not receive compensation from the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Each special assistant State fire marshal shall assist the State Fire Marshal in carrying out the duties of the State Fire Marshal under this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commission may remove an assistant or special assistant State fire marshal for just cause by a majority decision:<section prefix="(1)">on the recommendation of the State Fire Marshal; and</section><section prefix="(2)">after an administrative hearing.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
