<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-909</section_number>
  <catch_line>The requirements of this section and &#xA7;&#xA7; 12-910 and 12-911 of this subtitle do not apply to:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>909</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The requirements of this section and &#xA7;&#xA7; 12-910 and 12-911 of this subtitle do not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">a boiler or pressure vessel that is located on a farm and used solely for agricultural purposes;</section><section prefix="(2)">a heating boiler that is located in a private residence or an apartment house with less than six family units;</section><section prefix="(3)">a pressure vessel that:<section prefix="(i)">contains only water under pressure for domestic supply purposes, including a pressure vessel that contains air, the compression of which serves only as a cushion or airlift pumping system; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is located in a private residence or an apartment house with less than six family units; or</section></section><section prefix="(4)">an exhibition or antique boiler or pressure vessel, including a steam or gas engine, wheat thresher, or antique tractor, if the boiler or pressure vessel:<section prefix="(i)">has been inspected and issued a certificate of inspection by another state that has safety requirements equal to or greater than those of this State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">has been brought into this State to be used in a temporary exhibit or show.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Chief Boiler Inspector or a deputy boiler inspector shall have free access, during reasonable hours, to any premises in the State:<section prefix="(1)">to determine whether a boiler or pressure vessel is being constructed for use or installed in the State in accordance with this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">to inspect or investigate an accident or explosion that involves a boiler or pressure vessel;</section><section prefix="(3)">to make an inspection required under this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(4)">to investigate an inspection of a special inspector.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to the certificate inspections required under subsection (d) of this section, the Chief Boiler Inspector or a deputy boiler inspector shall:<section prefix="(i)">inspect or investigate accidents and explosions involving boilers and pressure vessels;</section><section prefix="(ii)">respond to and investigate complaints about the operation of boilers and pressure vessels; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">monitor the inspections of special inspectors.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Chief Boiler Inspector, a deputy boiler inspector, a special inspector, or an authorized inspection agency may:<section prefix="(i)">make certificate inspections of the installation of new boilers and pressure vessels; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">make certificate inspections of the repair or alteration of boilers and pressure vessels.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Chief Boiler Inspector or a deputy boiler inspector may make a certificate inspection of an antique boiler or pressure vessel or a model steam boiler.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Except as provided in paragraphs (1) through (3) of this subsection, if a boiler or pressure vessel:<section prefix="(i)">is insured by an insurer, a special inspector employed by the insurer or employed by an authorized inspection agency under contract with the insurer shall make the inspections required under subsection (d) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">is not insured by an insurer, the owner shall contract with the Chief Boiler Inspector, a deputy boiler inspector, a special inspector, or an authorized inspection agency to make the inspections required under subsection (d) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this paragraph, "private inspector" means an individual who:<section prefix="1.">has a level II or level III certification from the American Society for Nondestructive Testing (ASNT); and</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a boiler or pressure vessel is an exhibition or antique boiler or pressure vessel, including a steam or gas engine, wheat thresher, model steam boiler, or antique tractor, that will be used in an exhibit or show for noncommercial purposes, the inspections required under subsection (d) of this section may be made by a private inspector.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If a private inspector makes the inspections required under subsection (d) of this section, the private inspector shall file a report with the Chief Boiler Inspector on the results of the inspection.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">If the report of the private inspector shows that the exhibition or antique boiler or pressure vessel complies with the requirements of subsection (d) of this section and the regulations adopted under this subtitle, the Chief Boiler Inspector shall issue a certificate to the owner or user of the exhibition or antique boiler or pressure vessel that authorizes it to be used in an exhibit or show for noncommercial purposes.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">If a boiler or pressure vessel is not insured by an insurer, the Commissioner may contract with an insurer or an authorized inspection agency to have a special inspector who is employed by that insurer or authorized inspection agency make the inspections required under paragraph (1) of this subsection and subsection (d) of this section or conducted under paragraph (2) or (3) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for boilers and pressure vessels exempt under subsection (a) of this section or &#xA7; 12-903 of this subtitle, each boiler and each pressure vessel that is used or proposed to be used in the State shall be inspected, tested, and maintained in a safe operating condition in accordance with the regulations adopted by the Commissioner in conjunction with the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A certificate inspection required under this subsection shall be:<section prefix="(i)">an internal inspection if construction allows; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an inspection that is as complete as possible.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except for model steam boilers, a power boiler or a high pressure, high temperature water boiler shall:<section prefix="1.">receive a certificate inspection annually; and</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Board may extend to 2 years the interval between certificate inspections of a power boiler if:<section prefix="1.">the power boiler has internal continuous water treatment under the general supervision of a professional engineer who has experience in the treatment of boiler water; and</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A nuclear vessel within the scope of this subtitle shall be inspected and reported in a form and with appropriate information designated by the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, certificate inspections shall be conducted at time intervals set forth in regulations adopted under this subtitle and in accordance with Title 10 of the State Government Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The intervals shall protect public safety taking into consideration, consistent with &#xA7; 12-905 of this subtitle, the design, type, age, extent of automated monitoring, fuel, and operating characteristics of the boiler or pressure vessel.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If, at the discretion of the inspector, a hydrostatic test is considered necessary, the owner or user of a boiler or pressure vessel shall make the hydrostatic test.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, at least 30 days before installing a boiler or pressure vessel covered by this subtitle, the person who will perform the installation shall give the Commissioner notice of the installation in accordance with regulations adopted under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Under emergency circumstances, the person who will perform the installation of a boiler or pressure vessel may give the Commissioner notice of the installation less than 30 days before installation in accordance with regulations adopted under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except for a cast-iron sectional boiler or pressure vessel, each boiler to be installed in the State shall be inspected:<section prefix="(i)">during construction or field assembly, as required by regulations adopted under this subtitle, by the Chief Boiler Inspector, a deputy boiler inspector, a special inspector, or an authorized inspection agency; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the boiler is constructed outside the State, by an inspector who holds a commission issued by the National Board of Boiler and Pressure Vessel Inspectors.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 24 hours after an accident or explosion, the owner or user of a boiler or pressure vessel shall give the Chief Boiler Inspector notice of the accident or explosion in accordance with regulations adopted under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On notification or information, the Chief Boiler Inspector or a deputy boiler inspector shall investigate each accident or explosion that involves a boiler or pressure vessel covered by this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall provide for public safety and therefore has jurisdiction over the interpretation and application of the inspection requirements provided in the regulations adopted under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Inspection requirements of operating equipment shall:<section prefix="(i)">be in accordance with generally accepted practice; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">be compatible with the actual service conditions, including:<section prefix="1.">previous experience, based on records of performance and maintenance;</section><section prefix="3.">provision for related safe operation of controls; and</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The owner or user of a boiler or pressure vessel required by this subtitle to be inspected by the Chief Boiler Inspector or a deputy boiler inspector shall pay directly to the Chief Boiler Inspector, on completion of the inspection, a fee in accordance with the following schedule:<section prefix="(1)">certificate inspection:<section prefix="(i)">initial certificate inspection of a boiler or pressure vessel not previously inspected in the Stateno charge</section><section prefix="(ii)">follow-up inspection to determine compliance$50</section></section><section prefix="(2)">inspection of an antique or model steam boiler or pressure vessel................................................................................................................................$15</section><section prefix="(3)">investigation of an accident or complaintno charge</section><section prefix="(4)">other inspections, such as an inspection at a fabrication or repair facility, ASME joint review, or National Board of Inspection Code Repair Review, shall be charged at the following rates, and shall include all expenses such as travel and hotel costs:<section prefix="(i)">half day (up to 4 hours)$250</section><section prefix="(ii)">full day (up to 8 hours)$500</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
