<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-832</section_number>
  <catch_line>While an elevator mechanic license is in effect, it authorizes the licensee to erect, construct, wir...</catch_line>
  <order_by>832</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">While an elevator mechanic license is in effect, it authorizes the licensee to erect, construct, wire, alter, replace, maintain, repair, dismantle, or service elevator units under the direct supervision of a licensed elevator contractor.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">While an elevator contractor license is in effect, it authorizes the licensee to engage in the business of erecting, constructing, wiring, altering, replacing, maintaining, repairing, dismantling, or servicing elevator units.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">While an elevator renovator contractor license is in effect, it authorizes the licensee to engage in the business of performing work:<section prefix="(1)">on the interior of an elevator involving the removal or installation of the nonstructural surface of the elevator's wall, ceiling, floor, rail, or handle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">that does not affect the elevator's moving operation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">While an elevator renovator mechanic license is in effect, it authorizes the licensee to perform work:<section prefix="(1)">on the interior of an elevator involving the removal or installation of the nonstructural surface of the elevator's wall, ceiling, floor, rail, or handle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">that does not affect the elevator's moving operation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">While an accessibility lift mechanic license is in effect, the license authorizes the licensee to erect, construct, wire, alter, replace, maintain, repair, dismantle, and service commercial stairway chairlifts, vertical platform lifts, or incline platform lifts under the direct supervision of a licensed elevator contractor.</section>
  </text>
</law>
