<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-3-313</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, a commission is suspended or terminates when t...</catch_line>
  <order_by>313</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, a commission is suspended or terminates when the employer of the special police officer files written notice that states that the special police officer is suspended from or relieved of the duties of a special police officer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Governor may suspend or terminate a commission:<section prefix="(i)">on recommendation of the Secretary; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">on the Governor's own motion if the Governor finds it in the best interest of the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The suspension or termination shall be noted in the official records of the Governor.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The suspension or termination may not take effect until 5 days after notice is sent to both the special police officer and the special police officer's employer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Governor may delegate the power to suspend or terminate a commission to the Secretary of State, the Assistant Secretary of State, or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A commission does not terminate if:<section prefix="(1)">an employer no longer needs the services of a special police officer because the employer has transferred the business property described in the commission to another person for legal business purposes; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the other person executes a form prepared by the Secretary of State that affirms that the other person will employ the special police officer to protect that business property and will assume the responsibilities of the original employer as described in this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
