<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-6-307</section_number>
  <catch_line>The State Fire Marshal shall inspect for fire exits and reasonable safety standards:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>307</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Fire Marshal shall inspect for fire exits and reasonable safety standards:<section prefix="(i)">all institutions owned by the State or a county or municipal corporation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">all schools, theaters, churches, and other places of public assembly.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Fire Marshal shall report the findings of an inspection and any recommendations to the individual in charge of the institution or other place that was inspected.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to a building or premises actually occupied as a private dwelling.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Fire Marshal may enter a building or premises within the jurisdiction of the State Fire Marshal at reasonable hours to conduct an inspection that the State Fire Marshal considers necessary under this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An individual, including an employee of the State Fire Marshal, may not give prior notice of an inspection authorized under this subtitle without the written approval of the State Fire Marshal or designee of the State Fire Marshal.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to regulations adopted by the Commission, whenever the State Fire Marshal or designee of the State Fire Marshal inspects a place of employment, a representative of the employer and an authorized employee representative shall be given an opportunity to accompany the State Fire Marshal or designee during the inspection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If there is no authorized employee representative, the State Fire Marshal or designee shall consult with a reasonable number of employees about matters of safety and health in the place of employment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "trade secret" means a confidential formula, pattern, device, or compilation of information that:<section prefix="(i)">is used in an employer's business;</section><section prefix="(ii)">gives the employer an opportunity to obtain an advantage over competitors who do not know or use the information; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">is known only to the employer and those employees to whom it is necessary to confide the information.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, any information reported to or otherwise obtained by the State Fire Marshal or designee of the State Fire Marshal in connection with an inspection or proceeding under this subtitle that contains or might reveal a trade secret is confidential.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Information described in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph may be disclosed only:<section prefix="1.">to other officers or employees responsible for carrying out this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="2.">if relevant in a proceeding under this subtitle.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In a proceeding under this subtitle, the State Fire Marshal, designee of the State Fire Marshal, or a court of competent jurisdiction, as applicable, shall issue appropriate orders to protect the confidentiality of a trade secret.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
