<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-3-605</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>605</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Law enforcement agency" means a State, county, or municipal police department or agency, or a sheriff's department.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Missing offender" means an individual:<section prefix="(i)">whose whereabouts are unknown;</section><section prefix="(ii)">who is suspected of killing or seriously injuring a law enforcement officer;</section><section prefix="(iii)">whose disappearance poses a serious threat to the public and other law enforcement personnel; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">whose vehicle the reporting law enforcement agency is able to describe, including any information about the vehicle's registration plate.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department of State Police shall establish a Blue Alert Program to provide a system for rapid dissemination of information to assist in locating and apprehending a missing offender.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department of State Police shall:<section prefix="(i)">adopt guidelines and develop procedures for issuing a Blue Alert for a missing offender;</section><section prefix="(ii)">provide training to local law enforcement agencies on the guidelines and procedures to be used to make and handle a report of a missing offender;</section><section prefix="(iii)">provide assistance to a local law enforcement agency, as necessary, to assist in the location and apprehension of a missing offender;</section><section prefix="(iv)">recruit public and commercial television and radio broadcasters, local volunteer groups, and other members of the public to assist in developing and implementing a Blue Alert; and</section><section prefix="(v)">consult with the State Highway Administration and the Governor's Division of Emergency Management to establish a plan for providing information relevant to a Blue Alert to the public through the dynamic message sign system located across the State.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A law enforcement officer or agency that apprehends a missing offender who is the subject of a Blue Alert immediately shall notify the Department of State Police and the law enforcement agency that filed the report resulting in the Blue Alert that the missing offender has been apprehended.</section>
  </text>
</law>
