<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-8-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to subsection (b) of this section, each county shall receive an initial allocation of money based on a percentage to be determined in the following manner:<section prefix="(1)">the Director of Assessments and Taxation shall certify to the Director each county's total percentage of land use property tax accounts, including vacant unimproved properties, relative to the statewide total of all land use property tax accounts for the first completed fiscal year immediately preceding the fiscal year for which money is to be allocated;</section><section prefix="(2)">except as provided in item (3) of this subsection, the percentage determined in item (1) of this subsection shall then be applied for each county to any amount included in the State budget for the purposes of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(3)">each county shall receive an allocation of at least 2% of the total Fund as appropriated in the State budget, in addition to the amount that is distributed to fire, rescue, and ambulance companies, departments, or stations located in qualified municipal corporations in accordance with subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (6) of this subsection, each county shall distribute the money provided under this subtitle on the basis of need to fire, rescue, and ambulance companies, departments, or stations in the county, including  companies, departments, or stations:<section prefix="(i)">located in municipal corporations; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">located outside the State if the company, department, or station:<section prefix="1.">has been a member of the Maryland State Firemen's Association for at least the past 10 years; and</section><section prefix="2.">has a first due response area in the State.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each county shall determine need in accordance with procedures that the county uses to adopt its budget.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In determining need under this subsection, the county shall consider:<section prefix="(i)">the failure to meet minimum standards established by the county or the Maryland State Firemen's Association;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the existence or potential existence of an emergency situation as described in &#xA7; 8-203 of this title;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the age and condition of existing facilities and equipment;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the lack of availability of mutual aid;</section><section prefix="(v)">any service problems associated with demographic conditions; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">any other relevant factors.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In addition to consideration of the factors in paragraph (3) of this subsection, for a volunteer company the county shall consider the company's inability to raise money to pay for the item.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Notwithstanding paragraphs (3) and (4) of this subsection, each county shall give the highest funding priority to the failure to meet minimum standards or the existence of an emergency situation as described in &#xA7; 8-203 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Distribution of money to fire, rescue, and ambulance companies, departments, or stations located in qualified municipal corporations in a county in the aggregate may not be less than 50% of the proportion that the expenditures of the qualified municipal corporation bear to total aggregate expenditures for fire protection in that county.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">To receive money under this subsection, each county shall participate in the Maryland Fire Incident Reporting System and Ambulance Information System.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
