<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-3-508</section_number>
  <catch_line>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL SEPTEMBER 30, 2016 PER CHAPTERS 78 AND 79 OF 2011 //...</catch_line>
  <order_by>508</order_by>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL SEPTEMBER 30, 2016 PER CHAPTERS 78 AND 79 OF 2011 //<section prefix="(a)"><section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">"Discharge" means firing an ECD at a person.</section><section prefix="(ii)">"Discharge" does not include firing an ECD during a training exercise.</section></section><section prefix="(3)">"Electronic control device" or "ECD" means a portable device designed as a weapon capable of injuring, immobilizing, or inflicting pain on an individual by the discharge of electrical current.</section><section prefix="(4)">"Law enforcement agency" means an agency that is listed in &#xA7; 3-101(e) of this title.</section><section prefix="(5)">"Police Training Commission" means the unit within the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services established under &#xA7; 3-202 of this title.</section></section><section prefix="(b)">On or before March 31 of each year, a law enforcement agency that issues electronic control devices to its law enforcement officers shall report, for each time a law enforcement officer discharges an ECD, the following information to the Governor's Office of Crime Control and Prevention using the format developed under subsection (c) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">the date, time, and location of the discharge;</section><section prefix="(2)">the type of mode used and the point of impact;</section><section prefix="(3)">the number of ECD cycles, the duration of each cycle, and the duration between cycles;</section><section prefix="(4)">the race, gender, and age of the person against whom the ECD was discharged;</section><section prefix="(5)">the law enforcement officer's reason for discharging the ECD;</section><section prefix="(6)">the type of weapon, if any, possessed by the person against whom the ECD was discharged;</section><section prefix="(7)">the type of incident in which the person against whom the ECD was discharged was involved;</section><section prefix="(8)">any injuries or deaths resulting from the discharge other than punctures or lacerations caused by the ECD probes; and</section><section prefix="(9)">the type of medical care, if any, provided to the person against whom the ECD was discharged, other than the treatment of punctures or lacerations caused by the ECD probes.</section></section><section prefix="(c)">The Police Training Commission, in consultation with the Governor's Office of Crime Control and Prevention, the Maryland Chiefs of Police Association, and the Maryland Sheriffs' Association, shall develop a standardized format that each law enforcement agency shall use in reporting data to the Governor's Office of Crime Control and Prevention under subsection (b) of this section.</section><section prefix="(d)">A law enforcement agency shall:<section prefix="(1)">compile the data described in subsection (b) of this section for each year as a report in the format required under subsection (c) of this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">not later than March 31 of each year, submit the report to:<section prefix="(i)">the Governor's Office of Crime Control and Prevention; and</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">the local governing body of the jurisdiction served by the law enforcement agency that is the subject of the report; or</section><section prefix="2.">if the jurisdiction served by the law enforcement agency that is the subject of the report is a municipal corporation, the chief executive officer of the jurisdiction; and</section></section></section><section prefix="(3)">make the report available to the public on request.</section></section><section prefix="(e)"><section prefix="(1)">The Governor's Office of Crime Control and Prevention shall analyze and summarize the reports of law enforcement agencies submitted under subsection (d) of this section.</section><section prefix="(2)">The Governor's Office of Crime Control and Prevention shall submit a report of the analyses and summaries of the reports of law enforcement agencies described in paragraph (1) of this subsection to the Governor, the General Assembly, as provided in &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, and each law enforcement agency before September 1 of each year.</section></section><section prefix="(f)"><section prefix="(1)">If a law enforcement agency fails to comply with the reporting provisions of this section, the Governor's Office of Crime Control and Prevention shall report the noncompliance to the Police Training Commission.</section><section prefix="(2)">On receipt of a report of noncompliance, the Police Training Commission shall contact the law enforcement agency and request that the agency comply with the required reporting provisions.</section><section prefix="(3)">If the law enforcement agency fails to comply with the required reporting provisions of this section within 30 days after being contacted by the Police Training Commission with a request to comply, the Governor's Office of Crime Control and Prevention and the Police Training Commission jointly shall report the noncompliance to the Governor and the Legislative Policy Committee of the General Assembly.</section></section></text>
</law>
