<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-901" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-901</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Authorized inspection agency" means an entity that:<section prefix="(1)">is accredited in accordance with the National Board of Boiler and Pressure Vessel Inspectors NB-369; or</section><section prefix="(2)">meets the qualification and definition of the National Board of Boiler and Pressure Vessel Inspectors NB-360.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Board" means the Board of Boiler Rules.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Boiler" means:<section prefix="(1)">a closed vessel in which water is heated, steam is generated, steam is superheated, or a combination of these functions is accomplished, under pressure or vacuum for use externally to the vessel by the direct application of heat from the combustion of fuels or from electricity or nuclear energy; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a fired unit for heating or vaporizing liquids other than water if the unit is separate from a processing system and is complete within itself.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Certificate" means a certificate issued by the Chief Boiler Inspector to operate a boiler or pressure vessel.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Certificate inspection" means an inspection, the report of which is used by the Chief Boiler Inspector to determine whether to issue a certificate.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Labor and Industry.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Heating boiler" means:<section prefix="(1)">a steam boiler that operates at pressures not exceeding 15 psig; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a hot water boiler that operates at pressures not exceeding 160 psig or temperatures not exceeding 250 degrees Fahrenheit.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"High pressure, high temperature water boiler" means a water boiler that operates at pressures exceeding 160 psig or temperatures exceeding 250 degrees Fahrenheit.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Model steam boiler" means a boiler that is:<section prefix="(1)">individually fabricated for noncommercial use;</section><section prefix="(2)">used primarily for demonstration, exhibition, or educational purposes; and</section><section prefix="(3)">not for profit.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Power boiler" means a boiler in which steam or other vapor is generated at a pressure of more than 15 psig.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Pressure vessel" means a vessel in which the pressure is obtained:<section prefix="(i)">from an external source; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">by the application of heat from:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Pressure vessel" does not include a pipe, piping component, or structure whose primary function is to transport fluids.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Secretary" means the Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
