<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-9-804</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>804</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A fire official shall give written notice to the occupant of premises where combustible material has accumulated to remove the combustible material from the premises within 48 hours after receipt of the notice, if after an inspection made under this subtitle, the fire official determines that the accumulation of combustible material increases the danger of fire to:<section prefix="(1)">the premises where the combustible material has accumulated; or</section><section prefix="(2)">adjacent property.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the combustible material is not removed from the premises within 48 hours after receipt of a notice under subsection (a) of this section, the fire official may:<section prefix="(i)">remove the combustible material from the premises;</section><section prefix="(ii)">send a bill to the occupant of the premises for the cost of the removal; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">certify the cost of the removal to the treasurer of the jurisdiction.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the cost of the removal is not paid to the treasurer within 30 days after receipt of the bill, the jurisdiction may bring a civil action against the occupant to recover the cost.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not refuse or neglect to remove combustible material within 48 hours after receipt of a notice under subsection (a) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who violates this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine of not less than $5 and not exceeding $50 for each violation.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
