<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-2-502</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>502</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a statewide DNA data base system in the Crime Laboratory.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The statewide DNA data base system is the central repository for all DNA testing information as provided in this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Director shall:<section prefix="(1)">administer and manage the statewide DNA data base system;</section><section prefix="(2)">consult with the Secretary on the adoption of appropriate regulations for protocols and operations of the statewide DNA data base system;</section><section prefix="(3)">ensure compatibility with Federal Bureau of Investigation and CODIS requirements, including the use of comparable test procedures, quality assurance, laboratory equipment, and computer software;</section><section prefix="(4)">ensure the security and confidentiality of all records in the statewide DNA data base system; and</section><section prefix="(5)">provide for a liaison with the Federal Bureau of Investigation and other criminal justice agencies related to the State's participation in CODIS or in any DNA data base designated by the Department.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Crime Laboratory shall:<section prefix="(1)">receive DNA samples for analysis, classification, storage, and disposal;</section><section prefix="(2)">file the DNA record of identification characteristic profiles of DNA samples submitted to the Crime Laboratory; and</section><section prefix="(3)">make information that relates to DNA samples and DNA records available to other agencies and individuals as authorized by this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Director may contract with a qualified DNA laboratory to complete DNA typing analyses if the laboratory meets the guidelines established by the Director.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Subject to &#xA7; 2-511 of this subtitle, records of testing shall be permanently retained on file at the Crime Laboratory.</section>
  </text>
</law>
