<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-826</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided in Part III of this subtitle, a person shall be licensed by the Board a...</catch_line>
  <order_by>826</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in Part III of this subtitle, a person shall be licensed by the Board as an elevator mechanic before the person erects, constructs, wires, alters, replaces, maintains, repairs, dismantles, or services elevator units in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as otherwise provided in Part III of this subtitle, a person shall be licensed by the Board as an elevator contractor before the person engages in the business of erecting, constructing, wiring, altering, replacing, maintaining, repairing, dismantling, or servicing elevator units in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in Part III of this subtitle, a person shall be licensed by the Board as an elevator renovator contractor before the person engages in the business of elevator renovating.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">By June 1, 2004, a person who engages in the business of elevator renovating for a business incorporated before January 1, 2002, shall be licensed by the Board as an elevator renovator contractor before the person engages in the business of elevator renovating.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as otherwise provided in Part III of this subtitle, a person shall be licensed by the Board as an elevator renovator mechanic before the person performs elevator renovator work.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except as otherwise provided in Part III of this subtitle, a person shall be licensed by the Board as an accessibility lift mechanic before the person erects, constructs, wires, alters, replaces, maintains, repairs, dismantles, or services commercial stairway chairlifts, vertical platform lifts, or incline platform lifts in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensed elevator contractor is not required for removing or dismantling an elevator unit if:<section prefix="(i)">the elevator unit is destroyed as a result of a complete demolition of a building; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a hoistway or wellway is demolished back to the basic support structure.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An individual who works as an elevator apprentice under the direct supervision of a licensed elevator mechanic or licensed elevator renovator mechanic need not obtain a license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An individual commonly known as an elevator helper who works under the direct supervision of a licensed elevator mechanic or a licensed elevator renovator mechanic need not obtain a license.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An elevator refinisher need not obtain a license.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A crane mechanic performing work on elevators or lifts located on a port facility owned, leased, or operated by the Maryland Port Administration need not obtain a license.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A person installing a residential stairway chairlift need not obtain a license.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A person who is licensed under this subtitle as an elevator mechanic need not obtain a license to provide the services described in subsection (e) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall adopt regulations, including education and experience requirements, to certify accessibility lift mechanic specialists to erect, construct, wire, alter, replace, maintain, repair, dismantle, or service private residential elevators.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Until the Board adopts regulations to certify accessibility lift mechanic specialists to perform work on private residential elevators, an accessibility lift mechanic may provide the services described in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A candidate actively completing the certification requirements adopted by the Board under paragraph (1) of this subsection may continue to perform that work without certification for up to 4 years after the effective date of the regulations.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
