<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-6-308</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>308</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the State Fire Marshal shall collect the fees established by the Commission under &#xA7; 6-206 of this title for conducting inspections.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Fire Marshal may not collect a fee for inspecting property that is owned by:<section prefix="(i)">the State or a county or municipal corporation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a government-affiliated or volunteer fire, rescue, or emergency medical services entity.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection, "plan review" means the review of all construction drawings and specifications for commercial and residential construction.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Plan review" includes the review of site, architectural, mechanical, electrical, sprinkler, fire alarm, and special extinguishing systems drawings and specifications.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">construction of one- and two-family dwellings; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">construction for which plan review is conducted by the local authority.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The State Fire Marshal shall collect the fees established by the Commission under &#xA7; 6-206 of this title for reviewing building plans to ensure compliance with the State Fire Prevention Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The fee for plan review shall be submitted with the plans.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The State Fire Marshal shall:<section prefix="(1)">keep records of all fees collected under this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">pay the money collected under this section into the General Fund.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
