<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-5-132</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>132</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Authorized user" means the owner of a handgun or a person authorized by the owner to possess and use the handgun.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"External safety lock" means an external device that is:<section prefix="(i)">attached to a handgun with a key or combination lock; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">designed to prevent a handgun from being discharged unless the device has been deactivated.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Handgun" does not include a signal, starter, or blank pistol.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Handgun Roster Board" means the Handgun Roster Board established under &#xA7; 5-404 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Integrated mechanical safety device" means a disabling or locking device that is:<section prefix="(i)">built into a handgun; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">designed to prevent the handgun from being discharged unless the device has been deactivated.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Personalized handgun" means a handgun manufactured with incorporated design technology that:<section prefix="(i)">allows the handgun to be fired only by the authorized user; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">prevents any of the safety characteristics of the handgun from being readily deactivated.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">the purchase, sale, or transportation of a handgun to or by a federally licensed gun dealer or manufacturer that provides or services a handgun for:<section prefix="(i)">personnel of any unit of the federal government;</section><section prefix="(ii)">members of the armed forces of the United States or the National Guard;</section><section prefix="(iii)">law enforcement personnel of the State or any local law enforcement agency in the State while acting within the scope of their official duties; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">an organization that is required by federal law governing its specific business or activity to maintain handguns and applicable ammunition;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">a firearm modified to be permanently inoperative;</section><section prefix="(3)">the sale or transfer of a handgun by a federally licensed gun dealer or manufacturer covered under item (1) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(4)">the sale or transfer of a handgun by a federally licensed gun dealer or manufacturer to a lawful customer outside the State; or</section><section prefix="(5)">an antique firearm.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A dealer may not sell, offer for sale, rent, or transfer in the State a handgun manufactured on or before December 31, 2002, unless the handgun is sold, offered for sale, rented, or transferred with an external safety lock.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On or after January 1, 2003, a dealer may not sell, offer for sale, rent, or transfer in the State a handgun manufactured on or after January 1, 2003, unless the handgun has an integrated mechanical safety device.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Handgun Roster Board annually shall:<section prefix="(i)">review the status of personalized handgun technology; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">on or before July 1, report its findings to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In reviewing the status of personalized handgun technology under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Handgun Roster Board shall consider:<section prefix="(i)">the number and variety of models and calibers of personalized handguns that are available for sale;</section><section prefix="(ii)">each study, analysis, or other evaluation of personalized handguns conducted or commissioned by:<section prefix="1.">the National Institute of Justice;</section><section prefix="2.">a federal, State, or local law enforcement laboratory; or</section><section prefix="3.">any other entity with an expertise in handgun technology; and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">any other information that the Handgun Roster Board considers relevant.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
