<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-908" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-908</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A new boiler or pressure vessel may not be installed and operated in the State unless:<section prefix="(i)">the boiler or pressure vessel conforms to the regulations adopted under this subtitle that govern new construction and installation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Board issues a special installation and operating permit for the boiler or pressure vessel.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may issue a special installation and operating permit for a boiler or pressure vessel if it:<section prefix="(i)">is of special design or construction; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is not inconsistent with the spirit and safety objectives of the regulations adopted under this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For existing boiler and pressure vessel installations:<section prefix="(1)">the maximum allowable pressure of a boiler or pressure vessel that carries the ASME Code symbol shall be determined by the applicable provisions of the ASME Code under which it was constructed and stamped; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the maximum allowable pressure of a boiler or pressure vessel that does not carry the ASME Code symbol shall be computed in accordance with the Inspection Code of the National Board of Boiler and Pressure Vessel Inspectors.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This subtitle does not prevent the use, sale, or reinstallation of an existing boiler or pressure vessel if the boiler or pressure vessel:<section prefix="(1)">has been made to conform to the regulations adopted under this subtitle that govern existing installations; and</section><section prefix="(2)">has been inspected and found not to be in an unsafe condition.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
