<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-7-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only to Allegany County, Carroll County, Cecil County, Dorchester County, Frede...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section applies only to Allegany County, Carroll County, Cecil County, Dorchester County, Frederick County, Harford County, Kent County, Somerset County, Wicomico County, and Worcester County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as modified by this section, the provisions of &#xA7; 7-302 of this subtitle apply to this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the commanding officer may designate 12 members of a fire company to be appointed as deputy sheriffs.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Cecil County, the commanding officer may designate 20 members of a fire company to be appointed as deputy sheriffs.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The sheriff of a county subject to this section may require a member of a fire company appointed as deputy sheriff to demonstrate a satisfactory level of training in those areas of law enforcement commensurate with the duties of deputy sheriff described in this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the sheriff requires demonstration of a satisfactory level of training, then the sheriff must provide the training, at a time and place that the sheriff considers suitable.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The powers of members of fire companies appointed as deputy sheriffs under this section are limited to those necessary to perform the duties of deputy sheriffs while functioning at:<section prefix="(i)">parades;</section><section prefix="(ii)">accidents;</section><section prefix="(iii)">floods;</section><section prefix="(iv)">other emergencies; or</section><section prefix="(v)">public events conducted by or under the auspices of a fire company or the sheriff's department.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The powers authorized under this subsection may be exercised:<section prefix="(i)">in a municipal corporation, subject to the discretion and control of the chief of the police force of the municipal corporation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">in other areas of the county; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">on State roads, subject to the discretion and control of the Department of State Police.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member appointed as deputy sheriff is deemed to be performing the duties of deputy sheriff when on duty and wearing a badge of authority.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member appointed as deputy sheriff may not use a weapon in the performance of duties authorized under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In Allegany County, Carroll County, Frederick County, and Harford County, a member appointed as deputy sheriff may also perform traffic control for public functions held by a municipal corporation, group, or committee on request for and approval of the services by the sheriff.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A member appointed as deputy sheriff performing the duties of deputy sheriff in an emergency situation to which a fire company or ambulance company has been dispatched by the Allegany County Emergency Management Center in Allegany County, the Frederick County Central Alarm Board in Frederick County, or the Carroll County Emergency Operations Center in Carroll County, is subject to the authority of the commanding officer of that fire company or ambulance company.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a member appointed as deputy sheriff is not a member in good standing of the fire company or ambulance company that has been dispatched, then the member may not perform the duties described in this section.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member appointed as deputy sheriff performing the duties of deputy sheriff at a public event conducted by or under the auspices of a fire company or ambulance company is subject to the authority of the commanding officer of that fire company or ambulance company.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
