<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-3-503</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>503</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The purpose of this section is to preserve, promote, and protect public safety and peace in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to an agent, employee, or representative of another state or a political subdivision of another state who is present in this State to enforce the laws of the other state.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person subject to this section shall register with the law enforcement agency designated by the governing body of a county when the person enters the county for the purpose of surveillance of the presence or activities of customers or patrons of a business establishment in the State that is engaged in the lawful sale or supply of goods or services.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When registering, a person subject to this section shall provide:<section prefix="(i)">the name and address of the person;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the name of the person's employer or principal; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the location of the proposed surveillance.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On request, the registration record shall be made available during normal business hours to the public and to lawful business or commercial enterprises in the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who fails to register in accordance with this section may not register for 6 months after the failure to register is judicially determined.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The registration of a person who violates this section shall be suspended for 6 months after the violation is judicially determined.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person who violates this section while the person's right to register is suspended or while the person's registration is suspended, is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 2 years or a fine not exceeding $1,000 or both.</section>
  </text>
</law>
