<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-110.3" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-14-110.3</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "kidney dialysis center" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 19-3B-01 of the Health - General Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A kidney dialysis center shall have an emergency plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An emergency plan shall include policies and procedures that will be followed before, during, and after an emergency to address:<section prefix="(1)">the safe management of individuals who are receiving services at the kidney dialysis center when an emergency occurs;</section><section prefix="(2)">notification of patients, families, staff, and licensing authorities regarding actions that will be taken concerning the provision of dialysis services to the individuals served by the kidney dialysis center;</section><section prefix="(3)">staff coverage, organization, and assignment of responsibilities; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the continuity of operations, including procedures to secure access to essential goods, equipment, and dialysis services.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not prohibit a kidney dialysis center from applying for and receiving reimbursement:<section prefix="(i)">under any applicable insurance policy; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">from any State or federal funds that may be available due to a declared State or federal emergency.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A kidney dialysis center is solely responsible for any financial obligation arising from voluntary or mandatory activation of any aspect of the emergency plan developed by the kidney dialysis center under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">For purposes of coordinating local emergency planning efforts, a kidney dialysis center shall provide access to the emergency plans developed under this section to local organizations for emergency management.</section>
  </text>
</law>
