<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-8-302</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>302</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only to Dorchester County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection, the County Commissioners of Dorchester County shall pay at least the sum of $118,500 each year to the volunteer fire companies in the county for their benefit as long as the volunteer fire companies are active, fire-fighting organizations.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each volunteer fire company shall use the money received to support, maintain, equip, and operate the volunteer fire company for the purpose of fighting fires in the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each volunteer fire company shall comply with the bylaws of the Volunteer Fire Companies Association of Dorchester County.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The County Commissioners may not make a payment to a volunteer fire company unless the volunteer fire company complies with the bylaws of the Volunteer Fire Companies Association of Dorchester County.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The County Commissioners shall use property tax revenue to pay volunteer fire companies in accordance with subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The County Commissioners shall distribute the money required by subsection (b) of this section on October 1 of each year to the following volunteer fire companies in at least the following amounts:</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Elliotts Volunteer Fire Company shall receive an amount set by the County Commissioners.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before paying money to a volunteer fire company, the County Commissioners may require the officers of the volunteer fire company to appear before the County Commissioners and submit evidence satisfactory to the County Commissioners that the volunteer fire company:<section prefix="(i)">is an active fire-fighting organization; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">has spent the money received in prior years under this section in accordance with this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a volunteer fire company ceases to be an active fire-fighting organization or fails to spend the money received in accordance with this section, the County Commissioners shall:<section prefix="(i)">withhold the current year's money from the volunteer fire company; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">allocate the unspent money to the contingent fund of Dorchester County.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
