<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-806</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>806</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, each elevator unit shall be inspected, tested, and maintained in a safe operating condition in accordance with:<section prefix="(1)">the Safety Code; and</section><section prefix="(2)">any other regulations adopted by the Commissioner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, an elevator unit installed before July 1, 1955, may be used without being altered or rebuilt to comply with the requirements of the Safety Code.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Each elevator shall be equipped with standard hoistway entrance protection, and each passenger elevator of more than 100 feet per minute contract speed shall be provided with car doors or gates that meet the requirements of the Safety Code.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, each elevator unit installed before July 1, 1955:<section prefix="(i)">shall be maintained in a safe operating condition so as not to create a substantial probability of serious physical harm or death; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is subject to inspections and tests as required.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For purposes of this subsection, an alteration of an existing elevator unit is any change made to it other than the repair or replacement of damaged, worn, or broken parts necessary for normal operation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each alteration or relocation of an elevator unit installed after January 1, 1975, shall meet the requirements of the Safety Code.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">On written request, the Commissioner may grant exceptions from the literal requirements or allow the use of devices or methods other than those specified under the Safety Code and other regulations adopted by the Commissioner if:<section prefix="(1)">it is evident that the exception is necessary to prevent undue hardship; or</section><section prefix="(2)">existing conditions prevent practical compliance and in the opinion of the Commissioner reasonable safety can be secured.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
