<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-14-112</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>112</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Expenditures necessitated by emergencies shall first be made using money regularly appropriated to State and local agencies.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Governor finds that regularly appropriated money is inadequate to cope with an emergency, the Board of Public Works may make contingency money available in accordance with the State budget.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The State may:<section prefix="(1)">accept any allotment of federal money and commodities and manage and dispose of them in whatever manner may be required by federal law; and</section><section prefix="(2)">take advantage of the federal Disaster Relief Act of 1974 and any amendments or supplements to it, and any other federal law that provides grants and public assistance for the purposes of this subtitle and Subtitles 2 and 4 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In carrying out this subtitle, the Governor, Director, and executive officers or governing bodies of the political subdivisions shall use the services, equipment, supplies, and facilities of existing agencies and units of the State and the political subdivisions to the maximum extent practicable.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The officers and personnel of the agencies and units of the State and the political subdivisions shall cooperate with and extend services and facilities to the Governor, Adjutant General, Director, and the local organizations for emergency management on request.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the direction of the Governor, the Maryland National Guard shall use its services, equipment, supplies, and facilities in life-threatening emergencies that are beyond the capabilities of local authorities.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the federal government, another state, or an agency or officer of the federal government or another state offers to this State or a political subdivision services, equipment, supplies, materials, or money by way of gift, grant, or loan for purposes of emergency management, the State acting through the Governor, or the political subdivision acting with the consent of the Governor and through its executive officer or governing body, may:<section prefix="(i)">accept the offer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">authorize an officer of this State or the political subdivision to receive the services, equipment, supplies, materials, or money.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a person offers to the State or a political subdivision aid or assistance, the State or political subdivision may accept the aid and assistance in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
