<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-504" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-2-504</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In accordance with regulations adopted under this subtitle, an individual who is convicted of a felony or a violation of &#xA7; 6-205 or &#xA7; 6-206 of the Criminal Law Article shall:<section prefix="(i)">have a DNA sample collected either at the time of sentence or on intake to a correctional facility, if the individual is sentenced to a term of imprisonment; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">provide a DNA sample as a condition of sentence or probation, if the individual is not sentenced to a term of imprisonment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual who was convicted of a felony or a violation of &#xA7; 6-205 or &#xA7; 6-206 of the Criminal Law Article on or before October 1, 2003 and who remains confined in a correctional facility on or after October 1, 1999, shall submit a DNA sample to the Department.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In accordance with regulations adopted under this subtitle, each DNA sample required to be collected under this section shall be collected:<section prefix="(1)">at the correctional facility where the individual is confined, if the individual is confined in a correctional facility on or after October 1, 2003, or is sentenced to a term of imprisonment on or after October 1, 2003;</section><section prefix="(2)">at a facility specified by the Director, if the individual is on probation or is not sentenced to a term of imprisonment; or</section><section prefix="(3)">at a suitable location in a circuit court following the imposition of sentence.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A DNA sample shall be collected by an individual who is:<section prefix="(1)">designated by the Director; and</section><section prefix="(2)">trained in the collection procedures that the Crime Laboratory uses.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A second DNA sample shall be taken if needed to obtain sufficient DNA for the statewide DNA data base or if ordered by the court for good cause shown.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Failure of an individual who is not sentenced to a term of imprisonment to provide a DNA sample within 90 days after notice by the Director is a violation of probation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
