<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-203" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-3-203</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission consists of 15 members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 15 members of the Commission:<section prefix="(i)">one shall be the President of the Maryland Chiefs of Police Association;</section><section prefix="(ii)">one shall be the President of the Maryland Sheriffs Association;</section><section prefix="(iii)">one shall be the President of the Maryland Law Enforcement Officers, Inc.;</section><section prefix="(iv)">one shall be the Attorney General of the State;</section><section prefix="(v)">one shall be the Secretary of State Police;</section><section prefix="(vi)">one shall be the Police Commissioner of Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="(vii)">one shall be the Chancellor of the University System of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(viii)">one shall be the agent in charge of the Baltimore office of the FBI;</section><section prefix="(ix)">one shall be the President of the Eastern Shore Police Association;</section><section prefix="(x)">one shall represent the Maryland State Lodge of Fraternal Order of Police;</section><section prefix="(xi)">one shall be the Secretary of Public Safety and Correctional Services;</section><section prefix="(xii)">one shall be the Chairman of the Maryland Municipal League Police Executive Association; and</section><section prefix="(xiii)">three shall be police officials of the State appointed under subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall appoint the three police officials to be members of the Commission with the approval of the Governor and the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The three members appointed under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall represent different geographic areas of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member who is appointed under subsection (b) of this section is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of the members who are appointed under subsection (b) of this section are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Commission on October 1, 2003.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member who is appointed under subsection (b) of this section continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the remainder of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except for the three members appointed by the Secretary under subsection (b) of this section, a member of the Commission may serve personally at a Commission meeting or may designate a representative from the member's unit, agency, or association who may act at any meeting to the same effect as if the member were personally present.</section>
  </text>
</law>
