<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-313" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-2-313</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each publicly owned dog used for law enforcement work by the State or a local subdivision of the State shall have a license issued by the Department under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A license under this section shall be issued:<section prefix="(i)">on the form prepared and provided by the Department; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">to the law enforcement officer to whom the licensed dog is assigned.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each license shall:<section prefix="(i)">be dated and numbered;</section><section prefix="(ii)">state the law enforcement agency to which the dog belongs; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">describe the dog that is licensed.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A license issued under this section is valid for all dog licensing purposes anywhere in the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A license issued under this section is in effect until the earlier of:<section prefix="(1)">revocation of the license by the Department; and</section><section prefix="(2)">removal of the licensed dog from law enforcement work.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall provide with each license a metal tag that:<section prefix="(i)">is stamped "Department of State Police"; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">bears the license number of the dog.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The tag shall be affixed to a substantial collar to be provided by the law enforcement agency to which the dog belongs.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The tag and collar shall be kept on the licensed dog at all times unless the dog is confined in a kennel or is under the personal charge of the law enforcement officer to whom the dog is assigned.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The licensing responsibility of this section does not create liability for the Department or its officers or employees for any action of a licensed dog or the law enforcement officer to whom it is assigned.</section>
  </text>
</law>
