<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-204" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-204</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"ASHRAE" means the American Society of Heating, Refrigerating, and Air Conditioning Engineers.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Guidelines" means the guidelines for recommended illumination levels in existing public buildings.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Public building" means a building owned by the State, a county, or municipal corporation or a unit of the State, a county, or municipal corporation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to each public building that is 10,000 or more square feet in area per floor.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In conjunction with the Department of Natural Resources, the Department of Housing and Community Development shall develop guidelines for recommended illumination levels in existing public buildings in the State 6 months after ASHRAE 100 standards are adopted.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">After approval by the Joint Committee on Administrative, Executive, and Legislative Review, the guidelines shall be published in the Maryland Register and other appropriate media to:<section prefix="(1)">encourage use of the guidelines; and</section><section prefix="(2)">provide standards in accordance with which owners, operators, or both of existing public buildings, including local governments, the Department of General Services, and other governmental units that manage State buildings, may target their energy conservation effort with regard to illumination.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In conjunction with the Department of Natural Resources, the Department of Housing and Community Development shall provide training to local jurisdictions on the application of the guidelines.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The training may include a program developed by a federal agency or a contract agent.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department of Natural Resources shall assist local jurisdictions to:<section prefix="(1)">determine the cost-benefit impacts of implementing the guidelines; and</section><section prefix="(2)">perform audits of specific buildings or installations to determine lighting performance characteristics and the savings possible through implementing the guidelines.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is an advisory commission on energy conservation in buildings.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The commission consists of 15 members appointed by the Secretary of Housing and Community Development.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The members shall be broadly representative, including representatives from:<section prefix="(i)">State and local code enforcement agencies;</section><section prefix="(ii)">architectural and engineering professions;</section><section prefix="(iii)">public utilities;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the construction industry;</section><section prefix="(v)">legislative bodies of local government; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">the public.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member of the commission:<section prefix="(i)">may not receive compensation for service on the commission; but</section><section prefix="(ii)">is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
