<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-13-503</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Maryland Defense Force consists of:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>503</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Maryland Defense Force consists of:<section prefix="(1)">commissioned or assigned officers; and</section><section prefix="(2)">qualified individuals who volunteer to serve and are commissioned, appointed, or enlisted in the Maryland Defense Force.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An individual may not be commissioned or enlisted in the Maryland Defense Force if the individual:<section prefix="(1)">is not a citizen of the United States;</section><section prefix="(2)">has been dismissed from or received a bad conduct discharge or a dishonorable discharge, or any discharge other than under honorable conditions, from a military or naval organization of this State or of another state, or from any of the United States armed forces or its auxiliaries, or has been convicted of an offense under the laws of the United States or of any state punishable by imprisonment for more than 1 year, no matter what punishment was actually imposed; or</section><section prefix="(3)">does not meet the qualifications for commissioning, appointment, or enlistment specified in regulations governing the Maryland Defense Force.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A civil organization, society, club, post, order, fraternity, association, brotherhood, body, union, league, or other combination of persons or civil groups may not enlist in the Maryland Defense Force as an organization or unit.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">All members of the Maryland Defense Force serve on a voluntary basis and without pay, unless under orders, approved by the Adjutant General, specifying that their service is with pay.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an order approved by the Adjutant General specifies that the service of a member of the Maryland Defense Force is with pay, the member may be compensated in accordance with &#xA7; 13-406 of this title.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
