<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-5-504</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Cease Fire Council Grant Program....</catch_line>
  <order_by>504</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Cease Fire Council Grant Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Cease Fire Council Grant Program shall be funded as provided in the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Grants made by the Council shall be used to carry out the purposes of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">When making grants, the Council shall consider and give priority to:<section prefix="(1)">comprehensive and coordinated law enforcement and prosecution programs that target criminals and juveniles who use or illegally possess firearms;</section><section prefix="(2)">law enforcement and prosecution salaries and overtime in support of firearm violence reduction programs;</section><section prefix="(3)">covert firearms-related investigations and debriefing of criminal and juvenile arrestees and offenders for information related to illegal firearms trafficking;</section><section prefix="(4)">initiatives that support the tracing of firearms used to commit crimes or delinquent acts and the identification of illegal firearms traffickers;</section><section prefix="(5)">purchases of technology and information systems to support firearm violence reduction initiatives; and</section><section prefix="(6)">other efforts that aid in apprehending and prosecuting criminals or apprehending and filing a complaint against juveniles who use or illegally possess firearms.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Expenditures from the Cease Fire Council Grant Program may be made only in accordance with the State budget or by budget amendment.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Council shall adopt regulations for the grant process and the oversight of grants made by the Council.</section>
  </text>
</law>
