<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-2-702</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>702</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Vehicle Theft Prevention Council in the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The purpose of the Council is to help prevent and deter theft of private passenger and commercial motor vehicles and related crime, including vandalism and theft of property from vehicles, in the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Council consists of the following 13 members appointed by the Governor:<section prefix="(i)">as ex officio members of the Council:<section prefix="1.">the Secretary or a designee;</section><section prefix="2.">the Secretary of Juvenile Services or a designee;</section><section prefix="3.">the Secretary of Public Safety and Correctional Services or a designee; and</section><section prefix="4.">the Motor Vehicle Administrator of the Motor Vehicle Administration; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">nine regular members.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the nine regular members:<section prefix="(i)">one member shall represent a local law enforcement agency;</section><section prefix="(ii)">one member shall represent a State's Attorney's office in the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">one member shall represent a domestic insurer that issues private passenger automobile or commercial motor vehicle liability insurance in the State;</section><section prefix="(iv)">one member shall represent a foreign insurer that issues private passenger automobile or commercial motor vehicle liability insurance in the State;</section><section prefix="(v)">one member shall represent the Governor's Office;</section><section prefix="(vi)">one member shall represent the National Insurance Crime Bureau or a similar organization; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">three members shall represent the public, including one member who represents a neighborhood or community association.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The members serve at the pleasure of the Governor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The term of a regular member is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The terms of the regular members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Council on October 1, 2003.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Governor shall appoint the Chairman of the Council.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A member of the Council:<section prefix="(1)">may not receive compensation as a member of the Council; but</section><section prefix="(2)">is entitled to reimbursement for expenses from the Fund in accordance with the Standard State Travel Regulations.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Council shall employ an executive director, who shall be appointed by the Governor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The expenses of the Council, including staff salaries and administrative expenses, shall be paid from the Fund but may not exceed 7% of the total expenditures from the Fund in a fiscal year.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Assistant Attorney General assigned to the Department is the legal advisor to the Council.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Council has the following powers and duties:<section prefix="(i)">to make grants from the Fund for motor vehicle theft intervention programs, as provided in &#xA7; 2-703 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">to solicit and accept money for deposit into the Fund, to be used to carry out the purposes of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(iii)">to establish or assist in the establishment of programs designed to reduce the incidence of vehicle theft and related crime;</section><section prefix="(iv)">to identify priorities for theft prevention strategies in the State and criteria for the Council's evaluation of recipients of assistance from the Council; and</section><section prefix="(v)">to study and propose laws that will further prevent and deter vehicle theft and related crime.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Council shall develop and implement a plan of operation.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
