<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-307" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-307</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall determine whether each proposed industrialized building meets the standards contained in the regulations of the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The determination shall include the evaluation and testing of the industrialized building and the quality control system at the factory of origin and at the building site.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall perform the determination required by subsection (a) of this section through its own personnel or through a designated agent.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The designated agent shall be:<section prefix="(i)">qualified personnel of a local enforcement agency; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a testing facility that is approved by the Department.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The testing facility shall be:<section prefix="(i)">an architect or professional engineer whose registration is accepted by the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a testing organization that is determined by the Department to be specifically qualified by reason of facilities, personnel, experience, and demonstrated reliability to investigate, test, and evaluate industrialized buildings or their component parts.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In addition to evaluating and testing industrialized buildings or their component parts, the testing facility shall:<section prefix="(i)">list the units in compliance with the standards adopted by the Department;</section><section prefix="(ii)">provide adequate follow-up services at the point of manufacture to ensure that production units are in full compliance; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">provide for each unit an insignia in the form of a label, seal, or other evidence of compliance.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A manufacturer of a building exempted from the applicability of this subtitle under &#xA7; 12-301(d)(3)(iii) of this subtitle may elect to have the Department perform a determination under subsection (a) of this section for the purpose of the Department certifying and providing an insignia for the building under this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
