<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-508</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "agricultural building" means a structure designed and constructed to house farm im...</catch_line>
  <order_by>508</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section, "agricultural building" means a structure designed and constructed to house farm implements, hay, grain, poultry, livestock, or other horticultural products.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Agricultural building" does not include a place of human residence.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only to Calvert County, Charles County, Dorchester County, Frederick County, Harford County, Prince George's County, St. Mary's County, Somerset County, and Talbot County.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Standards do not apply to the construction, alteration, or modification of an agricultural building for which agritourism is an intended subordinate use.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An existing agricultural building used for agritourism is not considered a change of occupancy that requires a building permit if the subordinate use of agritourism:<section prefix="(1)">is in accordance with limitations set forth in regulations adopted by the Department;</section><section prefix="(2)">occupies only levels of the building on which a ground level exit is located; and</section><section prefix="(3)">does not require more than 50 people to occupy an individual building at any one time.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An agricultural building used for agritourism:<section prefix="(1)">shall be structurally sound and in good repair; but</section><section prefix="(2)">need not comply with:<section prefix="(i)">requirements for bathrooms, sprinkler systems, and elevators set forth in the Standards; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">any other requirements of the Standards or other building codes as set forth in regulations adopted by the Department.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department shall adopt regulations to implement this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
