<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-1007</section_number>
  <catch_line>At least every 3 years, the Department, in cooperation with the Maryland Building Rehabilitation Cod...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1007</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">At least every 3 years, the Department, in cooperation with the Maryland Building Rehabilitation Code Advisory Council, shall review the MBRC and adopt any necessary or desirable amendments.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A local jurisdiction may adopt amendments to the MBRC that apply only to the local jurisdiction.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A municipal corporation whose authority to adopt or amend a building code is limited, by law, by the authority of the county in which it is located, is not subject to an amendment to the MBRC adopted by the county unless the municipal corporation also adopts the amendment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To keep current the central database established under &#xA7; 12-506 of this title, a local jurisdiction that amends the MBRC shall provide a copy of the amendment to the Department:<section prefix="(1)">at least 15 days before the effective date of the amendment; or</section><section prefix="(2)">within 5 days after the adoption of an emergency local amendment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A local jurisdiction that amends the MBRC is not eligible for any funding appropriated above the appropriation in fiscal year 2000 for:<section prefix="(1)">circuit rider MBRC inspectors provided under the circuit rider program in the Department;</section><section prefix="(2)">training for the local jurisdiction's code enforcement officials, as provided for in &#xA7; 12-1003(h)(4) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">a smart growth mortgage program, to be established by the Department under Title 4, Subtitles 2 and 8 of the Housing and Community Development Article;</section><section prefix="(4)">the Neighborhood Conservation Program in the Department of Transportation; and</section><section prefix="(5)">the Rural Legacy Program established under Title 5, Subtitle 9A of the Natural Resources Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A local jurisdiction that amends the MBRC is not eligible for a priority under the Department of Transportation's transportation enhancements programs.</section>
  </text>
</law>
