<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-7-304</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "fire and ambulance company" means a volunteer, career, incorporated, or unincorpor...</catch_line>
  <order_by>304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "fire and ambulance company" means a volunteer, career, incorporated, or unincorporated fire or ambulance company.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only to Washington County.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The commanding officer may designate to the Sheriff of Washington County up to 20 individuals who are members of the commanding officer's fire or ambulance company to be appointed as fire police in Washington County.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A written certificate of designation signed by the commanding officer shall accompany each request for appointment under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Sheriff of Washington County shall appoint individuals to serve as fire police in Washington County from those members designated by the commanding officer under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The powers of individuals serving as fire police in Washington County are limited to traffic control and scene safety while functioning at:<section prefix="(i)">parades;</section><section prefix="(ii)">accidents;</section><section prefix="(iii)">fires;</section><section prefix="(iv)">floods;</section><section prefix="(v)">other emergencies; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">public events conducted by a fire or ambulance company or the Sheriff's department.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The powers authorized under this subsection may be exercised:<section prefix="(i)">in a municipal corporation in Washington County, subject to the discretion, and control of the chief of the police force of the municipal corporation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">in other areas of Washington County.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An individual appointed to serve as fire police in Washington County may not use a weapon in the performance of duties authorized under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The appointment of a member of a fire or ambulance company as fire police in Washington County terminates if the member ceases to be a member of the fire or ambulance company.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Sheriff of Washington County may remove a member appointed as fire police at any time.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a member appointed to serve as fire police in Washington County dies, resigns, is dismissed, refuses to serve, or is unable to serve, the commanding officer may designate another member of the fire or ambulance company to be appointed as fire police.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An individual appointed to serve as fire police in Washington County under this section is deemed an appointed official and shall be treated as an appointed official for purposes of Title 22 and Title 23 of the State Personnel and Pensions Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
