<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-5-133</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section supersedes any restriction that a local jurisdiction in the State imposes on the posses...</catch_line>
  <order_by>133</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section supersedes any restriction that a local jurisdiction in the State imposes on the possession by a private party of a regulated firearm, and the State preempts the right of any local jurisdiction to regulate the possession of a regulated firearm.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not possess a regulated firearm if the person:<section prefix="(1)">has been convicted of a disqualifying crime;</section><section prefix="(2)">has been convicted of a violation classified as a common law crime and received a term of imprisonment of more than 2 years;</section><section prefix="(3)">is a fugitive from justice;</section><section prefix="(4)">is a habitual drunkard;</section><section prefix="(5)">is addicted to a controlled dangerous substance or is a habitual user;</section><section prefix="(6)">suffers from a mental disorder as defined in &#xA7; 10-101(f)(2) of the Health - General Article and has a history of violent behavior against the person or another, unless the person has a physician's certificate that the person is capable of possessing a regulated firearm without undue danger to the person or to another;</section><section prefix="(7)">has been confined for more than 30 consecutive days to a facility as defined in &#xA7; 10-101 of the Health - General Article, unless the person has a physician's certificate that the person is capable of possessing a regulated firearm without undue danger to the person or to another;</section><section prefix="(8)">except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, is a respondent against whom a current non ex parte civil protective order has been entered under &#xA7; 4-506 of the Family Law Article; or</section><section prefix="(9)">if under the age of 30 years at the time of possession, has been adjudicated delinquent by a juvenile court for an act that would be a disqualifying crime if committed by an adult.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not possess a regulated firearm if the person was previously convicted of:<section prefix="(i)">a crime of violence;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a violation of &#xA7; 5-602, &#xA7; 5-603, &#xA7; 5-604, &#xA7; 5-605, &#xA7; 5-612, &#xA7; 5-613, or &#xA7; 5-614 of the Criminal Law Article; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">an offense under the laws of another state or the United States that would constitute one of the crimes listed in item (i) or (ii) of this paragraph if committed in this State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, a person who violates this subsection is guilty of a felony and on conviction is subject to imprisonment for not less than 5 years and not exceeding 15 years.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The court may not suspend any part of the mandatory minimum sentence of 5 years.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Except as otherwise provided in &#xA7; 4-305 of the Correctional Services Article, the person is not eligible for parole during the mandatory minimum sentence.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the time of the commission of the offense, if a period of more than 5 years has elapsed since the person completed serving the sentence for the most recent conviction under paragraph (1)(i) or (ii) of this subsection, including all imprisonment, mandatory supervision, probation, and parole:<section prefix="(i)">the imposition of the mandatory minimum sentence is within the discretion of the court; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the mandatory minimum sentence may not be imposed unless the State's Attorney notifies the person in writing at least 30 days before trial of the State's intention to seek the mandatory minimum sentence.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Each violation of this subsection is a separate crime.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a person who is under the age of 21 years may not possess a regulated firearm.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless a person is otherwise prohibited from possessing a regulated firearm, this subsection does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">the temporary transfer or possession of a regulated firearm if the person is:<section prefix="1.">under the supervision of another who is at least 21 years old and who is not prohibited by State or federal law from possessing a firearm; and</section><section prefix="2.">acting with the permission of the parent or legal guardian of the transferee or person in possession;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">the transfer by inheritance of title, and not of possession, of a regulated firearm;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a member of the armed forces of the United States or the National Guard while performing official duties;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the temporary transfer or possession of a regulated firearm if the person is:<section prefix="1.">participating in marksmanship training of a recognized organization; and</section><section prefix="2.">under the supervision of a qualified instructor;</section></section><section prefix="(v)">a person who is required to possess a regulated firearm for employment and who holds a permit under Subtitle 3 of this title; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">the possession of a firearm for self-defense or the defense of others against a trespasser into the residence of the person in possession or into a residence in which the person in possession is an invited guest.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This section does not apply to a respondent transporting a regulated firearm if the respondent is carrying a civil protective order requiring the surrender of the regulated firearm and:<section prefix="(1)">the regulated firearm is unloaded;</section><section prefix="(2)">the respondent has notified the law enforcement unit, barracks, or station that the regulated firearm is being transported in accordance with the civil protective order; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the respondent transports the regulated firearm directly to the law enforcement unit, barracks, or station.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
