<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-102" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-8-102</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Senator William H. Amoss Fire, Rescue, and Ambulance Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The purposes of the Fund are to promote:<section prefix="(1)">the delivery of effective and high quality fire protection, rescue, and ambulance services in the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">increased financial support for fire, rescue, and ambulance companies by counties; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the continued financial viability of volunteer fire, rescue, and ambulance companies given the greatly increased costs of equipment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Director shall administer the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, the Director may adopt procedures to carry out this subtitle, including additional auditing and reporting requirements.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Director may not:<section prefix="(i)">impose training or operational requirements as a precondition to receipt of money, except as otherwise expressly provided in this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">require that capital equipment purchased with State money have a useful life expectancy of greater than 1 year.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Fund consists of money appropriated in the State budget to the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">As authorized by the Director, the Treasurer shall make payments out of the Fund to each county on warrant of the Comptroller.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Treasurer shall make the payments required under this subsection to the appropriate county in approximately equal amounts on or about August 15, November 15, February 15, and May 15.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">State money provided under this section may only be used to:<section prefix="(i)">acquire or rehabilitate fire or rescue equipment, including ambulances;</section><section prefix="(ii)">acquire or rehabilitate capital equipment used in connection with fire or rescue equipment; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">rehabilitate facilities used primarily to house fire fighting equipment, ambulances, and rescue vehicles.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">State money provided under this section may not be used:<section prefix="(i)">for administrative costs;</section><section prefix="(ii)">for compensation or fringe benefits to employees or members of county governments, or fire, rescue, or ambulance companies;</section><section prefix="(iii)">for travel or meal expenses;</section><section prefix="(iv)">for fuel, utility, or routine maintenance costs of facilities or equipment;</section><section prefix="(v)">to acquire new or replacement fire hydrants, water mains, or emergency alarm systems not installed at a fire, rescue, or ambulance facility;</section><section prefix="(vi)">for insurance;</section><section prefix="(vii)">for fund-raising activities;</section><section prefix="(viii)">to refinance debt or another obligation incurred before July 1, 1985;</section><section prefix="(ix)">to replace or repair eligible items to the extent that insurance proceeds are available;</section><section prefix="(x)">for costs associated with the "9-1-1" emergency telephone system; or</section><section prefix="(xi)">for land or interests in land.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
