<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-13-215</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>215</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Adjutant General may organize a uniformed honor guard from the National Guard or the organized militia to attend the burial service of a deceased veteran if:<section prefix="(i)">the commander of an accredited veterans' organization or a relative or friend of the deceased veteran requests an honor guard to attend the burial service;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a uniformed honor guard from the active armed forces or veterans' organization is not available; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Adjutant General determines that providing an honor guard will not harm:<section prefix="1.">the readiness of the National Guard in the event of a State or federal emergency; or</section><section prefix="2.">the employment of a National Guard member.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an honor guard from the active armed forces is not available, the Adjutant General may request an honor guard from a veterans' organization to attend the burial service of a deceased veteran.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Adjutant General shall set reasonable compensation for honor guard members based on the availability of money in the budget.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Compensation may not exceed the expenses incurred to participate in the burial service of a deceased veteran plus the greater of:<section prefix="(i)">100% of 1 day's pay as determined by the current Department of Defense pay scale; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the minimum wage required under &#xA7; 3-413 of the Labor and Employment Article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Adjutant General shall adopt regulations to carry out this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
