<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-2-513</section_number>
  <catch_line>IN EFFECT...</catch_line>
  <order_by>513</order_by>
  <text>IN EFFECT<section prefix="(a)"><section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">On or before April 1, 2010, and on or before April 1 annually thereafter, the Department shall report to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly, on the status of the statewide DNA data base system as specified in subsection (b) of this section.</section><section prefix="(ii)">On or before January 31, 2010, and on or before January 31 annually thereafter, local law enforcement agencies shall report to the Department for the preceding calendar year with the information necessary for the Department to comply with the requirements of subsection (b) of this section.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The annual report shall be posted on the Department website on or before April 1 of each year.</section></section><section prefix="(b)">The annual report shall include, for the preceding calendar year:<section prefix="(1)">total expenses incurred for the operation and management of the DNA data base and DNA testing program, specifying the actual and human resource costs of DNA collection and transport, DNA analyses, data base operation and oversight, and State laboratory personnel and maintenance;</section><section prefix="(2)">total funding provided by the State to each forensic crime laboratory in the preceding year;</section><section prefix="(3)">a statistical analysis of the racial demographics of individuals who have been charged with a crime of violence or burglary, or attempt to commit a crime of violence or burglary, as defined in &#xA7; 2-501 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(4)">the number of DNA samples collected from individuals charged with a crime of violence or burglary, or attempt to commit a crime of violence or burglary, as defined in &#xA7; 2-501 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(5)">the sufficiency of protocols and procedures adopted to prevent the unlawful testing of DNA and ensure the expungement of DNA as required under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(6)">a detailed analysis of the investigations aided by DNA profiles that includes:<section prefix="(i)">the number of matches;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the number of matches that resulted in investigation of the person identified;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the number of matches that resulted in formal charges;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the number of matches that resulted in convictions;</section><section prefix="(v)">the number of matches that resulted in exonerations;</section><section prefix="(vi)">the number of matches that resulted in convictions for persons not already incarcerated; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">the prior offenses for which a person has been convicted where a match occurred.</section></section></section></text>
</law>
