<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-1003</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Maryland Building Rehabilitation Code Advisory Council....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1003</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Maryland Building Rehabilitation Code Advisory Council.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Council consists of the following 27 members:<section prefix="(1)">the Secretary of Housing and Community Development or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(3)">the State Fire Marshal or the Fire Marshal's designee;</section><section prefix="(4)">the State Historic Preservation Officer or the Officer's designee;</section><section prefix="(5)">the Secretary of Disabilities or the Secretary's designee; and</section><section prefix="(6)">the following 22 members appointed by the Governor:<section prefix="(i)">one representative of the State Fire Prevention Commission;</section><section prefix="(ii)">four representatives of the building trades who are directly involved or have experience in code setting or code enforcement, including plumbers, electricians, boiler operators, and heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, and refrigeration contractors;</section><section prefix="(iii)">two architects practicing in the State, a significant portion of whose practice includes rehabilitation projects;</section><section prefix="(iv)">one professional engineer;</section><section prefix="(v)">two contractors specializing in rehabilitation construction;</section><section prefix="(vi)">two representatives of county government;</section><section prefix="(vii)">two representatives of municipal government;</section><section prefix="(viii)">two building code officials serving local government;</section><section prefix="(ix)">one commercial and industrial building owner or developer;</section><section prefix="(x)">one multifamily building owner or developer;</section><section prefix="(xi)">two local fire officials; and</section><section prefix="(xii)">two members of the public.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The composition of the Council shall reflect the racial, gender, and geographic diversity of the population of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of an appointed member is 4 years and begins on July 1.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of appointed members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Council on October 1, 2003.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">An appointed member may serve no more than two terms.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Governor shall designate a chairman from among the Council members.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A member of the Council:<section prefix="(1)">may not receive compensation for service on the Council; but</section><section prefix="(2)">is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary of Housing and Community Development shall appoint the Director of the Council.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Director is a special appointment in the State Personnel Management System.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Council shall:<section prefix="(1)">advise the Department on the development and adoption of and amendments to the MBRC;</section><section prefix="(2)">provide technical advice on the interpretation of the MBRC to property owners, design professionals, contractors, and code officials and code appeal boards of local jurisdictions, the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission, and the Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission;</section><section prefix="(3)">develop the MBRC to the extent possible to avoid increased costs to local jurisdictions resulting from implementation of the MBRC; and</section><section prefix="(4)">to the extent provided in the State budget, provide training on the MBRC for code officials and other public and private construction-related professionals.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
