<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="1-401" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-1-401</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Sexual Offender Advisory Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board consists of the following members:<section prefix="(1)">the Secretary of Public Safety and Correctional Services, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(3)">the Secretary of Juvenile Services, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(4)">a representative of the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services, designated by the Secretary of Public Safety and Correctional Services;</section><section prefix="(5)">the Chairman of the Maryland Parole Commission, or the Chairman's designee;</section><section prefix="(6)">the Director of the Maryland Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository, or the Director's designee;</section><section prefix="(7)">the Executive Director of the Mental Hygiene Administration of the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene, or the Executive Director's designee;</section><section prefix="(8)">the Secretary of State Police, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(9)">the Executive Director of the Governor's Office of Crime Control and Prevention, or the Executive Director's designee;</section><section prefix="(10)">the following members, appointed by the Governor:<section prefix="(i)">a representative from a victims' advocacy organization or victim service provider with recognized expertise in sexual abuse and victimization;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a licensed mental health professional with recognized expertise in the treatment of sexual offenders;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a State's Attorney with expertise in the prosecution of sexual and child abuse crimes;</section><section prefix="(iv)">an assistant public defender with expertise in the defense of sexual and child abuse crimes;</section><section prefix="(v)">a representative of a local law enforcement unit with expertise in the investigation of sexual and child abuse crimes;</section><section prefix="(vi)">a representative from a child advocacy center with recognized expertise in sexual abuse and victimization; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">two citizen members.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member appointed by the Governor is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of the appointed members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Board on October 1, 2010.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term an appointed member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A member whose term has expired may be reappointed to the Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A Board member:<section prefix="(1)">may not receive compensation for serving on the Board; but</section><section prefix="(2)">is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Governor shall select a chairman from among the Board's members.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A majority of the Board's members constitutes a quorum.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may adopt rules for conducting business.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board shall meet at least twice annually at the times and places determined by the Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">in collaboration with the Division of Parole and Probation, develop criteria for measuring a person's risk of reoffending to assist the court in determining whether a person may be appropriately released from supervision under &#xA7;&#xA7; 11-723 and 11-724 of the Criminal Procedure Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">review the effectiveness of the State's laws and practices concerning sexual offenders, including:<section prefix="(i)">sexual offender registration and monitoring requirements; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">community notification requirements;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">review the laws and practices of other states and jurisdictions concerning sexual offenders;</section><section prefix="(4)">review practices and procedures of the Maryland Parole Commission and the Division of Parole and Probation concerning supervision and monitoring of sexual offenders;</section><section prefix="(5)">review developments and make recommendations for the treatment, management, and assessment of sexual offenders, including:<section prefix="(i)">existing and emerging technology for the tracking of sexual offenders;</section><section prefix="(ii)">civil commitment of sexual offenders;</section><section prefix="(iii)">existing and emerging technology for the treatment of sexual offenders; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">best practices for lowering recidivism rates and protecting the public;</section></section><section prefix="(6)">develop standards for the certification of sexual offender treatment providers based on current and evolving evidence-based practices and make recommendations for a statewide certification process;</section><section prefix="(7)">make recommendations to the Division of Parole and Probation for training sexual offender management teams; and</section><section prefix="(8)">consider ways to increase cooperation among states with regard to sexual offender registration and monitoring.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">On or before December 31, 2010, and every year thereafter, the Board shall report the findings and recommendations of the Board to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Each unit of State and local government shall cooperate with the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services shall provide staff to the Board.</section>
  </text>
</law>
