<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-911" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-911</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If the report filed in accordance with &#xA7; 12-910(a) of this subtitle shows that a boiler or pressure vessel complies with regulations adopted under this subtitle, the Chief Boiler Inspector shall issue to the owner or user of the boiler or pressure vessel a certificate that bears the date of inspection, specifies the inspection interval, and specifies the maximum pressure under which the boiler or pressure vessel may be operated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 12-909(d)(3) of this subtitle, the certificate is valid for the period that corresponds to the interval between certificate inspections as established by regulation under &#xA7; 12-909 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the certificate inspection interval for a boiler or pressure vessel is extended under &#xA7; 12-909(d)(5) of this subtitle, the Chief Boiler Inspector shall promptly issue a certificate to the owner of the boiler or pressure vessel that bears the new expiration date.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The certificate shall be posted under glass in the room that contains the boiler or pressure vessel that was inspected.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the boiler or pressure vessel is not located in a building, the certificate shall be posted in a location convenient to the boiler or pressure vessel that was inspected or in any place where the certificate will be accessible to interested parties.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Chief Boiler Inspector or an authorized deputy boiler inspector may suspend a certificate at any time when, in the opinion of the inspector, the boiler or pressure vessel for which the certificate was issued:<section prefix="(i)">cannot be operated without danger to public safety; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">is found not to comply with regulations adopted under this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The suspension of a certificate continues until:<section prefix="(i)">the boiler or pressure vessel is made to conform to the regulations adopted under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the certificate is reinstated.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If a boiler or pressure vessel for which a certificate was issued based on the report of a special inspector ceases to be insured by an authorized insurer, the certificate is invalid.</section>
  </text>
</law>
