<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-828" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-828</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant for a license shall:<section prefix="(i)">submit to the Board an application on the form that the Board provides;</section><section prefix="(ii)">submit to the Board any proof of eligibility that the Board requires; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">pay to the Board or designee of the Board an application fee set by the Board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The application fee is nonrefundable.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each application shall contain the following information:<section prefix="(1)">if the applicant is an individual, the name, residence, and business address of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(2)">if the applicant is a partnership, the name, residence, and business address of each general partner;</section><section prefix="(3)">if the applicant is a domestic corporation, the name and business address of the corporation and the name and residence address of the principal officer of the corporation;</section><section prefix="(4)">if the applicant is a corporation other than a domestic corporation, the name and address of the resident agent;</section><section prefix="(5)">the number of years the applicant has engaged in the business of installing, altering, repairing, renovating, or servicing elevators;</section><section prefix="(6)">the approximate number of individuals, if any, to be employed by an applicant that is an elevator contractor or elevator renovator contractor and, if applicable, evidence satisfactory to the Board that the employees are or will be covered by workers' compensation insurance;</section><section prefix="(7)">evidence satisfactory to the Board that the applicant is or will be covered by general liability, personal injury, and property damage insurance; and</section><section prefix="(8)">any other information that the Board requires.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
