<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-3-502</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>502</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "police officer" means a member of:<section prefix="(1)">a police force of this State or another state;</section><section prefix="(2)">a police force of a county or municipal corporation of this State or another state;</section><section prefix="(3)">the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division;</section><section prefix="(4)">the United States Park Police;</section><section prefix="(5)">the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (WMATA) Metro Transit Police;</section><section prefix="(6)">the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</section><section prefix="(7)">the Drug Enforcement Administration; or</section><section prefix="(8)">a division of a federal agency the primary duties of which are the investigation, apprehension, or detention of individuals suspected or convicted of federal crimes.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not, with fraudulent design on person or property, falsely represent that the person is a police officer, special police officer, sheriff, deputy sheriff, or constable.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, a person may not have, use, wear, or display a uniform, shield, button, ornament, badge, identification, or shoulder patch adopted by the Department of State Police to be worn by its members, insignia, or emblem of office, as is worn by a police officer, sheriff, deputy sheriff, or constable.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person may not, for the purpose of deception, have a simulation or imitation of an article described in subsection (c) of this section as is worn by a police officer, sheriff, deputy sheriff, or constable.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person may have, use, wear, or display an article described in subsection (c) of this section with the appropriate authority of:<section prefix="(1)">the Secretary of State Police;</section><section prefix="(2)">a police force of another state;</section><section prefix="(3)">the Police Commissioner of Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="(4)">the chief of police of a county or municipal corporation of this State or another state;</section><section prefix="(5)">a sheriff or deputy sheriff;</section><section prefix="(6)">a constable;</section><section prefix="(7)">the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division;</section><section prefix="(8)">the United States Park Police;</section><section prefix="(9)">the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (WMATA) Metro Transit Police;</section><section prefix="(10)">the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</section><section prefix="(11)">the Drug Enforcement Administration; or</section><section prefix="(12)">a division of a federal agency the primary duties of which are the investigation, apprehension, or detention of individuals suspected or convicted of federal crimes.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 2 years or a fine not exceeding $2,000 or both.</section>
  </text>
</law>
