<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-107" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-5-107</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant for a dealer's license shall:<section prefix="(i)">submit to the Secretary an application on the form that the Secretary provides; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">pay to the Secretary an application fee of $50, payable to the Comptroller.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A refund or proration of the application fee is prohibited.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An application for a dealer's license shall contain:<section prefix="(1)">the applicant's name, address, Social Security number, place and date of birth, height, weight, race, eye and hair color, and signature;</section><section prefix="(2)">a clear and recognizable photograph of the applicant, unless the photograph has been submitted with a prior year's application;</section><section prefix="(3)">a set of the applicant's fingerprints, unless the fingerprints have been submitted with a prior year's application; and</section><section prefix="(4)">a statement by the applicant that the applicant:<section prefix="(i)">is a citizen of the United States;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is at least 21 years old;</section><section prefix="(iii)">has never been convicted of a disqualifying crime;</section><section prefix="(iv)">has never been convicted of a violation classified as a common law crime and received a term of imprisonment of more than 2 years;</section><section prefix="(v)">is not a fugitive from justice;</section><section prefix="(vi)">is not a habitual drunkard;</section><section prefix="(vii)">is not addicted to a controlled dangerous substance or is not a habitual user; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">has never spent more than 30 consecutive days in a medical institution for treatment of a mental disorder, unless a physician's certificate issued within 30 days before the date of application is attached to the application, certifying that the applicant is capable of possessing a regulated firearm without undue danger to the applicant or to another.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each application for a dealer's license shall contain the following statement: "Any false information supplied or statement made in this application is a crime which may be punished by imprisonment for a period of not more than 3 years, or a fine of not more than $5,000 or both.".</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If an applicant is a corporation, a corporate officer who is a resident of the State shall complete and execute the application.</section>
  </text>
</law>
