<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-833</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>833</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, unless a license is renewed for a 2-year term as provided in this section, the license expires on the second anniversary of its effective date.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary may determine that licenses issued under Part III of this subtitle shall expire on a staggered basis.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">At least 1 month before a license expires, the Board shall mail to the licensee, at the last known address of the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">a renewal application form; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a notice that states:<section prefix="(i)">the date on which the current license expires;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the date by which the Board must receive the renewal application for the renewal to be issued and mailed before the license expires; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the amount of the renewal fee.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before the license expires, the licensee periodically may renew the license for an additional 2-year term if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">otherwise is entitled to be licensed;</section><section prefix="(2)">pays the renewal fee to the Board; and</section><section prefix="(3)">submits to the Board a renewal application on the form that the Board provides.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board shall adopt regulations to:<section prefix="(1)">require a demonstration of continuing professional competency for a licensee as a condition of renewal of a license under this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">establish criteria for continuing education providers;</section><section prefix="(3)">provide for a temporary waiver of continuing education under specified circumstances; and</section><section prefix="(4)">set record keeping criteria for approved continuing education providers.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board shall renew the license of and issue a renewal certificate to each licensee who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
