<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-311</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Department shall maintain a program of adequate inspection of industrialized buildings....</catch_line>
  <order_by>311</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department shall maintain a program of adequate inspection of industrialized buildings.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each manufacturer of industrialized buildings to be sold or offered for sale to first users in the State shall agree that the Department has the right to conduct unannounced inspections at the manufacturing site to review any aspect of the manufacturer's quality control program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The cost of two unannounced inspections may be charged to the manufacturer in accordance with a fee schedule established by the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In addition, the total travel costs on published air fare, or equivalent rate, between Baltimore and the location of the factory, plus necessary supplemental surface transportation and reimbursement for food and lodging consistent with allowances for State employees may be charged to the manufacturer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department may establish a program of training and accreditation of local enforcement agency personnel to:<section prefix="(i)">enable them to be most effective in inspection of industrialized buildings or manufactured homes; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">promote the possibility of reciprocal reliance between building personnel in this State and between this State and other states.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In those jurisdictions that employ accredited local enforcement agency personnel, the function of on-site inspection of the installation or assembly of industrialized buildings is reserved to those jurisdictions with appropriate appeal procedures from their decisions.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Local enforcement agency representatives, manufacturers, and installers may report to the Department an industrialized building that has been damaged en route to the site so that the Department may arrange for a reinspection of the industrialized building.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department may charge a reinspection fee to the installer of the industrialized building.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
