<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-906</section_number>
  <catch_line>Whenever the position of Chief Boiler Inspector or deputy boiler inspector becomes vacant, the Secre...</catch_line>
  <order_by>906</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whenever the position of Chief Boiler Inspector or deputy boiler inspector becomes vacant, the Secretary of Budget and Management as soon as practicable shall conduct a competitive examination in accordance with Title 7 of the State Personnel and Pensions Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The examination shall be the same as or equivalent to the examination given by the Board for special inspectors under &#xA7; 12-907 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">With the approval of the Secretary, the Commissioner shall appoint from the successful candidates a Chief Boiler Inspector or deputy boiler inspector.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If authorized by the Commissioner, the Chief Boiler Inspector shall:<section prefix="(1)">take action necessary to enforce the regulations adopted under this subtitle and the laws of the State that govern the use of boilers and pressure vessels to which this subtitle applies;</section><section prefix="(2)">keep a complete record of the type, dimensions, maximum allowable pressure, age, location, and date of the last recorded inspection of each boiler and each pressure vessel to which this subtitle applies;</section><section prefix="(3)">issue, and for cause shown, suspend or revoke certificates under &#xA7; 12-911 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(4)">refer for prosecution each person who violates this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each deputy boiler inspector:<section prefix="(1)">is responsible to the Chief Boiler Inspector; and</section><section prefix="(2)">shall perform the duties that the Chief Boiler Inspector directs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">All money received by the Chief Boiler Inspector from fees shall be deposited in the General Fund.</section>
  </text>
</law>
