<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-14-602</section_number>
  <catch_line>The contracting states solemnly agree:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>602</order_by>
  <text>The contracting states solemnly agree:<section prefix="(1)">ARTICLE 1. Purpose.</section><section prefix="(2)">ARTICLE 2. Emergency management and civil defense plans and programs.<section prefix="(a)">Insignia, arm bands and any other distinctive articles to designate and distinguish the different emergency management and civil defense services;</section><section prefix="(b)">Blackouts and practice blackouts, air raid drills, mobilization of emergency management and civil defense forces and other tests and exercises;</section><section prefix="(c)">Warnings and signals for drills or attacks and the mechanical devices to be used in connection therewith;</section><section prefix="(d)">The effective screening or extinguishing of all lights and lighting devices and appliances;</section><section prefix="(e)">Shutting off water mains, gas mains, electric power connections and the suspension of all other utility services;</section><section prefix="(f)">All materials or equipment used or to be used for emergency management and civil defense purposes in order to assure that such materials and equipment will be easily and freely interchangeable when used in or by any other party state;</section><section prefix="(g)">The conduct of civilians and the movement and cessation of movement of pedestrians and vehicular traffic, prior, during and subsequent to drills or attacks;</section><section prefix="(h)">The safety of public meetings or gatherings; and</section><section prefix="(i)">Mobile support units.</section></section><section prefix="(3)">ARTICLE 3. Resources; emergency management and civil defense forces.</section><section prefix="(4)">ARTICLE 4. Licenses and permits.</section><section prefix="(5)">ARTICLE 5. Liability.</section><section prefix="(6)">ARTICLE 6. Supplementary agreements.</section><section prefix="(7)">ARTICLE 7. Compensation and death benefits.</section><section prefix="(8)">ARTICLE 8. Reimbursement for loss, damage, expense, or cost.</section><section prefix="(9)">ARTICLE 9. Plans for evacuation of civil population.</section><section prefix="(10)">ARTICLE 10. Availability of compact; "state" defined.</section><section prefix="(11)">ARTICLE 11. Role of Federal Emergency Management Agency.</section><section prefix="(12)">ARTICLE 12. Compact operative on ratification.</section><section prefix="(13)">ARTICLE 13. Withdrawal from compact.</section><section prefix="(14)">ARTICLE 14. Construction of compact; severability.</section><section prefix="(15)">ARTICLE 15. Additional applicability.<section prefix="(a)">This article shall be in effect only as among those states which have enacted it into law or in which the governors have adopted it pursuant to constitutional or statutory authority sufficient to give it the force of law as part of this compact. Nothing contained in this article or in any supplementary agreement made in implementation thereof shall be construed to abridge, impair or supersede any other provision of this compact or any obligation undertaken by a state pursuant thereto, except that if its terms so provide, a supplementary agreement in implementation of this article may modify, expand or add to any such obligation as among the parties to the supplementary agreement.</section><section prefix="(b)">In addition to the occurrences, circumstances and subject matters to which preceding articles of this compact make it applicable, this compact and the authorizations, entitlements and procedures thereof shall apply to:<section prefix="(1)">Searches for and rescue of persons who are lost, marooned, or otherwise in danger;</section><section prefix="(2)">Action useful in coping with disasters arising from any cause or designed to increase capability to cope with any such disasters;</section><section prefix="(3)">Incidents, or the imminence thereof, which endanger the health or safety of the public and which require the use of special equipment, trained personnel or personnel in larger numbers than are locally available in order to reduce, counteract or remove the danger;</section><section prefix="(4)">The giving and receiving of aid by subdivisions of party states;</section><section prefix="(5)">Exercises, drills or other training or practice activities designed to aid personnel to prepare for, cope with, or prevent any disaster or other emergency to which this compact applies.</section></section><section prefix="(c)">Except as expressly limited by this compact or a supplementary agreement in force pursuant thereto, any aid authorized by this compact or any supplementary agreement may be furnished by any agency of a party state, a subdivision of a party state, or by a joint agency of any two or more party states or of their subdivisions. Any joint agency providing aid shall be entitled to reimbursement therefor to the same extent and in the same manner as a state. The personnel of a joint agency, when rendering aid pursuant to this compact, shall have the same rights, authority and immunity as personnel of party states.</section><section prefix="(d)">Nothing in this article shall be construed to exclude from the coverage of Articles 1-14 of this compact any matter which, in the absence of this article, could reasonably be construed to be covered thereby.</section></section></text>
</law>
