<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-501</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>501</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Building" has the meaning stated in the International Building Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Department" means the Department of Housing and Community Development.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"International Building Code" means the first printing of the most recent edition of the International Building Code issued by the International Code Council.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"International Building Code" does not include interim amendments or subsequent printings of the most recent edition of the International Building Code.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"International Energy Conservation Code" means the first printing of the most recent edition of the International Energy Conservation Code issued by the International Code Council.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"International Energy Conservation Code" does not include interim amendments or subsequent printings of the most recent edition of the International Energy Conservation Code.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"International Green Construction Code" means the first printing of the most recent edition of the International Green Construction Code issued by the International Code Council.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"International Green Construction Code" does not include interim amendments or subsequent printings of the most recent edition of the International Green Construction Code.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Local jurisdiction" means the county or municipal corporation that is responsible for implementation and enforcement of the Standards under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Standards" means the Maryland Building Performance Standards.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Structure" has the meaning stated in the International Building Code.</section>
  </text>
</law>
