<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-1001</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1001</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Addition" means an increase in:<section prefix="(1)">building area;</section><section prefix="(2)">aggregate floor area;</section><section prefix="(3)">height; or</section><section prefix="(4)">number of stories.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Change of occupancy" means a change in the purpose or level of activity in a building or structure that involves a change in application of the local building code requirements.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Construction permit application" means an application for a permit or other governmental approval for a rehabilitation project.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Department" means the Department of Housing and Community Development.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Existing building" means a building or structure that was erected and occupied, or was issued a certificate of occupancy, at least 1 year before a construction permit application for the building or structure was made to a local jurisdiction, the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission, or the Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Local jurisdiction" means:<section prefix="(1)">a county; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a municipal corporation in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"MBRC" means the Maryland Building Rehabilitation Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Modification" means:<section prefix="(1)">the reconfiguration of a space;</section><section prefix="(2)">the addition or elimination of a door or window;</section><section prefix="(3)">the reconfiguration or extension of a system; or</section><section prefix="(4)">the installation of any additional equipment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Reconstruction" means:<section prefix="(1)">the reconfiguration of a space that:<section prefix="(i)">affects an exit or element of the egress access that is shared by more than a single occupant; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">prevents occupancy of the work area because the existing means of egress and fire protection systems, or their equivalent, are not in place or continuously maintained; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">extensive modifications.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Rehabilitation project" means construction work undertaken in an existing building that includes repair, renovation, modification, reconstruction, change of occupancy, or addition.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Renovation" means:<section prefix="(i)">the change, strengthening, or addition of load bearing elements; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the refinishing, replacement, bracing, strengthening, upgrading, or extensive repair of existing materials, elements, components, equipment, or fixtures.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Renovation" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">reconfiguration of a space; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">interior or exterior painting.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Repair" means the patching, restoration, or minor replacement of materials, elements, components, equipment, or fixtures to maintain them in good or sound condition.</section>
  </text>
</law>
