<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-805" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-805</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "assisted living program" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 19-1801 of the Health - General Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commissioner shall administer and enforce Part II of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner shall adopt regulations that conform generally to the American National Standard/American Society of Mechanical Engineers Safety Code for Elevators, Dumbwaiters, Escalators, and Moving Walks, ANSI Code A17.1-1971, and all subsequent amendments and revisions to it.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If necessary to fulfill the Commissioner's responsibilities under Part II of this subtitle, the Commissioner shall:<section prefix="(i)">adopt regulations that amend standards set forth in the American National Standard/American Society of Mechanical Engineers Safety Code for Elevators, Dumbwaiters, Escalators, and Moving Walks, ANSI Code A17.1-1971, and all subsequent amendments and revisions to it; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">adopt other regulations.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commissioner may adopt regulations to authorize and regulate the installation and inspection of noncommercial elevator units in assisted living programs with five or fewer beds that are licensed by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene under &#xA7; 19-1804.1 of the Health - General Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The regulations shall be consistent with the requirements of &#xA7; 12-1006 of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commissioner may assign duties and functions imposed by Part II of this subtitle to the chief elevator inspector.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The cost of administering Part II of this subtitle is provided for under &#xA7; 5-204 of the Labor and Employment Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
