<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-7-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A fire, rescue, or emergency medical services entity may enter into an agreement with the federal government in accordance with this section to provide fire fighting or rescue activities on property under the jurisdiction of the United States.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An agreement entered into under this section shall be limited to the provision of fire fighting or rescue equipment and personnel or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An agreement entered into under this section shall include:<section prefix="(1)">a waiver by each party of any claim against any other party for compensation for any loss, damage, personal injury, or death that occurs in the performance of the agreement;</section><section prefix="(2)">a provision to indemnify and hold harmless each party to the agreement from any claim by a third party for property damage or personal injury, within the limitations permitted by federal law, that arise out of the activities of each party to the agreement; and</section><section prefix="(3)">a provision that entitles the fire, rescue, or emergency medical services entity to obtain reimbursement from the appropriate federal authority for all or part of the cost of providing fire protection on property under the jurisdiction of the United States in accordance with federal law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If an individual engaging in an activity authorized under this section sustains an injury that arises out of the activity, the individual is entitled to any or all benefits available under the Maryland Workers' Compensation Act as the primary remedy for reimbursement of expenses for medical bills, loss of earnings, and disability that arises under or as a result of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
