<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-13-406</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>406</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section:<section prefix="(1)">applies when the National Guard is ordered out for State active duty or training by the Governor or by the Governor's authority; and</section><section prefix="(2)">does not apply to the National Guard when ordered to duty incident to an order into the active military service of the United States.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to subsection (d) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">an officer, warrant officer, and enlisted individual shall receive the same pay, including longevity pay, subsistence, per diem, and allowances, as an officer, warrant officer, and enlisted individual of like grade and length of service in the United States Army or Air Force; and</section><section prefix="(2)">an individual ordered to active duty other than for training shall be paid a daily rate of at least 12 times the hourly federal minimum wage in effect at the time of active duty.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An enlisted individual who meets the qualifications that the Governor sets in small arms practice or for proficiency in the various duties of the branch or arm to which the individual belongs shall receive the following increase in pay of the individual's grade for 1 year beginning on the first January 1 after qualification:<section prefix="(1)">experts - 20%;</section><section prefix="(2)">sharpshooters, gunners, drivers, and medical, first class - 15%; and</section><section prefix="(3)">marksmen, gunners, drivers, and medical, second class - 10%.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">On the recommendation of the Adjutant General, the Governor may reduce the rates of pay, including longevity pay and qualification pay under subsections (b) and (c) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
