<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-204" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-13-204</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The general appropriations for the militia shall be exclusively applied to the necessary and contingent expenses of the office of the Adjutant General and to the equipment, maintenance, and general efficiency of the organized militia.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in this title, unless authorized by the Adjutant General, a person may not make a purchase, incur a debt or expense, or expend money for the militia.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Adjutant General shall adopt rules for the receipt and expenditure of all money that comes under the control of the Adjutant General.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Adjutant General may require bond from persons involved in the receipt and expenditure of money that the Adjutant General designates.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The commanding officer of an organization or detachment of the organized militia that is on State active duty may purchase necessities that are absolutely required for the immediate use and care of the officer's command.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a commanding officer on State active duty makes a purchase under this subsection, the commanding officer shall:<section prefix="(i)">take a receipt of the purchase in triplicate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">promptly submit a report of the purchase through regular channels to the Department's Finance Officer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The report shall contain:<section prefix="(i)">a list of the articles purchased;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the price of the articles; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the receipts.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, the Adjutant General shall audit and pay all bills and military accounts payable by the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Adjutant General shall follow as nearly as possible the financial operating procedures established by the United States Department of Defense.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Comptroller shall be the auditor of all accounts for property purchased by the Adjutant General.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Treasurer shall pay an audited military account from an appropriation made by the General Assembly, on the warrant of the Adjutant General, under the direction of the Governor.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
