<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-506" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-506</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department shall maintain a central automated database in accordance with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At a minimum, the Department shall include in the database:<section prefix="(i)">the Standards;</section><section prefix="(ii)">local amendments to the Standards;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the State Fire Prevention Code adopted by the State Fire Prevention Commission under Title 6 of this article;</section><section prefix="(iv)">fire prevention codes adopted by local jurisdictions;</section><section prefix="(v)">the Electrical Code required under Subtitle 6 of this title;</section><section prefix="(vi)">local amendments to the Electrical Code;</section><section prefix="(vii)">the Energy Code defined under the Energy Conservation Building Standards Act, Title 7, Subtitle 4 of the Public Utilities Article;</section><section prefix="(viii)">local code provisions that are more restrictive than the Energy Code defined under the Energy Conservation Building Standards Act;</section><section prefix="(ix)">information compiled by the Department under paragraph (2) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(x)">the Maryland Building Rehabilitation Code;</section><section prefix="(xi)">local amendments to the Maryland Building Rehabilitation Code; and</section><section prefix="(xii)">proposed federal or State legislation of which the Department is aware and that directly affects the construction industry.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department may compile and include in the database:<section prefix="(i)">any information provided by a local jurisdiction on the implementation and interpretation of the Standards by the local jurisdiction; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">interim amendments to the International Building Code including subsequent printings of the most recent edition.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">make information from the database available to a local jurisdiction, State unit, or other interested party;</section><section prefix="(2)">provide each local jurisdiction with the necessary hardware or software to enable the local jurisdiction to access the information in the database; and</section><section prefix="(3)">coordinate with local building officials, the State Fire Marshal, and local fire officials in compiling information for the database.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the Department may charge a fee for information provided from the database.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Department may not charge a fee to a State unit or local jurisdiction.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department may not charge a fee to a local jurisdiction for the ongoing maintenance of the database.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Fees collected in accordance with this subsection unexpended at the end of the fiscal year do not revert to the General Fund, but shall be kept in a special fund available to the Department to carry out this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A local jurisdiction shall provide to the Department a copy of each amendment to the local jurisdiction's fire prevention code or Electrical Code within 15 days after the effective date of the amendment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A local jurisdiction shall provide to the Department a copy of each amendment to the local jurisdiction's energy code that is more restrictive than the Energy Code defined under the Energy Conservation Building Standards Act within 15 days after the effective date of the amendment.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
