<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-305" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-6-305</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The State Fire Marshal shall enforce:<section prefix="(1)">all laws of the State that relate to:<section prefix="(i)">the prevention of fire;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the storage, sale, and use of explosives, combustibles, or other dangerous articles, in solid, liquid, or gaseous form;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the installation and maintenance of all kinds of equipment intended to control, detect, or extinguish fire;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the means and adequacy of exit, in case of fire, from buildings and all other places in which individuals work, live, or congregate, except buildings that are used solely as dwelling houses for no more than two families; and</section><section prefix="(v)">the suppression of arson; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the regulations adopted by the Commission under Subtitle 2 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">By delegation of authority vested in the Commission and within policy established by the Commission, the State Fire Marshal shall implement fire safety programs in the State to minimize fire hazards and disasters and loss of life and property from these causes, including:<section prefix="(1)">the establishment and enforcement of fire safety practices throughout the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">preventive inspection and correction activities;</section><section prefix="(3)">coordination of fire safety programs with volunteer and career fire companies and other State agencies and political subdivisions exercising enforcement aspects; and</section><section prefix="(4)">critical analysis and evaluation of State fire loss statistics to determine problems and solutions.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">On request, the State Fire Marshal shall assist in fire prevention matters:<section prefix="(1)">a chief of a fire company or department;</section><section prefix="(2)">a legally designated fire marshal of a county or municipal corporation; or</section><section prefix="(3)">a unit or agency of the State or a county or municipal corporation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Fire Marshal, assistant State fire marshals, and special assistant State fire marshals shall develop for each property owned or leased by the State:<section prefix="(i)">fire safety procedures, including fire drills at least quarterly; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">emergency evacuation procedures.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Information about fire safety and emergency evacuation procedures shall be available to all State employees on request.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The State Fire Marshal shall require the State unit exercising control over the property owned or leased by the State to keep records of fire drills or other exercises that relate to fire safety and emergency evacuation procedures conducted in the property.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The State Fire Marshal may issue permits and licenses as required under this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">On request, the State Fire Marshal may assist police and fire authorities to dispose of hazardous devices and substances.</section>
  </text>
</law>
