<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-13-210</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>210</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to the period of time that an employee is ordered by the Governor to active military duty in the organized militia of the State for service during:<section prefix="(i)">a civil disorder;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a natural disaster;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a labor disorder; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">any other activity requiring support of the State militia.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Adjutant General shall secure compensation under the Maryland Workers' Compensation Act for each officer and enlisted individual of the organized militia by maintaining an insurance policy with the Chesapeake Employers' Insurance Company or with a stock corporation or mutual association authorized to transact the business of workers' compensation insurance in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An officer, enlisted individual, or employee of the Department is not entitled to the benefits of this section if the officer, enlisted individual, or employee is injured in the course of employment and has insurance coverage through the federal government that is equal to or better than the coverage provided by this title.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a benefit provided by the federal government is less than that provided by the Maryland Workers' Compensation Act, the State and its insurer shall furnish the additional benefit necessary to make up the difference between the benefit provided by the federal government and the similar benefit required under the Maryland Workers' Compensation Act.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The insurance provided under this subsection shall only cover incidents that occur after July 1, 1979.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to the benefits under subsection (a) of this section, the Adjutant General shall maintain workers' compensation insurance for members of the Maryland Defense Force during training.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Adjutant General shall pay the premiums for the insurance policy required under this section from appropriations for the militia that the Governor includes in the State budget.</section>
  </text>
</law>
