<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-412" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-2-412</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Emergency" means a sudden or unexpected happening or an unforeseen combination of circumstances that calls for immediate action to protect health, safety, welfare, or property from actual or threatened harm or from an unlawful act.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Municipal corporation" includes Baltimore City.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Police employees have throughout the State the same powers, privileges, immunities, and defenses as sheriffs, constables, police officers, and other peace officers possessed at common law and may now or in the future exercise within their respective jurisdictions.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A police employee may execute an arrest warrant in any part of the State without further endorsement.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Police employees may not act within the limits of a municipal corporation that maintains a police force except:<section prefix="(1)">when in pursuit of a criminal or suspect;</section><section prefix="(2)">when in search of a criminal or suspect wanted for a crime committed outside of the limits of the municipal corporation or when interviewing or seeking to interview a witness or supposed witness to the crime;</section><section prefix="(3)">when a crime is committed in the presence of the police employee, and the arrested party must be immediately transferred to the custody of the local law enforcement agency;</section><section prefix="(4)">when requested to act by the chief executive officer or chief police officer of the municipal corporation;</section><section prefix="(5)">when ordered by the Governor to act within the municipal corporation;</section><section prefix="(6)">when enforcing the motor vehicle laws of the State, except in Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="(7)">in Baltimore City, only when enforcing Title 23 of the Transportation Article;</section><section prefix="(8)">in any building or place when ordered by either the President of the Senate or the Speaker of the House of Delegates to guard the safety of legislators or the integrity of the legislative process;</section><section prefix="(9)">to protect the safety of an elected State official;</section><section prefix="(10)">in the municipal corporations of Somerset County;</section><section prefix="(11)">when enforcing &#xA7; 11-207 of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(12)"><section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">when acting in accordance with regulations adopted by the Secretary to implement this item;</section></section><section prefix="(13)">when conducting investigations relating to or otherwise enforcing &#xA7; 7-302 of the Criminal Law Article; or</section><section prefix="(14)">when conducting an investigation under &#xA7; 9-602.1 of the Correctional Services Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A police employee may not be placed on detached service and act for a federal department, agency, or committee outside of the State without the written approval of the Governor or as otherwise provided by law.</section>
  </text>
</law>
