<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-835</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>835</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A licensed elevator contractor shall respond as necessary to ensure public safety if:<section prefix="(1)">an emergency exists in the State because of disaster, act of God, or work stoppage; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the number of licensed elevator mechanics in the State is insufficient to cope with the emergency.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Within 5 business days after beginning work that requires an elevator mechanic license, an individual certified by a licensed elevator contractor to have an acceptable combination of documented experience and education to perform elevator work without direct and immediate supervision shall seek an emergency elevator mechanic license from the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The licensed elevator contractor shall provide proof of competency as the Board may require for an individual certified by the licensed elevator contractor under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board shall issue emergency elevator mechanic licenses.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An emergency elevator mechanic license entitles the licensee to the rights and privileges of an elevator mechanic license issued under Part III of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An emergency elevator mechanic license is valid for 30 days for particular elevator units or geographical areas as the Board designates.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Board shall renew an emergency elevator mechanic license during the existence of an emergency.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Board may not charge a fee for the issuance or renewal of an emergency elevator mechanic license.</section>
  </text>
</law>
