<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-3-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Chief" means the head of a law enforcement agency.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Chief" includes the officer designated by the head of a law enforcement agency.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Hearing" means a proceeding during an investigation conducted by a hearing board to take testimony or receive other evidence.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Hearing" does not include an interrogation at which no testimony is taken under oath.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Hearing board" means a board that is authorized by the chief to hold a hearing on a complaint against a law enforcement officer.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Law enforcement officer" means an individual who:<section prefix="(i)">in an official capacity is authorized by law to make arrests; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is a member of one of the following law enforcement agencies:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Law enforcement officer" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">an individual who serves at the pleasure of the Police Commissioner of Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an individual who serves at the pleasure of the appointing authority of a charter county;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the police chief of a municipal corporation;</section><section prefix="(iv)">an officer who is in probationary status on initial entry into the law enforcement agency except if an allegation of brutality in the execution of the officer's duties is made;</section><section prefix="(v)">a Montgomery County fire and explosive investigator as defined in &#xA7; 2-208.1 of the Criminal Procedure Article;</section><section prefix="(vi)">an Anne Arundel County or City of Annapolis fire and explosive investigator as defined in &#xA7; 2-208.2 of the Criminal Procedure Article;</section><section prefix="(vii)">a Prince George's County fire and explosive investigator as defined in &#xA7; 2-208.3 of the Criminal Procedure Article;</section><section prefix="(viii)">a Worcester County fire and explosive investigator as defined in &#xA7; 2-208.4 of the Criminal Procedure Article; or</section><section prefix="(ix)">a City of Hagerstown fire and explosive investigator as defined in &#xA7; 2-208.5 of the Criminal Procedure Article.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
