<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-611" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-611</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless a certificate is renewed for a 3-year term as provided in this section, the certification expires on the date set by the State Fire Marshal.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Fire Marshal may determine that certificates issued under this subtitle shall expire on a staggered basis.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">At least 45 days before a certificate expires, the State Fire Marshal shall mail to the certificate holder, at the last known address of the certificate holder:<section prefix="(1)">a renewal application form; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a notice that states:<section prefix="(i)">the date on which the current certificate expires;</section><section prefix="(ii)">that the State Fire Marshal must receive the renewal application at least 15 days before the certificate expiration date for the renewal to be issued and mailed before the certificate expires;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the amount of the renewal fee;</section><section prefix="(iv)">that an individual may not be issued a certificate under this subtitle until all outstanding obligations are satisfied with the State Fire Marshal; and</section><section prefix="(v)">that the submission of a false statement in the renewal application or the submission of altered or false documents that are otherwise required is cause for revocation of the certification.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A certified nongovernmental electrical inspector may renew the certification for a 3-year term if the certificate holder:<section prefix="(1)">otherwise is entitled to be certified; and</section><section prefix="(2)">submits to the State Fire Marshal:<section prefix="(i)">a renewal application on the form the State Fire Marshal provides;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a renewal fee of $50; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">satisfactory evidence of compliance with any other requirements under this section for renewal of certification.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Certificate holders who fail to renew within 90 days from the date of expiration shall be required to submit an initial application and successfully pass the written examination.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The State Fire Marshal shall renew the certification of each applicant who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
