<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-312" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-5-312</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who is denied a permit or renewal of a permit or whose permit is revoked or limited may request the Board to review the decision of the Secretary by filing a written request with the Board within 10 days after receipt of written notice of the Secretary's final action.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person whose application for a permit or renewal of a permit is not acted on by the Secretary within 90 days after submitting the application to the Secretary may request a hearing before the Board by filing a written request with the Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Within 90 days after receiving a request to review a decision of the Secretary, the Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">review the record developed by the Secretary; or</section><section prefix="(2)">conduct a hearing.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board may receive and consider additional evidence submitted by a party in conducting a review of the decision of the Secretary.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Based on the Board's consideration of the record and any additional evidence, the Board shall sustain, reverse, or modify the decision of the Secretary.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the action by the Board results in the denial of a permit or renewal of a permit or the revocation or limitation of a permit, the Board shall submit in writing to the applicant or the holder of the permit the reasons for the action taken by the Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any hearing and any subsequent proceedings of judicial review shall be conducted in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, a court may not order the issuance or renewal of a permit or alter a limitation on a permit pending a final determination of the proceeding.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
