<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="1-310" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-1-310</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each subscriber to switched local exchange access service or CMRS or other 9-1-1-accessible service shall pay a 9-1-1 fee.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The 9-1-1 fee is 25 cents per month, payable when the bill for the telephone service or CMRS or other 9-1-1-accessible service is due.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Public Service Commission shall direct each telephone company to add the 9-1-1 fee to all current bills rendered for switched local exchange access service in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each telephone company:<section prefix="(i)">shall act as a collection agent for the 9-1-1 Trust Fund with respect to the 9-1-1 fees;</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall remit all money collected to the Comptroller on a monthly basis; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">is entitled to credit, against the money from the 9-1-1 fees to be remitted to the Comptroller, an amount equal to 0.75% of the 9-1-1 fees to cover the expenses of billing, collecting, and remitting the 9-1-1 fees and any additional charges.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Comptroller shall deposit the money remitted in the 9-1-1 Trust Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each 9-1-1 service carrier shall add the 9-1-1 fee to all current bills rendered for CMRS or other 9-1-1-accessible service in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each 9-1-1 service carrier:<section prefix="(i)">shall act as a collection agent for the 9-1-1 Trust Fund with respect to the 9-1-1 fees;</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall remit all money collected to the Comptroller on a monthly basis; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">is entitled to credit, against the money from the 9-1-1 fees to be remitted to the Comptroller, an amount equal to 0.75% of the 9-1-1 fees to cover the expenses of billing, collecting, and remitting the 9-1-1 fees and any additional charges.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Comptroller shall deposit the money remitted in the 9-1-1 Trust Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Board shall adopt procedures for auditing surcharge collection and remittance by CMRS providers.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">On request of a CMRS provider, and except as otherwise required by law, the information that the CMRS provider reports to the Board shall be confidential, privileged, and proprietary and may not be disclosed to any person other than the CMRS provider.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, the 9-1-1 fee does not apply to an intermediate service line used exclusively to connect a CMRS or other 9-1-1-accessible service, other than a switched local access service, to another telephone system or switching device.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A CMRS provider that pays or collects 9-1-1 fees under this section has the same immunity from liability for transmission failures as that approved by the Public Service Commission for local exchange telephone companies that are subject to regulation by the Commission under the Public Utilities Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
