<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-9-701</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to subsection (e) of this section, the local governing body of each county and the legislati...</catch_line>
  <order_by>701</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to subsection (e) of this section, the local governing body of each county and the legislative body of each municipal corporation in the State may adopt by ordinance or resolution a fire prevention code to:<section prefix="(1)">provide for protection against fires and the removal of fire hazards;</section><section prefix="(2)">provide for the appointment of inspectors to enforce the fire prevention code; and</section><section prefix="(3)">establish penalties for violation of the fire prevention code or an ordinance, resolution, or regulation for the prevention of fires or removal of fire hazards.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, a fire prevention code of a county or municipal corporation adopted under this section may incorporate by reference a code or part of a code prepared by a governmental unit or a trade or professional association for general distribution in printed form as a standard or model on any subject that relates to fire prevention, fire hazards, or flammable or dangerous substances.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An amendment to a standard or model code described in paragraph (1) of this subsection is not effective until specifically incorporated into the fire prevention code of the county or municipal corporation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, the local governing body of a county or legislative body of a municipal corporation may not adopt a fire prevention code under this section until a summary of the proposal is published for at least 3 weeks in one or more newspapers of general circulation in the county or municipal corporation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The summary shall specify the date for a public hearing on the proposal and shall state that copies of the proposal may be obtained on application to:<section prefix="(i)">for a county fire prevention code, the administrative officer of the county; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">for a municipal fire prevention code, the clerk of the municipal corporation.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, a fire prevention code adopted by a county under this section does not apply within a municipal corporation that has adopted a fire prevention code after the effective date of the adoption of the fire prevention code by the municipal corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only to Frederick County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The summary of the fire prevention code required to be published under subsection (c) of this section shall be published in one or more newspapers of general circulation in the county at least 2 weeks before the adoption of the fire prevention code by the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A copy of the fire prevention code proposed for adoption under this section may be obtained on application to the administrative officer of the county.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
