<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-3-208</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to the authority of the Secretary, the Commission has the following powers and duties:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>208</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the authority of the Secretary, the Commission has the following powers and duties:<section prefix="(1)">to adopt regulations necessary or appropriate to carry out this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">to adopt regulations that establish and enforce standards for prior substance abuse by individuals applying for certification as a police officer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to subsections (c) and (d) of this section, the Commission shall adopt regulations on or before January 1, 2001, for a certified firearms safety training course required for an applicant for a regulated firearms purchase, rental, or transfer made on or after January 1, 2002.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The certified firearms safety training course required under subsection (b) of this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">be offered by the Commission; or</section><section prefix="(2)">contain a handgun safety component and be conducted by an individual or organization certified by:<section prefix="(i)">the Commission;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Department of Natural Resources;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Department of State Police; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">any reputable organization:<section prefix="1.">that has as one of its objectives the promotion of competency and safety in handling handguns; and</section><section prefix="2.">whose course has been determined by the Commission to meet the regulations adopted by the Commission.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Any course offered by the Commission under subsection (c) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">shall be offered free of charge or fee;</section><section prefix="(2)">may not be more than 2 hours in duration;</section><section prefix="(3)">shall be conducted or offered at least once each week in all geographic areas of the State;</section><section prefix="(4)">shall be available after regular business hours;</section><section prefix="(5)">shall be open to each individual required by law to complete the firearms safety training course, within 2 weeks after request of the individual;</section><section prefix="(6)">shall only require attendance throughout the duration of the course in order to complete the course successfully; and</section><section prefix="(7)">may not require any skills or knowledge testing in the use of a regulated firearm in order to complete the course successfully.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
