<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-505</section_number>
  <catch_line>Each local jurisdiction shall implement and enforce the most current version of the Standards and an...</catch_line>
  <order_by>505</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each local jurisdiction shall implement and enforce the most current version of the Standards and any local amendments to the Standards.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Any modification of the Standards adopted by the State after December 31, 2009, shall be implemented and enforced by a local jurisdiction no later than 6 months after the modifications are adopted by the State.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At a minimum, the local jurisdiction shall ensure that implementation and enforcement of the Standards includes:<section prefix="(i)">review and acceptance of appropriate plans;</section><section prefix="(ii)">issuance of building permits;</section><section prefix="(iii)">inspection of the work authorized by the building permits; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">issuance of appropriate use and occupancy certificates.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each local jurisdiction shall determine the manner in which the minimum implementation and enforcement activities of this subsection are carried out.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the county in which a building or structure is located shall implement and enforce the Standards for that building or structure in accordance with this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A municipal corporation that did not adopt a building code on or before October 1, 1992, may elect to implement and enforce the Standards in accordance with this subtitle for buildings or structures located in the municipal corporation.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a municipal corporation elects to implement and enforce the Standards under this paragraph, the county in which the municipal corporation is located is not responsible for implementation and enforcement of the Standards in the municipal corporation.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A county that did not adopt a building code on or before October 1, 1992, shall implement and enforce the Standards in the county unless it elects to negotiate with a municipal corporation in the county to have the municipal corporation implement and enforce the Standards in the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A municipal corporation that adopted a building code on or before October 1, 1992, shall implement and enforce the Standards in the municipal corporation unless it elects to negotiate with the county in which the municipal corporation is located to have the county implement and enforce the Standards in the municipal corporation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A local jurisdiction may charge fees necessary to cover the cost of implementation and enforcement of the Standards and any local amendments to the Standards.</section>
  </text>
</law>
