<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Department" means the Department of Housing and Community Development.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each political subdivision shall adopt by regulation a local housing code that sets minimum property maintenance standards for housing in the subdivision.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department shall adopt by regulation a Minimum Livability Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Minimum Livability Code applies to residential structures used for human habitation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Minimum Livability Code does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">an owner-occupied housing unit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">any housing in a political subdivision that has adopted a local housing code that substantially conforms to the Minimum Livability Code; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">any housing exempted by the Department.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Minimum Livability Code shall:<section prefix="(1)">set minimum property standards for housing in the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">allow for exceptions and variations between political subdivisions:<section prefix="(i)">to reflect geographic differences; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the Department determines that unique local conditions justify exceptions or variations recommended by political subdivisions; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">include minimum standards for:<section prefix="(i)">basic equipment and facilities used for light, ventilation, heat, and sanitation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">safe and sanitary maintenance of residential structures and premises.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The political subdivision in which the housing is located shall enforce the Minimum Livability Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless alternative housing is provided, an individual may not be displaced by enforcement of the Minimum Livability Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A political subdivision may charge a property owner a fee for an inspection made to enforce the Minimum Livability Code.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On application of the property owner, a political subdivision may waive the applicability of the Minimum Livability Code to a unit of rental housing if:<section prefix="(i)">each tenant of the unit is given adequate notice in the form and manner specified by the political subdivision;</section><section prefix="(ii)">each tenant is given an opportunity to comment on the application in writing or in person; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the waiver would not threaten the health or safety of any tenant.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A political subdivision may waive applicability of the Minimum Livability Code if the waiver is granted on the basis of the religious practices of the tenant of a unit of rental housing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Department:<section prefix="(1)">shall decide questions of interpretation of the Minimum Livability Code, including questions that relate to uniform enforcement by political subdivisions; and</section><section prefix="(2)">may authorize waivers or exemptions under the Minimum Livability Code.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department may provide matching grants and technical assistance to political subdivisions to implement the Minimum Livability Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The matching grants shall be allocated using a formula developed by the Department to take into account population and other relevant factors.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department may waive the requirement of a match if adequate local money is not available.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A property owner may not willfully violate the Minimum Livability Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who violates this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject for each violation to imprisonment not exceeding 3 months or a fine not exceeding $500 for each day the violation exists or both.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A penalty imposed under this subsection is in addition to and not a substitute for any other penalty authorized under federal, State, or local law.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
