<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-910" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-910</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each authorized inspection agency that employs a special inspector shall file with the Chief Boiler Inspector a report on:<section prefix="(i)">each certificate inspection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any other inspection for which a report is required to be filed under regulations adopted under this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The report filed under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">be filed within 30 days after an inspection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">be in the form required by regulations adopted under this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For each report not filed electronically, the authorized inspection agency shall pay a $5 report filing fee.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Within 24 hours after an inspection, each authorized inspection agency that employs a special inspector shall notify the Chief Boiler Inspector if an inspection reveals a hazardous condition as described in &#xA7; 12-915(a)(2) of this subtitle that affects the safety of a boiler or pressure vessel.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each person that operates pressure vessels covered by an owner-user inspection service that meets the requirements of this subtitle shall maintain in its files an inspection record that lists, by a Maryland number and by an abbreviated identification description:<section prefix="(i)">each pressure vessel covered by this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the date of the last inspection of the pressure vessel; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the approximate date for the next inspection of the pressure vessel, calculated by applying the appropriate rules for inspection to all data available when the inspection record is compiled.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The inspection record shall be readily available for examination by the Chief Boiler Inspector or authorized representative during business hours.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In addition, the person shall file annually with the Chief Boiler Inspector a statement that:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The statement shall be accompanied by a filing fee of:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
