<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-106" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-11-106</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant for a license to engage in business as a manufacturer or dealer, to possess explosives other than explosives for use in firearms, or to possess explosives for use in firearms, and an applicant for a blaster's permit shall:<section prefix="(i)">submit an application to the State Fire Marshal on the form that the State Fire Marshal provides;</section><section prefix="(ii)">submit the documents required under this section; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">pay to the State Fire Marshal the fees required under subsection (d) of this section and the cost of the criminal history records check.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The application form shall require the following information:<section prefix="(i)">the name and address of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the reason for desiring the requested license or permit;</section><section prefix="(iii)">if the applicant is an individual, the citizenship of the individual;</section><section prefix="(iv)">if the applicant is a partnership, association, or corporation, the names, addresses, and citizenship of the partners of the partnership or officers and directors of the association or corporation; and</section><section prefix="(v)">proof of liability insurance in the amount that the State Fire Prevention Commission sets.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">As part of the application for a license or permit, the applicant shall submit to the State Fire Marshal the fingerprints required under subsection (e)(3)(i) of this section for each applicant and each officer, agent, or employee of the applicant who will be handling explosives.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">As part of the application for a license or permit, the State Fire Marshal shall require the applicant to submit with the application:<section prefix="(1)">the place where the explosives will be stored;</section><section prefix="(2)">the place where the explosives will be used; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the specific purpose for using the explosives.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each application for a license or permit shall be accompanied by the following fee:<section prefix="(1)">license to engage in business as a manufacturer of:<section prefix="(i)">less than 500 pounds of explosives $150</section><section prefix="(ii)">500 pounds or more of explosives but less than 5,000 pounds $300</section><section prefix="(iii)">5,000 pounds  or  more of explosives but less than 10,000 pounds  $750</section><section prefix="(iv)">10,000 pounds or more of explosives $1,500</section></section><section prefix="(2)">license to engage in business as a dealer for:<section prefix="(i)">retail only  $75</section><section prefix="(ii)">users $150</section><section prefix="(iii)">wholesale and retail $300</section></section><section prefix="(3)">license to possess explosives other than for use in firearms $150</section><section prefix="(4)">license to possess explosives for use in firearms $150</section><section prefix="(5)">storage license for:<section prefix="(i)">Class A - 500 pounds or more of explosives $150</section><section prefix="(ii)">Class B - less than 500 pounds of explosives $75</section></section><section prefix="(6)">blaster's permit $60</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "Central Repository" means the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository of the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Fire Marshal shall apply to the Central Repository for a State and national criminal history records check for each applicant and each officer, agent, or employee of the applicant who will be handling explosives.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">As part of the application for a criminal history records check, the State Fire Marshal shall submit to the Central Repository:<section prefix="(i)">two complete sets of legible fingerprints of each applicant and each officer, agent, or employee of the applicant who will be handling explosives, taken on forms approved by the Central Repository and the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the fee authorized under &#xA7; 10-221(b)(7) of the Criminal Procedure Article for access to State criminal history records; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the mandatory processing fee required by the Federal Bureau of Investigation for a national criminal history records check.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the Criminal Procedure Article, the Central Repository shall forward to the applicant and the State Fire Marshal a printed statement of the criminal history record information of the subject of the criminal history records check.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Information obtained from the Central Repository under this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">shall be confidential and may not be disseminated; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall be used only for the purpose authorized by this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The subject of a criminal history records check under this subsection may challenge the contents of the printed statement issued by the Central Repository as provided in &#xA7; 10-223 of the Criminal Procedure Article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
