<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="gps" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-14-405</section_number>
  <catch_line>If there is serious human suffering, death, personal injury, or property damage in a county because ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>405</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If there is serious human suffering, death, personal injury, or property damage in a county because of a military or warlike catastrophe, the local governing body has the powers granted in this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The powers in this section may be exercised only during the effective period of an official proclamation by the Governor that declares all or part of the county to be in an actual or threatened emergency area.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The local governing body may borrow money or contract for materials or services on the faith and credit of the county.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To pay for the money borrowed or the materials or services contracted for under subsection (b) of this section, the local governing body may issue bonds, notes, or other certificates of indebtedness on the faith and credit of the county to a person or governmental unit that lends the money or supplies the materials or services.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The local governing body may set the terms, conditions, rate of interest, and provisions for repayment of the bonds, notes, or other certificates of indebtedness issued under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The local governing body may impose a special levy on taxable property in the county in an amount sufficient to:<section prefix="(1)">pay for the money borrowed or the materials and services contracted for under subsection (b) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">make all payments of principal and interest on the bonds, notes, or other certificates of indebtedness issued under subsection (c) of this section that are outstanding.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Money, materials, or services obtained under subsection (b) of this section may be secured, expended, or used in cooperation with other governmental units on a matching basis or otherwise as determined by the local governing body.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Any legal restrictions or delaying procedures are waived and may be disregarded by the local governing body as to:<section prefix="(1)">the purchase, lease, or rental of materials and equipment;</section><section prefix="(2)">the securing and hiring of personal services;</section><section prefix="(3)">the face value of notes, bonds, or other certificates of indebtedness that may be issued and outstanding; or</section><section prefix="(4)">the rate of taxation that may be imposed.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
