<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-502" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-5-502</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Cease Fire Council in the Governor's Office of Crime Control and Prevention.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Council consists of 11 members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 11 members of the Council:<section prefix="(i)">one shall be the Secretary of Juvenile Services or a designee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">one shall be the Secretary of State Police or a designee;</section><section prefix="(iii)">one shall be the Secretary of Public Safety and Correctional Services or a designee;</section><section prefix="(iv)">one shall be the Executive Director of the Governor's Office of Crime Control and Prevention or a designee;</section><section prefix="(v)">two shall be State's Attorneys who are recommended by the President of the Maryland State's Attorneys' Association, appointed by the Governor;</section><section prefix="(vi)">one shall be a sheriff, appointed by the Governor;</section><section prefix="(vii)">one shall represent the Maryland Chiefs of Police Association, appointed by the Governor;</section><section prefix="(viii)">one shall represent the Maryland Municipal Police Executives Association, appointed by the Governor; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">two shall represent the public, appointed by the Governor.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The appointed members serve at the pleasure of the Governor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The term of an appointed member is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The terms of the appointed members are staggered as required by the terms provided for appointed members of the Council on October 1, 2003.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">At the end of a term, an appointed member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary of State Police or the Secretary's designee is the Chairman of the Council.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A member of the Council:<section prefix="(1)">may not receive compensation as a member of the Council; but</section><section prefix="(2)">is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor's Office of Crime Control and Prevention shall provide staff support for the Council.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Assistant Attorney General assigned to the Governor's Office of Crime Control and Prevention is the legal advisor to the Council.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
