<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-201" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-3-201</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Commission" means the Police Training Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Department" means the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Law enforcement agency" means a governmental police force, sheriff's office, or security force or law enforcement organization of the State, a county, or a municipal corporation that by statute, ordinance, or common law is authorized to enforce the general criminal laws of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Law enforcement agency" does not include members of the Maryland National Guard who:<section prefix="(i)">are under the control and jurisdiction of the Military Department;</section><section prefix="(ii)">are assigned to the military property designated as the Glenn L. Martin State Airport; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">are charged with exercising police powers in and for the Glenn L. Martin State Airport.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Police officer" means an individual who:<section prefix="(i)">is authorized to enforce the general criminal laws of the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is a member of one of the following law enforcement agencies:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Police officer" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a member of the Field Enforcement Bureau of the Comptroller's Office;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the State Fire Marshal or a deputy State fire marshal;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an investigator of the Internal Investigative Unit of the Department;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a Montgomery County fire and explosive investigator as defined in &#xA7; 2-208.1 of the Criminal Procedure Article;</section><section prefix="(v)">an Anne Arundel County or City of Annapolis fire and explosive investigator as defined in &#xA7; 2-208.2 of the Criminal Procedure Article;</section><section prefix="(vi)">a Prince George's County fire and explosive investigator as defined in &#xA7; 2-208.3 of the Criminal Procedure Article;</section><section prefix="(vii)">a Worcester County fire and explosive investigator as defined in &#xA7; 2-208.4 of the Criminal Procedure Article; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">a City of Hagerstown fire and explosive investigator as defined in &#xA7; 2-208.5 of the Criminal Procedure Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Police officer" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">an individual who serves as a police officer only because the individual occupies another office or position;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a sheriff, the Secretary of State Police, a commissioner of police, a deputy or assistant commissioner of police, a chief of police, a deputy or assistant chief of police, or another individual with an equivalent title who is appointed or employed by a government to exercise equivalent supervisory authority; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a member of the Maryland National Guard who:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Secretary" means the Secretary of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section>
  </text>
</law>
