<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gps" order_by="" level="1">Public Safety</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gps-12-1005</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1005</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">At a minimum, the MBRC shall:<section prefix="(1)">maintain a level of safety consistent with existing codes;</section><section prefix="(2)">provide for multiple categories of work with multiple compliance standards;</section><section prefix="(3)">be enforceable by local officials using existing enforcement procedures;</section><section prefix="(4)">apply to the repair, renovation, modification, and reconstruction of, a change of occupancy in, and an addition to, an existing building;</section><section prefix="(5)">provide an expedited review process for proposed amendments to the MBRC submitted by a local government or an organization that represents local governments; and</section><section prefix="(6)">provide an opportunity for a person proposing a complex project that involves multiple codes to meet, before submitting a construction permit application, with the local officials, or their designees, responsible for permit approval and enforcement of construction-related laws that apply to the project.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To the extent possible, the meeting provided for under subsection (a)(6) of this section shall include the officials responsible for permit approval and enforcement in any of the following areas that apply to the complex project:<section prefix="(1)">building code;</section><section prefix="(2)">mechanical code;</section><section prefix="(3)">plumbing code;</section><section prefix="(4)">electrical code;</section><section prefix="(5)">fire prevention code;</section><section prefix="(6)">Boiler Safety Code;</section><section prefix="(7)">energy code;</section><section prefix="(8)">elevator code; and</section><section prefix="(9)">local historic preservation ordinances.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The purpose of the meeting provided for under subsection (a)(6) of this section is to anticipate and expedite the resolution of problems that a complex project may have in complying with the MBRC and any other applicable laws.</section>
  </text>
</law>
