<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="24-104" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-24-104</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">in Montgomery County:<section prefix="(i)">an apartment house with fewer than five dwelling units; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a water supply or sewage collection and disposal system constructed:</section></section><section prefix="(2)">in Prince George's County, a water supply or sewage collection and disposal system:<section prefix="(i)">constructed to serve only a single family residence or a single building; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">owned and operated by a municipality on January 1, 1959.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to Calvert Manor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to subsection (c) of this section, a person shall obtain a permit from the Commission before the person may construct, alter, extend, or operate a water supply or sewage collection and disposal system outside the sanitary district in Montgomery County or Prince George's County.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may not issue a permit under subsection (b) of this section until the Commission approves:<section prefix="(i)">complete plans and specifications for the construction, alteration, extension, or operation of the water supply or sewage collection and disposal system; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any other information that the Commission requires.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">during construction, inspect all projects for which the permit was issued; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">require the construction to conform to the approved plans and specifications.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission may charge a reasonable permit fee not exceeding 6% of the estimated construction cost for a project described in this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person holding a permit under subsection (b) of this section shall submit to the Commission:<section prefix="(i)">any material change in the plans and specifications; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a statement of the reasons for the change.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall approve and issue a permit for a material change before the person may include the change in the actual construction.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A water supply or sewage collection and disposal system, including oxidation ponds and sewage lagoons, for which a permit is required under this section shall be installed, maintained, and operated under regulations that the Commission adopts.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">inspect the operations of any water supply or sewage collection and disposal system authorized under this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">require the owners or operators of the system to maintain and operate the system in compliance with the Commission's reasonable requirements and with regard to public health, safety, and comfort;</section><section prefix="(3)">set and collect from the owners or operators of the system a reasonable fee for the supervision and inspection of the system; and</section><section prefix="(4)">if the owner or operator fails or refuses to correct, maintain, or operate the system in compliance with the Commission's requirements:<section prefix="(i)">make the correction or take over the operation of the system for any period necessary; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">collect the costs for the correction or operation from the owner or operator.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Commission:<section prefix="(1)">shall adjust its inspection fees accordingly if a municipality in Montgomery County or Prince George's County:<section prefix="(i)">owns or operates a water supply or sewage collection and disposal system;</section><section prefix="(ii)">performs or has performed bacteriological and chemical analyses on the system by qualified personnel, as approved by the Department of the Environment and the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">files with the Commission a monthly report of the analyses showing that satisfactory operating conditions exist in the system; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">is not required to duplicate an analysis.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a water or sewage treatment facility is constructed under a Commission permit and operates subject to inspection by the Department of the Environment, the Commission is not required to duplicate the operational inspection functions that the Department of the Environment conducts.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission may eliminate or reduce its operation and inspection fee in proportion to the eliminated inspection activities.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">All other requirements of the Commission permit for the facility shall be applicable.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When a water supply or sewage collection and disposal system authorized under this section is completed, the person constructing the system shall file with the Commission as a permanent record a certified copy of the plans in full, showing the work as built.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The record shall include the information and be in the form that the Commission requires.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">A person found to have violated this section is not relieved from the requirement to secure and pay for a permit and comply with all other applicable provisions of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
