<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-7-213</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>213</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"System-average interruption duration index" or "SAIDI" means the sum of the customer interruption hours divided by the total number of customers served.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"System-average interruption frequency index" or "SAIFI" means the sum of the number of customer interruptions divided by the total number of customers served.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">It is the goal of the State that each electric company provide its customers with high levels of service quality and reliability in a cost-effective manner, as measured by objective and verifiable standards, and that each electric company be held accountable if it fails to deliver reliable service according to those standards.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section does not apply to small rural electric cooperatives or municipal electric companies.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">On or before July 1, 2012, the Commission shall adopt regulations that implement service quality and reliability standards relating to the delivery of electricity to retail customers by electric companies through their distribution systems, using:<section prefix="(1)">SAIFI;</section><section prefix="(2)">SAIDI; and</section><section prefix="(3)">any other performance measurement that the Commission determines to be reasonable.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The regulations adopted under subsection (d) of this section shall:<section prefix="(i)">include service quality and reliability standards, including standards relating to:<section prefix="1.">service interruption;</section><section prefix="2.">downed wire response;</section><section prefix="3.">customer communications;</section><section prefix="4.">vegetation management;</section><section prefix="5.">periodic equipment inspections;</section><section prefix="6.">annual reliability reporting; and</section><section prefix="7.">any other standards established by the Commission;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">account for major outages caused by events outside the control of an electric company; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">for an electric company that fails to meet the applicable service quality and reliability standards, require the company to file a corrective action plan that details specific actions the company will take to meet the standards.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The regulations adopted under subsection (d) of this section may include a separate reliability standard for each electric company in order to account for system reliability differentiating factors, including:<section prefix="(i)">system design;</section><section prefix="(ii)">existing infrastructure;</section><section prefix="(iii)">customer density; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">geography.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In adopting the regulations required under subsection (d) of this section, the Commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">consider applicable standards of the Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers;</section><section prefix="(ii)">ensure that the service quality and reliability standards are cost-effective; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">with respect to standards relating to vegetation management, consider:<section prefix="1.">limitations on an electric company's right to access private property; and</section><section prefix="2.">customer acceptance of vegetation management initiatives.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before September 1, 2013, and September 1 of each year thereafter, the Commission shall determine whether each electric company has met the service quality and reliability standards adopted by the Commission for that electric company under subsection (d) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph does not apply to electric cooperatives.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Commission shall take appropriate corrective action against an electric company that fails to meet any or all of the applicable service quality and reliability standards, including the imposition of appropriate civil penalties for noncompliance as provided in &#xA7; 13-201 of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">An electric company may not recover the cost of any civil penalty paid under this section from ratepayers.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before April 1 of each year, each electric company shall submit to the Commission an annual performance report that summarizes the actual electric service reliability results for the preceding year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual performance report shall include:<section prefix="(i)">the electric company's average 3-year performance results;</section><section prefix="(ii)">actual year-end performance measure results;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an assessment of the results and effectiveness of the reliability objectives, planned actions and projects, programs, and load studies in achieving an acceptable reliability level; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">annual information that the Commission determines necessary to assess the electric company's efforts to maintain reliable electric service to all customers in the electric company's service territory, including:<section prefix="1.">current year expenditures, labor resource hours, and progress measures for each capital and maintenance program designed to support the maintenance of reliable electric service;</section><section prefix="2.">the number of outages by outage type;</section><section prefix="3.">the number of outages by outage cause;</section><section prefix="4.">the total number of customers that experienced an outage;</section><section prefix="5.">the total customer minutes of outage time; and</section><section prefix="6.">to the extent practicable, a breakdown, by the number of days each customer was without electric service, of the number of customers that experienced an outage.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the request of an electric company, the Commission shall hold a hearing to discuss the annual performance report of the electric company.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">This section may not be construed to limit the Commission's authority to adopt and enforce engineering and safety standards for electric companies.</section>
  </text>
</law>
