<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-7-501</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>501</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Affiliate" means a person that directly or indirectly, or through one or more intermediaries, controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with, or has, directly or indirectly, any economic interest in another person.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Assignee" means a person to whom an electric company assigns or transfers all or a portion of its interest in intangible transition property, other than as security.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Assignee" includes a person to whom all or a portion of the interest is subsequently assigned or transferred.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Competitive transition charge" means a rate, charge, credit, or other appropriate mechanism authorized to be imposed for the recovery of transition costs as determined by the Commission under &#xA7; 7-513 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Consumer" and "customer" each means a retail electric customer.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Customer choice" means the right of electricity suppliers and customers to utilize and interconnect with the electric distribution system on a nondiscriminatory basis at rates, terms, and conditions of service comparable to the electric company's own use of the system to distribute electricity from an electricity supplier to a customer, under which a customer has the opportunity to purchase electricity from the customer's choice of licensed electricity suppliers.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Distribution territory" means the geographic area in which an electric company was providing electric transmission or distribution services to customers on July 1, 1999.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Independent system operator" means an entity authorized by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to control a regional transmission grid.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Initial implementation date" means:<section prefix="(1)">July 1, 2000, for investor-owned electric companies;</section><section prefix="(2)">the date or dates determined by the Commission for Electric Cooperatives and Municipal Electric Utilities; or</section><section prefix="(3)">another date or dates determined by the Commission under &#xA7; 7-510(b) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Intangible transition charge" means a nonbypassable rate, charge, or similar appropriate mechanism for the provision, availability, or termination of electric service, authorized to be imposed for the recovery of qualified transition costs under a qualified rate order of the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Intangible transition property" means the right, title, and interest of an electric company or assignee in a qualified rate order, including:<section prefix="(1)">all rights in, to, and under the order, including rights to revenues, collections, claims, payments, money, or other property and amounts arising from the imposition of intangible transition charges under the order; and</section><section prefix="(2)">in the hands of an assignee:<section prefix="(i)">the right to require the electric company to provide electric services, and to collect and remit the intangible transition charges authorized in the qualified rate order; but</section><section prefix="(ii)">not the right or duty to provide electric services.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Public purpose program" means a program implemented with the intention of furthering a public purpose.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Public purpose program" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a universal service program;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a program encouraging renewable energy resources;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a demand side management or other energy efficiency or conservation program; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">a consumer education program.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Qualified rate order" means an order of the Commission approving one or more intangible transition charges.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Standard offer service" means electric service that an electric company must offer to its customers under &#xA7; 7-510(c) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Transition bond" means a bond, debenture, note, certificate of participation or beneficial interest, or other evidence of indebtedness or ownership, approved in a qualified rate order and issued under an executed trust indenture or other agreement of an electric company or assignee, and which is secured by, evidences ownership interest in, or is payable from intangible transition property.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Transition cost" means a cost, liability, or investment that:<section prefix="(1)">traditionally would have been or would be recoverable under rate-of-return regulation, but which may not be recoverable in a restructured electricity supply market; or</section><section prefix="(2)">arises as a result of electric industry restructuring and is related to the creation of customer choice.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Universal service program" means a program that helps low-income customers maintain electric service.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Universal service program" includes customer bill assistance and payment programs, termination of service protection, and policies and services that help low-income customers to reduce or manage energy consumption in a cost-effective manner.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
