<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="25-106" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-25-106</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except for assessments and benefit charges authorized by Subtitle 2 of this title, this section applies to any fee or charge imposed by the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may file a written claim with the Commission, in a form and containing the information and supporting documents required by the Commission, for a refund of the amount of a fee or charge the person paid to the Commission that exceeds the amount that is properly and legally payable.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the property for which the fee or charge was paid has been transferred to a new owner after the payment, the new owner may file the claim for the refund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On the receipt of a claim for a refund under subsection (b) of this section, the Commission shall investigate the merits of the claim.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On the request of the claimant, the Commission, or the Commission's designee, shall hold a hearing on the claim.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A claim shall be disallowed unless it is filed within 3 years after the date of the payment for which the refund is requested.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Commission shall pay interest on any amount refunded under this section, calculated at the rate of 6% per year, starting 180 days from the date the claim was made.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the Commission fails to reach a final decision on a claim within 180 days after the date the claim is filed, the failure shall be deemed a final rejection of the claim.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Within 30 days after the date of final action by the Commission on a claim for a refund filed under subsection (b) of this section, a petition for judicial review may be filed with the circuit court as provided in Title 7, Chapter 200 of the Maryland Rules.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the Commission may refund a payment that the Commission determines was paid in excess of the amount that was properly and legally payable, whether or not the person who made the payment files a claim for a refund.</section>
  </text>
</law>
