<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-23-201</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Authorization for service" means an application by a property owner or developer to the Commission for water or sewer service that requires the construction of subdivision lines.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Development" means a project for the construction of:<section prefix="(i)">two or more residential dwelling units; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a commercial or industrial structure.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Health hazard" means an owner-occupied residential property with a failing well or septic system as certified by the State or a local health department.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Payment security" means security to guarantee payment to the utility contractor, subcontractors, and suppliers that provide labor, materials, or construction equipment for the construction of subdivision lines.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Performance security" means security to guarantee completion of the construction of subdivision lines.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Subdivision lines" means the water and sewer pipelines or facilities necessary to provide service to a development, including service connections to individual lots or properties in a development.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Subdivision lines" does not include pipelines or facilities that constitute major projects as defined in &#xA7; 23-301 of this title.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, this section does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">authorizations for service for which:<section prefix="1.">application was made with the Commission on or before June 30, 1999; and</section><section prefix="2.">	the Commission entered into a contract for construction of subdivision lines with notice to proceed issued by the Commission to its contractor on or before June 30, 2001; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">authorizations for service for the relief of health hazards.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each part of a multipart authorization for service shall be considered a separate authorization under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law and except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, the owner or developer of a development in the sanitary district shall construct all subdivision lines for the development at the expense of the owner or developer.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Before constructing subdivision lines, the owner or developer of a development shall enter into an agreement with the Commission that:<section prefix="(1)">requires the subdivision lines to be constructed under plans and specifications submitted to and approved by the Commission;</section><section prefix="(2)">requires the owner or developer to comply with all applicable laws and requirements for the construction of the subdivision lines;</section><section prefix="(3)">provides for the inspection of the subdivision lines by the Commission before the line is placed in service;</section><section prefix="(4)">requires the property owner or developer to provide:<section prefix="(i)">performance security payable to the Commission in an amount acceptable to the Commission, taking into account potential cost escalation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">payment security payable to the Commission in an amount equal to the amount of the performance security; and</section></section><section prefix="(5)">provides that before the subdivision lines are placed in service, the property owner or developer shall provide the Commission with a release of liens, on a form acceptable to the Commission, signed by the utility contractor and notarized, stating that the utility contractor, subcontractors, and suppliers have been paid.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Acceptable forms of performance security and payment security under subsection (d) of this section are:<section prefix="(1)">a certified check;</section><section prefix="(2)">a cash deposit;</section><section prefix="(3)">a certificate of deposit;</section><section prefix="(4)">an irrevocable letter of credit from a financial institution acceptable to the Commission and in a form acceptable to the Commission;</section><section prefix="(5)">a bond executed by a surety company authorized to do business in the State; or</section><section prefix="(6)">any other form of security acceptable to the Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A utility contractor, subcontractor, or supplier providing labor, materials, or equipment for the construction of the subdivision lines that has not been paid may file a claim against the payment security within 180 days after completion of construction of the subdivision lines under the procedure required in the payment security.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a procedure is not specified in the payment security, the procedure shall be as established by regulations adopted by the Commission.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission may not release or reduce the amount of the payment security until:<section prefix="(i)">all claimants have been paid; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">180 days have passed since completion of construction and no claims have been made.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
