<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-7-701</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>701</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Administration" means the Maryland Energy Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Fund" means the Maryland Strategic Energy Investment Fund established under &#xA7; 9-20B-05 of the State Government Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c-1)">"Geothermal heating and cooling system" means a system that:<section prefix="(1)">exchanges thermal energy from groundwater or a shallow ground source to generate thermal energy through a geothermal heat pump or a system of geothermal heat pumps interconnected with any geothermal extraction facility that is:<section prefix="(i)">a closed loop or a series of closed loop systems in which fluid is permanently confined within a pipe or tubing and does not come in contact with the outside environment; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an open loop system in which ground or surface water is circulated in an environmentally safe manner directly into the facility and returned to the same aquifer or surface water source;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">meets or exceeds the current federal Energy Star product specification standards;</section><section prefix="(3)">replaces or displaces inefficient space or water heating systems whose primary fuel is electricity or a nonnatural gas fuel source;</section><section prefix="(4)">replaces or displaces inefficient space cooling systems that do not meet federal Energy Star product specification standards;</section><section prefix="(5)">is manufactured, installed, and operated in accordance with applicable government and industry standards; and</section><section prefix="(6)">does not feed electricity back to the grid.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Industrial process load" means the consumption of electricity by a manufacturing process at an establishment classified in the manufacturing sector under the North American Industry Classification System, Codes 31 through 33.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Old growth timber" means timber from a forest:<section prefix="(1)">at least 5 acres in size with a preponderance of old trees, of which the oldest exceed at least half the projected maximum attainable age for the species; and</section><section prefix="(2)">that exhibits several of the following characteristics:<section prefix="(i)">shade-tolerant species are present in all age and size classes;</section><section prefix="(ii)">randomly distributed canopy gaps are present;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a high degree of structural diversity characterized by multiple growth layers reflecting a broad spectrum of ages is present;</section><section prefix="(iv)">an accumulation of dead wood of varying sizes and stages of decomposition accompanied by decadence in live dominant trees is present; and</section><section prefix="(v)">pit and mound topography can be observed.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"PJM region" means the control area administered by the PJM Interconnection, Inc., as the area may change from time to time.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Poultry litter" means the fecal and urinary excretions of poultry, including wood shavings, sawdust, straw, rice hulls, and other bedding material for the disposition of manure.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Qualifying biomass" means a nonhazardous, organic material that is available on a renewable or recurring basis, and is:<section prefix="(i)">waste material that is segregated from inorganic waste material and is derived from sources including:<section prefix="1.">except for old growth timber, any of the following forest-related resources:</section><section prefix="2.">a pallet, crate, or dunnage;</section><section prefix="3.">agricultural and silvicultural sources, including tree crops, vineyard materials, grain, legumes, sugar, and other crop by-products or residues; or</section><section prefix="4.">gas produced from the anaerobic decomposition of animal waste or poultry waste; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">a plant that is cultivated exclusively for purposes of being used at a Tier 1 renewable source or a Tier 2 renewable source to produce electricity.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Qualifying biomass" includes biomass listed in paragraph (1) of this subsection that is used for co-firing, subject to &#xA7; 7-704(d) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Qualifying biomass" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">unsegregated solid waste or postconsumer wastepaper; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an invasive exotic plant species.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h-1)">"Thermal biomass system" means a system that:<section prefix="(1)">uses:<section prefix="(i)">primarily animal manure, including poultry litter, and associated bedding to generate thermal energy; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">food waste or qualifying biomass for the remainder of the feedstock;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">is used in the State; and</section><section prefix="(3)">complies with all applicable State and federal statutes and regulations, as determined by the appropriate regulatory authority.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Renewable energy credit" or "credit" means a credit equal to the generation attributes of 1 megawatt-hour of electricity that is derived from a Tier 1 renewable source or a Tier 2 renewable source that is located:<section prefix="(1)">in the PJM region; or</section><section prefix="(2)">outside the area described in item (1) of this subsection but in a control area that is adjacent to the PJM region, if the electricity is delivered into the PJM region.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Renewable energy portfolio standard" or "standard" means the percentage of electricity sales at retail in the State that is to be derived from Tier 1 renewable sources and Tier 2 renewable sources in accordance with &#xA7; 7-703(b) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Renewable on-site generator" means a person who generates electricity on site from a Tier 1 renewable source or a Tier 2 renewable source for the person's own use.</section>
    <section prefix="(k-1)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Solar water heating system" means a system that:<section prefix="(i)">is comprised of glazed liquid-type flat-plate or tubular solar collectors as defined and certified to the OG-100 standard of the Solar Ratings and Certification Corporation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">generates energy using solar radiation for the purpose of heating water; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">does not feed electricity back to the electric grid.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Solar water heating system" does not include a system that generates energy using solar radiation for the sole purpose of heating a hot tub or swimming pool.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Tier 1 renewable source" means one or more of the following types of energy sources:<section prefix="(1)">solar energy, including energy from photovoltaic technologies and solar water heating systems;</section><section prefix="(2)">wind;</section><section prefix="(3)">qualifying biomass;</section><section prefix="(4)">methane from the anaerobic decomposition of organic materials in a landfill or wastewater treatment plant;</section><section prefix="(5)">geothermal, including energy generated through geothermal exchange from or thermal energy avoided by, groundwater or a shallow ground source;</section><section prefix="(6)">ocean, including energy from waves, tides, currents, and thermal differences;</section><section prefix="(7)">a fuel cell that produces electricity from a Tier 1 renewable source under item (3) or (4) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(8)">a small hydroelectric power plant of less than 30 megawatts in capacity that is licensed or exempt from licensing by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission;</section><section prefix="(9)">poultry litter-to-energy;</section><section prefix="(10)">waste-to-energy;</section><section prefix="(11)">refuse-derived fuel; and</section><section prefix="(12)">thermal energy from a thermal biomass system.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Tier 2 renewable source" means hydroelectric power other than pump storage generation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
