<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-118" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-2-118</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">taxicabs;</section><section prefix="(2)">powerboat companies;</section><section prefix="(3)">toll bridges;</section><section prefix="(4)">towing and lightering companies; or</section><section prefix="(5)">small rural electric cooperatives described in &#xA7; 7-502(a) of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission shall require each public service company subject to its jurisdiction to formulate and, after approval by the Commission, to implement long-range plans to provide regulated service.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission shall require each electric company in the State to include in the long-range plan adequate, cost-effective provisions to promote energy conservation to decrease or moderate electric and, as appropriate, natural gas demand for regulated service from customers.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall review each plan for adequacy under the criteria of &#xA7; 2-113 of this subtitle, giving attention to the interrelationship of services of other public service companies and to provisions for research and development to ensure adequate service.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">As part of the review, and subject to any applicable Freedom of Information Act, the Commission shall consult with other State units and provide an opportunity for public comment.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission shall require the revisions to a plan that the Commission considers appropriate unless the authority to review and approve a plan has been granted to another State unit by other law.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
