<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-201" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-13-201</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to a violation of the following provisions of this article:<section prefix="(1)">Title 5, Subtitle 4;</section><section prefix="(2)">Title 7, Subtitle 1;</section><section prefix="(3)">&#xA7; 7-213 as it applies to electric cooperatives;</section><section prefix="(4)">Title 8, Subtitles 1 and 3;</section><section prefix="(5)">Title 9, Subtitle 3; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Title 8, Subtitle 4.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Commission may impose a civil penalty not exceeding $25,000 against a person who violates a provision of this division, or an effective and outstanding direction, ruling, order, rule, or regulation of the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The civil penalty that the Commission may impose on a common carrier for each violation may not exceed $2,500.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A civil penalty may be imposed in addition to any other penalty authorized by this division.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each violation is a separate offense.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each day or part of a day the violation continues is a separate offense.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commission shall determine the amount of any civil penalty after considering:<section prefix="(1)">the number of previous violations of any provision of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">the gravity of the current violation;</section><section prefix="(3)">the good faith efforts of the violator in attempting to achieve compliance after notification of the violation; and</section><section prefix="(4)">any other matter that the Commission considers appropriate and relevant.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A civil penalty collected under this section shall be paid into the General Fund of the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
