<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="25-508" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-25-508</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Prince George's County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is an Office of Prince George's County Ombudsman in the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Prince George's County Executive, with the approval of the Prince George's County Council, shall appoint an Ombudsman.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Prince George's County shall:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The county may pay for any legal expenses incurred by the Ombudsman, as provided in the county budget.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Prince George's County Council shall determine the salary of the Ombudsman.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">While holding office, the Ombudsman may participate in any Commission program of group health, life, or disability insurance to the same extent and under the same terms as other Commission officers and employees.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Ombudsman may represent the interests of a Prince George's County residential or commercial customer who files a written claim with the Commission for:<section prefix="(1)">a refund of a payment on a bill for water and sewer usage charges that exceeds the amount that is properly and legally payable; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a reduction in a bill for water and sewer usage charges that exceeds the amount that is properly and legally payable that has not yet been paid.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Ombudsman:<section prefix="(1)">shall:<section prefix="(i)">receive a copy of, and review, any written claim filed with the Commission under &#xA7; 25-106(b) of this title;</section><section prefix="(ii)">investigate the merits of the claim;</section><section prefix="(iii)">attend any hearing held in accordance with &#xA7; 25-106(c)(2) of this title and present any findings and recommendations on the merits of the claim during the hearing; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">prepare a written statement of findings and recommendations on the claim and provide copies of the statement to the Commission and the claimant; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">may represent the customer in any appeal process.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this division, as to Prince George's County residential customers, if all undisputed bills for water and sewer usage charges are paid when due, the Commission may not interrupt service during the pendency of a written claim filed for a reduction in a bill for water and sewer usage charges that exceeds the amount that is properly and legally payable.</section>
  </text>
</law>
