<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-12-127</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person may begin excavation or demolition only after the person receives notification from the und...</catch_line>
  <order_by>127</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may begin excavation or demolition only after the person receives notification from the underground facilities information exchange system of the one-call system confirming that all applicable owner-members have:<section prefix="(1)">marked their underground facilities in accordance with &#xA7; 12-126(c) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">marked the applicable portion of their underground facilities in accordance with &#xA7; 12-126(d) of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(3)">reported that they have no underground facilities in the vicinity of the excavation or demolition.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After an owner-member has marked the location of an underground facility in accordance with &#xA7; 12-126 of this subtitle, the person performing the excavation or demolition is responsible for the maintenance of the designated marker.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the marker is obliterated, destroyed, or removed, the person shall repeat the notification required under &#xA7; 12-124 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person performing an excavation or demolition shall exercise due care to avoid interference with or damage to an underground facility that an owner-member has marked in accordance with &#xA7; 12-126 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before using mechanized equipment for excavation or demolition within 18 inches of an underground facility marking, a person shall expose the underground facility to its outermost surfaces by hand or other nondestructive techniques.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A person may not use mechanized equipment to excavate within 18 inches of the outermost surface of an exposed underground facility.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The person performing an excavation or demolition immediately shall notify the owner-member of the facility if the person discovers or causes any damage to or dislocation or disturbance of an underground facility in connection with the excavation or demolition.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the damage, dislocation, or disturbance results in the escape of a flammable, toxic, or corrosive gas or liquid, the person performing the excavation or demolition immediately shall report the damage to the 9-1-1 emergency system.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a person knows or has reason to know that an underground facility in the area of a planned or ongoing excavation or demolition is not marked as required by this subtitle, the person may not begin or continue the excavation or demolition unless the person:<section prefix="(i)">has repeated the notification required under &#xA7; 12-124 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">receives notification from the underground facilities information exchange system of the one-call system confirming that all applicable owner-members that have underground facilities in the vicinity of the excavation or demolition have marked:<section prefix="1.">the underground facilities in accordance with &#xA7; 12-126(c) of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="2.">the applicable portion of the underground facilities in accordance with 12-126(d) of this subtitle.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the underground facility is not marked as required by this subtitle after the person receives notification from the underground facilities information exchange system under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the person may proceed with the excavation or demolition.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
