<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-703" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-7-703</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Commission shall implement a renewable energy portfolio standard that, except as provided under paragraph (2) of this subsection, applies to all retail electricity sales in the State by electricity suppliers.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the standard becomes applicable to electricity sold to a customer after the start of a calendar year, the standard does not apply to electricity sold to the customer during that portion of the year before the standard became applicable.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A renewable energy portfolio standard may not apply to electricity sales at retail by any electricity supplier:<section prefix="(i)">in excess of 300,000,000 kilowatt-hours of industrial process load to a single customer in a year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">to residential customers in a region of the State in which electricity prices for residential customers are subject to a freeze or cap contained in a settlement agreement entered into under &#xA7; 7-505 of this title until the freeze or cap has expired; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">to a customer served by an electric cooperative under an electricity supplier purchase agreement that existed on October 1, 2004, until the expiration of the agreement.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The renewable energy portfolio standard shall be as follows:<section prefix="(1)">in 2006, 1% from Tier 1 renewable sources and 2.5% from Tier 2 renewable sources;</section><section prefix="(2)">in 2007, 1% from Tier 1 renewable sources and 2.5% from Tier 2 renewable sources;</section><section prefix="(3)">in 2008, 2.005% from Tier 1 renewable sources, including at least 0.005% derived from solar energy, and 2.5% from Tier 2 renewable sources;</section><section prefix="(4)">in 2009, 2.01% from Tier 1 renewable sources, including at least 0.01% derived from solar energy, and 2.5% from Tier 2 renewable sources;</section><section prefix="(5)">in 2010, 3.025% from Tier 1 renewable sources, including at least 0.025% derived from solar energy, and 2.5% from Tier 2 renewable sources;</section><section prefix="(6)">in 2011, 5.0% from Tier 1 renewable sources, including at least 0.05% derived from solar energy, and 2.5% from Tier 2 renewable sources;</section><section prefix="(7)">in 2012, 6.5% from Tier 1 renewable sources, including at least 0.1% derived from solar energy, and 2.5% from Tier 2 renewable sources;</section><section prefix="(8)">in 2013, 8.2% from Tier 1 renewable sources, including at least 0.25% derived from solar energy, and 2.5% from Tier 2 renewable sources;</section><section prefix="(9)">in 2014, 10.3% from Tier 1 renewable sources, including at least 0.35% derived from solar energy, and 2.5% from Tier 2 renewable sources;</section><section prefix="(10)">in 2015, 10.5% from Tier 1 renewable sources, including at least 0.5% derived from solar energy, and 2.5% from Tier 2 renewable sources;</section><section prefix="(11)">in 2016, 12.7% from Tier 1 renewable sources, including at least 0.7% derived from solar energy, and 2.5% from Tier 2 renewable sources;</section><section prefix="(12)">in 2017, 13.1% from Tier 1 renewable sources, including at least 0.95% derived from solar energy, and 2.5% from Tier 2 renewable sources;</section><section prefix="(13)">in 2018, 15.8% from Tier 1 renewable sources, including at least 1.4% derived from solar energy, and 2.5% from Tier 2 renewable sources;</section><section prefix="(14)">in 2019, 17.4% from Tier 1 renewable sources, including at least 1.75% derived from solar energy, and 0% from Tier 2 renewable sources;</section><section prefix="(15)">in 2020, 18% from Tier 1 renewable sources, including at least 2.0% derived from solar energy, and 0% from Tier 2 renewable sources;</section><section prefix="(16)">in 2021, 18.7% from Tier 1 renewable sources, including at least 2.0% derived from solar energy, and 0% from Tier 2 renewable sources; and</section><section prefix="(17)">in 2022 and later, 20% from Tier 1 renewable sources, including at least 2% derived from solar energy, and 0% from Tier 2 renewable sources.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before calculating the number of credits required to meet the percentages established under subsection (b) of this section, an electricity supplier shall exclude from its total retail electricity sales all retail electricity sales described in subsection (a)(2) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Subject to subsections (a) and (c) of this section, an electricity supplier shall meet the renewable energy portfolio standard by accumulating the equivalent amount of renewable energy credits that equal the percentages required under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
