<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="17-204" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-17-204</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Commission may enter into a contract or agreement concerning the construction, maintenance, and operation of the water supply, sewer, or drainage systems under its control or under the control or ownership of the District of Columbia or any other agency, authority, or commission specified in this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission may enter into a contract or agreement under paragraph (1) of this subsection with:<section prefix="(i)">the District of Columbia;</section><section prefix="(ii)">any federal, state, county, or municipal authority in the State or any other state; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">any public water, sewer, or drainage commission in the State or any other state.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission may contract with, as a primary party or as a subcontractor, or invest in any person for the ownership, joint-venturing, management, operation, supervision, assistance, participation, or any other activity relating to the design, construction, operation, maintenance, or management of water or wastewater systems, including systems, services, expertise, intellectual property, and techniques developed in connection with, or usable or marketable with respect to, water or wastewater systems.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any contract or agreement entered into under this section has the full effect of a contract between the District of Columbia and the State or between the other agencies, authorities, or persons described in the section and this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The authority granted in this section is in addition to, and is not limited by, the authority granted by any other Act of the General Assembly.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
