<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-25-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may not impose a front foot benefit charge on:<section prefix="(i)">property owned by the State, a county, or a municipality;</section><section prefix="(ii)">property in the sanitary district that is connected to or authorized by the Commission to be connected to a water or sewer system operated by:<section prefix="1.">a municipality; or</section><section prefix="2.">a water or sewer company under the jurisdiction of the Department of the Environment;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">property owned by a regularly organized volunteer fire department that is used for public purposes; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, property classified as agricultural that is actually used for farming purposes, unless a connection is made to a water main or sewer running through or adjacent to the property.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission may impose a reasonable front foot benefit charge on property classified as agricultural, which may not exceed the charge for 300 feet of front footage.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission may suspend the imposition and collection of a front foot benefit charge:<section prefix="(1)">with respect to a sewer line, for property otherwise subject to a front foot benefit charge that the Commission determines cannot obtain service from the sewer pipe on which the benefit charge would be based;</section><section prefix="(2)">for construction of a water main if the owner of the property that is otherwise subject to the benefit charge is not permitted to connect to the water main because of a finding:<section prefix="(i)">by the Commission that there is no sewer and the extension of an improved sewer system is not reasonably feasible; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">by a county health department that a septic system would not be approved for the disposal of the water for which the connection is requested; or</section></section><section prefix="(3)">if the property that is otherwise subject to the front foot benefit charge for a water main or sewer has a preexisting residential dwelling that is served by a well or septic system, until the property owner requests service from the water main or sewer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a property is exempt from front foot benefit charges or if the Commission has suspended front foot benefit charges for a property and the property is no longer eligible for the exemption or suspension, the Commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">classify the property in accordance with &#xA7; 25-203 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">impose a front foot benefit charge at a rate and for a period of time equal to that of property that was originally classified or for which the Commission imposed benefit charges in the year of the suspension.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall use money from front foot benefit charges imposed on property under paragraph (1) of this subsection to:<section prefix="(i)">amortize bonds issued to construct water mains and sewers for which benefit charges were imposed under this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">construct other water mains and sewers for which benefit charges are imposed.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
