<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-11-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may adopt regulations that establish safety standards and practices applicable to the design, construction, operation, and maintenance of intrastate pipeline facilities.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For any intrastate pipeline regulatory program that the Commission establishes under this subtitle, the Commission shall adopt as minimum standards the federal safety standards in Title 49, C.F.R. Parts 195 and 199, as periodically amended.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In collaboration with the American Society of Mechanical Engineers, the Commission shall:<section prefix="1.">establish and adopt by regulation methods and best practices for intrastate pipeline facilities; and</section><section prefix="2.">require introduction of these methods and best practices as soon as may be practicable.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The methods shall include quantitative criteria, based on engineering evaluations, to determine whether a wrinkle or other deformity may remain in a pipeline or should be remedied.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may enter, inspect, and examine, at reasonable times and in a reasonable manner, the records and property of an intrastate pipeline operator to determine whether the pipeline operator is acting in compliance with this subtitle and regulations adopted by the Commission under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall inspect each intrastate pipeline at least once each year.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission shall require an intrastate pipeline operator to prepare, maintain, and carry out a written plan for the operation and maintenance of each pipeline facility owned or operated by the intrastate pipeline operator.</section>
  </text>
</law>
