<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-6-208</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>208</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A public service company shall list in its annual report the name and address, basis of control, and principal business activities of:<section prefix="(1)">the public service company; and</section><section prefix="(2)">each:<section prefix="(i)">parent;</section><section prefix="(ii)">subsidiary of the public service company;</section><section prefix="(iii)">organization the public service company controls; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">joint venture in excess of $1,000,000 in which the public service company is involved.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For each principal business activity described in subsection (a) of this section, a public service company shall list and describe by SIC code and short title each industry in which the public service company's activities generated, during the reporting year, at least 10% of gross revenues or $5,000,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The public service company shall compile the list described under paragraph (1) of this subsection in order of significance relative to the total activities of the public service company, based on the percentage of gross revenues generated within each industry.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For each corporation, partnership, or other business organization in which a public service company owns more than 5% of the outstanding voting securities or other ownership interests, the public service company shall, in its annual report:<section prefix="(1)">list the corporation, partnership, or other business organization; and</section><section prefix="(2)">indicate the percentage that the public service company owns.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
