<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-20-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is an Office of Small, Local, and Minority Business Enterprise in the Commission....</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is an Office of Small, Local, and Minority Business Enterprise in the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The head of the Office is the Director of the Office of Small, Local, and Minority Business Enterprise.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Office shall:<section prefix="(1)">administer each Commission program that is created to promote the growth of or participation by minority or local small business enterprises, including:<section prefix="(i)">the minority business enterprise utilization program for design/build and construction contracts under &#xA7; 20-203 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the minority business enterprise utilization program for the procurement of other goods and services under &#xA7; 20-204 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the local small business enterprise program under Subtitle 3 of this title;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">promote and coordinate the plans, programs, and operations of the Commission that promote or affect the establishment, preservation, and strengthening of minority business enterprises;</section><section prefix="(3)">promote activities and the use of the resources of the Commission, local governments, and private entities for the growth of minority business enterprises;</section><section prefix="(4)">provide technical and managerial assistance to minority business enterprises;</section><section prefix="(5)">schedule seminars and workshops to educate minority businesses on how the Commission conducts business; and</section><section prefix="(6)">ensure compliance with certified minority business enterprise subcontract participation goals under &#xA7; 20-206 of this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
