<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-23-102</section_number>
  <catch_line>A privately owned or municipally owned water supply or sanitary sewer system or part of a system, wa...</catch_line>
  <order_by>102</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A privately owned or municipally owned water supply or sanitary sewer system or part of a system, water main, sewer, water purification or sewage disposal plant, or connection with these facilities may not be constructed or installed, except as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A municipality or the property owners or residents of a locality in the sanitary district may construct and operate a water supply or sanitary sewer system or part of a system at their own expense if the Commission decides that it is inexpedient or impracticable to build the system due to remoteness from the Commission's general system or for other reasons.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A system constructed in accordance with subsection (b) of this section shall be constructed under plans and specifications submitted to and approved by the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The construction, maintenance, and operation of the system shall be under the supervision and general control of the Commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">All construction and operating records for the system, including cost records, shall be filed with the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commission may take over the system or a part of the system, water main, sewer, water purification or sewage disposal plant, or connection with these facilities in the same manner as provided in &#xA7; 23-103 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Except as provided in this division, the powers and authority in this section may not be restricted by any other general, special, or local law.</section>
  </text>
</law>
