<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-2-110.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Public Utility Regulation Fund....</catch_line>
  <order_by>110.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Public Utility Regulation Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">all revenue received through the imposition and collection of assessments under &#xA7; 2-110 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">fees received by the Commission under &#xA7; 2-123 of this subtitle for filings and for other services rendered by the Commission;</section><section prefix="(3)">income from investments that the State Treasurer makes for the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(4)">any other fee, examination assessment, or revenue received by the Commission under this division.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding subsection (b) of this section, the Commission shall pay all fines and penalties collected by the Commission under this article into the General Fund of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The purpose of the Fund is to pay all the costs and expenses incurred by the Commission and the Office of People's Counsel that are related to the operation of the Commission and the Office of People's Counsel, including:<section prefix="(1)">expenditures authorized under this division; and</section><section prefix="(2)">any other expense authorized in the State budget.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">All the costs and expenses of the Commission and the Office of People's Counsel shall be included in the State budget.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Expenditures from the Fund to cover costs and expenses of the Commission and Office of People's Counsel may only be made:<section prefix="(i)">with an appropriation from the Fund approved by the General Assembly in the State budget; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">by budget amendment in accordance with &#xA7; 7-209 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Treasurer is the custodian of the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Treasurer shall deposit payments received from the Commission into the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund is a continuing, special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article, and may not be considered a part of the General Fund of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless otherwise provided by law, no part of the Fund may revert or be credited to:<section prefix="(i)">the General Fund of the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">any other special fund of the State.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
