<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-24-201</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "sewer cleaning" means the cleaning or clearing of and the removal of stoppages or ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section, "sewer cleaning" means the cleaning or clearing of and the removal of stoppages or obstructions in sanitary sewer lines, pipes, and fixtures.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Sewer cleaning" does not include any installation, maintenance, extension, removal, or alteration of any pipe, sanitary fixture, or other sewer apparatus.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section may not be construed to:<section prefix="(1)">require a person to have a sewer cleaner's license to clean a sewer on the person's own property;</section><section prefix="(2)">prevent a person from cleaning a sewer on the person's own property; or</section><section prefix="(3)">apply to or prohibit the cleaning by any person of a sewer or sanitary fixture of any dwelling, commercial or industrial establishment, or premises owned or operated by the person.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission shall adopt and enforce regulations governing sewer cleaning in sanitary sewer lines, pipes, and fixtures connected to the Commission's sanitary sewer system.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">To qualify for a sewer cleaner's license, a person need not be a master plumber.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A sewer cleaner's license does not authorize the licensee to engage in the plumbing business other than sewer cleaning.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission:<section prefix="(i)">shall require that a person other than a licensed master plumber who is engaged in or represents the person to the public as engaged in sewer cleaning be licensed by the Commission;</section><section prefix="(ii)">may require a bond of the licensee to insure compliance with and adherence to the regulations adopted by the Commission;</section><section prefix="(iii)">may establish qualifications and examine applicants concerning their competency and qualifications for a license under this section; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">may require a reasonable fee for the issuance and renewal of a license in an amount not more than one-half of the fee charged for a master plumber's license.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
