<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-5-406</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>406</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A railroad company may change the location or grade of any portion of its road if the company finds the change is necessary for any reasonable cause, including to avoid:<section prefix="(i)">inconvenience to public travel;</section><section prefix="(ii)">dangerous or difficult curves or grades; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">unsafe or unsubstantial grounds or foundations.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A change of location or grade under this section shall follow the general route of the existing road.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A railroad company may enter on and take land and make surveys necessary to make the change in location or grade in accordance with Title 12 of the Real Property Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A railroad company is liable to the owner of the land on which the road was constructed for any damages caused by a change in location or grade of the road.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The amount of damages determined shall be paid to the owner or deposited into court.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An owner shall claim damages within:<section prefix="(i)">30 days after actual notice of the intended change has been given to the owner, if the owner resides on the premises; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">60 days after publication of notice in a newspaper in general circulation in the county, if the owner is a nonresident.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a railroad company condemns land under this section, the condemnation is binding on the company, unless the company chooses to abandon the location within 30 days after making the condemnation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
