<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-10-209</section_number>
  <catch_line>A taxicab driver shall make maximum use of service communications with the driver's switchboard oper...</catch_line>
  <order_by>209</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A taxicab driver shall make maximum use of service communications with the driver's switchboard operator or dispatcher in order to keep the driver's taxicab available for response to calls.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A taxicab driver may not solicit the patronage of a person who is at the terminal of another common carrier or at an intermediate point along an established route of that carrier to use that common carrier's service.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Paragraph (1) of this subsection does not prohibit or interfere with a response to a call for a taxicab whether the call is made by telephone or by signal from a pedestrian.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Taxicabs being operated in Baltimore City:<section prefix="(i)">may transport a passenger from Baltimore City into Baltimore County and return to Baltimore County for the same passenger; but</section><section prefix="(ii)">may not solicit a passenger within Baltimore County at any time.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">This subtitle may not impede the operation of taxicabs between Baltimore City and Baltimore-Washington International Thurgood Marshall Airport in the manner allowed by law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A taxicab may not carry more than the number of passengers designated on the rate card.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A child in a passenger's arms is not counted as a passenger.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Only one person may occupy the front seat with the driver.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A taxicab may be used from a railroad station or other public place of special assembly to serve jointly not more than four passengers who are bound for the same, or approximately the same, location.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A passenger who has engaged a taxicab may not be compelled to share the taxicab with another person.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A taxicab driver may not refuse service in order to group passengers more profitably.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, if a taxicab is occupied by several passengers bound for different destinations, each passenger or party shall be charged the fare recorded on the meter at the time of arrival at the passenger's or party's destination.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A party or individual passenger may not be charged more than the fare applicable at the established rate for transportation over the shortest and most direct route.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A taxicab driver may not solicit another passenger while en route to the destination of passengers or parties initially occupying the cab.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A driver of a taxicab may not operate the taxicab:<section prefix="(1)">recklessly;</section><section prefix="(2)">in an unsafe manner; or</section><section prefix="(3)">in disregard of the public general or local laws or municipal ordinances governing the operation of motor vehicles.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
