<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="22-114" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-22-114</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission may borrow money and issue refunding bonds to refund bonds issued and outstanding by the Commission if:<section prefix="(1)">the county executives and county councils of Montgomery County and Prince George's County approve the plan for the issuance of refunding bonds; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the Commission determines that issuing refunding bonds will result in total savings in debt service costs, directly or through any debt restructuring.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission shall authorize the issuance of refunding bonds by resolution that may include:<section prefix="(1)">the date of the refunding bonds;</section><section prefix="(2)">the maturity dates of the refunding bonds, which may not exceed 40 years from the date of issue;</section><section prefix="(3)">the interest rates on the refunding bonds, which may not exceed 10% annually;</section><section prefix="(4)">the denominations of the refunding bonds;</section><section prefix="(5)">the form of the refunding bonds, which may be coupon or registered;</section><section prefix="(6)">registration or conversion privileges;</section><section prefix="(7)">the manner of executing the refunding bonds;</section><section prefix="(8)">the manner of payment at places in or outside of the State;</section><section prefix="(9)">terms for redemption before maturity;</section><section prefix="(10)">terms for replacement of mutilated, destroyed, stolen, or lost bonds; and</section><section prefix="(11)">any other terms, conditions, or covenants.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Refunding bonds issued to refund outstanding bonds for which front foot benefit charges have been imposed shall mature on or before 1 year after the date set for the payment of the final installment of the front foot benefit charge.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Refunding bonds may be:<section prefix="(i)">exchanged for bonds being refunded;</section><section prefix="(ii)">sold at public sale; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, sold at a negotiated sale in an open meeting.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Refunding bonds may be sold at a negotiated sale if the Commission determines:<section prefix="(i)">that a public sale would be impracticable to effectuate the purpose of the refunding bonds; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the price, terms, and conditions are in the best interest of the Commission.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 45 days before the sale or exchange of any refunding bonds, the Commission shall deliver its plan on the issuance of the refunding bonds to the county executives and county councils of Montgomery County and Prince George's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, the Commission may not sell or exchange the refunding bonds unless the plan under paragraph (1) of this subsection is approved by the county executives and county councils of Montgomery County and Prince George's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">On or before 30 days after the delivery of the plan, the county executives and county councils of Montgomery County and Prince George's County shall approve or disapprove of the plan.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Failure of a county executive or county council of Montgomery County or Prince George's County to act within 30 days is deemed as approval of the plan by that county.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The county executives and county councils of Montgomery County and Prince George's County may waive the time period requirements under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If an officer whose signature or facsimile signature appears on a refunding bond or coupon ceases to be an officer before the delivery of the refunding bond, the signature or facsimile is valid and sufficient as if the officer remained in office until delivery.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Refunding bonds issued to refund bonds guaranteed as to payment of principal and interest by Montgomery County or Prince George's County may be guaranteed in the same manner and form as under &#xA7; 22-104 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Refunding bonds authorized under this section are:<section prefix="(1)">in addition to any other bonds authorized under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">included in computing the amount of bonds that may be issued under the 7% limitation under &#xA7; 22-103 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Refunding bonds authorized under this section are forever exempt from taxation by the State and counties and municipalities in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The powers granted under this section are not subject to the provisions of any other law in conflict with the powers.</section>
  </text>
</law>
