<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="25-405" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-25-405</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission may allow a developer to design and construct any on-site or off-site facility necessary for the developer's project if the facility is:<section prefix="(1)">in the Commission Capital Improvement Program and the 10-year Comprehensive Water Supply and Sewerage System Plan adopted by one of the county councils;</section><section prefix="(2)">a major project included in the Commission Capital Improvement Program; or</section><section prefix="(3)">a project that includes a sewer main or water main that:<section prefix="(i)">provides only local service;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is 2,000 feet or less;</section><section prefix="(iii)">has a diameter of:</section><section prefix="(iv)">is built to avoid unnecessary and uneconomical duplication when a major project is constructed.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A facility constructed under this section shall be designed, constructed, and inspected in accordance with:<section prefix="(1)">the standards used by the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(2)">all applicable laws, regulations, and written policies of the Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">After the Commission approves a facility constructed by a developer under this section, the Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">accept the facility as part of the Commission system; and</section><section prefix="(2)">subject to subsection (d) of this section, grant the developer a credit against any charge imposed under this subtitle in an amount equal to the cost of constructing the facility.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commission's internal auditor shall review and approve the costs incurred by the developer.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commission and the developer shall enter into an agreement that incorporates the provisions of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If the Commission rejects a developer's request to design and construct facilities under this section, the Commission shall explain in writing to the developer the reasons for the rejection.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall submit a report at the end of each fiscal year to the Montgomery County and Prince George's County Delegations to the General Assembly and to the county councils of Montgomery County and Prince George's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The report shall state the number of requests made by developers under this section, including:<section prefix="(i)">the number of acceptances and rejections by the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the justification for any rejections.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
