<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-17-201</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission is a body corporate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission may:<section prefix="(i)">use a common seal;</section><section prefix="(ii)">sue and be sued; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">do any other corporate act for the purpose of carrying out this division.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall certify to the county councils of Montgomery County and Prince George's County a tax rate that will, when imposed and collected in accordance with &#xA7; 22-106 of this article, produce an amount sufficient to satisfy:<section prefix="(i)">a judgment against the Commission, including related costs and attorney's fees; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a settlement agreement to resolve threatened or pending litigation, including related costs and attorney's fees.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall certify the tax rate under paragraph (1) of this subsection at the beginning of the taxable year for property taxes of the county councils of Montgomery County and Prince George's County immediately following the date of the judgment or settlement agreement described in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The tax rate described in this subsection is in addition to any tax required under this division for interest, serial bonds, or sinking fund requirements.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">All acts, orders, and regulations previously passed by the Commission while sitting in the District of Columbia are ratified and shall be given the same force and effect as if passed in the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
