<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-124" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-12-124</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person that intends to perform an excavation or demolition in the State shall initiate a ticket request by notifying the one-call system serving the geographic area where the excavation or demolition is to be performed of the person's intent to perform the excavation or demolition.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notice provided to a one-call system under subsection (a) of this section shall indicate:<section prefix="(1)">the location of the proposed excavation or demolition;</section><section prefix="(2)">whether the proposed excavation or demolition is within rights-of-way owned or controlled by the Department of Transportation, an administration of the Department of Transportation, or the Maryland Transportation Authority and, if so, the entity and the permit number or authorization number obtained from that entity; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the type of work to be performed in connection with the proposed excavation or demolition.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, on receiving notice, the one-call system shall promptly transmit a copy of the ticket to all owner-members in the geographic area indicated for that ticket.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Based on information collected under &#xA7; 12-124(b)(2) of this subtitle, the one-call system shall promptly transmit a copy of the ticket to the Department of Transportation, an administration of the Department of Transportation, or the Maryland Transportation Authority, as applicable.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A ticket is valid for 12 business days after the day on which the ticket is transmitted by the one-call system to an owner-member.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
