<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-8-406</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>406</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">When a customer, or a telephone company or reseller providing a new telecommunications service on behalf of the customer, makes a change in the customer's telephone company or reseller, the telephone company or reseller providing the new telecommunications service shall provide a conspicuous notice to the customer, informing the customer that the change was made.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">When a customer, or a telephone company or reseller on behalf of the customer, makes a change in the customer's selection of a telecommunications service option for which the telephone company or reseller imposes a charge, the telephone company or reseller providing the new telecommunications service option shall provide a conspicuous notice to the customer, informing the customer that the change was made.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">When a customer, or a telephone company or reseller on behalf of a customer, makes a change in the person who bills the customer or the customer's billing arrangement, the telephone company or reseller providing the new billing service or arrangement shall provide a conspicuous notice to the customer, informing the customer that the change was made.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A telephone company or reseller that is required to provide notice under this section shall provide the notice by:<section prefix="(1)">inserting the notice on or with the customer's first bill for which the change is effective; or</section><section prefix="(2)">sending a separate notice to the customer within 30 days after the change takes effect.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A telephone company or reseller may not, on behalf of a customer, fail to make any change in a customer's telephone company, reseller, or telecommunications service options, or in the person who bills the customer or the customer's billing arrangement when the change order has been received in a manner that complies with federal and State rules and regulations. All such change orders shall be properly processed to assure that the order is completed and service will be provided by the new telephone company or reseller of choice within 15 business days of receipt of the compliant change order or as otherwise negotiated with the customer.</section>
  </text>
</law>
