<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-4-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Commission shall establish pilotage fees and charges for pilotage services to vessels at a just ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission shall establish pilotage fees and charges for pilotage services to vessels at a just and reasonable rate.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission shall give notice and hold a public hearing on each rate proposal as provided in this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In determining a just and reasonable rate, the Commission shall consider:<section prefix="(1)">the draft, dimensions, and tonnage of the vessel piloted;</section><section prefix="(2)">the difficulty and inconvenience of the particular service and the time and skill required to render the service;</section><section prefix="(3)">the time required to render pilotage service at other United States ports and the fees and charges for the service;</section><section prefix="(4)">the public interest in maintaining efficient and reliable pilotage service; and</section><section prefix="(5)">other factors relevant to the determination of a just and reasonable rate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A pilot may not demand or receive a different compensation for providing pilotage service than the rate set by the Commission under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commission shall impose an assessment on the Association of Maryland Pilots based on assessment guidelines established for public service companies under &#xA7; 2-110 of this article. The assessment imposed under this subsection may not be less than $25,000.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">All pilotage fees and charges provided by applicable law shall remain in effect until changed by the Commission.</section>
  </text>
</law>
