<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="17-205" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-17-205</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "product" or "technology" does not include water or sewer service provided as part of the primary mission of the Commission in the sanitary district or through systems connected directly to and operated as part of the water and sewer system in the sanitary district.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to subsection (d) of this section, the Commission may sell, lease, or license to the public, or enter into a contract concerning:<section prefix="(1)">any product or technology that is produced or developed by the Commission in the normal course of operations, including patents, trademarks, and copyrights;</section><section prefix="(2)">any service directly related to a product or technology described in item (1) of this subsection; or</section><section prefix="(3)">any system, service, expertise, intellectual property, or technique developed, owned, or controlled by or under the jurisdiction of the Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission may adopt a price structure for an item described in subsection (b) of this section based on any factors that the Commission considers relevant, including:<section prefix="(1)">the costs of creating, developing, reproducing, and delivering the product or technology;</section><section prefix="(2)">overhead and labor costs; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the fair market value of the product or technology.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall account for expenditures and revenues resulting from sales under this section by establishing a separate set of accounts.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The accounts established under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be itemized and included in the Commission's annual budget.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commission shall use any net revenues earned from projects and contracts entered into under this section to stabilize or reduce rates and to reduce debt.</section>
  </text>
</law>
