<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-18-207</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Commission and an employee organization certified as the exclusive representative shall meet and...</catch_line>
  <order_by>207</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission and an employee organization certified as the exclusive representative shall meet and engage in collective bargaining in good faith regarding:<section prefix="(1)">salary and wages, including the percentage of the increase in the salary and wages budget that will be devoted to merit increments and cash awards;</section><section prefix="(2)">pension and other retirement benefits for active employees;</section><section prefix="(3)">employee benefits such as insurance, leave, holidays, and vacations;</section><section prefix="(4)">hours and working conditions;</section><section prefix="(5)">provisions for the orderly processing and settlement of grievances concerning the interpretation and implementation of a collective bargaining agreement that may include:<section prefix="(i)">binding third party arbitration; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">provisions for the exclusivity of forum;</section></section><section prefix="(6)">matters affecting the health and safety of employees; and</section><section prefix="(7)">the effect on employees of the exercise of the Commission's rights and responsibilities under &#xA7; 18-211 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not require the Commission or the employee organization to agree to any proposal or to make any concession.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Collective bargaining may not begin later than September 1 before the beginning of a fiscal year for which an agreement has not been reached between the Commission and the certified representative.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Collective bargaining shall finish on or before the following February 1.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">During the period set in paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection, the parties shall negotiate in good faith.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Salaries and wages shall be uniform for all employees in the same classification.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commission and the employee organization shall share equally the costs of binding arbitration.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, pension and other retirement benefits for active employees may not be subject to binding arbitration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Collective bargaining regarding pension and other retirement benefits for active employees may not require the Commission to offer more than one pension plan to its employees.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If more than one employee organization is certified as an exclusive representative of a bargaining unit, the Commission shall engage in collective bargaining with all exclusive representatives at the same time about the terms of pension and other retirement benefits for active employees.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
