<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-23-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, this section does not apply to streets, roads, alleys, sidewalks, or public property in the jurisdiction of Montgomery County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall make taps in installations of the Commission at a charge that the Commission considers reasonable.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission may construct and make water service connections of 2 inches or larger and charge for the connections at the actual cost to the Commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission may authorize the construction of service connections by a master plumber, who is registered in the sanitary district, under the supervision of the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Commission, by resolution, authorizes service connections to be made by a master plumber, under regulations and after issuance of a written permit by the Commission, the master plumber may enter on and cut into a street under the jurisdiction of a public authority to the same extent that the Commission may enter on and cut into the street.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The master plumber shall first post with the Commission an indemnity bond in an amount set by and with sureties approved by the Commission.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The bond shall indemnify the Commission and any State, county, or municipal authority having jurisdiction over the street against all loss, cost, or damage that may be caused by the master plumber's entering on and cutting into the street.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The master plumber shall deposit with the Commission in cash a sum set by the Commission to cover the cost of resurfacing the cut.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The only permit required shall be a permit issued by the Commission in accordance with this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The master plumber shall notify the authority having control of the street to be entered and cut of the time and nature of the work to be done.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Before cutting into a street, road, alley, sidewalk, or public property under the jurisdiction of Montgomery County, a master plumber shall secure a permit from the county and pay a fee and comply with regulations established by the county.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commission shall adopt regulations to implement this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
