<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-28-201</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Commission police force.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A Commission police officer may exercise the powers of a law enforcement officer in the State on property that is owned, leased, or operated by or under the control of the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A Commission police officer may not exercise law enforcement powers on any other property unless the officer is:<section prefix="(i)">engaged in fresh pursuit of a suspected offender;</section><section prefix="(ii)">requested or authorized to do so in a political subdivision by the chief executive officer or chief police officer of the political subdivision;</section><section prefix="(iii)">needed for the orderly flow of traffic to and from property owned, leased, or operated by or under the control of the Commission; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">ordered to do so by the Governor.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After consulting with the Secretary of State Police and the Police Training Commission, the Commission shall adopt regulations to carry out this section, including standards for character, training, education, human relations, experience, and job performance for Commission police officers.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To the extent practicable, the Commission shall adopt standards that are similar to the standards of the Department of State Police.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Standards adopted on or after October 1, 2002, on minimum hiring qualifications of Commission police officers do not affect the status of an individual who was a qualified Commission special police officer on October 1, 2002.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
