<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-126" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-12-126</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An owner-member shall mark its underground facility if the owner-member has determined that a proposed excavation or demolition:<section prefix="(1)">is within 5 feet of the horizontal plane of the underground facility; or</section><section prefix="(2)">because of planned blasting, is so near to the underground facility that the underground facility may be damaged or disturbed.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An owner-member shall mark the location of its underground facility by marking on the ground within 18 inches on a horizontal plane on either side of the underground facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">When marking the location of an underground facility, an owner-member shall use the current color codes established by the American Public Works Association for marking underground facilities.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If two or more owner-members share the same color code, each owner-member shall include information with the marking that indicates the owner-member of the marked underground facility.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, within 2 business days after the day on which a ticket is transferred to an owner-member, the owner-member shall:<section prefix="(1)">mark the location of the owner-member's underground facility and report to the underground facilities information exchange system that the underground facility has been marked; or</section><section prefix="(2)">report to the underground facilities information exchange system that the owner-member has no underground facilities in the vicinity of the planned excavation or demolition.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an owner-member is unable to mark the location of the owner-member's underground facility within the time period prescribed in subsection (c) of this section because of the scope of the proposed excavation or demolition, the owner-member shall:<section prefix="(i)">promptly notify the underground facilities information exchange system and the person that intends to perform the excavation or demolition; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">work with the person that intends to perform the excavation or demolition to develop a mutually agreeable schedule for marking the underground facility.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the owner-member and person that intends to perform the excavation or demolition cannot reach a mutually agreeable schedule for marking under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the owner-member shall mark that portion of the site where excavation or demolition will first occur, and the owner-member shall mark the remainder of the site within a reasonable time.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If, due to circumstances beyond an owner-member's control and for reasons other than those specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection, an owner-member is unable to mark the location of the owner-member's underground facility within the time period prescribed in subsection (c) of this section, the owner-member shall report to the underground facilities information exchange system that an extension is required.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In connection with extensive or contiguous excavation or demolition projects, the person performing the excavation or demolition and the owner-member may establish a working agreement regarding the time periods for marking the underground facility.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
