<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-7-511</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except for electric cooperatives and municipal electric utilities:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>511</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except for electric cooperatives and municipal electric utilities:<section prefix="(1)">competitive billing shall begin on July 1, 2000;</section><section prefix="(2)">competitive metering for large customers shall begin on January 1, 2002; and</section><section prefix="(3)">competitive metering for all other customers shall begin on April 1, 2002, or earlier if requested by the electric company.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission shall adopt regulations or issue orders to implement this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person other than an electric company or a municipal electric utility may not engage in the business of competitive billing services in a local jurisdiction that assesses a local energy tax, unless the person holds a license issued by that jurisdiction.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An application for a local competitive billing services license shall be made in accordance with the requirements of the local jurisdiction.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A local jurisdiction may require an applicant or licensee to:<section prefix="1.">hold a license issued by the Commission, as provided under &#xA7; 7-507 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="2.">post a bond or other similar instrument in an amount equal to 15% of the bond required under &#xA7; 7-507 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="3.">have a resident agent in the State.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A local jurisdiction may not require an applicant or licensee to pay a fee or other charge for the local license.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A local jurisdiction may revoke or suspend the local license if the licensee fails, within 15 days of the due date established by the local jurisdiction, to pay or remit all of the applicable local energy taxes on services.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A local jurisdiction may reinstate the license after payment of all local energy taxes due.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A local jurisdiction may choose not to reinstate a license that has been revoked or suspended 3 times in a 12-month period.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A local jurisdiction shall report any revocation or suspension of a license to the Commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commission shall adopt regulations or issue an order to establish procedures for the assumption of billing responsibilities by the electric company that distributes electricity in the relevant service territory if a local license is revoked or suspended.</section>
  </text>
</law>
