<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-5-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to &#xA7; 6-101 of this article, without prior authorization of the Commission, a public service company may not purchase, acquire, take, or hold any part of the capital stock of another public service company that operates in Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to corporations that operate in Maryland.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraph (5) of this subsection, without prior authorization of the Commission, a public service company may not:<section prefix="(i)">assume or guarantee an obligation or liability with respect to stocks, bonds, securities, notes, or other evidence of indebtedness that is payable as a whole or in part to any person more than 12 months after the date of issuance; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">issue stocks, bonds, securities, notes, or other evidence of indebtedness payable as a whole or in part more than 12 months after the date of issuance.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Stocks, bonds, securities, notes, or other evidence of indebtedness described under paragraph (2)(ii) of this subsection shall be issued in accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 6-102 and 6-103 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Commission shall take action on an application for authorization under this section within a reasonable time after receipt.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Prior authorization of the Commission is not required for an assumption or guarantee under paragraph (2)(i) of this subsection or an issuance under paragraph (2)(ii) of this subsection made by a gas company, electric company, or telephone company whose gross annual revenues, for the most recent calendar year for which data are available, are less than 3% of the total gross annual revenues of all public service companies in the State during the same calendar year, if the gas company, electric company, or telephone company:<section prefix="(i)">provides prior written notice to the Commission of the transaction; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">obtains approval of the transaction from the entity in another state that regulates the gas company, electric company, or telephone company.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
