<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-12-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Authority" means the Maryland Underground Facilities Damage Prevention Authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Business day" means a calendar day other than a Saturday, Sunday, or legal holiday.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Demolition" means an operation in which a structure or mass of material is wrecked, razed, rended, moved, or removed using any tool, equipment, or explosive.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Designer" means a licensed architect, professional engineer, professional land surveyor, or licensed landscape architect, as those terms are defined in the Business Occupations and Professions Article, who prepares a drawing for a project that may require excavation or demolition.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Excavation" means an operation in which earth, rock, or other material in or on the ground is moved, removed, or otherwise displaced by using any tool, equipment, or explosive.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Excavation" includes grading, trenching, digging, ditching, dredging, drilling, boring, augering, tunnelling, scraping, cable or pipe plowing and driving a mass of material.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Fund" means the Maryland Underground Facilities Damage Prevention Education and Outreach Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Legal holiday" means:<section prefix="(1)">the day on which a legal holiday, as defined in Article 1, &#xA7; 27 of the Code, is observed; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a federal legal holiday.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"One-call system" means a communications system in the State that:<section prefix="(1)">allows a person to notify owner-members of planned excavation or demolition by:<section prefix="(i)">calling a toll-free number or abbreviated dialing code; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">initiating an interactive Internet ticket request; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">maintains an underground facilities information exchange system.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Owner" means a person that:<section prefix="(i)">owns or operates an underground facility; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">has the right to bury an underground facility.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Owner" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a public utility;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a telecommunications corporation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a cable television corporation;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a political subdivision;</section><section prefix="(v)">a municipal corporation;</section><section prefix="(vi)">a steam heating company;</section><section prefix="(vii)">an authority; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">a unit of the State.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Owner-member" means an owner that participates as a member in a one-call system.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Person" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 1-101 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Person" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a municipal corporation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a political subdivision of the State; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">any governmental unit, department, or agency.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Ticket" means a numbered document issued by a one-call system to notify owner-members that:<section prefix="(1)">a person intends to perform an excavation or demolition; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a designer has requested information on the location of underground facilities under &#xA7; 12-131 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Underground facilities information exchange system" means an automated voice response unit or interactive Internet access system that is maintained as part of a one-call system.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Underground facility" means personal property that is buried or submerged for:<section prefix="(i)">use in connection with the storage or conveyance of water, sewage, oil, gas, or other substances; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">transmission or conveyance of electronic, telephonic, or telegraphic communications or electricity.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Underground facility" includes pipes, sewers, conduits, cables, valves, lines, wires, manholes, attachments, and those portions of poles below ground.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Underground facility" does not include a stormwater drain.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
