<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-9-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a Maryland railroad company may locate, cons...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a Maryland railroad company may locate, construct, maintain, and operate a railroad in the State if the railroad is not more than 100 feet wide at the graded surface.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A railroad may be wider than 100 feet if the Maryland railroad company determines that it is necessary for:<section prefix="(i)">cuts and fills for a slope or embankment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">multiple sets of tracks; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">sidetracks, turnouts, depots, buildings, and other works connected with the operation of the railroad.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A Maryland railroad company may acquire land and other property that it determines is convenient or necessary for the site of the railroad or for additions to the railroad by:<section prefix="(i)">purchase, either in fee simple or any lesser estate, in accordance with law; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">condemnation under Title 5, Subtitle 4 of this article and Title 12 of the Real Property Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A Maryland railroad company may acquire by purchase or gift lands near the railroad that it determines are necessary to secure the right-of-way or aid in the construction of the railroad.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Land that a Maryland railroad company acquires may be held or conveyed as determined by the board of directors of the Maryland railroad company.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Deeds and conveyances made by a Maryland railroad company shall be signed by the president of the company under its corporate seal.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section does not authorize a Maryland railroad company to condemn, use, or occupy any part of a highway, including the space under or over a highway, without the consent of the proper authorities of the municipal corporation or county where the highway is located.</section>
  </text>
</law>
