<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="25-304" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-25-304</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may provide for the installation of the water or sewer connection as part of the construction of a water or sewer lateral line where the property to which the connection is made has not been assessed a front foot benefit charge under &#xA7; 25-203 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an installation is made under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Commission shall collect the deferred part of the connection charge by the benefit charge assessment procedure under &#xA7;&#xA7; 25-204(e) and 25-209 of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the water or sewer lateral line has been constructed or where the property for which an application for connection is made has been assessed a benefit charge under &#xA7; 25-204 of this title and the property is in an agricultural, small acreage, or residential class, the Commission may provide for an installment payment method for all or a part of the water and sewer connection charges for single family residential units with individual water or sewer connections.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an installment payment method is established and chosen by an applicant for connection:<section prefix="(i)">the installation of the connection is an additional benefit to the property; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the applicant is liable for payment for the additional benefit until the deferred charge has been amortized under the schedule that the Commission requires.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The connection charge benefit assessment is payable as provided in &#xA7;&#xA7; 25-204(e) and 25-209 of this title.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
