<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-29-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "enforcement official" means an employee of the Commission authorized by the Commission to issue a citation for a Commission infraction under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to the violations of the following:<section prefix="(1)">regulations governing sewer cleaning adopted under &#xA7; 24-201 of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">regulations governing plumbing adopted under &#xA7; 17-403, Title 24, Subtitle 1, &#xA7; 26-102, or &#xA7; 26-204 of this article;</section><section prefix="(3)">regulations governing erosion and sediment control for utility construction adopted under &#xA7; 17-403 of this article and &#xA7; 4-105 of the Environment Article;</section><section prefix="(4)">regulations governing gas fitting adopted under &#xA7; 17-404 of this article;</section><section prefix="(5)">regulations governing required permits for public utility construction adopted under &#xA7;&#xA7; 27-101, 27-107, and 27-108 of this article;</section><section prefix="(6)">regulations governing the Commission Pretreatment Program adopted under &#xA7; 17-403 of this article and &#xA7; 9-332 of the Environment Article; or</section><section prefix="(7)">any other regulation adopted in accordance with &#xA7; 17-406 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A person who violates any provision of a regulation listed in subsection (b) of this section has committed a Commission infraction and on delivery of a citation by the Commission under subsection (d)(1) of this section shall pay to the Commission a civil fine in the amount of:<section prefix="1.">for a first violation of the regulation, $250;</section><section prefix="2.">for a second violation of the regulation, $500;</section><section prefix="3.">for a third violation of the regulation, $750; and</section><section prefix="4.">for a fourth or subsequent violation, $1,000.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Each day that a violation of the regulation remains uncorrected is a separate Commission infraction subject to an additional citation and fine in the amount of $250.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The payment due date for the fine may not be less than 10 or more than 20 calendar days after the date of delivery of the citation.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The recipient of the citation may pay the fine before the payment due date specified in the citation.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After verifying a Commission infraction the enforcement official shall deliver the citation to any person charged with committing the Commission infraction in accordance with the enforcement procedures of the regulations.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The citation shall be on a form adopted by the Commission and shall include:<section prefix="(i)">the date of delivery of the citation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the name and address of the person charged;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the specific provision of the regulations that has been violated;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the nature of the Commission infraction;</section><section prefix="(v)">the location and time that the Commission infraction occurred;</section><section prefix="(vi)">the amount of the civil fine assessed for the Commission infraction;</section><section prefix="(vii)">the manner, location, and time in which the fine may be paid to the Commission;</section><section prefix="(viii)">a statement that each day that a violation continues is a separate Commission infraction subject to additional citation;</section><section prefix="(ix)">the name, business address, title, and telephone number of the enforcement official who issued the citation; and</section><section prefix="(x)">notice of the person's right to a trial for the Commission infraction and instructions and time limits for that election.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who receives a citation for a Commission infraction under this section may elect to stand trial by filing with the Commission a notice of the person's intent to stand trial.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice of intent to stand trial shall be given at least 5 days before the payment due date specified in the citation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On receipt of the notice of intent to stand trial, the Commission shall forward to the District Court having venue a copy of the citation and a copy of the notice of intent to stand trial that was filed by the person who received the citation.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On receipt of the citation and the notice of intent to stand trial, the District Court shall schedule the case for trial and notify the defendant and Commission of the trial date.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The District Court shall remit to the Commission all fines, penalties, or forfeitures the Court collects for Commission infractions.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a person who receives a citation for a Commission infraction fails to pay the fine by the payment due date specified in the citation and fails to file a notice of the person's intent to stand trial for the offense:<section prefix="(i)">the person is liable for the assessed fine; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Commission shall send a notice of the Commission infraction to the person's last known address.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the fine is not paid within 35 days after the date of the notice, the Commission may request adjudication of the case through the District Court, which may include the filing of a demand for judgment on affidavit.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">On receipt of the request for adjudication, the District Court shall schedule the case for trial and summon the defendant to appear.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the defendant fails to respond to the summons and the Commission has made a proper demand for judgment on affidavit, the District Court shall enter judgment against the defendant in favor of the Commission in the amount then due.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For the purpose of this section, a Commission infraction is a civil offense.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The adjudication of a Commission infraction:<section prefix="(i)">is not a criminal conviction; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">does not impose any of the civil disabilities ordinarily imposed by a criminal conviction.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">In a proceeding for a Commission infraction before the District Court, the violation shall be prosecuted in the same manner and to the same extent provided for municipal infractions under Article 23A, &#xA7; 3(b)(7), (10), and (12) through (15) of the Code.</section>
  </text>
</law>
