<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-18-126</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person may not impersonate another in an examination held under this subtitle....</catch_line>
  <order_by>126</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not impersonate another in an examination held under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not willfully or corruptly falsify a score or report on an examination held under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person, acting alone or in cooperation with another, may not:<section prefix="(i)">willfully or corruptly deceive an individual about the right to take an examination held under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">willfully or corruptly interfere with the right of an individual to take an examination held under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(iii)">falsify, or assist another to falsify, a score, grade, estimate, or report on the examination or standing of an individual examined under this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">give to an individual any special information in order to improve or harm the individual's rating for appointment or employment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1)(iv) of this subsection, a person may answer any inquiry from the Secretary.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A candidate for employment may not deceive the Commission or the Secretary in order to improve the candidate's chances for appointment.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A candidate for appointment to a merit system position may not sign a resignation from that position in advance of the appointment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A resignation signed in violation of paragraph (1) of this subsection is void and of no effect.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
