<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-7-214</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>214</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Contact voltage" means a voltage condition that may result in an object or surface being inadvertently energized.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Contact voltage risk zone" or "CVRZ" means the portions of each electric company's service territory that:<section prefix="(i)">are served by underground electric distribution plant; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">have substantial pedestrian traffic or population density, whether permanent, seasonal, or varying by time of day.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Contact voltage survey" means a survey performed by an electric company to detect contact voltage consistent with the electric company's voltage survey plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Electric distribution plant" means all electric company plant used to distribute electricity to its customers.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Electric distribution plant" includes covers and protective structures.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Electric distribution plant" does not include customer meters and meter enclosures.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Voltage survey plan" means a plan, submitted by an electric company and approved by the Commission, that governs the electric company's contact voltage detection and testing equipment and voltage detection and testing procedures to be used when conducting contact voltage surveys.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before September 1, 2012, each electric company shall file with the Commission for approval:<section prefix="(i)">a list and location map for all CVRZs within its service territory, if applicable; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if no CVRZs are designated in its service territory, a voltage survey plan.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 30 days after the Commission approves a CVRZ within an electric company's service territory, the electric company shall file its voltage survey plan for Commission approval.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On Commission approval of its voltage survey plan, each electric company shall conduct:<section prefix="(i)">an initial contact voltage survey of each CVRZ within 1 year after the Commission approves an electric company's voltage survey plan; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">subsequent surveys of each CVRZ as set forth in its voltage survey plan.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Each electric company shall conduct an initial and each subsequent contact voltage survey within each CVRZ of all objects and surfaces that are:<section prefix="(i)">publicly accessible;</section><section prefix="(ii)">capable of conducting electricity; and</section><section prefix="(iii)"><section prefix="1.">electric distribution plant;</section><section prefix="2.">streetlights owned or maintained by the electric company;</section><section prefix="3.">streetlights and traffic signals owned by a municipal corporation or other unit of government, with the consent of the appropriate authority; and</section><section prefix="4.">public parks and playgrounds, with the consent of the appropriate authority.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">For areas in each electric company's service territory not located in a CVRZ, except for wooden poles, the electric company shall conduct a contact voltage survey on all publicly accessible electric distribution plant and publicly accessible streetlights that the electric company owns or maintains that are capable of conducting electricity:<section prefix="1.">within 3 years after the initial approval of the voltage survey plan; and</section><section prefix="2.">subsequently as set forth in its voltage survey plan.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An electric company shall test each streetlight for contact voltage after dark or when the light is illuminated.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">At least 60 days before implementing a material change to a voltage survey plan, an electric company shall file an amended voltage survey plan for Commission approval.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The Commission may modify the frequency or scope of any contact voltage survey requirement on a showing of good cause.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each electric company shall include in its voltage survey plan all equipment used for detecting contact voltage.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The type of each equipment must be certified by an independent test laboratory as being able to reliably detect voltages of 6 to 600 volts.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Each electric company shall include the certification when filing the voltage survey plan.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each electric company shall confirm and document all contact voltage detected in its contact voltage survey using a voltmeter and a 500 ohm shunt resistor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Until a potential contact voltage condition can be confirmed under paragraph (1) of this subsection, each electric company shall make an area safe after detecting a potential contact voltage condition during its contact voltage survey.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If an electric company detects a contact voltage measurement under paragraph (1) of this subsection that is at least 1 volt of alternating current, the electric company shall:<section prefix="(i)">perform a contact voltage survey on all objects and surfaces that are capable of conducting electricity and are publicly accessible within at least 30 feet of the location of the measured contact voltage;</section><section prefix="(ii)">when electric distribution plant or a street light that the electric company owns or maintains is indicating contact voltage:<section prefix="1.">immediately and continuously make the area safe; and</section><section prefix="2.">use best efforts to make a permanent repair to mitigate the contact voltage as soon as possible, but not later than 45 days, unless extraordinary circumstances exist and the area continues to be made safe through a temporary measure to mitigate the contact voltage;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">when property that is not owned by the electric company is indicating contact voltage, immediately use best efforts to:<section prefix="1.">make the area safe; and</section><section prefix="2.">notify the customer or responsible person associated with the premises or customer-owned facility of the unsafe condition and the need for the customer to make a permanent repair to mitigate contact voltage; and</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">maintain written records of its actions to make the area safe and mitigate the contact voltage.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before April 1 of each year, each electric company shall file a compliance report with the Commission:<section prefix="(i)">describing the results of its contact voltage surveys; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">summarizing each known contact voltage electric shock and each contact voltage electric shock complaint received from a member of the public, whether the shock affected an individual or an animal.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall approve the form of the report.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commission may impose a civil penalty under this division for a violation of this subsection.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Commission may, in its discretion, through order or regulation:<section prefix="(1)">waive or modify any provision of this section; or</section><section prefix="(2)">impose additional requirements as circumstances require.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
