<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-4-208</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>208</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to a public service company that:<section prefix="(1)">provides gas or electric services;</section><section prefix="(2)">is subject to a cost allocation manual approved by the Commission;</section><section prefix="(3)"><section prefix="(i)">engages in an unregulated business activity; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">has a subsidiary that engages in an unregulated business activity; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">does not meet the standards for rate proceedings provided for under &#xA7; 4-207 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A public service company subject to this section shall file an independent audit opinion prepared by an entity approved by the Commission on the earliest of:<section prefix="(i)">once every 2 years; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">when the public service company:<section prefix="1.">files a request for a change in its base rate under this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="2.">has a major change in its corporate organization or structure as determined by the Commission.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The independent auditor shall:<section prefix="(i)">examine:<section prefix="1.">compliance by the public service company with policies and procedures of the public service company's cost allocation manual;</section><section prefix="2.">proper allocation of costs to an affiliate of the public service company in accordance with the manual; and</section><section prefix="3.">appropriate charging of costs and transactions relative to the manual to the public service company and its affiliates; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">identify adjustments that should be made:<section prefix="1.">to the manual consistent with prior Commission rulings; and</section><section prefix="2.">to the public service company or to an affiliate of the public service company relative to the examination of the allocation of costs and charging of costs and transactions.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The cost of the independent audit opinion filed under subsection (b) of this section shall be borne by the stockholders of the public service company.</section>
  </text>
</law>
