<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-7-207.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies to a person who:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>207.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to a person who:<section prefix="(1)">constructs a generating station:<section prefix="(i)">designed to provide on-site generated electricity if:<section prefix="1.">the capacity of the generating station does not exceed 70 megawatts; and</section><section prefix="2.">the electricity that may be exported for sale from the generating station to the electric system is sold only on the wholesale market pursuant to an interconnection, operation, and maintenance agreement with the local electric company; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">that produces electricity from wind if:<section prefix="1.">the generating station is land-based;</section><section prefix="2.">the capacity of the generating station does not exceed 70 megawatts;</section><section prefix="3.">the electricity that may be exported for sale from the generating station to the electric system is sold only on the wholesale market pursuant to an interconnection, operation, and maintenance agreement with the local electric company;</section><section prefix="4.">the Commission provides an opportunity for public comment at a public hearing as provided in subsection (e) of this section; and</section><section prefix="5.">the generating station's wind turbines are not located within a distance from the Patuxent River Naval Air Station that is determined by regulations adopted by the Commission in coordination with the Commander, Naval Air Warfare Center Aircraft Division, provided that the distance requirement under the regulation is:</section></section></section><section prefix="(2)">constructs a generating station if:<section prefix="(i)">the capacity of the generating station does not exceed 25 megawatts;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the electricity that may be exported for sale from the generating station to the electric system is sold only on the wholesale market pursuant to an interconnection, operation, and maintenance agreement with the local electric company; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">at least 10% of the electricity generated at the generating station each year is consumed on-site.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall require a person that is exempted from the requirement to obtain a certificate of public convenience and necessity to obtain approval from the Commission under this section before the person may construct a generating station described in subsection (a) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An application for approval under this section shall:<section prefix="(i)">be made to the Commission in writing on a form adopted by the Commission;</section><section prefix="(ii)">be verified by oath or affirmation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">contain information that the Commission requires, including:<section prefix="1.">proof of compliance with all applicable requirements of the independent system operator; and</section><section prefix="2.">a copy of an interconnection, operation, and maintenance agreement between the generating station and the local electric company.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">When reviewing an application for approval under this section, the Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">ensure the safety and reliability of the electric system;</section><section prefix="(2)">require the person constructing the generating station to notify the Commission 2 weeks before the first export of electricity from a generating station approved under this section; and</section><section prefix="(3)">conduct its review and approval in an expeditious manner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commission may waive an element of the approval process under this section if the Commission determines that the waiver is in the public interest.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall provide an opportunity for  public comment and hold a public hearing as provided under this subsection on an application for approval made under subsection (a)(1)(ii) of this section in each county and municipal corporation in which any portion of the construction of a generating station is proposed to be located.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Upon the request of the governing body of a county or municipal corporation in which any portion of the construction of a generating station is proposed to be located, the Commission shall hold the public hearing jointly with the governing body.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Once in each of 2 successive weeks immediately before the hearing date, the Commission, at the expense of the applicant, shall provide weekly notice of the public hearing and opportunity for public comment by advertisement in a newspaper of general circulation in the county or municipal corporation affected by the application.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
