<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-2-108</section_number>
  <catch_line>The principal office of the Commission shall be in Baltimore City at the place that the Commission s...</catch_line>
  <order_by>108</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The principal office of the Commission shall be in Baltimore City at the place that the Commission selects.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except for legal holidays, the offices of the Commission shall be open for business during regular business hours from Monday through Friday and at other times as the Commission considers necessary.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission shall meet at the times and places in the State as the Commission considers necessary.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission shall have a seal.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State budget shall provide sufficient money for the Commission to hire, develop, and organize a staff to perform the functions of the Commission, including analyzing data submitted to the Commission and participating in proceedings as provided in &#xA7; 3-104 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">As the Commission considers necessary, the Commission shall hire experts including economists, cost of capital experts, rate design experts, accountants, engineers, transportation specialists, and lawyers.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">To assist in the regulation of intrastate hazardous liquid pipelines under Title 11, Subtitle 2 of this article, the Commission shall include on its staff at least one engineer who specializes in the storage of and the transportation of hazardous liquid materials by pipeline.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission may retain on a case by case basis additional experts as required for a particular matter.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The lawyers who represent the Commission staff in proceedings before the Commission shall be appointed by the Commission and shall be organized and operate independently of the office of General Counsel.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">As required, the Commission shall hire hearing examiners.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Hearing examiners are a separate organizational unit and shall report directly to the Commission.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Commission shall hire personal staff members for each commissioner as required to provide advice, draft proposed orders and rulings, and perform other personal staff functions.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Subject to &#xA7; 3-104 of this article, the Commission may delegate to a commissioner or personnel the authority to perform an administrative function necessary to carry out a duty of the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph or otherwise by law, all personnel of the Commission are subject to the provisions of the State Personnel and Pensions Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The following are in the executive service, management service, or are special appointments in the State Personnel Management System:<section prefix="1.">each commissioner of the Commission;</section><section prefix="2.">the Executive Director;</section><section prefix="3.">the General Counsel and each assistant general counsel;</section><section prefix="4.">the Executive Secretary;</section><section prefix="5.">the commissioners' personal staff members;</section><section prefix="6.">the chief hearing examiner; and</section><section prefix="7.">each license hearing officer.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The compensation of the following personnel shall be determined by the Commission and, if possible, in accordance with the State pay plan:<section prefix="(1)">the Executive Director;</section><section prefix="(2)">the General Counsel;</section><section prefix="(3)">the special appointment attorneys in the office of General Counsel;</section><section prefix="(4)">the Executive Secretary;</section><section prefix="(5)">the chief hearing examiner;</section><section prefix="(6)">each license hearing officer; and</section><section prefix="(7)">all Commission personnel in positions in:<section prefix="(i)">the management service; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">professional and technical classifications unique to the Commission.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 45 days before the effective date of the change, the Commission shall submit to the Secretary of Budget and Management each change to salary plans that involves increases or decreases in salary ranges other than those associated with routine reclassifications and promotions or general salary increases approved by the General Assembly.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Reportable changes include creation or abolition of classes, regrading the classes from one established range to another, changes in salary guidelines to administer the pay schedules, or creation of new pay schedules or ranges.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary of Budget and Management shall:<section prefix="(i)">review the proposed changes; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">at least 15 days before the effective date of the proposed changes, advise the Commission whether the changes would have an adverse effect on comparable State jobs.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Failure of the Secretary to respond in a timely manner is not considered a statement of adverse effect.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">On or before January 31 of each year, the Commission shall report to the Secretary of Budget and Management and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly setting forth all personnel positions, classifications, and salaries in the Commission as of the end of the preceding calendar year.</section>
  </text>
</law>
