<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="18-201" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-18-201</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Confidential employee" means an employee who assists or acts in a confidential capacity with respect to an individual who formulates, determines, or implements management policies in the field of labor-management relations.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Probationary employee" means a Commission merit system employee during the employee's initial probationary period after hiring.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The rights granted to Commission merit system employees under this subtitle do not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">attorneys in the Office of the General Counsel;</section><section prefix="(ii)">confidential employees;</section><section prefix="(iii)">probationary employees;</section><section prefix="(iv)">employees in the Office of the General Manager;</section><section prefix="(v)">employees in the Internal Audit Office;</section><section prefix="(vi)">employees in the Office of the Secretary; or</section><section prefix="(vii)">supervisors, as defined in &#xA7; 2(11) of the National Labor Relations Act, 29 U.S.C. &#xA7; 152(11).</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Commission employees are divided into four bargaining units consisting of:<section prefix="(i)">an office/technical unit that includes:</section><section prefix="(ii)">a professional unit that includes professional classification titles in which employees have special or theoretical knowledge that is usually acquired through college training or other training that provides comparable knowledge or work experience;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a service, labor, and trade unit that includes:</section><section prefix="(iv)">a law enforcement unit that includes Commission police officers.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a single employee organization is certified to represent more than one bargaining unit, the Commission shall negotiate a single contract with that organization covering all employees the organization represents.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
