<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-17-105</section_number>
  <catch_line>From among its members, the Commission shall elect a chair and a vice chair....</catch_line>
  <order_by>105</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">From among its members, the Commission shall elect a chair and a vice chair.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The election of the chair and vice chair shall be at the first meeting of the Commission in June of each year, or as soon after the meeting as possible.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the chair and vice chair:<section prefix="(i)">one shall be from Montgomery County and the other shall be from Prince George's County; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">each office shall alternate annually between Montgomery County and Prince George's County.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">By unanimous vote the Commission may waive the provisions of paragraph (2)(ii) of this subsection for 1 year.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Commission may not waive the provisions of paragraph (2)(ii) of this subsection for 2 successive years.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Each officer shall serve for 1 year or until a successor is elected.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each officer shall perform the duties designated by the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a vacancy exists in the position of chair or vice chair, the Commission promptly shall elect a new chair or vice chair for the remaining portion of the 1-year term of office.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, if the vacancy in the position of chair or vice chair results from resignation or removal from the Commission, the election to fill the unexpired portion of the officer's term shall be held only after the Commission vacancy has been filled.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Commission may elect an acting chair or vice chair to serve until the vacancy has been filled.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
