<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-207" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-7-207</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this section and &#xA7; 7-208 of this subtitle, "construction" means:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Construction" does not include a change that is needed for the temporary use of a site or route for nonutility purposes or for use in securing geological data, including any boring that is necessary to ascertain foundation conditions.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In this section, "qualified generator lead line" means an overhead transmission line that is designed to carry a voltage in excess of 69,000 volts and would allow an out-of-state Tier 1 or Tier 2 renewable source to interconnect with a portion of the electric system in Maryland that is owned by an electric company.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Unless a certificate of public convenience and necessity for the construction is first obtained from the Commission, a person may not begin construction in the State of:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a person obtains Commission approval for construction under &#xA7; 7-207.1 of this subtitle, the Commission shall exempt a person from the requirement to obtain a certificate of public convenience and necessity under this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Notwithstanding subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, a person may not apply to obtain a certificate of public convenience and necessity for construction of a qualified generator lead line unless:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless a certificate of public convenience and necessity for the construction is first obtained from the Commission, and the Commission has found that the capacity is necessary to ensure a sufficient supply of electricity to customers in the State, a person may not exercise a right of condemnation in connection with the construction of a generating station.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, unless a certificate of public convenience and necessity for the construction is first obtained from the Commission, an electric company may not begin construction of an overhead transmission line that is designed to carry a voltage in excess of 69,000 volts or exercise a right of condemnation with the construction.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For construction related to an existing overhead transmission line, the Commission may waive the requirement in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph for good cause.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, for construction related to an existing overhead transmission line designed to carry a voltage in excess of 69,000 volts, the Commission shall waive the requirement to obtain a certificate of public convenience and necessity if the Commission finds that the construction does not:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On receipt of an application for a certificate of public convenience and necessity under this section, the Commission shall provide notice to the Department of Planning and to all other interested persons.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department of Planning shall forward the application to each appropriate State unit and unit of local government for review, evaluation, and comment regarding the significance of the proposal to State, area-wide, and local plans or programs.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall provide an opportunity for public comment and hold a public hearing on the application for a certificate of public convenience and necessity in each county and municipal corporation in which any portion of the construction of a generating station, an overhead transmission line designed to carry a voltage in excess of 69,000 volts, or a qualified generator lead line is proposed to be located.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall hold the public hearing jointly with the governing body of the county or municipal corporation in which any portion of the construction of the generating station, overhead transmission line, or qualified generator lead line is proposed to be located, unless the governing body declines to participate in the hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Once in each of the 4 successive weeks immediately before the hearing date, the Commission shall provide weekly notice of the public hearing and an opportunity for public comment by advertisement in a newspaper of general circulation in the county or municipal corporation affected by the application.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Commission shall ensure presentation and recommendations from each interested State unit, and shall allow representatives of each State unit to sit during hearing of all parties.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Commission shall allow each State unit 15 days after the conclusion of the hearing to modify the State unit's initial recommendations.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commission shall take final action on an application for a certificate of public convenience and necessity only after due consideration of:<section prefix="(1)">the recommendation of the governing body of each county or municipal corporation in which any portion of the construction of the generating station, overhead transmission line, or qualified generator lead line is proposed to be located; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the effect of the generating station, overhead transmission line, or qualified generator lead line on:<section prefix="(i)">the stability and reliability of the electric system;</section><section prefix="(ii)">economics;</section><section prefix="(iii)">esthetics;</section><section prefix="(iv)">historic sites;</section><section prefix="(v)">aviation safety as determined by the Maryland Aviation Administration and the administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration;</section><section prefix="(vi)">when applicable, air and water pollution; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">the availability of means for the required timely disposal of wastes produced by any generating station.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">For the construction of an overhead transmission line, in addition to the considerations listed in subsection (e) of this section, the Commission shall take final action on an application for a certificate of public convenience and necessity only after due consideration of the need to meet existing and future demand for electric service.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may not authorize, and an electric company may not undertake, the construction of an overhead transmission line that is aligned with and within 1 mile of either end of a public airport runway, unless:<section prefix="(i)">the Federal Aviation Administration determines that the construction of an overhead transmission line will not constitute a hazard to air navigation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Maryland Aviation Administration concurs in that determination.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A privately owned airport runway shall qualify as a public airport runway under this subsection only if the runway has been on file with the Federal Aviation Administration for at least 2 years as being open to the public without restriction.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
