<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-7-705</section_number>
  <catch_line>Each electricity supplier shall submit a report to the Commission each year in a form and by a date ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>705</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each electricity supplier shall submit a report to the Commission each year in a form and by a date specified by the Commission that:<section prefix="(1)">demonstrates that the electricity supplier has complied with the applicable renewable energy portfolio standard under &#xA7; 7-703 of this subtitle and includes the submission of the required amount of renewable energy credits; or</section><section prefix="(2)">demonstrates the amount of electricity sales by which the electricity supplier failed to meet the applicable renewable energy portfolio standard.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If an electricity supplier fails to comply with the renewable energy portfolio standard for the applicable year, the electricity supplier shall pay into the Maryland Strategic Energy Investment Fund established under &#xA7; 9-20B-05 of the State Government Article:<section prefix="(1)">except as provided in item (2) of this subsection, a compliance fee of:<section prefix="(i)">4 cents for each kilowatt-hour of shortfall from required Tier 1 renewable sources other than the shortfall from the required Tier 1 renewable sources that is to be derived from solar energy;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the following amounts for each kilowatt-hour of shortfall from required Tier 1 renewable sources that is to be derived from solar energy:<section prefix="1.">45 cents in 2008;</section><section prefix="2.">40 cents in 2009 through 2014;</section><section prefix="3.">35 cents in 2015 and 2016;</section><section prefix="4.">20 cents in 2017 and 2018;</section><section prefix="5.">15 cents in 2019 and 2020;</section><section prefix="6.">10 cents in 2021 and 2022; and</section><section prefix="7.">5 cents in 2023 and later; and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">1.5 cents for each kilowatt-hour of shortfall from required Tier 2 renewable sources; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">for industrial process load:<section prefix="(i)">for each kilowatt-hour of shortfall from required Tier 1 renewable sources, a compliance fee of:<section prefix="1.">0.8 cents in 2006, 2007, and 2008;</section><section prefix="2.">0.5 cents in 2009 and 2010;</section><section prefix="3.">0.4 cents in 2011 and 2012;</section><section prefix="4.">0.3 cents in 2013 and 2014;</section><section prefix="5.">0.25 cents in 2015 and 2016; and</section><section prefix="6.">0.2 cents in 2017 and later; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">nothing for any shortfall from required Tier 2 renewable sources.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission may allow an electricity supplier to submit the report required under &#xA7; 7-505(b)(4) of this title to demonstrate compliance with the renewable energy portfolio standard.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An aggregator or broker who assists an electricity customer in purchasing electricity but who does not supply the electricity or take title to or ownership of the electricity may require the electricity supplier who supplies the electricity to demonstrate compliance with this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding the requirements of &#xA7; 7-703(b) of this subtitle, if the actual or projected dollar-for-dollar cost incurred or to be incurred by an electricity supplier solely for the purchase of Tier 1 renewable energy credits derived from solar energy in any 1 year is greater than or equal to, or is anticipated to be greater than or  equal to, 1% of the electricity supplier's total annual  electricity sales revenues in Maryland, the electricity supplier  may request that the Commission:<section prefix="(i)">delay by 1 year each of the scheduled  percentages for solar energy under &#xA7; 7-703(b) of this subtitle that would apply to  the electricity supplier; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">allow the renewable energy portfolio  standard for solar energy for that year to continue to apply to the  electricity supplier for the following year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In making its determination under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Commission shall consider the actual or  projected dollar-for-dollar compliance costs of other electricity suppliers.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If an electricity supplier makes a request under  paragraph (1) of this subsection based on projected costs, the  electricity supplier shall provide verifiable evidence of the  projections to the Commission at the time of the request.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the Commission allows a delay under paragraph  (1) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">the renewable energy portfolio standard for solar energy applicable to the electricity supplier under the delay continues for each subsequent consecutive year that the actual or projected dollar-for-dollar costs incurred, or to be incurred, by the electricity supplier solely for the purchase of solar renewable energy credits is greater than or equal to, or is anticipated to be greater than or equal to, 1% of the electricity supplier's total annual retail electricity sales revenues in Maryland; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the renewable energy portfolio standard for solar energy applicable to the electricity supplier under the delay is increased to the next scheduled percentage increase under &#xA7; 7-703(b) of this subtitle for each year in which the actual or projected dollar-for-dollar costs incurred, or to be incurred, by the electricity supplier solely for the purchase of solar renewable energy credits is less than, or is anticipated to be less than, 1% of the electricity supplier's total annual retail electricity sales revenues in Maryland.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
