<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-7-211</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>211</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Affiliate" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 7-501 of this title.	</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Demand response program" means a program established by an electric company that promotes changes in electric usage by customers from their normal consumption patterns in response to:<section prefix="(i)">changes in the price of electricity over time; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">incentives designed to induce lower electricity use at times of high wholesale market prices or when system reliability is jeopardized.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Electricity consumption" and "electricity consumed" mean the sum of retail electricity sales to all customers and reported electricity losses within the electric distribution system.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Peak demand" means the highest level of electricity demand in the State measured in megawatts during the period from May 1 to September 30 on a weather-normalized basis.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Per capita electricity consumption" means the result calculated by dividing the total gigawatt-hours of electricity consumed by electricity customers in the State as of December 31 of a year, as determined by the Commission, by the population of the State as of December 31 of that year, as determined by the Department of Planning.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Plan" means an electricity savings and demand reduction plan and cost recovery proposal.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Provide heating, ventilation, air conditioning, or refrigeration services" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 9A-101 of the Business Regulation Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The General Assembly finds and declares that:<section prefix="(1)">energy efficiency is among the least expensive ways to meet the growing electricity demands of the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">to provide affordable, reliable, and clean energy for consumers of Maryland, it is the goal of the State to achieve the following energy efficiency, conservation, and demand response targets, based on 2007 electricity consumption:<section prefix="(i)">a 15% reduction in per capita electricity consumption by the end of 2015; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a 15% reduction in per capita peak demand by the end of 2015.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Beginning with the 2008 calendar year and each year thereafter, the Commission shall calculate:<section prefix="(1)">the per capita electricity consumption for that year; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the peak demand for that year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Subject to review and approval by the Commission, each gas company and electric company shall develop and implement programs and services to encourage and promote the efficient use and conservation of energy by consumers, gas companies, and electric companies.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">As directed by the Commission, each municipal electric utility and each electric cooperative that serves a population of less than 250,000 in its distribution territory shall include energy efficiency and conservation programs or services as part of their service to their customers.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">require each gas company and electric company to establish any program or service that the Commission deems appropriate and cost effective to encourage and promote the efficient use and conservation of energy;</section><section prefix="(2)">adopt rate-making policies that provide cost recovery and, in appropriate circumstances, reasonable financial incentives for gas companies and electric companies to establish programs and services that encourage and promote the efficient use and conservation of energy; and</section><section prefix="(3)">ensure that adoption of electric customer choice under Subtitle 5 of this title does not adversely impact the continuation of cost-effective energy efficiency and conservation programs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, on or before December 31, 2008, by regulation or order, the Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">to the extent that the Commission determines that cost-effective energy efficiency and conservation programs and services are available, for each affected class, require each electric company to procure or provide for its electricity customers cost-effective energy efficiency and conservation programs and services with projected and verifiable electricity savings that are designed to achieve a targeted reduction of at least 5% by the end of 2011 and 10% by the end of 2015 of per capita electricity consumed in the electric company's service territory during 2007; and</section><section prefix="(2)">require each electric company to implement a cost-effective demand response program in the electric company's service territory that is designed to achieve a targeted reduction of at least 5% by the end of 2011, 10% by the end of 2013, and 15% by the end of 2015, in per capita peak demand of electricity consumed in the electric company's service territory during 2007.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">On or before July 1, 2008, and every 3 years thereafter, each electric company shall consult with the Maryland Energy Administration regarding the design and adequacy of the electric company's plan to achieve the electricity savings and demand reduction targets specified in subsection (g) of this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An electric company shall provide the Maryland Energy Administration with any additional information regarding the plan, as requested.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On or before September 1, 2008, and every 3 years thereafter, an electric company shall submit its plan to the Commission that details the electric company's proposals for achieving the electricity savings and demand reduction targets specified in subsection (g) of this section for the 3 subsequent calendar years.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission shall consider any written findings provided by the Maryland Energy Administration regarding the design and adequacy of the plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Each electric company shall provide annual updates to the Commission and the Maryland Energy Administration on plan implementation and progress towards achieving the electricity savings and demand reduction targets specified in subsection (g) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The plan shall include a description of the proposed energy efficiency and conservation programs and services and the proposed demand response program, anticipated costs, projected electricity savings, and any other information requested by the Commission.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The plan shall address residential, commercial, and industrial sectors as appropriate, including low-income communities and low- to moderate-income communities.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">
          <section prefix="1.">If, in connection with a program or service, the electric company proposes to provide heating, ventilation, air conditioning, or refrigeration services for its customers, the plan shall include procedures for the competitive selection of heating, ventilation, air conditioning, or refrigeration service providers.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">On request by the electric company and for good cause shown, the Commission may waive the requirement that the electric company competitively select heating, ventilation, air conditioning, or refrigeration providers under subsubparagraph 1 of this subparagraph.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The plan and any updates shall include a certification or recertification by the electric company that, if an affiliate of the electric company provides heating, ventilation, air conditioning, or refrigeration services through any existing contract or obligation in connection with a program or service, the customers of the electric company's regulated services will not subsidize the operations of the affiliate.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The Commission shall review each electric company's plan to determine if the plan is adequate and cost-effective in achieving the electricity savings and demand reduction targets specified in subsection (g) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In determining whether a program or service encourages and promotes the efficient use and conservation of energy, the Commission shall consider the:<section prefix="(i)">cost-effectiveness;</section><section prefix="(ii)">impact on rates of each ratepayer class;</section><section prefix="(iii)">impact on jobs; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">impact on the environment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall monitor and analyze the impact of each program and service to ensure that the outcome of each program and service provides the best possible results.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In monitoring and analyzing the impact of a program or service under paragraph (2) of this subsection, if the Commission finds that the outcome of the program or services may not be providing the best possible results, the Commission shall direct the electric company to include in its annual update under subsection (h)(4) of this section specific measures to address the findings.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An electric company that enters into a contract or obligation with an affiliate of the electric company to provide heating, ventilation, air conditioning, or refrigeration services in connection with a program or service shall notify the Commission within 30 days after entering into the contract or obligation that the electric company:<section prefix="(i)">has entered into a contract or obligation with an affiliate of the electric company; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">certifies that the customers of the electric company's regulated services will not subsidize the operations of the affiliate.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least once each year, each electric company and gas company shall notify affected customers of the energy efficiency and conservation charges imposed and benefits conferred.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice shall be provided by publication on the company's website and inclusion with billing information such as a bill insert or bill message.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">On or before March 1 of each year, the Commission, in consultation with the Maryland Energy Administration, shall report, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly on:<section prefix="(1)">the status of programs and services to encourage and promote the efficient use and conservation of energy, including an evaluation of the impact of the programs and services that are directed to low-income communities, low- to moderate-income communities to the extent possible, and other particular classes of ratepayers;</section><section prefix="(2)">a recommendation for the appropriate funding level to adequately fund these programs and services; and</section><section prefix="(3)">in accordance with subsection (c) of this section, the per capita electricity consumption and the peak demand for the previous calendar year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">Notwithstanding any other law, the Commission may not require or allow an electric company to require an electric customer to authorize the electric company to control the amount of the electric customer's electricity usage, including through control of the electric customer's thermostat.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before June 30, 2013, by regulation or order, the Commission shall establish a pilot program for electric customers to recharge electric vehicles during off-peak hours.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An electric company may request to participate in the pilot program.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Commission shall make every effort to include at least two electric companies in the pilot program.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The pilot program shall include incentives for residential, commercial, and governmental customers to recharge electric vehicles in a manner that will:<section prefix="(i)">increase the efficiency and reliability of the electric distribution system; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">lower electricity use at times of high demand.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Incentives may include:<section prefix="(i)">time-of-day pricing of electricity;</section><section prefix="(ii)">credits on distribution charges;</section><section prefix="(iii)">rebates on the cost of charging systems;</section><section prefix="(iv)">demand response programs; or</section><section prefix="(v)">other incentives approved by the Commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">On or before February 1, 2015, the Commission shall report to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly on the experience of the pilot program and the Commission's findings.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
