<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-7-507</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person, other than an electric company providing standard offer service under &#xA7; 7-510(c) of this ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>507</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person, other than an electric company providing standard offer service under &#xA7; 7-510(c) of this subtitle or a municipal electric utility serving customers solely in its distribution territory, may not engage in the business of an electricity supplier in the State unless the person holds a license issued by the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An application for an electricity supplier license shall:<section prefix="(1)">be made to the Commission in writing on a form adopted by the Commission;</section><section prefix="(2)">be verified by oath or affirmation; and</section><section prefix="(3)">contain information that the Commission requires, including:<section prefix="(i)">proof of technical and managerial competence;</section><section prefix="(ii)">proof of compliance with all applicable requirements of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, and any independent system operator or regional or system transmission operator to be used by the licensee;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a certification of compliance with applicable federal and State environmental laws and regulations that relate to the generation of electricity; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">payment of the applicable licensing fee.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission shall, by regulation or order:<section prefix="(1)">require proof of financial integrity;</section><section prefix="(2)">require a licensee to post a bond or other similar instrument, if, in the Commission's judgment, the bond or similar instrument is necessary to insure an electricity supplier's financial integrity;</section><section prefix="(3)">require a licensee to:<section prefix="(i)">provide proof that it is qualified to do business in the State with the Department of Assessments and Taxation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">agree to be subject to all applicable taxes; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">adopt any other requirements it finds to be in the public interest, which may include different requirements for:<section prefix="(i)">electricity suppliers that serve only large customers; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the different categories of electricity suppliers.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A license issued under this section may not be transferred without prior Commission approval.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commission shall adopt regulations or issue orders to:<section prefix="(1)">protect consumers, electric companies, and electricity suppliers from anticompetitive and abusive practices;</section><section prefix="(2)">require each electricity supplier to provide, in addition to the requirements under &#xA7; 7-505(b)(5) of this subtitle, adequate and accurate customer information to enable customers to make informed choices regarding the purchase of any electricity services offered by the electricity supplier;</section><section prefix="(3)">establish reasonable restrictions on telemarketing;</section><section prefix="(4)">establish procedures for contracting with customers;</section><section prefix="(5)">establish requirements and limitations relating to deposits, billing, collections, and contract cancellations;</section><section prefix="(6)">establish provisions providing for the referral of a delinquent account by an electricity supplier to the standard offer service under &#xA7; 7-510(c) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(7)">establish procedures for dispute resolution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In accordance with regulations or orders of the Commission, electricity bills, for competitive and regulated electric services, provided to consumers may provide, in addition to the requirements of &#xA7; 7-505(b)(5) of this subtitle and subsection (e)(2) of this section, the following information:<section prefix="(1)">the identity and phone number of the electricity supplier of the service;</section><section prefix="(2)">sufficient information to evaluate prices and services; and</section><section prefix="(3)">information identifying whether the price is regulated or competitive.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An electricity supplier or any person or governmental unit may not, without first obtaining the customer's permission:<section prefix="(i)">make any change in the electricity supplier for a customer; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">add a new charge for a new or existing service or option.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall adopt regulations or issue orders establishing procedures to prevent the practices prohibited under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An electricity supplier may not discriminate against any customer based wholly or partly on race, color, creed, national origin, or sex of an applicant for service or for any arbitrary, capricious, or unfairly discriminatory reason.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An electricity supplier may not refuse to provide service to a customer except by the application of standards that are reasonably related to the electricity supplier's economic and business purposes.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">An electricity supplier shall be subject to all applicable federal and State environmental laws and regulations.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">An electricity supplier shall post on the Internet information that is readily understandable about its services and rates for small commercial and residential electric customers.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may revoke or suspend the license of an electricity supplier, impose a civil penalty or other remedy, order a refund or credit to a customer, or impose a moratorium on adding or soliciting additional customers by the electricity supplier, for just cause on the Commission's own investigation or on complaint of the Office of People's Counsel, the Attorney General, or an affected party.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A civil penalty may be imposed in addition to the Commission's decision to revoke, suspend, or impose a moratorium.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Just cause includes:<section prefix="(i)">intentionally providing false information to the Commission;</section><section prefix="(ii)">switching, or causing to be switched, the electricity supply for a customer without first obtaining the customer's permission;</section><section prefix="(iii)">failing to provide electricity for its customers;</section><section prefix="(iv)">committing fraud or engaging in deceptive practices;</section><section prefix="(v)">failing to maintain financial integrity;</section><section prefix="(vi)">violating a Commission regulation or order;</section><section prefix="(vii)">failing to pay, collect, remit, or calculate accurately applicable State or local taxes;</section><section prefix="(viii)">violating a provision of this article or any other applicable consumer protection law of the State;</section><section prefix="(ix)">conviction of a felony by the licensee or principal of the licensee or any crime involving fraud, theft, or deceit; and</section><section prefix="(x)">suspension or revocation of a license by any State or federal authority.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An electricity supplier or person selling or offering to sell electricity in the State in violation of this section, after notice and an opportunity for a hearing, is subject to:<section prefix="(i)">a civil penalty of not more than $10,000 for the violation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">license revocation or suspension.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each day a violation continues is a separate violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission shall determine the amount of any civil penalty after considering:<section prefix="(i)">the number of previous violations of any provision of this division;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the gravity of the current violation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the good faith of the electricity supplier or person charged in attempting to achieve compliance after notification of the violation.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">In connection with a consumer complaint or Commission investigation under this section, an electricity supplier shall provide to the Commission access to any accounts, books, papers, and documents which the Commission considers necessary to resolve the matter at issue.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">The Commission may order the electricity supplier to cease adding or soliciting additional customers or to cease serving customers in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">The Commission shall consult with the Consumer Protection Division of the Office of the Attorney General before issuing regulations designed to protect consumers.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">The People's Counsel shall have the same authority in licensing, complaint, and dispute resolution proceedings as it has in Title 2 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">Nothing in this subtitle may be construed to affect the authority of the Division of Consumer Protection in the Office of the Attorney General to enforce violations of Titles 13 and 14 of the Commercial Law Article or any other applicable State law or regulation in connection with the activities of electricity suppliers.</section>
  </text>
</law>
