<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="20-206" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-20-206</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Office shall verify that a certified minority business enterprise listed in a schedule of participation is actually performing work and receiving compensation as established in the schedule.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To facilitate the Office completing its duties under subsection (a) of this section, a contractor shall:<section prefix="(1)">allow the Office to inspect any relevant matter, including records and the job site;</section><section prefix="(2)">allow the Office to interview subcontractors and employees of the contractor;</section><section prefix="(3)">if performing a construction contract, ensure that subcontractors:<section prefix="(i)">are paid any undisputed amount to which the subcontractor is entitled as provided under &#xA7; 15-226 of the State Finance and Procurement Article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">comply with Commission regulations;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">include in the agreement with the certified minority business enterprise subcontractor a requirement that the subcontractor submit a monthly report to the Commission that:<section prefix="(i)">identifies the prime contract; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">lists payments received from the contractor in the previous month and invoices sent to the contractor that have not been paid; and</section></section><section prefix="(5)">submit a monthly report to the Commission that lists:<section prefix="(i)">unpaid invoices that are more than 30 days old received from certified minority business enterprise subcontractors; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the reason payments have not been made.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">On completion of a contract or before final payment or release of retainage, the Commission may require a general contractor on a contract having a minority business enterprise subcontracting goal to submit to the Commission a final report of all payments made to or withheld from minority business enterprise subcontractors.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The final report shall be in affidavit form and under the penalties for perjury.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each solicitation shall contain notice of the requirements of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On a finding that a contractor is noncompliant, the Commission shall notify the contractor in writing of the findings and state the required corrective action.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A noncompliant contractor shall:<section prefix="(i)">initiate the corrective action within 10 days after receiving the written notice; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">complete the corrective action within the time specified by the Commission.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the Commission finds that a general contractor is in material noncompliance with minority business enterprise contract provisions and the general contractor fails to take the corrective action required by the Commission, the Commission may:<section prefix="(1)">terminate the contract;</section><section prefix="(2)">refer the general contractor to the general manager of the Commission or the full Commission for appropriate action; or</section><section prefix="(3)">initiate any other specific remedy identified in the contract.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
