<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-3-110</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person shall:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>110</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person shall:<section prefix="(1)">attend a proceeding before the Commission, if ordered by the Commission, a commissioner, or the Executive Secretary of the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(2)">give any relevant testimony or produce any relevant evidence, if ordered by the Commission, a commissioner, or an authorized hearing examiner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a person refuses without valid cause to comply with an order issued under subsection (a) of this section, on affidavit that sets forth the violation to a court of general jurisdiction, the Commission or a commissioner may apply for an order to show cause why the person should not be held in contempt.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An order issued under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be returned to the court that issued the order, not less than 2 days and not more than 5 days after the date of issue.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On the return of an order issued under this subsection, if the court determines that the person has violated subsection (a) of this section and persists in the violation, the court may hold the person in contempt.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not refuse to comply with subsection (a)(2) of this section on the ground that giving testimony or producing evidence may tend to incriminate or subject the person to penalty or forfeiture.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except for perjury committed by an individual giving evidence before the Commission, an individual may not be prosecuted, punished, or subjected to penalty or forfeiture for producing any evidence required under subsection (a) of this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
