<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-7-206</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies to the installation of pollution control equipment or a change in the method of...</catch_line>
  <order_by>206</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to the installation of pollution control equipment or a change in the method of operation at a generating station that a person performs in order to comply with Phase II pollution control requirements of the federal Clean Air Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Any person that performs an installation or change in operation under subsection (a) of this section shall obtain prior review and approval of the Commission in accordance with:<section prefix="(1)">&#xA7;&#xA7; 7-203, 7-207, and 7-208 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the procedures set forth in &#xA7; 7-205 of this subtitle and &#xA7; 2-405 of the Environment Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In order to meet compliance dates established under Title 2, Subtitle 10 of the Environment Article or the federal Clean Air Act, a Commission review and approval, or processing of an application for a certificate of public convenience and necessity under &#xA7; 7-207 of this subtitle, shall be expedited and take precedence over other review and approval by the Commission if the review and approval or certificate of public convenience and necessity is required:<section prefix="(1)">for pollution control equipment or a change in the method of operation at a generating station; and</section><section prefix="(2)">for compliance with:<section prefix="(i)">Title 2, Subtitle 10 of the Environment Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">regulations adopted by the Department of the Environment under Title 2, Subtitle 10 of the Environment Article; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the federal Clean Air Act.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
