<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="29-107" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-29-107</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person who violates any of the following provisions is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 30 days or a fine not exceeding $1,000 or both:<section prefix="(1)">&#xA7; 17-403 of this article (Commission regulations, except for those specified in subsection (c) of this section and &#xA7;&#xA7; 29-101(b) and 29-102(a) of this title);</section><section prefix="(2)">Title 22, Subtitle 1 of this article (general obligation bonds and notes);</section><section prefix="(3)">&#xA7; 23-102(a) of this article (construction of private or municipal systems);</section><section prefix="(4)">&#xA7; 23-202 of this article (service connections);</section><section prefix="(5)">&#xA7; 26-103 of this article (tampering with Commission system in Anne Arundel County);</section><section prefix="(6)">&#xA7; 26-205 of this article (tampering with Commission system in Howard County);</section><section prefix="(7)">&#xA7;&#xA7; 27-101(c) and  27-108 of this article (public utilities construction);</section><section prefix="(8)">&#xA7; 29-105 of this title (unlawful use of Commission property, except for the regulations governing publicly owned watershed property); or</section><section prefix="(9)">&#xA7; 29-106 of this title (leaving dead animals or fecal matter unburied).</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person who violates the provisions of Title 20, Subtitle 2 of this article as they relate to the minority business enterprise utilization program by committing a prohibited act listed under &#xA7; 14-308 of the State Finance and Procurement Article, on conviction, is subject to the penalties provided under that section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person who violates emergency water use restrictions adopted in accordance with &#xA7; 17-403 of this article is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $500.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person who violates Title 18, Subtitle 1 of this article (Personnel Management) is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $500.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person who violates &#xA7; 19-102(b) of this article (ethics) is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 1 year or a fine not exceeding $1,000 or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person may be convicted of a second or subsequent violation of a provision of this Division II or a regulation adopted under this Division II.</section>
  </text>
</law>
