<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-18-212</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>212</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may not:<section prefix="(i)">interfere with, coerce, or restrain an employee in the exercise of rights under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">dominate, interfere with, or assist in the formation, administration, or existence of any employee organization or contribute financial assistance or other support to an employee organization;</section><section prefix="(iii)">encourage or discourage membership in any employee organization by discriminating against an employee through hiring, tenure, promotion, or other conditions of employment;</section><section prefix="(iv)">discharge or discriminate against an employee because the employee has signed or filed an affidavit, petition, or complaint or given any information or testimony under this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(v)">refuse to bargain in good faith with an employee organization that is certified as the exclusive representative of a bargaining unit over any subject of bargaining or refuse to participate in good faith in binding arbitration or grievance procedures under this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection does not prohibit the Commission from allowing employees to negotiate or to confer with the Commission over labor matters during work hours without the loss of pay or time.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission may not contract out work that will displace employees in a bargaining unit unless the Commission gives written notice to the certified representative of the bargaining unit at least 90 days before signing the contract or within a different period of time as agreed by the parties.</section>
  </text>
</law>
