<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-9-304</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A Maryland railroad company may cross or divert an unnavigable stream whenever it is necessary to construct a railroad.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A Maryland railroad company that diverts a stream is liable for damage caused by the diversion.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A Maryland railroad company may cross a canal or a navigable stream if the company:<section prefix="(1)">submits to the Board of Public Works a plan for the canal or stream crossing that includes the location and building plans of the bridge and other necessary fixtures; and</section><section prefix="(2)">receives written approval from the Board of Public Works.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Board of Public Works disapproves a plan submitted by a Maryland railroad company or fails to approve the plan within 20 days after filing, the Maryland railroad company may apply to the circuit court of the county where the canal or stream crossing is planned or to another court of competent jurisdiction.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court shall:<section prefix="(i)">provide reasonable notice to the Board of Public Works;</section><section prefix="(ii)">for good cause shown, appoint a disinterested and competent engineer, who does not reside in a county through which the Maryland railroad company's railroad passes and who, within 20 days of being appointed:<section prefix="1.">shall examine the canal or stream crossing; and</section><section prefix="2.">shall establish a plan and any conditions necessary to cross the canal or stream in a way that will not impede navigation; and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">examine the engineer's plan and conditions for the canal or stream crossing, and unless good cause is shown, approve the plan and conditions.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An order by the court approving the plan and conditions for the canal or stream crossing shall be sufficient authority for the Maryland railroad company to elect, use, and occupy the bridge.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
