<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-17-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The County Executive shall make an appointment from a list of applicants.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The list shall be:<section prefix="(i)">completed at least 3 weeks before the date the appointment is made; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">open to the public for inspection from the time the list is prepared until the appointment is made.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If an individual is not appointed from the names on the list, the County Executive shall prepare additional lists and follow the procedure under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The 3-week period before the date the appointment is made begins with the closing of each list.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the County Executive or a designee of the County Executive may interview in private each applicant for appointment or reappointment to the Commission regarding possible or potential conflicts of interest.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before appointment, the County Executive or a designee of the County Executive shall interview in private an applicant who is selected for appointment to the Commission regarding possible or potential conflicts of interest.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Before appointment, the County Executive of Prince George's County or a designee of the County Executive shall inform the Prince George's County Council of possible or potential conflicts of interest of an applicant who is selected for appointment to the Commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A written transcript of an interview under subsection (b) of this section:<section prefix="(i)">shall be made;</section><section prefix="(ii)">may be reviewed by the applicant, unless the right to review is waived by the applicant;</section><section prefix="(iii)">may be altered for the applicant by the transcribing officer, if the transcript is accompanied by a statement of the reason given by the applicant for the alteration; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">shall be signed by the applicant.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The transcribing officer shall certify on the transcript that:<section prefix="(i)">the applicant was sworn by the officer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the transcript is a true record of the testimony given by the applicant.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The County Executive of Montgomery County or a designee of the County Executive shall:<section prefix="(i)">publicly disclose the complete transcribed testimony of an appointee to the Commission 3 weeks after the appointment; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">destroy immediately the complete transcript of any other applicant without disclosure of any information contained in the transcript.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Montgomery County, if the County Executive or a designee of the County Executive conducts an interview under subsection (b) of this section, the applicant shall be interviewed:<section prefix="(i)">in a question and answer fashion;</section><section prefix="(ii)">under oath; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">about all sources of income, property holdings, business interests, and financial interests of the applicant and the applicant's spouse, father, mother, brother, sister, and child.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The County Executive of Montgomery County or a designee of the County Executive may require the applicant to produce documents.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
