<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="25-209" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-25-209</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A water or sewer connection benefit charge imposed by the Commission under this section is in addition to a benefit charge imposed under any other section of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">When a benefit charge or portion of a benefit charge for a water main or sewer connection is made payable on an installment basis as provided in &#xA7; 25-304(b) of this title, the deferred amount and interest shall be paid by an annual benefit charge in an amount and for the period of years necessary to amortize the account.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Property subject to a benefit charge imposed under this section is subject to the benefit charge until payments have amortized the charge, including accrued interest.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall allow a property owner subject to a benefit charge for the deferred portion of a connection benefit charge to extinguish the account by paying the principal and interest due up to the time of payment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a federal, State, county, or other governmental unit or municipality acquires property for public use that is subject to a benefit charge under this section, the benefit charge shall be paid and extinguished as provided in &#xA7; 25-212 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A benefit charge imposed under this section shall be collected as provided in &#xA7; 25-214 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">To implement this section, the Commission may:<section prefix="(1)">include in the sale of bonds the cost of making service connections that are paid on an installment basis; and</section><section prefix="(2)">use any funds obtained from the sale.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
