<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-18-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>The labor relations administrator shall conduct an election for an exclusive representative after:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The labor relations administrator shall conduct an election for an exclusive representative after:<section prefix="(1)">an employee organization demonstrates, by petition, that at least 30% of the eligible employees in a bargaining unit support representation by an exclusive representative for collective bargaining; or</section><section prefix="(2)">an employee or an employee organization demonstrates, by petition, that at least 30% of the eligible employees in a bargaining unit no longer support the current exclusive representative.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 45 days before an election, the labor relations administrator shall provide, and the Commission shall post in conspicuous places in the Commission's facilities, a notice of the upcoming election.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice shall contain:<section prefix="(i)">the date, time, and place of the election;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a description of which employees are eligible to vote in the election;</section><section prefix="(iii)">	notification that a list of the names and home addresses of employees eligible to vote will be provided to the participating employee organizations;</section><section prefix="(iv)">instructions on how employees can remove their addresses from the list in accordance with subsection (c)(2) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(v)">any other information that, in the judgment of the labor relations administrator, is appropriate to convey to Commission employees.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 45 days before an election, the labor relations administrator shall obtain from the Commission the eligible employee voting list, which includes the names and home addresses of every employee in the bargaining unit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Commission employees may have their addresses removed from the eligible employee voting list by individually notifying the labor relations administrator in writing within 15 days after the posting of the notice required in subsection (b) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">After the 15-day period, the labor relations administrator shall provide the redacted eligible employee voting list to the employee organization.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The provision of the eligible employee voting list under this subsection by the Commission, the labor relations administrator, or a Commission official, employee, or other agent does not constitute a violation of &#xA7; 10-617(e) of the State Government Article or any State or local law, regulation, or ordinance.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Elections shall be conducted by secret ballot containing:<section prefix="(1)">the name of each employee organization that submits a valid petition requiring an election;</section><section prefix="(2)">the name of any other employee organization supported by a petition signed by at least 10% of the eligible employees in the bargaining unit; and</section><section prefix="(3)">an option for no representation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If none of the choices on the ballot receives a majority of the votes cast, the labor relations administrator shall hold a runoff election.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the runoff election, the ballot shall contain the two choices that received the highest number of votes in the initial election.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">After the election, the labor relations administrator shall certify an employee organization that received a majority of the votes cast as the exclusive representative.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Commission and the employee organization or organizations shall share equally the costs of the election.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Elections may not be conducted:<section prefix="(i)">within 1 year after the date of a valid initial election under this section; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, during the term of a collective bargaining agreement.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">During the term of a collective bargaining agreement, a petition for an election may be filed only during November of the fiscal year in which the agreement expires.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
