<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-7-528</section_number>
  <catch_line>A qualified rate order shall become effective in accordance with its terms....</catch_line>
  <order_by>528</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A qualified rate order shall become effective in accordance with its terms.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">After a qualified rate order becomes effective, the qualified rate order and the qualified rate stabilization charges authorized in the qualified rate order are irrevocable and are not subject to reduction, impairment, or adjustment by further action of the Commission except in accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 7-531, 7-533, and 7-534 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A qualified rate order is not subject to rehearing by the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A qualified rate order may be reviewed by appeal only to the Circuit Court of Baltimore City by a party to the proceeding filed within 15 days after the qualified rate order is signed by the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The judgment of the circuit court may be reviewed only by direct appeal to the Court of Appeals of Maryland filed within 15 days after entry of judgment.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">All appeals shall be heard and determined by the circuit court and by the Court of Appeals of Maryland as expeditiously as possible with lawful precedence over other matters.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Review on appeal shall be based solely on the record before the Commission and briefs to the courts and shall be limited to whether the qualified rate order conforms to the Constitution and laws of this State and the United States and is within the authority of the Commission under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The review process in this subsection shall be the exclusive remedy to challenge or review a qualified rate order.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
