<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-7-709</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>709</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An electricity supplier may use accumulated renewable energy credits to meet the renewable energy portfolio standard, including credits created by a renewable on-site generator.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A renewable energy credit may be sold or otherwise transferred.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If an electricity supplier purchases solar renewable energy credits directly from a renewable on-site generator with a capacity that exceeds 10 kilowatts to meet the solar component of the Tier 1 renewable energy portfolio standard, the duration of the contract term for the solar renewable energy credits may not be less than 15 years.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The minimum required term under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph does not affect the ability of the parties to negotiate a price for a solar renewable energy credit that varies over time in any manner.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An electricity supplier that purchases solar renewable energy credits from a renewable on-site generator with a capacity not exceeding 10 kilowatts shall purchase the credits with a single initial payment representing the full estimated production of the system for the life of the contract.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">	The Commission shall:<section prefix="1.">develop a method for estimating annual production from the type of system described in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph and allocating the credits to the electricity supplier in a manner that is consistent with the duration of the contract; and</section><section prefix="2.">determine the rate for a payment made to a renewable on-site generator under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as authorized under paragraph (2) of this subsection, a renewable energy credit shall exist for 3 years from the date created.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A renewable energy credit may be diminished or extinguished before the expiration of 3 years by:<section prefix="(i)">the electricity supplier that received the credit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a nonaffiliated entity of the electricity supplier:<section prefix="1.">that purchased the credit from the electricity supplier receiving the credit; or</section><section prefix="2.">to whom the electricity supplier otherwise transferred the credit; or</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">demonstrated noncompliance by the generating facility with the requirements of &#xA7; 7-704(f) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Notwithstanding subsection (d)(2)(iii) of this section, and only if the demonstrated noncompliance does not result in environmental degradation, an electricity supplier that reasonably includes in its annual report under &#xA7; 7-705 of this subtitle a renewable energy credit that is extinguished for noncompliance with &#xA7; 7-704(f)(1) or (2) of this subtitle:<section prefix="(1)">may continue to rely on that credit for that year; but</section><section prefix="(2)">for later years must:<section prefix="(i)">demonstrate a return to compliance of the generating facility under &#xA7; 7-704(f) of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">replace the credit with a renewable energy credit from another source.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commission by regulation shall establish requirements for documentation and verification of renewable energy credits by licensed electricity suppliers and other generators that create and receive credits for compliance with the standards for Tier 1 renewable sources and Tier 2 renewable sources.</section>
  </text>
</law>
