<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-27-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Homeowner corporation" means a homeowner association with 5,000 or more members that has:<section prefix="(i)">filed a written request with the Commission to receive the information required by this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">provided the Commission with a map of the homeowner corporation's geographic boundaries.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"System repair" means work to install, maintain, or operate the Commission system that involves cutting into a public roadway, sidewalk, or other improvement on public property of a county or municipality located in the sanitary district.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before September 1 of each year, the Commission shall submit to each county, municipality, and homeowner corporation located in the sanitary district a plan of system repairs scheduled for the next 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall submit the plan of scheduled system repairs to the person designated by the county, municipality, or homeowner corporation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For each scheduled system repair, the plan shall include:<section prefix="(1)">the anticipated system repair date and time;</section><section prefix="(2)">the system repair location; and</section><section prefix="(3)">an analysis of the impact that the system repair will have on the affected counties, municipalities, and homeowner corporations.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Before submitting the plan of system repairs, the Commission shall consult with the affected counties, municipalities, and homeowner corporations located in the sanitary district.</section>
  </text>
</law>
