<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-22-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>The bonds shall be:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The bonds shall be:<section prefix="(i)">issued under the hand and seal of the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">guaranteed as to payment of principal and interest by Montgomery County and Prince George's County.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each bond shall contain the following statement:</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The bonds of the sanitary district shall be signed:<section prefix="(i)">by the chair, secretary, and treasurer of the Commission; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if authorized by the Commission, by any two commissioners.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The official seal of the Commission shall be impressed on a bond of the sanitary district.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For bonds issued for the purposes described under &#xA7; 22-102(a)(1) and (2) of this subtitle, the Commission may authorize:<section prefix="(i)">any of its officials to sign a bond by facsimile signature; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a facsimile of the official seal to be printed on the bond.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">For bonds issued for the purposes described under &#xA7; 22-102(a)(3) of this subtitle, the Commission may authorize:<section prefix="(i)">any of its officials to sign a bond by facsimile signature, provided that the bond is manually signed by at least one official; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a facsimile of the official seal to be printed on the bond.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Within 20 days after the bonds are presented by the Commission for signing, the guaranty or endorsement by Montgomery County and Prince George's County shall be signed on each of the bonds on behalf of each county by the county executives of Montgomery County and Prince George's County, or by the county executive's designee, by facsimile or manual signature as the county executive determines.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The liability under the guarantee for each county is in the same proportion that the assessable base of that part of that county within the sanitary district bears to the assessable base of the sanitary district.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may waive the guarantee required under subsection (d) of this section, if the Commission determines that:<section prefix="(i)">the waiver would not seriously affect the sale of the bonds of the sanitary district; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">money market conditions justify the sale of the bonds of the sanitary district without the guarantee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The waiver of the guarantee under paragraph (1) of this subsection on one issue of bonds may not be construed to be a waiver of the guarantee of future bond issues.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
