<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-5-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies to a domestic or foreign corporation that is or may become engaged in the busin...</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to a domestic or foreign corporation that is or may become engaged in the business of transmitting or supplying natural gas, artificial gas, or a mixture of natural and artificial gases.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to subsection (c) of this section, a corporation described in subsection (a) of this section may acquire by condemnation, in accordance with Title 12 of the Real Property Article, rights-of-way or easements necessary to lay, construct, modify, repair, maintain, operate, and remove pipelines and appurtenances to pipelines for transmitting and supplying gas.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a corporation may not condemn rights-of-way or easements under subsection (b) of this section unless the corporation:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">transmits gas directly to local consumers in the State along the corporation's proposed rights-of-way; and</section><section prefix="2.">offers to contract with those local consumers to supply them directly with gas on terms and conditions subject to the approval of the Commission; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">has certified to the State Department of Assessments and Taxation the name and address of a resident agent of the corporation in the State, service of process on whom shall bind the corporation until the appointment of a substitute is certified to the State Department of Assessments and Taxation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Paragraph (1) of this subsection does not affect the right of a corporation that was transmitting natural gas, artificial gas, or a mixture of natural and artificial gases for public use through one or more pipelines in the State on or before June 1, 1931, to condemn for public use necessary rights-of-way or easements for:<section prefix="(i)">a pipeline or appurtenances to a pipeline in use on or before June 1, 1931;</section><section prefix="(ii)">any incidental relocations of a pipeline or appurtenances to a pipeline in use on or before June 1, 1931; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">any additional pipelines or appurtenances to pipelines along and on the same routes or along and on any incidental relocations of a pipeline or appurtenances to a pipeline in use on or before June 1, 1931.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section does not affect the application of any provision of this article that applies generally or specifically to a corporation that is or may become engaged in the business of transmitting or supplying natural gas, artificial gas, or a mixture of natural and artificial gases.</section>
  </text>
</law>
