<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-7-208</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies to any person:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>208</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to any person:<section prefix="(1)">constructing a generating station and its associated overhead transmission lines designed to carry a voltage in excess of 69,000 volts; or</section><section prefix="(2)">exercising the right of condemnation in connection with the construction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To obtain the certificate of public convenience and necessity required under &#xA7; 7-207 of this subtitle for construction under this section, a person shall file an application with the Commission at least 2 years before construction of the facility will commence.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission may waive the 2-year requirement on a showing of good cause.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">include in an application under this section the information that the Commission requests initially; and</section><section prefix="(2)">furnish any additional information that the Commission requests subsequently.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On the receipt of an application under this section, together with any additional information requested under subsection (c)(2) of this section, the Commission shall provide notice to:<section prefix="(i)">all interested persons;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Department of Agriculture;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Department of Business and Economic Development;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Department of the Environment;</section><section prefix="(v)">the Department of Natural Resources;</section><section prefix="(vi)">the Department of Transportation; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">the Department of Planning.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall hold a public hearing on the application as required by &#xA7; 7-207 of this subtitle, after:<section prefix="(i)">the receipt of any additional information requested under subsection (c)(2) of this section that the Commission considers necessary; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any publication of notice the Commission considers to be proper.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">At the public hearing, the Commission shall ensure presentation of the information and recommendations of the State units specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection and shall allow the official representative of each unit to sit during hearing of all parties.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Based on the evidence relating to the unit's areas of concern, the Commission shall allow each unit 15 days after the conclusion of the hearing to modify or affirm the unit's initial recommendations.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Within 90 days after the conclusion of the hearing on an application under this section, the Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">grant a certificate of public convenience and necessity unconditionally;</section><section prefix="(ii)">grant the certificate, subject to conditions the Commission determines to be appropriate; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">deny the certificate; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">notify all interested parties of its decision.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall include in each certificate it issues under subsection (e) of this section:<section prefix="(i)">the requirements of the federal and State environmental laws and standards that are identified by the Department of the Environment; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the methods and conditions that the Commission determines are appropriate to comply with those environmental laws and standards.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission may not adopt any method or condition under paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection that the Department of the Environment determines is inconsistent with federal and State environmental laws and standards.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A decision of the Commission regarding the issuance of a certificate requires the vote of a majority of the members of the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a majority of the members of the Commission fails to reach agreement on the conditions to be attached to a conditional certificate, the certificate shall be denied.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The grant of a certificate by the Commission to any person under subsection (e) of this section constitutes:<section prefix="(1)">authority for the person to dredge and construct bulkheads in the waters or private wetlands of the State and to appropriate or use the waters; and</section><section prefix="(2)">registration and a permit to construct, as required under Title 2, Subtitle 4 of the Environment Article.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
