<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-135" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-12-135</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person that performs an excavation or demolition without first providing the notice required under &#xA7; 12-124(a) of this subtitle and damages, dislocates, or disturbs an underground facility is deemed negligent and is subject to a civil penalty assessed by the Authority not exceeding:<section prefix="(i)">$2,000 for the first offense; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">subject to subsection (c) of this section, $4,000 for each subsequent offense.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Instead of or in addition to a civil penalty assessed under this subsection, the Authority may:<section prefix="(i)">require that a person:</section><section prefix="(ii)">impose other similar measures.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A person that violates any provision of Part IV of this subtitle is subject to a civil penalty assessed by the Authority not exceeding $2,000.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies if a proceeding has not been initiated before the Authority.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A court of competent jurisdiction may assess a civil penalty of up to 10 times the cost of repairs to the underground facility caused by the damage, dislocation, or disturbance against a person that has committed a subsequent offense under subsection (a)(1) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An action to recover a civil penalty under this subsection shall be brought by an owner of a damaged, dislocated, or disturbed underground facility or the Attorney General in a court of competent jurisdiction in Baltimore City or the county in which the damage, dislocation, or disturbance occurred.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The party bringing an action under this subsection may recover reasonable attorney's fees.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Authority may not assess a civil penalty under subsection (a)(1)(ii) of this section if an action to recover a civil penalty has been brought under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">All civil penalties recovered under this section shall be paid into the Fund.</section>
  </text>
</law>
