<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-304.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-7-304.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "master meter" means a meter used to measure, for billing purposes, the total amount of electricity or natural gas used in a building by a heating, ventilation, and air conditioning system, including the combined use from all individually leased or owned units and all common areas.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission may authorize the use of a master meter in a residential multiple occupancy building for heating, ventilation, and air conditioning services without requiring individual metering or submetering for heating, ventilation, and air conditioning services as provided under &#xA7; 7-303 or &#xA7; 7-304 of this subtitle if:<section prefix="(1)">the utility bill for heating, ventilation, and air conditioning services for each individually leased or owned occupancy unit is included in the rent for that unit;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Commission is satisfied that the use of the master meter for heating, ventilation, and air conditioning services will result in a net savings of energy over the energy savings that would result from individual metering or submetering for heating, ventilation, and air conditioning services; and</section><section prefix="(3)">each individually leased or owned occupancy unit:<section prefix="(i)">has individual metered service for other energy services; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">directly receives the utility bill for the other energy services.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before authorizing the use of a master meter for heating, ventilation, and air conditioning services, the Commission may review the proposed allocation of heating, ventilation, and air conditioning system expenses among individual units and common areas served by the master meter.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In accordance with &#xA7; 7-301 of this subtitle, an electric company or a gas company may inspect and test a master meter authorized for use by the Commission under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
