<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-2-117</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>117</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Commission believes that a public service company or gas master meter operator that is subject to the Commission's jurisdiction is violating or will violate this division, the Commission shall bring an action in the Commission's name for injunction or other appropriate action in the circuit court of a county where the public service company or gas master meter operator does business or has its principal place of business.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court:<section prefix="(i)">shall allow a period not exceeding 20 days for the defendant to show cause why the relief sought should not be granted;</section><section prefix="(ii)">after the period, shall inquire immediately into the merits of the case, without other or formal pleadings and without respect to any technical requirement;</section><section prefix="(iii)">may join as parties any persons as is necessary or proper to make a judgment or process effective; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">shall issue a final order that grants appropriate relief.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall notify an offender to appear and answer charges on complaint filed by a carrier or on discovery of a violation or infringement by the Commission's own investigation that:<section prefix="(i)">the offender is or has been infringing on or violating a permit granted to the carrier by the Commission;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the offender, without a permit, is exercising or using a right granted in a permit;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a right granted in a permit is being subjected to unrestricted or unregulated competition; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">the offender, without a permit, is serving, wholly or partly, directly or indirectly, a route set forth in a granted permit.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice shall be sent to or served on the offender as provided by &#xA7; 3-103 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the Commission finds that the offender is violating or infringing, or has violated or infringed on the rights of a carrier, the Commission shall order the offender to stop the operations that led to the violation or infringement.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the offender does not obey the order of the Commission, the Commission shall notify the offender to show cause within 10 days after the notice is mailed or served why the registration certificate for each vehicle involved in the operations should not be suspended or revoked.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If cause is not shown or if, after hearing, the Commission finds that cause is not shown, the Commission shall certify to the Motor Vehicle Administration:<section prefix="(i)">that the registration certificate of each vehicle involved in the operations shall be suspended or revoked;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the condition of the suspension or revocation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">if possible, the license number of each vehicle for which the certificate of registration is to be suspended or revoked.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">On receipt of the certification, the Motor Vehicle Administration automatically shall suspend or revoke each certificate of registration in accordance with the conditions contained in the certification.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The action of the Motor Vehicle Administration may not be appealed but judicial review of an order or certification of the Commission may be sought as provided in Title 3, Subtitle 2 of this article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
