<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-18-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>After a public hearing, the Commission shall appoint an experienced neutral third party to serve as ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">After a public hearing, the Commission shall appoint an experienced neutral third party to serve as labor relations administrator for 1 year.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After the term for the labor relations administrator appointed under subsection (a) of this section expires, the exclusive representative or representatives and the Commission shall jointly appoint a labor relations administrator from a list of five nominees on whom they have agreed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the exclusive representative or representatives and the Commission are unable to jointly agree on a list of five nominees or are unable to jointly appoint a labor relations administrator from the list, the Commission shall request from the American Arbitration Association a list of 15 candidates located in the State or the Washington, D.C. metropolitan area.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission and the exclusive representative or representatives shall select the labor relations administrator by each of the parties striking one name from the list until the last name remains.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A random drawing shall determine the order in which the parties shall strike names.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The labor relations administrator shall be appointed for a term of 3 years.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">After the term for the labor relations administrator appointed under subsection (a) of this section expires and after a public hearing on the appointment, if no exclusive representative has been certified under this subtitle, the Commission shall appoint the next labor relations administrator for a term not exceeding 1 year.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A labor relations administrator is eligible for reappointment.</section>
  </text>
</law>
