<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-20-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Commission shall provide an opportunity for a hearing before proceeding with the design or const...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission shall provide an opportunity for a hearing before proceeding with the design or construction of a water supply or sanitary sewer system.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to subsection (c) of this section, the Commission:<section prefix="(1)">shall advertise in newspapers and technical media that the Commission considers appropriate for bids or proposals for design or construction services for any part of a water supply or sanitary sewer system; and</section><section prefix="(2)">may readvertise any part of the services needed if the Commission considers the prices quoted in response to a prior advertisement to be unreasonable.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Commission may use day labor to complete any part of the design or construction of a water supply or sanitary sewer system.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding &#xA7; 20-105(a) of this subtitle, the Commission may spend up to $15,000 for day labor for any part of construction services without advertising for or receiving bids or proposals.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Commission may enter into any type of contract under this subtitle that promotes the best interest of the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission:<section prefix="(i)">may not enter a cost-plus-percentage-of-cost contract; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall prohibit a cost-plus-percentage-of-cost subcontract under a contract with the Commission.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commission may only enter into a design/build contract for a facilities construction contract with costs exceeding $2,000,000.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commission may reject any bid or proposal.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may require a contract to be secured by bonds, penalties, and conditions.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Security authorized under this subsection is enforceable in any court of competent jurisdiction.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Commission:<section prefix="(1)">may adopt regulations to establish a prequalification process for bidders or offerors; and</section><section prefix="(2)">shall adopt regulations to govern discussions held with offerors under &#xA7; 20-105(c)(3) of this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
