<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-8-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section, "telephone solicitation" means an organized activity, program, or campaign to communicate by telephone with residents of Maryland in order to:<section prefix="(i)">sell, lease, or rent goods or services;</section><section prefix="(ii)">attempt to sell, lease, or rent goods or services;</section><section prefix="(iii)">offer or attempt to offer a gift or prize;</section><section prefix="(iv)">conduct or attempt to conduct a poll; or</section><section prefix="(v)">request or attempt to request survey information, if the results of the survey will be used directly to solicit persons to purchase, lease, or rent goods or services.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Telephone solicitation" includes the act of managing, directing, or supervising an individual engaged in telephone solicitation under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to a unit of federal, State, or local government.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the telephone service or equipment of a person engaged in telephone solicitation allows that person to choose to restrict or display the transmission of the person's telephone number to the recipient of a telephone solicitation, the person may not:<section prefix="(1)">intentionally use any device or method to block the transmission of the person's telephone number to a recipient; or</section><section prefix="(2)">take any other action to prevent or control the transmission of the person's telephone number to a recipient.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to:<section prefix="(1)">for a first offense, a fine not exceeding $1,000; and</section><section prefix="(2)">for each subsequent offense, a fine not exceeding $5,000.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
