<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-7-307</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>307</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "termination of service" means the termination, reduction, or refusal to reinstate gas or electric service, or any other action that has the effect of reducing or denying gas or electric service because of nonpayment.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Commission shall adopt regulations concerning the prohibition against or limitation of authority of a public service company to terminate service for gas or electricity to a low income residential customer during the heating season for nonpayment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In adopting the regulations required under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Commission shall consider and may include provisions relating to:<section prefix="(i)">the circumstances under which service may and may not be limited or terminated;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the minimum heating levels required to maintain life, health, and safety;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the medical, age, disabling, or other individual characteristics that are relevant to a prohibition against or limitation on the termination of service;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the availability of and qualification for State and federal energy assistance;</section><section prefix="(v)">the financial eligibility standards relevant to a prohibition against or limitation on the termination of service;</section><section prefix="(vi)">the availability and appropriateness of equipment designed to limit the flow of service for gas or electricity;</section><section prefix="(vii)">the short-term and long-term alternative payment plans, for appropriate customers whose accounts are in arrears, that are best designed:<section prefix="1.">to allow present and future continuation of service; and</section><section prefix="2.">to encourage full payment over a period of time;</section></section><section prefix="(viii)">the methods that a public service company might use before and during the heating season to anticipate customer nonpayment, to assist those customers, and to avoid termination of service;</section><section prefix="(ix)">the procedures that a public service company uses to mitigate the problems of termination of service to customers, including customer contact;</section><section prefix="(x)">the procedure that a public service company shall follow before termination of service to a customer to avoid a threat to life, health, or safety;</section><section prefix="(xi)">the appropriate customer notice before the termination of service;</section><section prefix="(xii)">the appropriate opportunity and procedure for a customer to contest a proposed termination of service;</section><section prefix="(xiii)">the existence of other circumstances that because of an emergency, might justify a prohibition against or a limitation on the termination of service; and</section><section prefix="(xiv)">the economic implication of any restriction on termination of service.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, on or before June 1 of each year, the Commission shall report to the General Assembly on terminations of service by public service companies during the previous heating season.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The report shall include information in sufficient detail to indicate the effect of the terminations of service on various categories of customers, including:<section prefix="(i)">income levels;</section><section prefix="(ii)">geographic areas;</section><section prefix="(iii)">energy assistance recipients; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">any other category that the Commission determines is relevant to evaluate how the State may best address the problem of assuring adequate gas and electric service for low income residential customers.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
