<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-4-207</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>207</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only to a gas company, electric company, or telephone company whose gross annual revenues, for the most recent calendar year for which data are available, are less than 3% of the total gross annual revenues of all public service companies in the State during the same calendar year.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When the Commission suspends a proposed new rate for a company subject to this section that is based on the existing authorized fair rate of return, the Commission promptly shall institute proceedings to determine if additional revenues are required to allow the company to earn the existing fair rate of return authorized in the previous base rate proceeding.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">serve each of the parties to the previous base rate proceeding of that company with a copy of the suspension order; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">order the company to publish a display advertisement about the proposal in newspapers of general circulation in its service area.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Proceedings under this section shall:<section prefix="(i)">account for revenues, expenses, and rate base in the same manner that the Commission employed in determining a just and reasonable rate in the previous base rate proceeding; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">exclude consideration of any increase in the rate of return, any change in rate structure, or any change in an accounting approach to any item pertaining to revenues, expenses, or rate base inconsistent with that used by the Commission in determining a just and reasonable rate in the previous base rate proceeding on the company.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In proceedings under this section, the Commission may use a more recent past test period than that used in the previous base rate proceeding for the company.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Commission shall enter a final order as to the revenue requirement determined under this section within 90 days after the proposed new rate is filed.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The final order shall:<section prefix="(i)">authorize a new rate distributing any change in the revenue requirement proportionally among the ratepayers without change in the rate structure; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">state whether further proceedings shall be held.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">If, in the final order, the Commission decides to conduct further proceedings under subsection (c) of this section, the final order may provide for refund, consistent with the provisions of &#xA7; 4-204(c) of this subtitle, of any difference between the new rate authorized under this subsection and the rate the Commission sets under subsection (c) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Commission decides to conduct further proceedings under subsection (b) of this section, the Commission, after a hearing, may:<section prefix="(i)">modify the rate structure;</section><section prefix="(ii)">lower the authorized fair rate of return; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">modify the accounting approach to an item that pertains to revenues, expenses, or rate base.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall take any action under this subsection within 120 days after entry of a final order under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section does not apply to a proposed new rate that is filed:<section prefix="(i)">less than 1 year after a previously proposed new rate under this section is filed; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">with a request for temporary rates under &#xA7; 4-205 of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A company may not file a proposed new rate under this subtitle if any proposed new rate filed by the company under this section is pending, or a new rate filed by the company under this section has been in effect fewer than 90 days.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">This paragraph does not preclude a company from filing a proposed new rate for a new service if the proposal does not affect the authorized rate of return.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Unless the Commission provides otherwise, this section does not apply to a proposed new rate that is filed more than 3 years after the Commission enters a final order authorizing the existing fair rate of return in the previous base rate proceeding.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
