<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-3-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Commission shall institute and conduct proceedings reasonably necessary and proper to the exerci...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall institute and conduct proceedings reasonably necessary and proper to the exercise of its powers or the performance of its duties.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall conduct its proceedings en banc or in panels of:<section prefix="(i)">at least three commissioners; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">one hearing examiner and at least two commissioners.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A quorum consists of a majority of the Commission or a majority of a panel.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission, a commissioner, or a hearing examiner may conduct hearings, examine witnesses, administer oaths, and perform any other acts necessary to the conduct of proceedings.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Executive Secretary of the Commission may administer oaths.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each record of a proceeding of the Commission is a public record.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To the extent necessary to receive public comment for each application for a rate increase, the Commission shall hold a hearing at a convenient location and time during evening hours in the service area affected.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may delegate to a commissioner or to a hearing examiner the authority to conduct a proceeding that is within the Commission's jurisdiction.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In a delegated proceeding, the commissioner or hearing examiner shall:<section prefix="(i)">conduct the hearing and any other proceeding that the commissioner or hearing examiner considers necessary; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">file with the Commission, and simultaneously serve on all parties, a proposed order and findings of fact.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The proposed order shall become final unless appealed as provided in &#xA7; 3-113(d) of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies unless, after considering any staff recommendation as to the extent of staff participation, the Commission determines that the public interest would not be served by staff participation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In each matter before the Commission, the staff of the Commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">analyze the data submitted to the Commission;</section><section prefix="(ii)">prepare a staff position based on that analysis; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">make an evidentiary presentation setting forth the staff's analysis of the issues and its recommendations.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In making analyses and recommendations, the staff is:<section prefix="(i)">governed by the criteria in &#xA7; 2-113 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a party and has the rights of a party to the proceeding, including the rights specified in &#xA7; 3-107 of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The staff shall present direct and redirect cases of its own, cross-examine, submit briefs, and engage in oral argument as the staff considers necessary to ensure that the Commission has a complete record on all relevant issues in a particular case.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
