<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-7-401</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>401</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"B.T.U." means a British Thermal Unit which is the quantity of heat required to raise the temperature of 1 pound of water 1 degree Fahrenheit.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Builder" means:<section prefix="(1)">the person with whom the owner of a building enters into a contract or agreement to be principally responsible for the construction of the building, either individually or as a general contractor; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the owner of a building, if the owner constructs the building or serves as the owner's own general contractor.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Building" means any new structure that:<section prefix="(i)">is designed for human use or occupancy;</section><section prefix="(ii)">provides a method of controlling energy usage within its exterior envelope; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">as designed, does not have a peak design rate of energy usage per square foot of floor area of less than 3.5 B.T.U. per hour or 1 watt.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Building" includes any portion of an otherwise excluded new structure if that portion of the structure is primarily for human use or occupancy because the exterior envelopes, heating, venting and air conditioning systems, service water heating, and electrical distribution and illuminating systems are designed for that portion of the structure that is primarily for human use or occupancy.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Building" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">an addition to an existing structure or a single-family dwelling that is to constitute the principal residence of the builder;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a structure with a permanent heating and cooling system that utilizes a source other than natural gas, a petroleum product, or electricity;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an industrialized building as defined in &#xA7; 12-301 of the Public Safety Article that bears an insignia furnished by the Department of Housing and Community Development under Title 12, Subtitle 3 of the Public Safety Article; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">a manufactured home as defined in &#xA7; 12-301 of the Public Safety Article that bears an insignia issued by the Department of Housing and Community Development under Title 12, Subtitle 3 of the Public Safety Article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Energy Code" means energy conservation standards adopted under COMAR 05.02.07.04 Maryland Building Performance Standards (MBPS) under the authority of Title 12, Subtitle 5 of the Public Safety Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Political subdivision" means a county, Baltimore City, or a municipal corporation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
