<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-22-110</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Commission may borrow money in anticipation of taxe...</catch_line>
  <order_by>110</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Commission may borrow money in anticipation of taxes, sale of bonds, or other revenue of the fiscal year in which the loan is made or the next succeeding fiscal year to:<section prefix="(i)">pay the principal and interest of bonds due or to become due within 4 months;</section><section prefix="(ii)">pay the interest becoming due on any bonds within 4 months and not otherwise adequately provided for; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">meet payments required to be made to employees and laborers and not otherwise provided for.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The loan shall be payable not later than the end of the fiscal year after the year in which the loan is made.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall issue negotiable notes for all money borrowed under subsection (a) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notes may be renewed and money may be borrowed on new notes to pay any indebtedness.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The notes and loans shall mature within the time limit for the payment of the original loan.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Commission shall authorize, by resolution, the notes and set:<section prefix="(i)">the actual or maximum face amount of the notes;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the actual or maximum rate of interest to be paid on the amount borrowed; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the actual or approximate maturity of the notes.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Commission shall determine the form and manner of execution of the notes.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Commission may determine the manner in which the notes may be disposed of.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The aggregate amount of notes outstanding at any one time may not exceed an amount equal to the total principal of and interest on bonds of the sanitary district due and payable in the fiscal year in which the notes are issued.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
