<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-8-409</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>409</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A telephone company or reseller may not fail or neglect to comply with this subtitle or with a regulation adopted under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For the purpose of enforcing the provisions of this subtitle, the Commission may:<section prefix="(1)">exercise any of the powers conferred under this division against a telephone company or reseller; and</section><section prefix="(2)">in the case of a complaint filed against a telephone company or reseller, order the telephone company or reseller to make reparations to the complaining party in accordance with &#xA7; 8-405 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In addition to any other available penalty, the Commission may assess directly, after an opportunity for hearing, an administrative penalty on a telephone company or reseller that violates the provisions of this subtitle, or a regulation adopted under this subtitle, or federal law or regulation on unauthorized changes to a customer's telephone company, reseller, or telecommunications service options, or to the person who bills the customer or the customer's billing arrangement.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The administrative penalty assessed under this section may not exceed $1,000 for each violation associated with a specific access line in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In assessing an administrative penalty under this section, the Commission shall consider:<section prefix="(1)">the nature, circumstances, extent, gravity, and number of violations;</section><section prefix="(2)">the degree of culpability of the violator;</section><section prefix="(3)">prior offenses and repeated violations of the violator; and</section><section prefix="(4)">any other matter that the Commission considers appropriate and relevant.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An administrative penalty collected under this section shall be paid into the General Fund of the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
