<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-25-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When construction begins or within 12 months after completion of a water supply or sewer project, the Commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">in accordance with a classification established under &#xA7; 25-203 of this subtitle, impose a benefit charge on each property that abuts on the water main or sewer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">notify each property owner in writing of:<section prefix="1.">the classification of the owner's property;</section><section prefix="2.">the benefit charge imposed on the property; and</section><section prefix="3.">the time and place of a hearing to contest the imposition of the charge.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission may deliver the notice required under this subsection by:<section prefix="(i)">mailing the notice to the last known address of the property owner;</section><section prefix="(ii)">giving the notice in person to an adult occupying the property; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">if the property is vacant or unimproved, posting the notice on the property.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For each class of property, the Commission shall impose a benefit charge for water supply or sewer construction, or both, that is based on:<section prefix="(i)">the approximate cost of construction as an integral part of the whole system; and</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">the number of front feet abutting on the street, road, lane, alley, right-of-way, or easement in which the water main or sewer is placed; or</section><section prefix="2.">for multiunit classes, the number of units in or on the property that abut on the water main or sewer.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In accordance with paragraph (1) and subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, in imposing a front foot benefit charge the Commission:<section prefix="(i)">for an irregularly shaped lot that abuts on a street, road, lane, alley, right-of-way, or easement in which there is or is being constructed a water main or sewer, shall use a front footage the Commission considers reasonable and fair;</section><section prefix="(ii)">for all the lots in a block owned by the same property owner and appurtenant to a residence, may use a continuous front footage for all the lots regardless of the streets on which the lots face;</section><section prefix="(iii)">for a lot with a front and rear on separate streets, may use a front footage on both the front and rear; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">for a corner lot of less than 2 acres in the residential subdivision classification:<section prefix="1.">may not use a front footage on more than one side unless the corner lot abuts on two parallel streets; and</section><section prefix="2.">if the corner lot abuts on two parallel streets, shall use a front footage that is reasonable and fair, taking into consideration the front footage toward which the building on the lot would naturally face.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission may impose a front foot benefit charge on the full front footage for a lot described in paragraph (2) of this subsection even if a water main or sewer does not extend along the full length of a boundary.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The benefit charge shall be:<section prefix="(1)">unless otherwise provided in this subtitle, uniform for each classification of property in the sanitary district for any 1 year;</section><section prefix="(2)">determined by the Commission as costs and conditions require; and</section><section prefix="(3)">imposed once a year to begin on the January 1 or July 1 after the date of its imposition and may not be increased in that year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Beginning when the Commission imposes a benefit charge for a property, the Commission shall require the property owner to pay the benefit charge annually for a period of years equal to the period of maturity of the bonds the proceeds of which financed the construction of the water main or sewer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a property of the Housing Opportunities Commission of Montgomery County is subject to a benefit charge under this subtitle, the benefit charge shall be paid in the same manner as by a private property owner.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each benefit charge imposed under this subtitle is a lien against the property that continues until the benefit charge is paid and the account is extinguished in accordance with this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
