<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-25-502</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>502</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in this subtitle, the service rate  for water shall consist of:<section prefix="(i)">a minimum or a ready to serve charge; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a charge for water used.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The minimum or ready to serve charge shall be based on the size of the meter on the water connection leading to the property.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The charge for water used shall be based on the amount of water passing the meter during the period between the last two readings.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The meter shall be placed on each water connection by and at the expense of the Commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission may provide that a specified minimum number of gallons of water:<section prefix="(1)">be included in the minimum or ready to serve charge without additional service charges for the water; and</section><section prefix="(2)">may vary with the size of the meter involved.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Commission furnishes water to a federal, State, or other unit of government that is exempt from benefit charges or ad valorem taxes imposed under this division, the Commission shall set the water service charge at an amount the Commission considers necessary and reasonable.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In setting the charge, the Commission shall take into consideration the general tax, the benefit charge imposed in the sanitary district, and the regular service rate as provided in subsections (a) and (b) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If, because of public necessity, the Commission has extended the Commission's water system outside the boundaries of the sanitary district to render a needed service, the Commission may pay for the extension out of its funds.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission may set any charge that it considers reasonable for all connections to its water system made outside of the sanitary district.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In setting the charge the Commission shall take into consideration the general tax and front foot benefit charge imposed in the sanitary district.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Commission has the same authority over connections made to the Commission's water system outside the sanitary district as it has in the sanitary district.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On request by the Mayor and City Council of the City of Laurel, the Commission shall furnish water from the Patuxent River supply to the city.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The service rate for the water supplied by the Commission to the City of Laurel shall be at the actual cost of supplying the water to the city's water system.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Mayor and City Council of the City of Laurel may construct a system to receive water from the Commission to the nearest convenient point to the Commission's Patuxent River supply.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The connection point between the Commission's system and the city's water system must be at or near the Commission's dam.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
