<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="17-403" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-17-403</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided by this division, the Commission may adopt regulations to carry out the provisions of this division and any other laws the administration and enforcement of which are vested in the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission may:<section prefix="(i)">limit or regulate the use and supply of water service and sanitary sewer service on a temporary basis in any area or to any premises served by the Commission's facilities, as the needs of the occasion and the protection of the Commission's systems require;</section><section prefix="(ii)">adopt regulations that the Commission considers necessary for the public safety, health, comfort, or convenience in the construction, operation, maintenance, expansion, relocation, replacement, renovation, and repair of the Commission's water system and sanitary sewer system; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">establish the forms of permits and specify the nature, type, and amount of information, detail, and engineering data that a person must submit to the Commission for any permit authorized or required by this division.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except for the immediate preservation of the public health and safety or for emergency provisions required to protect the Commission's systems, the Commission shall publish a notice of any new regulation that is authorized by this section at least 30 days before its effective date in at least one newspaper of general circulation in each county of the sanitary district.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A regulation adopted by the Commission under this section has the force and authority of law.</section>
  </text>
</law>
