<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-6-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>This subsection does not apply to railroads....</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to railroads.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, each public service company shall file with the Commission an annual report containing information on its corporate structure, affiliations of its officers and directors, and debt holdings.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Notwithstanding any specific reporting requirements in this subtitle, the Commission may prescribe the contents of the annual report to be filed by a public service company whose gross annual revenues for the most recent calendar year for which data are available are less than 0.003% of the total gross annual revenues of all public service companies in the State during the same calendar year.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A small rural electric cooperative described in &#xA7; 7-502(a) of this article may satisfy the reporting requirement by submitting to the Commission a copy of a report including the required information that the small rural electric cooperative submits to the rural utilities service.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Unless otherwise directed by the Commission, a public service company is not required to comply with subsection (a) of this section if the public service company is:<section prefix="(1)">a common carrier; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a telephone company whose rates are not regulated by the Commission under Title 4 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The president, treasurer, or general manager of a public service company shall verify the company's annual report under oath.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commission may:<section prefix="(1)">require a public service company to submit reports and information that the Commission reasonably desires;</section><section prefix="(2)">prescribe the form, contents, and deadlines for the reports and information; and</section><section prefix="(3)">require amendments or corrections to the reports within a set period.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
