<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-12-311</section_number>
  <catch_line>In a proceeding for a conversion, the county or municipal corporation and any public agency or publi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>311</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In a proceeding for a conversion, the county or municipal corporation and any public agency or public utility supplying electric service or communication service with the county or municipal corporation shall provide by agreement that:<section prefix="(1)">at the start or on completion of the conversion, the public agency or public utility has legal title to the electric or communication facilities; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the electric or communication facilities are:<section prefix="(i)">a part of the system of the public agency or public utility; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">to be used, operated, maintained, and managed by the public agency or public utility as part of its system.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to any rules, regulations, or tariffs applicable to the public agency or public utility, the agreement also shall provide for the following:<section prefix="(1)">the supplying of or approval by the public agency or public utility of plans and specifications related to the conversion and labor or materials to be used in the conversion; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the performance by the public agency or public utility of all or part of the conversion or improvements and payment to the public agency or public utility for the conversion or improvements.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An agreement made under this section must be made before the legislative body of the county or municipal corporation adopts a resolution ordering the conversion.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the proceeding for a conversion is discontinued:<section prefix="(i)">any agreement made under this section is void;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the petitioners shall reimburse the public agency or public utility for engineering and other preliminary expenses incurred that exceed $2,500; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the petitioners or the county or municipal corporation may not reimburse the public agency or public utility for engineering and other preliminary expenses incurred that are $2,500 or less.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the proposed conversion is completed, any engineering and other preliminary expenses incurred by the public agency or public utility shall be included as part of the cost of the conversion.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Before an agreement made under this section takes effect, the Commission may conduct proceedings and shall:<section prefix="(1)">determine that the agreement is in the public interest; and</section><section prefix="(2)">issue an order to approve the agreement, disapprove the agreement, or approve the agreement subject to specified conditions.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
