<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-11-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each year an intrastate pipeline operator shall submit an annual report on the state of its pipeline facility to the Commission and to each owner of real property:<section prefix="(1)">on which the pipeline facility is located; or</section><section prefix="(2)">adjacent to or contiguous to real property on which the pipeline facility is located.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The annual report shall include:<section prefix="(1)">a summary description of the system that includes the pipeline facility;</section><section prefix="(2)">a description of the product transported in the pipeline facility and system;</section><section prefix="(3)">State and local emergency response liaison information;</section><section prefix="(4)">a description of the leak detection system in use for the pipeline facility;</section><section prefix="(5)">a description of periodic testing methods used on the pipeline facility and a summary of results of the testing; and</section><section prefix="(6)">any other information that the Commission requires.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission shall make annual reports available to the public, including publication using the Internet.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">At least once every 5 years, an intrastate pipeline operator shall:<section prefix="(1)">identify each owner of real property on which the pipeline facility is located;</section><section prefix="(2)">notify each property owner of the presence of the pipeline facility on the owner's property;</section><section prefix="(3)">verify that each property owner has received the notice; and</section><section prefix="(4)">provide to the Commission a current list of all property owners.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
