<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-102" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-10-102</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This subtitle supplements other law relating to the operation and licensing of motor vehicles.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This title applies to any motor vehicle used in the transportation of persons in exchange for remuneration except:<section prefix="(1)">motor vehicles designed to transport more than 15 persons; and</section><section prefix="(2)">transportation solely provided by or on behalf of a unit of federal, State, or local government, or a not-for-profit organization as identified in &#xA7; 501(c)(3) and (4) of the Internal Revenue Code, that requires a criminal history records check and driving record check for its drivers, for clients of services including:<section prefix="(i)">aging support;</section><section prefix="(ii)">developmental and other disabilities;</section><section prefix="(iii)">kidney dialysis;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Medical Assistance Program;</section><section prefix="(v)">Head Start;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Welfare-to-Work;</section><section prefix="(vii)">mental health; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">job training.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subsection (b)(2) of this section may not be construed to limit the application of this title or Title 9 of this article to a for-hire driver or other person who operates a motor vehicle for hire or provides transportation of persons for hire in addition to providing transportation services to clients of services listed in subsection (b)(2) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding subsection (b)(2) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">a not-for-profit organization that provides transportation for remuneration to clients of services listed in subsection (b)(2) of this section may be required to obtain a motor carrier permit under Title 9 of this article; but</section><section prefix="(2)">a driver employed by the not-for-profit organization may not be required to obtain a for-hire driver's license or other authorization from the Commission to perform transportation services solely under subsection (b)(2) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A driver employed or offered employment by a governmental unit or not-for-profit organization under subsection (b)(2) of this section shall apply to the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository of the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services for a State criminal history records check on or before the first day of the driver's actual employment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">As part of the application for a State criminal history records check, the driver employed or offered employment by the governmental unit or not-for-profit organization shall submit to the Central Repository:<section prefix="(i)">one complete set of the driver's legible fingerprints taken on a form approved by the Secretary of Public Safety and Correctional Services; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the fee authorized under &#xA7; 10-221(b)(7) of the Criminal Procedure Article for access to State criminal history records.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the Criminal Procedure Article, the Central Repository shall provide a printed statement listing the driver's criminal convictions to:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If criminal history record information is reported to the Central Repository after the date of the initial criminal history records check, the Central Repository shall provide a revised printed statement listing the driver's criminal convictions to:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In accordance with regulations adopted by the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services, the governmental unit or not-for-profit organization shall verify periodically a list of its drivers.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Information the governmental unit or not-for-profit organization obtains from the Central Repository under this subsection shall be:<section prefix="(i)">confidential and may not be redisseminated; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">used only for the employment purpose authorized by this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">In accordance with &#xA7; 10-223 of the Criminal Procedure Article, a driver employed by a governmental unit or not-for-profit organization may challenge the contents of a printed statement or revised printed statement issued by the Central Repository.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">This subtitle does not limit the power of a political subdivision of the State to adopt reasonable traffic regulations such as:<section prefix="(1)">the designation of taxicab stands; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the restriction or prohibition of cruising along a public street when the cruising would menace the public safety or unduly congest traffic.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
