<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-5-410</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies to:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>410</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to:<section prefix="(1)">a telegraph company that has its principal office in the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">a telephone company that has its principal office in the State;</section><section prefix="(3)">a corporation formed as a Class 13 corporation under Article 23, &#xA7; 28 of the Code of 1904; and</section><section prefix="(4)">a telephone company that owns lines and provides local exchange or interexchange service in the State with the approval of the Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A company described in subsection (a) of this section has the same power granted to telegraph and telephone companies by &#xA7;&#xA7; 8-103, 8-104, 8-105, and 8-106(a) of this article and may:<section prefix="(1)">construct and lay lines underground or above ground on any route for which it is authorized to construct lines as a whole or in part; and</section><section prefix="(2)">except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, acquire by condemnation, in accordance with Title 12 of the Real Property Article, any property or right that the company considers necessary for its purposes.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before using either the surface of or the ground beneath the streets or highways of Baltimore City, the company shall obtain the consent of the Mayor and City Council.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection does not apply to corporations that were in practical operation on June 1, 1910, and that had laid or constructed lines, pipes, mains, or other structures in Baltimore City, unless the corporations use new and additional streets and highways in Baltimore City for their lines, pipes, mains, or other structures.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section does not authorize a telephone company described in subsection (a)(4) of this section that, as of September 30, 1993, did not have the power of condemnation granted to a telegraph company under &#xA7;&#xA7; 8-103, 8-104, 8-105, and 8-106(a) of this article, to acquire property for communications towers or buildings.</section>
  </text>
</law>
