<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-107" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-12-107</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Authority consists of nine members appointed by the Governor.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The nine members shall be appointed as follows:<section prefix="(1)">one member from a list submitted to the Governor by the Associated Utility Contractors of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(2)">one member from a list submitted to the Governor by the Public Works Contractors Association of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(3)">two underground facility owners that are members of a one-call system from a list submitted to the Governor by the Maryland members of the Maryland/DC Subscribers Committee;</section><section prefix="(4)">one member from a list submitted to the Governor by the one-call centers operating in the State;</section><section prefix="(5)">one member who represents the State's underground utility locator community from a list submitted to the Governor by the Maryland members of the Maryland/DC Damage Prevention Committee;</section><section prefix="(6)">one member who has experience in the field of underground utilities from a list submitted to the Governor by the Maryland Association of Counties;</section><section prefix="(7)">one member who has experience in the field of underground utilities from a list submitted to the Governor by the Maryland Municipal League; and</section><section prefix="(8)">one member of the general public from a list submitted to the Governor by the other appointed and qualified members of the Authority.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To the extent practicable, members appointed to the Authority shall reasonably reflect the geographic, racial, and gender diversity of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 2 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Authority on October 1, 2010.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A member may not be appointed for more than two consecutive full terms.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">To the extent practicable, the Governor shall fill any vacancy in the membership of the Authority within 60 days after the vacancy.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">On the recommendation of the Authority, the Governor may remove a member for incompetence or misconduct.</section>
  </text>
</law>
