<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-17-102</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>102</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission consists of:<section prefix="(1)">three commissioners from Prince George's County, appointed by the County Executive subject to the confirmation of the County Council; and</section><section prefix="(2)">three commissioners from Montgomery County, appointed by the County Executive subject to the confirmation of the County Council.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each commissioner shall be a resident of the sanitary district.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each commissioner from Montgomery County shall be a registered voter of Montgomery County.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Each commissioner from Prince George's County shall be a registered voter of Prince George's County.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual may not be appointed or continue in office as a commissioner if the individual holds any other position of profit or trust under the Constitution or laws of the State or any political subdivision of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Not more than two commissioners from Montgomery County may be of the same political party.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a commissioner is 4 years and begins on June 1 of the year of appointment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of commissioners are staggered as required by the terms provided for commissioners on July 1, 1982.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a commissioner continues to serve until a successor is appointed and takes the oath of office.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A commissioner who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and takes the oath of office.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A vacancy on the Commission does not impair the right of the remaining commissioners to exercise all the powers of the Commission.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
