<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gpu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="21-104" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-21-104</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"High performance building" means a building that:<section prefix="(i)">meets or exceeds the current version of the U.S. Green Building Council's Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design (LEED) Green Building Rating System Silver rating; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">achieves at least a comparable numeric rating according to a nationally recognized, accepted, and appropriate numeric sustainable development rating system, guideline, or standard approved by the Secretary of Budget and Management and the Secretary of General Services.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Major renovation" means the renovation of a building where:<section prefix="(i)">the building shell is to be reused for the new construction;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the heating, ventilating, and air-conditioning (HVAC), electrical, and plumbing systems are to be replaced; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the scope of the renovation is 7,500 square feet or greater.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">It is the intent of the General Assembly that, to the extent practicable:<section prefix="(1)">the Commission shall employ green building technologies when constructing or renovating a Commission-owned building not subject to this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">high performance buildings shall meet the criteria and standards established under the "High Efficiency Green Building Program" adopted by the Maryland Green Building Council.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as provided in subsections (d) and (e) of this section, if a capital project includes the construction or major renovation of a building that is 7,500 square feet or greater, the building shall be constructed or renovated to be a high performance building.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The following types of unoccupied buildings are not required to be constructed or renovated to be high performance buildings:<section prefix="(1)">warehouse and storage facilities;</section><section prefix="(2)">garages;</section><section prefix="(3)">maintenance facilities;</section><section prefix="(4)">transmitter buildings;</section><section prefix="(5)">pumping stations; and</section><section prefix="(6)">other similar types of buildings, as determined by the Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may request from the county where the proposed capital project is located a waiver from complying with subsection (c) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On receipt of a written request of a waiver under this subsection, with approval of the county executive, the county council of the county where the proposed capital project is located may issue a waiver under this subsection if the county council determines that the use of a high performance building in a proposed capital project is not practicable.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
