<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-12-120</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c) of this section, a person that obtains the information...</catch_line>
  <order_by>120</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c) of this section, a person that obtains the information required under this subtitle is not excused from:<section prefix="(1)">performing an excavation or demolition in a careful and prudent manner; and</section><section prefix="(2)">liability for damages or injury that results from the excavation or demolition.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If an underground facility is damaged by a person that fails to comply with this subtitle, the person is deemed negligent and is liable to the owner for the total cost of repair of the underground facility, unless the owner has failed to become an owner-member in accordance with &#xA7; 12-123 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If an underground facility is damaged by a person who is in compliance with this subtitle and the owner has failed to become an owner-member in accordance with &#xA7; 12-123 of this subtitle:<section prefix="(1)">the person is not liable to the owner for the cost of repair of the underground facility; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the owner is liable for any repairs or restoration of property damaged by the excavation or demolition.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Subsection (c) of this section may not be construed to interfere with the right of:<section prefix="(1)">a third party to recover damages arising out of the excavation or demolition from the person or from the owner; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the person to seek contribution from an owner for damages sought by a third party under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
