<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gpu" order_by="gpu" level="1">Public Utilities</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gpu-7-708</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Commission shall establish and maintain a market-based renewable electricity trading system to f...</catch_line>
  <order_by>708</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall establish and maintain a market-based renewable electricity trading system to facilitate the creation and transfer of renewable energy credits.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To the extent practicable, the trading system shall be consistent with and operate in conjunction with the trading system developed by PJM Interconnection, Inc., if available.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission may contract with a for-profit or a nonprofit entity to assist in the administration of the electricity trading system required under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The system shall include a registry of pertinent information regarding all:<section prefix="(i)">available renewable energy credits; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">renewable energy credit transactions among electricity suppliers in the State, including:<section prefix="1.">the creation and application of renewable energy credits;</section><section prefix="2.">the number of renewable energy credits sold or transferred; and</section><section prefix="3.">the price paid for the sale or transfer of renewable energy credits.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The registry shall provide current information to electricity suppliers and the public on the status of renewable energy credits created, sold, or transferred in the State.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Registry information shall be available by computer network access through the Internet.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
