<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="grp" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-13-310</section_number>
  <catch_line>After the surveyor has completed the survey, the surveyor shall:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>310</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">After the surveyor has completed the survey, the surveyor shall:<section prefix="(1)">Prepare a certificate of survey and one additional duplicate certificate for each county in which any vacant land embraced within the survey is located; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Return the certificate and all of these duplicates to the Commissioner in the time required by this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The certificate of survey shall contain, as to all the land embraced within the survey:<section prefix="(1)">A plat that meets the requirements of &#xA7; 3-108(c) of this article and any rules or regulations adopted under this title;</section><section prefix="(2)">A description of any vacant land and a separate description of any land owned by the applicant, each of which descriptions:<section prefix="(i)">Shall include the area covered by it; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall be referenced to adjoining tracts in the manner generally accepted in the profession of land surveying;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">A statement of the character and condition of any improvements on the land, or a statement that no improvements exist; and</section><section prefix="(4)">A certification by the surveyor that the surveyor:<section prefix="(i)">Actually has run and measured on the land the distance of each boundary; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has complied with all the requirements of this subsection.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The certificate and all duplicates shall be signed and verified by the surveyor.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the surveyor fails to return the certificate and all duplicates in the time required by this subtitle, the Commissioner shall dismiss the application and enter an order of termination in the proceeding.</section>
  </text>
</law>
