<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-8A-1001</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1001</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A park owner may not impose a security deposit in excess of the equivalent of 2 months' rent, or $50, whichever is greater. If a security deposit exceeds this amount, the resident may recover up to threefold the extra money charged, plus reasonable attorney's fees.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">After receiving payment of the initial security deposit from the resident, a park owner may not increase the security deposit.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the resident was not required to pay a security deposit during a prior lease or rental term, a park owner may not impose a security deposit.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An action under this section may be brought at any time during the tenancy or within 2 years after its termination.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The park owner shall give the resident a receipt for the security deposit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The receipt may be included in a written rental agreement.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The park owner shall be liable to the resident in the sum of $25 if the park owner fails to provide a written receipt for the security deposit.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The receipt or rental agreement shall contain language informing the resident of his rights under this section to receive from the park owner a written list of all existing damages if the resident makes a written request of the park owner within 15 days of the resident's occupancy.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the park owner imposes a security deposit, on written request, he promptly shall provide the resident with a written list of all existing damages. The request must be made within 15 days of the resident's occupancy.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Failure to provide the resident with this written statement renders the park owner liable to the resident for threefold the amount of the security deposit. The total amount of damages shall be subject to a setoff for damages and unpaid rent which reasonably could be withheld under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The park owner shall maintain all security deposits in a banking or savings institution in the State. This account shall be devoted exclusively to security deposits and bear interest.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A security deposit shall be deposited in the account within 30 days after the park owner receives it.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In the event of sales or transfer of any sort, including receivership or bankruptcy, the security deposit is binding on the successor in interest to the person to whom the deposit is given. Security deposits are free from any attachment by creditors.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Any successor in interest is liable to the resident for failure to return the security deposit, together with interest, as provided in this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 45 days after the end of the tenancy, the park owner shall return the security deposit to the resident together with simple interest which has accrued in the amount of 3 percent per annum less any damages rightfully withheld.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Interest shall accrue at 6-month intervals from the day the resident gives the park owner the security deposit. Interest is not compounded.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Interest shall be payable only on security deposits of $50 or more.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the park owner, without a reasonable basis, fails to return any part of the security deposit, plus accrued interest, within 45 days after the termination of the tenancy, the resident has an action of up to threefold of the withheld amount, plus reasonable attorney's fees.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The security deposit, or any portion of the security deposit, may be withheld for unpaid rent, damage due to breach of the rental agreement, or damage to the leased premises by the resident or the resident's family, agents, employees, or social guests in excess of ordinary wear and tear.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The resident has the right to be present when the park owner or his agent inspects the premises in order to determine if any damage was done to the premises, if the resident notifies the park owner in writing of his intention to move, the date of moving and his new address. The notice to be furnished by the resident to the park owner shall be mailed at least 15 days prior to the date of moving. Upon receipt of the notice, the park owner shall notify the resident in writing of the time and date when the premises are to be inspected. The date of inspection shall occur within 5 days after the moving as designated in the resident's notice. The resident shall be advised of his rights under this subsection in writing which may be included in the rental agreement at the time of his payment of the security deposit. Failure by the park owner to comply with this requirement forfeits the right of the park owner to withhold any part of the security deposit for damages.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
