<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-8-208.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>208.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For any reason listed in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a landlord of any residential property may not:<section prefix="(i)">Bring or threaten to bring an action for possession against a tenant;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Arbitrarily increase the rent or decrease the services to which a tenant has been entitled; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Terminate a periodic tenancy.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A landlord may not take an action that is listed under paragraph (1) of this subsection for any of the following reasons:<section prefix="(i)">Because the tenant or the tenant's agent has provided written or actual notice of a good faith complaint about an alleged violation of the lease, violation of law, or condition on the leased premises that is a substantial threat to the health or safety of occupants to:<section prefix="1.">The landlord; or</section><section prefix="2.">Any public agency against the landlord;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Because the tenant or the tenant's agent has:<section prefix="1.">Filed a lawsuit against the landlord; or</section><section prefix="2.">Testified or participated in a lawsuit involving the landlord; or</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">Because the tenant has participated in any tenants' organization.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A landlord's violation of subsection (a) of this section is a "retaliatory action".</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A tenant may raise a retaliatory action of a landlord:<section prefix="(i)">In defense to an action for possession; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">As an affirmative claim for damages resulting from a retaliatory action of a landlord occurring during a tenancy.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If in any proceeding the court finds in favor of the tenant because the landlord engaged in a retaliatory action, the court may enter judgment against the landlord for damages not to exceed the equivalent of 3 months' rent, reasonable attorney fees, and court costs.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If in any proceeding the court finds that a tenant's assertion of a retaliatory action was in bad faith or without substantial justification, the court may enter judgment against the tenant for damages not to exceed the equivalent of 3 months' rent, reasonable attorney fees, and court costs.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The relief provided under this section is conditioned upon:<section prefix="(1)">The tenant being current on the rent due and owing to the landlord at the time of the alleged retaliatory action, unless the tenant withholds rent in accordance with the lease, &#xA7; 8-211 of this subtitle, or a comparable local ordinance; and</section><section prefix="(2)">If the alleged retaliatory action is a landlord's termination of a periodic tenancy:<section prefix="(i)">In the case of tenancies measured by a period of one month or more, the court having not entered against the tenant more than 3 judgments of possession for rent due and unpaid in the 12-month period immediately prior to the initiation of the action by the tenant or by the landlord; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">In the case of tenancies requiring the weekly payment of rent, the court having not entered against the tenant more than 5 judgments of possession for rent due and unpaid in the 12-month period immediately prior to the initiation of the action by the tenant or by the landlord, or, if the tenant has lived on the premises 6 months or less, the court having not entered against the tenant 3 judgments of possession for rent due and unpaid.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An action by a landlord may not be deemed to be retaliatory for purposes of this section if the alleged retaliatory action occurs more than 6 months after a tenant's action that is protected under subsection (a)(2) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">As long as a landlord's termination of a tenancy is not the result of a retaliatory action, nothing in this section may be interpreted to alter the landlord's or the tenant's rights to terminate or not renew a tenancy.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If any county has enacted or enacts an ordinance comparable in subject matter to this section, this section shall supersede the provisions of the ordinance to the extent that the ordinance provides less protection to a tenant.</section>
  </text>
</law>
