<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="grp" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-11A-122</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Commission may issue regulations and orders consistent with this title....</catch_line>
  <order_by>122</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission may issue regulations and orders consistent with this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission may bring suit in the appropriate court to enforce this title and may intervene in any action involving a registered developer.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission may accept grants in aid from any governmental source and may contract with agencies charged with similar functions in furtherance of the objectives of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commission may cooperate with agencies performing similar functions to develop uniform filing procedures and forms, disclosure standards, and administrative practices.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the Commission determines, after notice and hearing, that any person has disseminated or caused to be disseminated any false or misleading promotional materials in connection with a time-share, or that any person has otherwise violated any provision of this title or the Commission's regulations or orders, the Commission may issue an order to cease and desist from that conduct, to comply with the provisions of this title and the Commission's regulations and orders, or to take affirmative action to correct conditions resulting from that conduct or failure to comply.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may initiate investigations to determine whether any representation in any document or information filed with the Commission is false or misleading or whether any person has engaged, is engaging, or is about to engage in any unlawful act or practice.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the course of any investigation or hearing, the Commission may subpoena witnesses and documents, administer oaths and affirmations, and adduce evidence. If a person fails to comply with a subpoena or to answer questions propounded during the investigation or hearing, the Commission may apply to an appropriate court to secure compliance.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the applicant or developer fails to demonstrate financial solvency, the Commission may deny an application for a certificate of registration or revoke a certificate of registration already granted.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission may adopt regulations under paragraph (1) of this subsection requiring an applicant or developer to:<section prefix="(i)">Provide information;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Grant access to records; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Otherwise demonstrate financial solvency.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
