<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-5A-02" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-8-5A-02</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the requirements of subsections (b) and (c) of this section, a tenant may terminate the tenant's future liability under a residential lease if the tenant or legal occupant is:<section prefix="(1)">A victim of domestic violence; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A victim of sexual assault.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a tenant or legal occupant is a victim of domestic violence or a victim of sexual assault, the tenant may provide to the landlord the written notice required under &#xA7; 8-5A-03 or &#xA7; 8-5A-04 of this subtitle and, if the written notice is provided, the tenant shall have 30 days to vacate the leased premises from the date of providing the written notice.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A tenant who vacates leased premises under this section is responsible for rent only for the 30 days following the tenant providing notice of an intent to vacate.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a tenant does not vacate the leased premises within 30 days of providing to the landlord the written notice required under &#xA7; 8-5A-03 or &#xA7; 8-5A-04 of this subtitle, the landlord is, at the landlord's option and with written notice to the tenant, entitled to:<section prefix="(1)">All legal remedies against a tenant holding over available under &#xA7; 8-402 of this title; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Deem the tenant's notice of an intent to vacate to have been rescinded and the terms of the original lease to be in full force and effect.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The termination of a tenant's future liability under a residential lease under this section does not terminate or in any other way impact the future liability of a tenant who is the respondent in the action that results in:<section prefix="(1)">A protective order issued for the benefit of the victim tenant or victim legal occupant under &#xA7; 4-506 of the Family Law Article; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A peace order issued for the benefit of the victim tenant or victim legal occupant for which the underlying act was sexual assault under &#xA7; 3-1505 of the Courts Article.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
