<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="grp" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-10-801</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>801</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Home builder" means a person that undertakes to erect or otherwise construct a new home.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Minimum visitability features" means:<section prefix="(i)">A ground level entrance:<section prefix="1.">That has a width of 36 or more inches;</section><section prefix="2.">That is accessible from the outside of the new home or an attached garage; and</section><section prefix="3.">In which the threshold of the entrance is no more than 1.5 inches higher than the interior floor and the exterior landing; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">A circulation route from the ground level entrance to an unattached garage, parking space, or public right-of-way that is free of any curbs, steps, landings, obstacles, or other vertical changes in level that are more than 1.5 inches.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"New home" means a newly constructed single-family dwelling unit.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"New home" does not include:<section prefix="1.">A custom home as defined in &#xA7; 10-501 of this title; or</section><section prefix="2.">A mobile home as defined in &#xA7; 8A-101 of this article.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">A new home that is located above another new home;</section><section prefix="(2)">An attached new home;</section><section prefix="(3)">A new home:<section prefix="(i)">That does not have a garage; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">In which the slope between the finished ground level at all unit entrances to the nearest point along a property line that borders a public right-of-way is greater than 10%; or</section></section><section prefix="(4)">A new home in which compliance with the design flood elevation restrictions will cause:<section prefix="(i)">The finished floor to be more than 30 inches above the finished ground level at all unit entrances; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The slope between the finished floor at all unit entrances to the nearest point along a property line that borders a public right-of-way to be greater than 10%.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section applies only to a home builder that constructs 11 or more new homes in a subdivision that contains 11 or more new homes.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, at the time of offering new homes in a subdivision for sale, a home builder shall offer minimum visitability features as an option for purchase.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The offer of minimum visitability features shall be accompanied by:<section prefix="(i)">A point of sale document that describes the minimum visitability features; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A generic drawing or photograph that shows the minimum visitability features and the lots and new home types that are conducive to the minimum visitability features that could be constructed.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
