<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-13-402</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>402</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each objection in a proceeding shall be filed with the Commissioner:<section prefix="(1)">After the filing of the application for a warrant; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Within the later to occur of:<section prefix="(i)">Six months after the issuance of the warrant; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">60 days after the surveyor returns the certificate of survey under this title.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each objection shall be in writing and contain:<section prefix="(1)">The name and address of the objector;</section><section prefix="(2)">A description of that portion of the land to which the objection applies, referenced to the description contained in the certificate of survey and accompanying plat;</section><section prefix="(3)">The reasons for the objection;</section><section prefix="(4)">All available documentary and factual information necessary to support the claim of the objector;</section><section prefix="(5)">If the objection is made by a person claiming ownership under &#xA7; 13-401(2) of this subtitle:<section prefix="(i)">The name and current address of each person that has possessed the land under claim of ownership in the manner described in &#xA7; 13-401 (2) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The term of each possession; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any physical signs that accompanied each possession; and</section></section><section prefix="(6)">If the objection is made by the State or any agency of the State claiming public use under &#xA7; 13-401(3) of this subtitle:<section prefix="(i)">A statement of the particular public purpose for which the land is required;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A description of a clear and compelling need for the land;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The anticipated date when the land will be used for the specified public purpose; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">A statement of whether the land adjoins any land already held by the objector.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each objection shall be signed and verified by the objector and contain a certification that a copy of the objection was forwarded, at the address on record with the Commissioner, to:<section prefix="(1)">The applicant;</section><section prefix="(2)">Each other party in the proceeding; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Each other person entitled to notice under &#xA7; 13-404(b) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If any information required by this section is unavailable when the objection is filed, it may be included in an amendment to the objection, if the amendment is filed in advance of any hearing before the Commissioner or any proceeding for declaratory relief.</section>
  </text>
</law>
