<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="grp" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-11-109.3</section_number>
  <catch_line>If the council of unit owners fails to fill vacancies on the board of directors sufficient to consti...</catch_line>
  <order_by>109.3</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If the council of unit owners fails to fill vacancies on the board of directors sufficient to constitute a quorum in accordance with the bylaws, three or more unit owners may petition the circuit court for the county where the condominium is located to appoint a receiver to manage the affairs of the council of unit owners.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 30 days before petitioning the circuit court, the unit owners acting under the authority granted by subsection (a) of this section shall mail to the council of unit owners a notice describing the petition and the proposed action.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The unit owners shall post a copy of the notice in a conspicuous place on the condominium property.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the council of unit owners fails to fill vacancies sufficient to constitute a quorum within the notice period, the unit owners may proceed with the petition.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A receiver appointed by a court under this section may not reside in or own a unit in the condominium governed by the council of unit owners.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A receiver appointed under this section shall have all powers and duties of a duly constituted board of directors.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The receiver shall serve until the council of unit owners fills vacancies on the board of directors sufficient to constitute a quorum.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The salary of the receiver, court costs, and reasonable attorney's fees are common expenses.</section>
  </text>
</law>
