<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="grp" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-14-118</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "governing body" means a person who has the authority to enforce:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>118</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section, "governing body" means a person who has the authority to enforce:<section prefix="(i)">The provisions of a declaration, as defined under &#xA7; 11-103 of the Maryland Condominium Act;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Articles of incorporation of a council of unit owners, of a cooperative housing corporation as defined under the Maryland Cooperative Housing Corporation Act, or of a homeowners association, as defined under the Maryland Homeowners Association Act; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">The provisions of bylaws, rules, and regulations of a condominium, as defined under the Maryland Condominium Act, of a cooperative housing corporation as defined under the Maryland Cooperative Housing Corporation Act, or of a homeowners association, as defined under the Maryland Homeowners Association Act.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Governing body includes:<section prefix="(i)">A homeowners association, as defined under the Maryland Homeowners Association Act;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A council of unit owners of a condominium, as described in the Maryland Condominium Act; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A cooperative housing corporation.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person sustaining an injury as a result of the tortious act of an officer or director of a governing body while the officer or director is acting within the scope of the officer's or director's duties may recover only in an action brought against the governing body for the damages described under &#xA7; 5-422(b) of the Courts and Judicial Proceedings Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In a proceeding against a governing body, a director or officer of a governing body shall have the immunity from liability described under &#xA7; 5-422(c) of the Courts and Judicial Proceedings Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
