<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-710" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-10-710</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "community amenity" includes:<section prefix="(1)">A country club;</section><section prefix="(2)">A golf course;</section><section prefix="(3)">A health club;</section><section prefix="(4)">A park;</section><section prefix="(5)">A swimming pool;</section><section prefix="(6)">A tennis court; and</section><section prefix="(7)">A walking trail.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Prince George's County, a contract of sale for residential real property that includes an agreement by the home builder to provide a community amenity shall include a disclosure statement that:<section prefix="(i)">Identifies the community amenity provided in the contract of sale; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Specifies when the community amenity will be completed in accordance with a recreational facilities agreement recorded with the Prince George's County Planning Department.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The disclosure statement required under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be:<section prefix="(i)">Dated and signed by the purchaser and the home builder; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Included in or attached to the contract of sale.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A purchaser who does not receive the disclosure statement required under paragraph (1) of this subsection on or before entering into the contract of sale has an unconditional right, on written notice to the home builder, to rescind the contract of sale at any time:<section prefix="(i)">Before the receipt of the disclosure statement; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Within 5 days after receipt of the disclosure statement.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any advertising for a community development in Prince George's County that will include a community amenity shall include disclosure of the requirements under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In Prince George's County, a home builder that does not make the community amenity available as provided in the contract of sale may be liable for breach of contract.</section>
  </text>
</law>
