<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-7-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Financial Regulation in the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Foreclosure consultant" means a person who:<section prefix="(1)">Solicits or contacts a homeowner in writing, in person, or through any electronic or telecommunications medium and directly or indirectly makes a representation or offer to perform any service that the person represents will:<section prefix="(i)">Stop, enjoin, delay, void, set aside, annul, stay, or postpone a foreclosure sale;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Obtain forbearance from any servicer, beneficiary or mortgagee;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Assist the homeowner to exercise a right of reinstatement provided in the loan documents or to refinance a loan that is in foreclosure and for which notice of foreclosure proceedings has been published;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Obtain an extension of the period within which the homeowner may reinstate the homeowner's obligation or extend the deadline to object to a ratification;</section><section prefix="(v)">Obtain a waiver of an acceleration clause contained in any promissory note or contract secured by a mortgage on a residence in default or contained in the mortgage;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Assist the homeowner to obtain a loan or advance of funds;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Avoid or ameliorate the impairment of the homeowner's credit resulting from the filing of an order to docket or a petition to foreclose or the conduct of a foreclosure sale;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Save the homeowner's residence from foreclosure;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Purchase or obtain an option to purchase the homeowner's residence within 20 days of an advertised or docketed foreclosure sale; or</section><section prefix="(x)">Arrange for the homeowner to become a lessee or renter entitled to continue to reside in the homeowner's residence after a sale or transfer; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Systematically contacts owners of residences in default to offer foreclosure consulting services.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Foreclosure consulting contract" means a written, oral, or equitable agreement between a foreclosure consultant and a homeowner for the provision of any foreclosure consulting service.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Foreclosure consulting service" includes:<section prefix="(1)">Receiving money for the purpose of distributing it to creditors in payment or partial payment of any obligation secured by a lien on a residence in default;</section><section prefix="(2)">Contacting creditors on behalf of a homeowner;</section><section prefix="(3)">Arranging or attempting to arrange for an extension of the period within which a homeowner may cure the homeowner's default and reinstate the homeowner's obligation;</section><section prefix="(4)">Arranging or attempting to arrange for any delay or postponement of the sale of a residence in default;</section><section prefix="(5)">Arranging or facilitating the purchase of a homeowner's equity of redemption or legal or equitable title;</section><section prefix="(6)">Arranging or facilitating the sale of a homeowner's residence or the transfer of legal title, in any form, to another party as an alternative to foreclosure; or</section><section prefix="(7)">Arranging for or facilitating a homeowner remaining in the homeowner's residence after a sale or transfer as a tenant, renter, or lessee under terms provided in a written lease.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Foreclosure rescue transaction" means a transaction:<section prefix="(1)">In which a residence in default is conveyed by a homeowner who retains a legal or equitable interest in all or part of the property, including an interest under a lease-purchase agreement, an option to reacquire the property, or any other legal or equitable interest in the property conveyed; and</section><section prefix="(2)">That is designed or intended by the parties to prevent or delay actual or anticipated foreclosure proceedings against the residence in default.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Foreclosure surplus acquisition" means a transaction involving the transfer, sale, or assignment of the surplus remaining and due the homeowner based on the audit account during a foreclosure proceeding.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Foreclosure surplus purchaser" means a person who acts as the acquirer by assignment, purchase, grant, or conveyance of the surplus resulting from a foreclosure sale.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Foreclosure surplus purchaser" includes a person who acts in joint venture or joint enterprise with one or more acquirers.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Homeowner" means the record owner of a residence in default or a residence in foreclosure, or an individual occupying the residence under a use and possession order issued under Title 8, Subtitle 2 of the Family Law Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Residence in default" means residential real property located in the State consisting of not more than four single family dwelling units, one of which is occupied by the owner, or the owner's spouse or former spouse under a use and possession order issued under Title 8, Subtitle 2 of the Family Law Article, as the individual's principal place of residence, and on which the mortgage is at least 60 days in default.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Residence in foreclosure" means residential real property located in the State consisting of not more than four single family dwelling units, one of which is occupied by the owner, or the owner's spouse or former spouse under a use and possession order issued under Title 8, Subtitle 2 of the Family Law Article, as the individual's principal place of residence, and against which an order to docket or a petition to foreclose has been filed.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Settlement" means an in-person, face-to-face meeting with the homeowner to complete final documents incident to the sale or transfer of real property or the creation of a mortgage or equitable interest in real property, conducted by a settlement agent, during which the homeowner must be presented with a completed copy of the HUD-1 Settlement Form.</section>
  </text>
</law>
