<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-11-139</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>139</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A county or an incorporated municipality may provide by local law or ordinance, that a unit in a rental facility occupied by a tenant entitled to receive the notice required by &#xA7; 11-136 of this title may not be granted unless the county, incorporated municipality, or housing agency has first been offered in writing the right to purchase the unit at the same price and on the same terms and conditions initially offered for that unit to any other person. The local law or ordinance shall designate the title and mailing address of the person to whom the offer to the county, incorporated municipality or housing agency is to be delivered and the title of the person who may accept the offer on behalf of the county, incorporated municipality or housing agency.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The local law or ordinance shall provide that the offer to the county, incorporated municipality or housing agency shall be made at the same time an offer is made to a tenant of the unit under &#xA7; 11-136 of this title. If a tenant accepts an offer of a unit made under &#xA7; 11-136 of this title, then the rights of the county, incorporated municipality or housing agency to such unit under an offer made under this section, whether or not accepted, shall terminate.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Unless written acceptance of the offer is sooner delivered to the owner of the rental facility by the county, incorporated municipality or housing agency, the offer shall terminate, without further act, 120 days after it is delivered to the county, incorporated municipality or housing agency.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A county, incorporated municipality or housing agency may not accept an offer made under this section for any unit if that unit together with the aggregate of other units previously accepted or not accepted, subject to an extended lease by a designated family under &#xA7; 11-136 of this title, exceeds 20 percent of the total number of units in the condominium.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a grant for a unit contains an affidavit by the grantor that the provisions of any law or ordinance enacted under this section have been fulfilled, then the grantee in that grant takes title to the unit free and clear of all claims and rights of any county, incorporated municipality or housing agency under a local law or ordinance enacted under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Within 30 days of the enactment of a law or ordinance under this section, the county or incorporated municipality shall forward a copy of the law or ordinance to the Secretary of State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
