<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-105" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-7-105</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "individual" means a natural person.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A mortgage or deed of trust may authorize the sale of the property or declare the borrower's assent to the passing of a decree for the sale of the property, on default in a condition on which the mortgage or deed of trust provides that a sale may be made.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A power of sale or assent to decree authorized in a mortgage or deed of trust may be exercised only by an individual.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The individual selling the property under a power of sale need not be named in the mortgage or deed of trust.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An error or omission in a mortgage or deed of trust concerning the designation of the trustee or the individual authorized to exercise a power of sale does not invalidate the instrument or the ability of the mortgagee or beneficiary of the deed of trust to appoint an individual to exercise the power of sale.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If a mortgage or deed of trust allows for the appointment or substitution of a trustee or an individual authorized to exercise a power of sale, the holder of the mortgage or deed of trust may make the appointments or substitutions from time to time.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A sale made pursuant to this section, &#xA7;&#xA7; 7-105.1 through 7-105.8 of this subtitle, or the Maryland Rules, after final ratification by the court and grant of the property to the purchaser on payment of the purchase money, has the same effect as if the sale and grant were made under decree between the proper parties in relation to the mortgage or deed of trust and in the usual course of the court, and operates to pass all the title which the borrower had in the property at the time of the recording of the mortgage or deed of trust.</section>
  </text>
</law>
