<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-135" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-11-135</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, a contract for the resale of a unit by a unit owner other than a developer is not enforceable unless the contract of sale contains in conspicuous type a notice in the form specified in subsection (g)(1) of this section, and the unit owner furnishes to the purchaser not later than 15 days prior to closing:<section prefix="(1)">A copy of the declaration (other than the plats);</section><section prefix="(2)">The bylaws;</section><section prefix="(3)">The rules or regulations of the condominium;</section><section prefix="(4)">A certificate containing:<section prefix="(i)">A statement disclosing the effect on the proposed conveyance of any right of first refusal or other restraint on the free alienability of the unit other than any restraint created by the unit owner;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A statement setting forth the amount of the monthly common expense assessment and any unpaid common expense or special assessment currently due and payable from the selling unit owner;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A statement of any other fees payable by the unit owners to the council of unit owners;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A statement of any capital expenditures approved by the council of unit owners planned at the time of the conveyance which are not reflected in the current operating budget disclosed under subparagraph (vi) of this paragraph;</section><section prefix="(v)">The most recent regularly prepared balance sheet and income expense statement, if any, of the condominium;</section><section prefix="(vi)">The current operating budget of the condominium including details concerning the reserve fund for repair and replacement and its intended use, or a statement that there is no reserve fund;</section><section prefix="(vii)">A statement of any judgments against the condominium and the existence of any pending suits to which the council of unit owners is a party;</section><section prefix="(viii)">A statement generally describing any insurance policies provided for the benefit of unit owners, a notice that copies of the policies are available for inspection, stating the location at which the copies are available, and a notice that the terms of the policy prevail over the description;</section><section prefix="(ix)">A statement as to whether the council of unit owners has knowledge that any alteration or improvement to the unit or to the limited common elements assigned to the unit violates any provision of the declaration, bylaws, or rules or regulations;</section><section prefix="(x)">A statement as to whether the council of unit owners has knowledge of any violation of the health or building codes with respect to the unit, the limited common elements assigned to the unit, or any other portion of the condominium;</section><section prefix="(xi)">A statement of the remaining term of any leasehold estate affecting the condominium and the provisions governing any extension or renewal thereof; and</section><section prefix="(xii)">A description of any recreational or other facilities which are to be used by the unit owners or maintained by them or the council of unit owners, and a statement as to whether or not they are to be a part of the common elements;</section></section><section prefix="(5)">A statement by the unit owner as to whether the unit owner has knowledge:<section prefix="(i)">That any alteration to the unit or to the limited common elements assigned to the unit violates any provision of the declaration, bylaws, or rules and regulations;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Of any violation of the health or building codes with respect to the unit or the limited common elements assigned to the unit; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">That the unit is subject to an extended lease under &#xA7; 11-137 of this title or under local law, and if so, a copy of the lease must be provided; and</section></section><section prefix="(6)">A written notice of the unit owner's responsibility for the council of unit owners' property insurance deductible and the amount of the deductible.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A contract for the resale by a unit owner other than a developer of a unit in a condominium containing less than 7 units is not enforceable unless the contract of sale contains in conspicuous type a notice in the form specified in subsection (g)(2) of this section, and the unit owner furnishes to the purchaser not later than 15 days prior to closing:<section prefix="(1)">A copy of the declaration (other than the plats);</section><section prefix="(2)">The bylaws;</section><section prefix="(3)">The rules and regulations of the condominium;</section><section prefix="(4)">A statement by the unit owner of the unit owner's expenses during the preceding 12 months relating to the common elements; and</section><section prefix="(5)">A written notice of the unit owner's responsibility for the council of unit owners' property insurance deductible and the amount of the deductible.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The council of unit owners, within 20 days after a written request by a unit owner and receipt of a reasonable fee therefor, not to exceed the cost to the council of unit owners, if any, shall furnish a certificate containing the information necessary to enable the unit owner to comply with subsection (a) of this section. A unit owner providing a certificate under subsection (a) of this section is not liable to the purchaser for any erroneous information provided by the council of unit owners and included in the certificate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">With respect to the remaining information that the unit owner is required to disclose under subsection (a) of this section that is not provided by the council of unit owners and included in the certificate, a unit owner:<section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, is liable to the purchaser under this section for damages proximately caused by:</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is not liable to the purchaser under this section if the owner had, after reasonable investigation, reasonable grounds to believe, and did believe, at the time the information was provided to the purchaser, that the statements were true and that there was no omission to state a material fact necessary to make the statements made not misleading, in light of the circumstances under which the statements were made.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A purchaser is not liable for any unpaid assessment or fee greater than the amount set forth in the certificate prepared by the council of unit owners. A unit owner is not liable to a purchaser for the failure or delay of the council of unit owners to provide the certificate in a timely manner.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The rights of a purchaser under this section may not be waived in the contract of sale, and any attempted waiver is void. However, if a purchaser proceeds to closing, his right to rescind the contract under subsection (f) of this section is terminated.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any purchaser may at any time within 7 days following receipt of all of the information required under subsection (a) or (b) of this section, whichever is applicable, rescind in writing the contract of sale without stating any reason and without any liability on his part.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The purchaser, upon rescission, is entitled to the return of any deposits made on account of the contract.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If any deposits are held in trust by a licensed real estate broker, the return of the deposits to a purchaser under this subsection shall comply with the procedures set forth in &#xA7; 17-505 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A notice given as required by subsection (a) of this section shall be sufficient for the purposes of this section if it is in substantially the following form:<section prefix="(i)">A copy of the declaration (other than the plats);</section><section prefix="(ii)">A copy of the bylaws;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A copy of the rules and regulations of the condominium;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A certificate containing:</section><section prefix="(v)">A statement by the unit owner as to whether the unit owner has knowledge:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A notice given as required by subsection (b) of this section shall be sufficient for the purposes of this section if it is in substantially the following form:</section>
      <section prefix="(1)">A copy of the declaration (other than the plats);</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A copy of the bylaws;</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A copy of the rules and regulations of the condominium; and</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A statement by the seller of his expenses relating to the common elements during the preceding 12 months.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Upon any sale of a condominium unit, the purchaser or his agent shall provide to the council of unit owners to the extent available, the name and forwarding address of the prior unit owner, the name and address of the purchaser, the name and address of any mortgagee, the date of settlement, and the proportionate amounts of any outstanding condominium fees or assessments assumed by each of the parties to the transaction.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">This section does not apply to the sale of any unit which is to be used and occupied for nonresidential purposes.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">Subsections (a), (b), (c), (d), (e), (f), and (g) of this section do not apply to a sale of a unit in an action to foreclose a mortgage or deed of trust.</section>
  </text>
</law>
