<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-105" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-3-105</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A mortgage or deed of trust may be released validly by any procedure enumerated in this section or &#xA7; 3-105.2 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A release may be endorsed on the original mortgage or deed of trust by the mortgagee or his assignee, the trustee or his successor under a deed of trust, or by the holder of the debt or obligation secured by the deed of trust. The mortgage or the deed of trust, with the endorsed release, then shall be filed in the office in which the mortgage or deed of trust is recorded. The clerk shall record the release photographically, with an attachment or rider affixed to it containing the names of the parties as they appear on the original mortgage or deed of trust, together with a reference to the book and page number where the mortgage or deed of trust is recorded.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">At the option of the clerk of the court in whose office the book form of recording is used, the release may be written by the mortgagee, or his assignee, or the trustee, or his successor under a deed of trust, on the record in the office where the mortgage or deed of trust is recorded and attested by the clerk of the court. At the time of recording any mortgage or deed of trust, the clerk of the court in whose office the book form of recording is used shall leave a blank space at the foot of the mortgage or deed of trust for the purpose of entering such release.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When the debt secured by a deed of trust is paid fully or satisfied, and any bond, note, or other evidence of the total indebtedness is marked "paid" or "canceled" by the holder or his agent, it may be received by the clerk and indexed and recorded as any other instrument in the nature of a release. The marked note has the same effect as a release of the property for which it is the security, as if a release were executed by the named trustees, if there is attached to or endorsed on the note an affidavit of the holder, the party making satisfaction, or an agent of either of them, that it has been paid or satisfied, and specifically setting forth the land record reference where the original deed of trust is recorded.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When the debt secured by a mortgage is paid fully or satisfied, and the original mortgage is marked "paid" or "canceled" by the mortgagee or his agent, it may be received by the clerk and indexed and recorded as any other instrument in the nature of a release. The marked mortgage has the same effect as a release of the property for which it is the security, as if a release were executed by the mortgagee, if there is attached to or endorsed on the mortgage an affidavit of the mortgagee, the mortgagor, the party making satisfaction, or the agent of any of them, that it has been paid or satisfied, and specifically setting forth the land record reference where the mortgage is recorded.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">When the debt secured by a mortgage or deed of trust is paid fully or satisfied, and the canceled check evidencing final payment or, if the canceled check is unavailable, a copy of the canceled check accompanied by a certificate from the institution on which the check was drawn stating that the copy is a true and genuine image of the original check is presented, it may be received by the clerk and indexed and recorded as any other instrument in the nature of a release. The canceled check or copy accompanied by the certificate has the same effect as a release of the property for which the mortgage or deed of trust is the security, as if a release were executed by the mortgagee or named trustees, if:<section prefix="(i)">The party making satisfaction of the mortgage or deed of trust has:</section><section prefix="(ii)">The canceled check or copy accompanied by the certificate contains the name of the party whose debt is being satisfied, the debt account number, if any, and words indicating that the check is intended as payment in full of the debt being satisfied; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">There is attached to the canceled check or copy accompanied by the certificate an affidavit made by a member of the Maryland Bar that the mortgage or deed of trust has been satisfied, that the notice required under item (i) of this paragraph has been sent, and specifically setting forth the land record reference where the original mortgage or deed of trust is recorded.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">When the debt secured by a mortgage or deed of trust is fully paid or satisfied and the holder or the agent of the holder of the mortgage or deed of trust note or other obligation secured by the deed of trust, or the trustee or successor trustee under the deed of trust, executes and acknowledges a certificate of satisfaction substantially in the form specified under &#xA7; 4-203(d) of this article, containing the name of the debtor, holder, the authorized agent of the holder, or the trustee or successor trustee under the deed of trust, the date, and the land record recording reference of the instrument to be released, it may be received by the clerk and indexed and recorded as any other instrument in the nature of a release. The certificate of satisfaction shall have the same effect as a release executed by the holder of a mortgage or the named trustee under a deed of trust.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">When the holder of a mortgage or deed of trust note or other obligation secured by the deed of trust has agreed to release certain property from the lien of the mortgage or deed of trust and the holder or the agent of the holder of the mortgage or deed of trust note or other obligation secured by the deed of trust, or the trustee or successor trustee under the deed of trust executes and acknowledges a certificate of partial satisfaction or partial release substantially in the form specified under &#xA7; 4-203(e) of this article, containing the name of the debtor, holder, the authorized agent of the holder, or the trustee or successor trustee under the deed of trust, the date, the land record recording reference of the instrument to be partially released, and a description of the real property being released, it may be received by the clerk and indexed and recorded as any other instrument in the nature of a partial release. The certificate of partial satisfaction or partial release shall have the same effect as a partial release executed by the holder of a mortgage, the holder of the debt secured by a deed of trust, or the named trustee under a deed of trust.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A release of a mortgage or deed of trust may be made on a separate instrument if it states that the mortgagee, holder of the debt or obligation secured by the deed of trust, trustee, or assignee releases the mortgage or deed of trust and states the names of the parties to the mortgage or deed of trust and the date and recording reference of the mortgage or deed of trust to be released. In addition, any form of release that satisfies the requirements of a deed and is recorded as required by this article is sufficient.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A holder of a debt secured by a mortgage or deed of trust, or a successor of a holder, may release part of the collateral securing the mortgage or deed of trust by executing and acknowledging a partial release on an instrument separate from the mortgage or deed of trust.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A partial release shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be executed and acknowledged;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Contain the names of the parties to the mortgage or deed of trust, the date, and the land record recording reference of the instrument subject to the partial release; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Otherwise satisfy the requirements of a valid deed.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The clerk of the court shall accept, index, and record, as a partial release, an instrument that complies with and is filed under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Unless otherwise stated in an instrument recorded among the land records, a trustee under a deed of trust may execute, acknowledge, and deliver partial releases.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If a full or partial release of a mortgage or deed of trust is recorded other than at the foot of the recorded mortgage or deed of trust, the clerk shall place a reference to the book and page number or other place where the release is recorded on the recorded mortgage or deed of trust.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Unless otherwise expressly provided in the release, a full or partial release that is recorded for a mortgage or deed of trust that is re-recorded, amended, modified, or otherwise altered or affected by a supplemental instrument and which cites the released mortgage or deed of trust by reference to only the original recorded mortgage, deed of trust, or supplemental instrument to the original mortgage or deed of trust, shall be effective as a full or partial release of the original mortgage or deed of trust and all supplemental instruments to the original mortgage or deed of trust.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Unless otherwise expressly provided in the release, a full or partial release that is recorded for a mortgage or deed of trust, or for any re-recording, amendment, modification, or supplemental instrument to the mortgage or deed of trust shall terminate or partially release any related financing statements, but only to the extent that the financing statements describe fixtures that are part of the collateral described in the full or partial release.</section>
  </text>
</law>
