<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="grp" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-8-212.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section does not apply to a tenant under a residential lease that contains a liquidated damages...</catch_line>
  <order_by>212.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to a tenant under a residential lease that contains a liquidated damages clause or early termination clause that:<section prefix="(1)">Requires written notice to vacate of 1 month or less; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Imposes liability for rent less than or equal to 2 months' rent after the date on which the tenant vacates the leased premises.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to subsection (a) of this section and notwithstanding any other provision of this title, if a tenant under a residential lease meets the conditions set forth in subsection (c) of this section, the tenant's liability for rent under the lease may not exceed 2 months' rent after the date on which the tenant vacates the leased premises.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To qualify for the limitation of liability under subsection (b) of this section, the tenant shall provide to the landlord before the tenant vacates the leased premises:<section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of subsection (d) of this section, a written certification from a physician regarding an individual who is a named party in, or an authorized occupant under the terms of, the lease that states in substantially the following form:</section><section prefix="(1)">Substantially restricts the physical mobility of the patient within, or from entering and exiting, the leased premises; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Requires the patient to move to a home, facility, or institution to obtain a higher level of care than can be provided at the leased premises.</section><section prefix="(2)">A written notice of the termination of the lease stating the date by when the tenant will vacate the leased premises.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A certification that is provided to a landlord under subsection (c)(1) of this section shall be:<section prefix="(1)">Written by a physician who is licensed by the State Board of Physicians to practice medicine in the State under Title 14 of the Health Occupations Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">Prepared on the letterhead or printed prescription form of the physician; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Signed by the physician.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
