<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-8-210</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>210</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The landlord of any residential rental property shall include in a written lease or post a sign in a conspicuous place on that property listing the name, address, and telephone number of:<section prefix="(i)">The landlord; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The person, if any, authorized to accept notice or service of process on behalf of the landlord.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a landlord fails to comply with paragraph (1) of this subsection, notice or service of process shall be deemed to be proper if the tenant sends notice or service of process by any of the following means:<section prefix="(i)">To the person to whom the rent is paid;</section><section prefix="(ii)">To the address where the rent is paid; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">To the address where the tax bill is sent.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Montgomery County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In this subsection, "development" has the meaning provided in &#xA7; 11B-101 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Before execution by a tenant of a lease for an initial term of 125 days or more, the owner of any residential rental property within any condominium or development shall provide to the prospective tenant, to the extent applicable, a copy of the rules, declaration, and recorded covenants and restrictions that limit or affect the use and occupancy of the property or common areas and to which the owner is obligated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The written lease shall include a statement, if applicable, that the obligations of the owner that limit or affect the use and occupancy of the property are enforceable against the owner's tenant.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
