<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="grp" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-14-131</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following terms have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>131</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following terms have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Community association" means:<section prefix="(i)">A condominium council of unit owners organized under Title 11, Subtitle 1 of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A homeowners association organized under Title 11B of this article; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A cooperative housing corporation organized under Title 5, Subtitle 6B of the Corporations and Associations Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Community association management" means to manage the common property and services of a community association with the authority of the community association in its business, legal, financial, or other transactions with association members and nonmembers for a fee, commission, or other valuable consideration, including:<section prefix="(i)">Collecting monthly assessments;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Preparing budgets, financial statements, or other financial reports;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Negotiating contracts or otherwise coordinating or arranging for services or the purchase of property or goods for or on behalf of a community association;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Executing the resolutions and decisions of a community association and assisting the governing body of a community association and association members in complying with laws, contracts, covenants, rules, and bylaws;</section><section prefix="(v)">Managing the operation and maintenance of community-owned properties, including community centers, pools, golf courses, and parking areas; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Arranging, conducting, or coordinating meetings of a community association or the governing body of an association.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Office" means the Prince George's County Office of Community Relations.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Registry" means the Community Association Managers Registry.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only in Prince George's County.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">On or after January 1, 2011, the Office shall establish a Registry.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Any entity, including a sole proprietorship, that provides community association management services for community associations located in the county shall register with the Registry and renew its registration by January 31 of each year.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Office shall:<section prefix="(i)">Provide the registration form; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Collect a fee from each entity that registers under this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual fee charged shall be set at $100.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The registration form shall include:<section prefix="(1)">The name, address, and telephone number of the entity providing community association management services;</section><section prefix="(2)">The names, titles, and business telephone numbers of the principal officers of the entity;</section><section prefix="(3)">The designated contact person of the entity, including name, address, title, telephone number, and electronic mail address;</section><section prefix="(4)">The length of time the entity has been in existence and the length of time the entity has provided community association management services; and</section><section prefix="(5)">A listing of all community associations in the county as of December 31 of the previous year for which the entity provided community association management services.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Office may make any information received under this section available to the public, subject to the provisions of the Maryland Public Information Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A person who commits a willful violation of this section or who causes a person to commit a willful violation of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $1,000.</section>
  </text>
</law>
