<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-121" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-14-121</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Burial site" means any natural or prepared physical location, whether originally located below, on, or above the surface of the earth into which human remains or associated funerary objects are deposited as a part of a death rite or ceremony of any culture, religion, or group.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Burial site" includes the human remains and associated funerary objects that result from a shipwreck or accident and are intentionally left to remain at the site.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Cultural affiliation" means a relationship of shared group identity that can be reasonably traced historically between a present-day group, tribe, band, or clan and an identifiable earlier group.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Person in interest" means a person who:<section prefix="(i)">Is related by blood or marriage to the person interred in a burial site;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is a domestic partner, as defined in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Health - General Article, of a person interred in a burial site;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Has a cultural affiliation with the person interred in a burial site; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Has an interest in a burial site that the Office of the State's Attorney for the county where the burial site is located recognizes is in the public interest after consultation with a local burial sites advisory board or, if such a board does not exist, the Maryland Historical Trust.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Any person in interest may request the owner of a burial site or of the land encompassing a burial site that has been documented or recognized as a burial site by the public or any person in interest to grant reasonable access to the burial site for the purpose of restoring, maintaining, or viewing the burial site.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person requesting access to a burial site under subsection (b) or (d) of this section may execute an agreement with the owner of the burial site or of the land encompassing the burial site using a form similar to the form below:</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The owner of the burial site or of the land encompassing the burial site may grant access to the burial site in accordance with the terms of the agreement signed under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition to the provisions of subsection (b) of this section, if burials are still taking place at a burial site, any person who is related by blood or marriage, heir, appointed representative, or any other person in interest may request the owner of the land encompassing the burial site to grant reasonable access to the burial site for the purpose of transporting human remains to the burial site to inter the remains of a person for whose burial the site is dedicated, if access has not been provided in a covenant or deed of record describing the metes and bounds of the burial site.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except for willful or malicious acts or omissions, the owner of a burial site or of the land encompassing a burial site who allows persons to enter or go on the land for the purposes provided in subsections (b) and (d) of this section is not liable for damages in a civil action to a person who enters on the land for injury to person or property.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An owner of a burial site, a person who is related by blood or marriage to the person interred in a burial site, heir, appointed representative, or any other person in interest, or any other person may report the location of a burial site to the supervisor of assessments for a county, together with supporting documentation concerning the location and nature of the burial site.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The supervisor of assessments for a county may note the presence of a burial site on a parcel on the county tax maps maintained under &#xA7; 2-213 of the Tax - Property Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Nothing in this section may be construed to interfere with the normal operation and maintenance of a public or private cemetery being operated in accordance with State law.</section>
  </text>
</law>
