<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-105.9" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-7-105.9</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Bona fide tenant" means a tenant under a lease or tenancy described in &#xA7; 7-105.6(b)(1) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Residential property" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 7-105.1 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to any other notice required to be given by this Code or the Maryland Rules, the person authorized to make a sale in an action to foreclose a mortgage or deed of trust on residential property shall send, at the same time as the notice required under &#xA7; 7-105.1(f)(2) of this subtitle, a written notice addressed to "all occupants" at the address of the residential property in substantially the following form:</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The written notice required by this subsection shall be:<section prefix="(i)">A separate document;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Printed in at least 12 point type; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Sent by first-class mail.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The outside of the envelope containing the written notice required by this subsection shall state, on the address side, in bold, capitalized letters in at least 12 point type, the following: "IMPORTANT NOTICE TO ALL OCCUPANTS: FORECLOSURE INFORMATION ENCLOSED. OPEN IMMEDIATELY.".</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to any other notice required to be given by this Code or the Maryland Rules, the person authorized to make a sale in an action to foreclose a mortgage or deed of trust on residential property shall send a written notice of the sale not earlier than 30 days and not later than 10 days before the date of sale addressed to "all occupants" at the address of the residential property in substantially the following form:</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The written notice required by this subsection shall be:<section prefix="(i)">A separate document;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Printed in at least 12 point type; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Sent by first-class mail.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The outside of the envelope containing the written notice required by this subsection shall state, on the address side, in bold, capitalized letters in at least 12 point type, the following: "IMPORTANT NOTICE TO ALL OCCUPANTS: FORECLOSURE INFORMATION ENCLOSED. OPEN IMMEDIATELY.".</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to any other notice required to be given by this Code or the Maryland Rules, the person who purchases residential property in a foreclosure sale shall send, after the entry of a judgment awarding possession and before any attempt to execute the writ of possession, a written notice addressed to "all occupants" at the address of the residential property in substantially the following form:</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The written notice required by this subsection shall be:<section prefix="(i)">A separate document;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Printed in at least 12 point type; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Sent by first-class mail.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The outside of the envelope containing the written notice required by this subsection shall state, on the address side, in bold, capitalized letters in at least 12 point type, the following: "IMPORTANT NOTICE TO ALL OCCUPANTS: EVICTION INFORMATION ENCLOSED. OPEN IMMEDIATELY.".</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The person giving a notice required by this section shall file in the foreclosure proceeding after each notice is sent an affidavit of compliance with the provisions of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In the event of postponement of the sale, which may be done in the discretion of the person authorized to make the sale, no new or additional notice need be given pursuant to this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
