<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-130" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-14-130</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Single-family property" includes:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Single-family property" does not include property that contains more than four dwelling units.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Townhouse" means a single-family dwelling unit that is constructed in a horizontal series of attached units with property lines separating the units.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to a restriction concerning the installation or use of clotheslines on historic property that is listed in, or determined by the Director of the Maryland Historical Trust to be eligible for inclusion in, the Maryland Register of Historic Properties.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A contract, deed, covenant, restriction, instrument, declaration, rule, bylaw, lease agreement, rental agreement, or any other document concerning the installation or use of clotheslines on single-family property may not prohibit a homeowner or tenant from installing or using clotheslines on single-family property.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law or the terms of any contract, deed, covenant, restriction, instrument, declaration, rule, bylaw, lease agreement, rental agreement, or any other document concerning the installation or use of clotheslines on single-family property, a homeowner or tenant may not be prohibited from installing or using clotheslines on single-family property.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This section does not prohibit reasonable restrictions on:<section prefix="(1)">The dimensions, placement, or appearance of clotheslines for the purpose of protecting aesthetic values; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The placement of clotheslines for the purpose of protecting persons or property in the event of fire or other emergencies.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Before adopting any restriction concerning the installation or use of clotheslines on single-family property, a landlord or the governing body of a condominium, homeowners association, or housing cooperative shall:<section prefix="(1)">Hold an open meeting on the proposed restriction for the purpose of providing affected homeowners and tenants an opportunity to be heard; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide advance notice of the time and place of the open meeting by publishing the notice:<section prefix="(i)">In a community newsletter;</section><section prefix="(ii)">On a community bulletin board;</section><section prefix="(iii)">By means provided in the lease or governing documents of the condominium, homeowners association, or housing cooperative; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">By other means reasonably calculated to inform the affected homeowners and tenants.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
