<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-412" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-13-412</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an objection by a person claiming ownership under &#xA7; 13-401(2) of this subtitle is sustained under &#xA7; 13-408(a)(2) of this subtitle, then, within 60 days after entry of the final judgment sustaining the objection, the objector may apply under the previously returned certificate of survey for a patent for any of the vacant land which is described in the certificate of survey and to which the objection was sustained.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On filing an application in the proper form, the objector shall be substituted in the proceeding for the prior applicant, and further notice or proof is not required.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an order of abandonment is entered under &#xA7; 13-411 of this subtitle, then, within six months after entry of the order, any person may apply under the previously returned certificate of survey for a patent for any of the vacant land which is described in the certificate of survey.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner shall docket the applications for a patent under this subsection in the order received. In granting a request for the patent, any prior applicant for a warrant for the same land, other than the prior applicant whose proceeding was abandoned, shall be preferred in the order of original receipt of the applications for a warrant.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a request for a patent is granted under this subsection, the new applicant shall be substituted in the proceeding for the prior applicant, and further notice or proof is not required.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An application for a patent under subsection (a) or (b) of this section shall be in writing and contain:<section prefix="(1)">The name and address of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(2)">The name and address of each person, other than the applicant, who would obtain a direct or indirect title interest in the land for which the patent is sought if the patent were issued to the applicant;</section><section prefix="(3)">A description of the land to which the application applies, referenced to the description contained in the certificate of survey and accompanying plat;</section><section prefix="(4)">A description of any family, business, or financial relationship between the surveyor and all persons signing the application;</section><section prefix="(5)">The name to be given the land to be patented;</section><section prefix="(6)">A certification that the applicant has reimbursed the prior applicant for all reasonable expenses and surveyor's fees incurred by the prior applicant in the proceeding in connection with the land to which the application applies;</section><section prefix="(7)">Any other information the Commissioner requests under a rule or regulation adopted under &#xA7; 13-203 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(8)">A request for the issuance of a patent for the land described in the application.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The application shall be:<section prefix="(1)">Signed and verified by the applicant and each person required to be named under subsection (c)(2) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Accompanied by a deposit on the purchase price for the land and any outstanding expenses owed to the State by the prior applicant.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
