<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="grp" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-14-116.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>116.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Ground lease" means a residential lease or sublease for a term of years renewable forever subject to the payment of a periodic ground rent.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Ground lease holder" means the holder of the reversionary interest under a ground lease.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Ground lease holder" includes an agent of the ground lease holder.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Ground rent" means a rent issuing out of, or collectible in connection with, the reversionary interest under a ground lease.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Leasehold interest" means the tenancy in real property created under a ground lease.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Leasehold tenant" means the holder of the leasehold interest under a ground lease.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section applies to residential property that was or is used, intended to be used, or authorized to be used for four or fewer dwelling units.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not apply to property:<section prefix="(i)">Leased for business, commercial, manufacturing, mercantile, or industrial purposes, or any other purpose that is not primarily residential;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Improved or to be improved by any apartment, condominium, cooperative, or other building for multifamily use of greater than four dwelling units; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Leased for dwellings or mobile homes that are erected or placed in a mobile home development or mobile home park.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A ground lease holder may not collect a yearly or half-yearly installment payment of a ground rent due under the ground lease unless:<section prefix="(1)">The ground lease is registered with the State Department of Assessments and Taxation under Title 8, Subtitle 7 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">At least 60 days before the payment is due, the ground lease holder mails a bill to the last known address of the leasehold tenant and to the address of the property subject to the ground lease.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The bill shall include a notice in boldface type, at least as large as 14 point, in substantially the following form:</section>
  </text>
</law>
