<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8B-302" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-8B-302</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An affidavit of severance shall contain or be accompanied by:<section prefix="(1)">A statement identifying the owner of the real property from which the manufactured home is to be severed, including the name, residence, and mailing address of the owner;</section><section prefix="(2)">A description of the manufactured home, including the name of the manufacturer, the make, model name, model year, dimensions, manufacturer's serial number, and a statement whether the manufactured home is new or used;</section><section prefix="(3)">The liber and folio number for and the recordation date of the affidavit of affixation for the manufactured home; and</section><section prefix="(4)">A statement by an attorney admitted to practice law in the State, or a title insurance producer licensed by the State, that states that the manufactured home and the real property from which the manufactured home is to be severed are free and clear of any lien, security interest, or encumbrance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An affidavit of severance shall be acknowledged in writing and notarized.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The clerk of the circuit court of the county in which the real property from which a manufactured home is to be severed is located:<section prefix="(1)">Shall accept an affidavit of severance and any attachments for recordation and indexing; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May charge a reasonable fee for the recordation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In accordance with regulations adopted by the Motor Vehicle Administration, the Administration shall:<section prefix="(1)">Accept a certified copy of a recorded affidavit of severance for filing; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Issue a certificate of title for the severed manufactured home.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
