<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-12-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to payment otherwise authorized, a displacing agency  shall make an additional payment not in excess of $45,000 to any displaced person who is displaced from a dwelling actually owned and occupied by the displaced  person for not less than 180 days prior to the initiation of negotiations for the acquisition of the real property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The displacing agency may exceed the monetary limit stated  in paragraph (1) of this subsection on a case-by-case basis if it determines that  comparable housing cannot otherwise be made available within the limit; or</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The displacing agency may use any other measures  necessary to remedy the unavailability of comparable housing.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The additional payments shall include the following elements:<section prefix="(1)">Any amount which when added to the acquisition cost of the  dwelling acquired by the displacing agency, equals the reasonable cost of a comparable  replacement dwelling as defined in &#xA7; 12-201(d) of this subtitle.</section><section prefix="(2)">Any amount which will compensate the displaced person for any  increased interest costs and other debt service costs which the person is required to  pay for financing the acquisition of any comparable replacement dwelling. The amount  shall be paid only if the dwelling acquired by the displacing agency was encumbered   by a bona fide mortgage which was a valid lien on the dwelling for not less than 180  days prior to the initiation of negotiations for the acquisition of the dwelling. The  method of calculation shall be determined by the lead agency.</section><section prefix="(3)">Reasonable expenses incurred by the displaced person for evidence  of title, recording fees, and other closing costs incident to the purchase of the  replacement dwelling, but not including prepaid expenses.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
