<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-121" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-2-121</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "family child care home" means a unit:<section prefix="(1)">Registered under Title 5, Subtitle 5 of the Family Law Article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">In which the family child care provider or one or more of the children cared for resides.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to a recorded covenant or restriction affecting property that is:<section prefix="(1)">Governed by the provisions of Title 11B of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">Part of a condominium regime governed by Title 11 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Part of a cooperative housing corporation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A recorded covenant or restriction in a deed that prohibits or restricts commercial or business activity in general, but does not expressly apply to family child care homes, may not be construed to prohibit or restrict the establishment or operation of family child care homes.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The operation of a family child care home shall be considered a residential activity for purposes of construing a covenant or restriction described in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The provisions of this section do not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">A building containing more than four dwelling units located on one parcel of property or at one location;</section><section prefix="(2)">A covenant or restriction imposed in connection with a loan made or purchased by the Community Development Administration under Title 4, Subtitle 2 of the Housing and Community Development Article; or</section><section prefix="(3)">A lease.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
