<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-14-119</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>119</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section:<section prefix="(1)">"Cemetery" means the land or structures in Carroll County identified by the Carroll County Genealogical Society that are used for the interment of human remains; and</section><section prefix="(2)">"Cemetery" includes a grave, burial ground, monument, or gravestone.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to a permanent cemetery that is owned by:<section prefix="(1)">A cemetery company regulated under Title 5 of the Business Regulation Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">A nonprofit organization; or</section><section prefix="(3)">A governmental unit within the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person who owns land in Carroll County on which all or a part of a cemetery is located shall:<section prefix="(1)">Record the location of the cemetery without using a survey in the Office of the Clerk of the Circuit Court for Carroll County; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Give written notice of the location of the cemetery without using a survey to any prospective buyer of the land.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person who removes any human remains, monument, or gravestone from a cemetery located on land in Carroll County shall:<section prefix="(1)">Comply with &#xA7; 10-402 or &#xA7; 10-404 of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">Place the human remains, monument, or gravestone in a permanent cemetery in Carroll County; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Record the new location of the human remains, monument, or gravestone in the Office of the Clerk of the Circuit Court for Carroll County.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Clerk of the Circuit Court for Carroll County shall index and file documents received under this section in the land records under the grantor index.</section>
  </text>
</law>
