<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-11-105</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>105</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">When the declaration and bylaws are recorded, the developer shall record a condominium plat.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The condominium plat may consist of one or more sheets and shall contain at least the following particulars:<section prefix="(1)">The name of the condominium;</section><section prefix="(2)">A boundary survey of the property described in the declaration showing the location of all buildings on the property and the physical markings at the corners of the property;</section><section prefix="(3)">Diagrammatic floor plans of each building on the property which show the measured dimensions, floor area, and location of each unit in it. Common elements shall be shown diagrammatically to the extent feasible; and</section><section prefix="(4)">The elevation, or average elevation in case of minor variances, above sea level, or from a fixed known point, of the upper and lower boundaries of each unit delineated on the condominium plat.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each unit shall be designated on the condominium plat by a letter or number, or a combination of them, or other appropriate designation.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A condominium plat or any amendment to a condominium plat is sufficient for the purposes of this title if there is attached to, or included in it, a certificate of a professional land surveyor or property line surveyor authorized to practice in the State that:<section prefix="(1)">The plat, together with the applicable wording of the declaration, is a correct representation of the condominium described; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The identification and location of each unit and the common elements, as constructed, can be determined from them.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection or otherwise provided in this title, the condominium plat may be amended in the same manner and to the same extent as the declaration under &#xA7; 11-103(c)(1) of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The council of unit owners may petition the circuit court in equity for the county in which the condominium is located to correct an improper description of the units or common elements.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The petition may be brought only if:<section prefix="1.">The unit owners, at a special meeting called for that purpose, vote to petition the court to correct a specific error by a vote of at least 66 2/3 percent of the unit owners present and voting at a properly convened meeting;</section><section prefix="2.">The council of unit owners gives notice of the special meeting to each mortgagee of record for the condominium; and</section><section prefix="3.">An opportunity is provided for the mortgagees to speak at the special meeting upon written request to the council of unit owners.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The court may reform the condominium plat to correct the error or omission as the court considers appropriate, if:<section prefix="1.">The council of unit owners gives notice of the filing of the petition to each mortgagee and unit owner within 15 days of filing;</section><section prefix="2.">The council of unit owners files an affidavit with the court stating that the conditions of subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph have been met;</section><section prefix="3.">The council of unit owners proves, by a preponderance of the evidence, that there is an error or omission as provided in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph;</section><section prefix="4.">Any mortgagee with an interest in the condominium is permitted to intervene in the proceedings upon filing a motion to intervene as provided in the Maryland Rules;</section><section prefix="5.">The reformation does not substantially impair the property rights of any unit owner or mortgagee; and</section><section prefix="6.">The court issues an order of reformation.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">A final order of reformation may be appealed by any party within 30 days of its issuance. An order of reformation may not be recorded until the appeal period has lapsed or all appeals have been completed.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An amendment or order of reformation becomes effective upon recordation in the same manner as the condominium plat. If the condominium is registered with the Secretary of State, the council of unit owners shall file a copy of the reformation amendment with the Secretary of State within 15 days of recordation.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
