<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="grp" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-14-120</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>120</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Commercial property" does not include residential rental property.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Community association" means:<section prefix="(i)">A nonprofit association, corporation, or other organization that is:<section prefix="1.">Comprised of residents of a community within which a nuisance is located;</section><section prefix="2.">Operated exclusively for the promotion of social welfare and general neighborhood improvement and enhancement; and</section><section prefix="3.">Exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 501(c)(3) or (4) of the Internal Revenue Code; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">A nonprofit association, corporation, or other organization that is:<section prefix="1.">Comprised of residents of a contiguous community that is defined by specific geographic boundaries, within which a nuisance is located; and</section><section prefix="2.">Operated for the promotion of the welfare, improvement and enhancement of that community.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Controlled dangerous substance" means a substance listed in Schedule I or Schedule II under &#xA7; 5-402 or &#xA7; 5-403 of the Criminal Law Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Nuisance" means a property that is used:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">By persons who assemble for the specific purpose of illegally administering a controlled dangerous substance;</section><section prefix="2.">For the illegal manufacture, or distribution of:</section><section prefix="3.">For the illegal storage or concealment of a controlled dangerous substance in sufficient quantity to reasonably indicate under all the circumstances an intent to manufacture, distribute, or dispense:</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">For prostitution.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Operator" means a person that exercises control over property.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Operator" includes a property manager or any other person that is authorized to evict a tenant.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Owner" includes an owner-occupant.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Owner-occupant" includes an owner of commercial property that conducts business in any part of the property.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">"Property" includes a mobile home.</section>
      <section prefix="(10)">"Prostitution" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 11-301 of the Criminal Law Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(11)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Tenant" means the lessee or a person occupying property, whether or not a party to a lease.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Tenant" includes a lessee or a person occupying a mobile home, whether or not a party to a lease.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Tenant" does not include:<section prefix="1.">The owner of the property; or</section><section prefix="2.">A mobile home owner who leases or rents a site for residential use and resides in a mobile home park.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An action under &#xA7; 4-401 of the Courts Article to abate a nuisance may be brought by:<section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney of the county in which the nuisance is located;</section><section prefix="(2)">The county attorney or solicitor of the county in which the nuisance is located;</section><section prefix="(3)">A community association within whose boundaries the nuisance is located; or</section><section prefix="(4)">A municipal corporation within whose boundaries the nuisance is located.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An action under &#xA7; 4-401 of the Courts Article to abate a nuisance may be brought against:<section prefix="(1)">A tenant of the property where the nuisance is located;</section><section prefix="(2)">An owner of the property where the nuisance is located; or</section><section prefix="(3)">An operator of the property where the nuisance is located.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, an action may not be brought under this section concerning a commercial property until 30 days after the tenant, if any, and owner of record receive notice from a person entitled to bring an action under this section that a nuisance exists.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In Baltimore City, an action may not be brought under this section concerning a commercial property until 15 days after the tenant, if any, and owner of record receive notice from a person entitled to bring an action under this section that a nuisance exists.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice shall specify:<section prefix="(i)">The date and time of day the nuisance was first discovered; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The location on the property where the nuisance is allegedly occurring.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The notice shall be:<section prefix="(i)">Hand delivered to the tenant, if any, and the owner of record; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Sent by certified mail to the tenant, if any, and the owner of record.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to any service of process required by the Maryland Rules, the plaintiff shall cause to be posted in a conspicuous place on the property no later than 48 hours before the hearing the notice required under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice shall indicate:<section prefix="(i)">The nature of the proceedings;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The time and place of the hearing; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The name and telephone number of the person to contact for additional information.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A plaintiff is entitled to relief under this section whether or not an adequate remedy exists at law.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If, after a hearing, the court determines that a nuisance exists, the court may order any appropriate injunctive or other equitable relief.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, and in addition to or as a component of any remedy ordered under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the court may order:<section prefix="(i)">A tenant who knew or should have known of the existence of the nuisance to vacate the property within 72 hours; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">An owner or operator of the property to submit for court approval a plan of correction to ensure, to the extent reasonably possible, that the property will not again be used for a nuisance if:<section prefix="1.">The owner or operator is a party to the action; and</section><section prefix="2.">The owner or operator knew or should have known of the existence of the nuisance.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If a tenant fails to comply with an order under subsection (g) of this section and the owner or operator, and tenant, are parties to the action, the court, after a hearing, may order restitution of the possession of the property to the owner or operator.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the court orders restitution of the possession of the property under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the court shall immediately issue its warrant to the sheriff or constable commanding execution of the warrant within 5 days after issuance of the warrant.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph does not apply to an action brought under this section alleging the use of a property for prostitution.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If an owner, including an owner-occupant, fails to comply with an order under subsection (g) of this section, after a hearing the court may, in addition to issuing a contempt order or an order for any other relief, order that:<section prefix="1.">The property be sold, at the owner's expense, in accordance with the Maryland Rules governing judicial sales; or</section><section prefix="2.">The property be demolished if the property is unfit for habitation and the estimated cost of rehabilitation significantly exceeds the estimated market value of the property after rehabilitation.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies only to an action brought under this section alleging the use of a property for prostitution.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If an owner, including an owner-occupant, fails to comply with an order under subsection (g) of this section, after a hearing, the court may issue a contempt order.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If an owner-occupant fails to comply with an order under subsection (g) of this section regarding a nuisance in the owner-occupied unit of the property, after a hearing the court may, in addition to issuing a contempt order or an order for any other relief, order that:<section prefix="(i)">The owner-occupied unit be vacated within 72 hours; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The owner-occupied unit remain unoccupied for a period not to exceed 1 year or until the property is sold in an arm's length transaction.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subsection (g)(2) of this section, the court may order appropriate relief under subsection (g) of this section without proof that a defendant knew of the existence of the nuisance.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">In any action brought under this section:<section prefix="(1)">Evidence of the general reputation of the property is admissible to corroborate testimony based on personal knowledge or observation, or evidence seized during the execution of a search and seizure warrant, but shall not, in and of itself, be sufficient to establish the existence of a nuisance under this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Evidence that the nuisance had been discontinued at the time of the filing of the complaint or at the time of the hearing does not bar the imposition of appropriate relief by the court under subsection (g) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to an action against an owner, other than an owner-occupant, brought under this section alleging the use of a property for prostitution.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court may award court costs and reasonable attorney's fees to a community association that is the prevailing plaintiff in an action brought under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">An action under this section shall be heard within 14 days after service of process on the parties.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">This section does not abrogate any equitable or legal right or remedy under existing law to abate a nuisance.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An appeal from a judgment or order under this section shall be filed within 10 days after the date of the order or judgment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If either party files a request for oral argument, the court shall hear the oral argument within 7 days after the request is filed.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the appellant files a request for oral argument, the request shall be filed at the time of the filing of the appeal.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the appellee files a request for oral argument, the request shall be filed within 2 days of receiving notice of the appeal.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">Provisions of this article or public local laws applicable to actions between a landlord and tenant are not applicable to actions brought against a landlord or a tenant under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">All proceedings under this section are equitable in nature.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, when necessary to accomplish the purposes of this section, a law enforcement officer, an attorney in a municipal or county attorney's office, or an attorney in an office of the State's Attorney may disclose the contents of an executed search warrant and papers filed in connection with the search warrant to:<section prefix="(i)">An officer or director of the community association in which the nuisance is located, or the attorney representing the community association;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An owner, tenant, or operator of the searched property or an agent of the owner, tenant, or operator of the searched property; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">An attorney in a municipal or county attorney's office.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An affidavit may not be disclosed under this subsection while under seal in accordance with &#xA7; 1-203 of the Criminal Procedure Article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
