<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-8-402.3</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>402.3</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Ground lease" means a residential lease or sublease for a term of years renewable forever subject to the  payment of a periodic ground rent.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Ground lease holder" means the holder of the reversionary interest under a ground lease.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Ground lease holder" includes an agent of the ground lease holder.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Ground rent" means a rent issuing out of, or collectible in connection with, the reversionary interest under a ground lease.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Leasehold interest" means the tenancy in real property created under a ground lease.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Leasehold tenant" means the holder of the leasehold interest under a ground lease.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Property" means property subject to a ground lease against which a lien is intended to be imposed under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section applies to residential property that is or was used, intended to be used, or authorized to be used for four or fewer dwelling units.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not apply to property:<section prefix="(i)">Leased for business, commercial, manufacturing, mercantile, or industrial purposes, or any other purpose that is not primarily residential;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Improved or to be improved by any apartment, condominium, cooperative, or other building for multifamily use of greater than four dwelling units; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Leased for dwellings or mobile homes that are erected or placed in a mobile home development or mobile home park.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any provision of a ground lease giving the ground lease holder the right to reenter, the establishment of a lien under this section is the remedy for nonpayment of a ground rent.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not affect the right of a ground lease holder to bring a civil action against the leasehold tenant seeking a money judgment for the amount of the past due ground rent.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to &#xA7;&#xA7; 8-111 and 8-111.1 of this title and paragraph (2) of this subsection, if a ground rent is unpaid 6 months after its due date, the ground lease holder may obtain a lien under this section in the amount of the ground rent due.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The ground lease holder may not obtain a lien under this section unless:<section prefix="(i)">The ground lease is registered with the State Department of Assessments and Taxation under Subtitle 7 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The ground lease holder has mailed a bill for the payment due to the last known address of the leasehold tenant and to the address of the property subject to the ground lease in accordance with &#xA7; 14-116.1 of this article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A ground lease holder seeking to create a lien under this section shall give written notice to:<section prefix="(i)">The leasehold tenant; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Each mortgagee or trustee of the property whose lien is on record.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Notice under this subsection shall be served on the leasehold tenant by:<section prefix="1.">Certified mail, return receipt requested, addressed to the leasehold tenant or the leasehold tenant's successor in interest at the individual's current address; or</section><section prefix="2.">Personal delivery to the leasehold tenant or the leasehold tenant's successor in interest.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the ground lease holder is unable to serve the leasehold tenant under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, notice under this subsection shall be given by:<section prefix="1.">Mailing the notice to the leasehold tenant's last known address; and</section><section prefix="2.">Posting the notice in a conspicuous manner on the property on the door or other front part of the property by the ground lease holder in the presence of a competent witness.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Notice to any mortgagee or trustee under this subsection shall be given by sending the notice by certified and first-class mail to the most current address for notices as set forth in the land records or, if no such address is contained in the land records, to the mortgagee's or trustee's current address.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A notice under this subsection shall include:<section prefix="(i)">The name and address of the party seeking to create the lien;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A statement of intent to create a lien;</section><section prefix="(iii)">An identification of the ground lease;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A statement that the ground lease is registered with the State Department of Assessments and Taxation;</section><section prefix="(v)">The amount of ground rent alleged to be due;</section><section prefix="(vi)">A description of the property sufficient to identify the property;</section><section prefix="(vii)">A statement that the party to whom notice is given under this subsection has the right to object to the establishment of a lien by filing a complaint in the circuit court and the right to a hearing;</section><section prefix="(viii)">An explanation of the procedure to file a complaint and request a hearing; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">A statement that, unless the past due ground rent is paid or a complaint is filed under subsection (f) of this section within 45 days after the notice is served, a lien will be imposed on the property.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A party to whom notice is given under subsection (e) of this section may, within 45 days after the notice is served on the party, file a complaint in the circuit court for the county in which the property is located to determine whether a lien should be established.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A complaint filed under this subsection shall include:<section prefix="(i)">The name of the complainant and the name of the party seeking to establish the lien;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A copy of the notice served under subsection (e) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">An affidavit containing a statement of facts that would preclude establishment of the lien for the unpaid ground rent alleged in the notice.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A party filing a complaint under this subsection may request a hearing at which any party may appear to present evidence.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If a complaint is filed, the party seeking to establish the lien has the burden of proof.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Before any hearing held under subsection (f) of this section, the party seeking to establish a lien may supplement, by means of an affidavit, any information contained in the notice given under subsection (e) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">If a complaint is filed under subsection (f) of this section, the court shall review any pleadings filed, including any supplementary affidavit filed under subsection (h) of this section, and shall conduct a hearing if requested under subsection (f)(3) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the court determines that a lien should be established, it shall enter an order finding the amount of ground rent due and imposing a lien on the property identified in the notice under subsection (e) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the court determines that a lien should not be established, it shall enter an order denying a lien.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The court may award to the prevailing party in an action under this section:<section prefix="(i)">Court costs; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Reasonable expenses and attorney's fees not exceeding $500.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If a complaint was filed under subsection (f) of this section, the amount of the lien shall be for the ground rent found by the court to be due and any costs, expenses, and attorney's fees awarded by the court.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a complaint was not filed under subsection (f) of this section and the past due ground rent was not paid, the amount of the lien shall be for the amount alleged to be due in the notice under subsection (e) of this section and reasonable expenses and attorney's fees not exceeding $150.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The amount of the lien shall increase by the amount of ground rent accruing after the filing of the statement of lien in the land records plus simple interest at the rate prescribed by law accruing from the date of the filing of the statement of lien in the land records.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the court orders a lien to be imposed under subsection (j) of this section, or if the leasehold tenant or any mortgagee of the property fails to pay the amount of the lien under subsection (k)(1)(ii) of this section or file a complaint under subsection (f) of this section, the ground lease holder may file a statement of lien in the land records of the county in which the property is located.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A lien imposed under this subtitle has priority from the date the ground lease was created.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">A statement of lien is sufficient for purposes of this section if it is in substantially the following form:</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A lien under this section may be enforced and foreclosed by the party who obtained the lien in the same manner and subject to the same requirements, as the foreclosure of a mortgage or deed of trust containing neither a power of sale nor an assent to decree.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A foreclosure sale may not be made if, at any time before the sale, the lien is satisfied and the costs of giving notice of the sale are paid.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the property subject to the lien is sold at a foreclosure sale, the ground lease holder shall be paid out of the proceeds of the sale:<section prefix="(i)">For a redeemable ground rent, the amount of the lien and the redemption amount under &#xA7; 8-110(b)(2) of this title and the purchaser shall take title to the property free and clear of the ground lease; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">For an irredeemable ground rent, the amount of the lien and the purchaser shall take title to the property subject to the ground lease.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">If the lienholder cannot be located, the lien may be satisfied and the redeemable ground rent redeemed in accordance with &#xA7; 8-110(f) of this title by paying the amount of the lien and the amount set forth in &#xA7; 8-110(f)(4) of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
