<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="grp" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-14-125</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>125</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Community association" means a Maryland nonprofit corporation that:<section prefix="(i)">Is comprised of at least 20% of the total number of households as members, with a minimum membership of 25 households, of a local community that consists of 40 or more individual households as defined by specific geographic boundaries in the bylaws or charter of the community association;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Requires, as a condition of membership, the payment of monetary dues at least annually;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is operated primarily for the promotion of social welfare and general neighborhood improvement and enhancement;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Has been in existence for at least 1 year when it files suit under this section;</section><section prefix="(v)"><section prefix="1.">Is exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 501(c)(3) or (4) of the Internal Revenue Code; or</section><section prefix="2.">Has been included for a period of at least 1 year prior to bringing an action under this section in the "Directory of Organizations in Baltimore County" that is published by the Baltimore County Public Library; and</section></section><section prefix="(vi)">Is in good standing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Local code violation" means a violation under Title 22. "Nuisances" of the Baltimore County Code 1988.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Nuisance" means, within the boundaries of the community represented by the community association, an act or condition created, performed, or maintained on private property that constitutes a local code violation and that:<section prefix="(i)">Negatively impacts the well-being of other residents of the neighborhood; and</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">Is injurious to public health, safety, or welfare of neighboring residents; or</section><section prefix="2.">Obstructs the reasonable use of other property in the neighborhood.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section only applies to a nuisance located within the boundaries of Baltimore County.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A community association may seek injunctive and other equitable relief in the Circuit Court for Baltimore County for abatement of a nuisance upon showing that:<section prefix="(i)">The notice requirements under paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection have been satisfied; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The nuisance has not been abated.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An action may not be brought under this section based on a nuisance until 60 days after the community association gives notice of the violation and of the community association's intent to bring an action under this section by certified mail, return receipt requested, to the County Code enforcement agency.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An action under this section may not be brought if the County Code enforcement agency has filed an action for equitable relief from the nuisance.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An action may not be brought under this section until 60 days after the tenant, if any, and owner of record receive notice by certified mail, return receipt requested, from the community association that a nuisance exists and that legal action may be taken if the nuisance is not abated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The notice shall specify:<section prefix="1.">The nature of the alleged nuisance;</section><section prefix="2.">The date and time of day the nuisance was first documented;</section><section prefix="3.">The location on the property where the nuisance is allegedly occurring; and</section><section prefix="4.">The relief sought.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">In filing a suit under this section, an officer of the community association shall certify to the court:<section prefix="1.">What steps the community association has taken to satisfy the notice requirements under this subsection; and</section><section prefix="2.">That each condition precedent to the filing of an action under this section has been met.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The court shall determine in what amount and under what conditions, if any, a bond shall be filed by a community association in an action for relief under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A political subdivision of the State or any agency of a political subdivision is not subject to any action brought under this section or an action resulting from an action brought under this section against a private property owner.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, this section may not be construed to abrogate any equitable or legal right or remedy otherwise available under the law to abate a nuisance.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section may not be construed as granting standing for an action:<section prefix="(i)">Challenging any zoning, development, special exception, or variance application or approval;</section><section prefix="(ii)">In which the alleged nuisance consists of:<section prefix="1.">A condition relating to lead paint;</section><section prefix="2.">An interior physical defect of a property, except in situations that present a threat to neighboring properties; or</section><section prefix="3.">A vacant dwelling that is maintained in a boarded condition, free from trash and debris, and secure against trespassers and weather entry;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">Involving any violation of alcoholic beverages laws under Article 2B of the Code; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Involving any matter in which a certificate, license, permit, or registration is required or allowed under the Environment Article.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
