<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-132" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-14-132</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "wrongful detainer" means to hold possession of real property without the right of possession.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply if:<section prefix="(1)">The person in actual possession of the property has been granted possession under a court order;</section><section prefix="(2)">A remedy is available under Title 8 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Any other exclusive means to recover possession is provided by statute or rule.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not hold possession of property unless the person is entitled to possession of the property under the law.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a person violates subsection (c) of this section, a person claiming possession may make complaint in writing to the District Court of the county in which the property is located.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On receipt of a complaint under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the court shall summons immediately the person in possession to appear before the court on the day specified in the summons to show cause, if any, why restitution of the possession of the property to the person filing the complaint should not be made.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If, for any reason, the person in actual possession cannot be found, the person authorized to serve process by the Maryland Rules shall affix an attested copy of the summons conspicuously on the property.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If notice of the summons is sent to the person in possession by first-class mail, the affixing of the summons in accordance with paragraph (3) of this subsection shall constitute sufficient service to support restitution of possession.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A counterclaim or cross-claim may not be filed in an action brought under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the court determines that the complainant is legally entitled to possession, the court shall:<section prefix="(i)">Give judgment for restitution of the possession of the property to the complainant; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Issue its warrant to the sheriff or constable commanding the sheriff or constable to deliver possession to the complainant.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court may also give judgment in favor of the complainant for damages due to the wrongful detainer and for court costs and attorney fees if:<section prefix="(i)">The complainant claimed damages in the complaint; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The court finds that:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A person in actual possession who is not personally served with a summons is not subject to the personal jurisdiction of the District Court if the person appears in response to the summons and prior to the time that evidence is taken by the court and asserts that the appearance is only for the purpose of defending an in rem action.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Not later than 10 days from the entry of the judgment of the District Court, either party may appeal to the circuit court for the county in which the property is located.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The person in actual possession of the property may retain possession until the determination of the appeal if the person:<section prefix="(i)">Files with the court an affidavit that the appeal is not taken for delay; and</section><section prefix="(ii)"/></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On application of either party, the court shall set a hearing date for the appeal that is not less than 5 days or more than 15 days after the application for appeal.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Notice of the order for a hearing shall be served on the parties or the parties' counsels not less than 5 days before the hearing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">If the judgment of the circuit court shall be in favor of the person claiming possession, a warrant shall be issued by the court to the sheriff, who shall proceed immediately to execute the warrant.</section>
  </text>
</law>
