<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-304" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-9-304</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "retention proceeds" means moneys earned but retained under the terms of a contract or subcontract:<section prefix="(1)">By an owner to guarantee performance of the contract by a contractor;</section><section prefix="(2)">By a contractor to guarantee performance of a subcontract by a subcontractor; or</section><section prefix="(3)">By a subcontractor to guarantee performance of a subcontract by another subcontractor.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">A contract in an amount less than $250,000; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A contract or subcontract for a project funded wholly or in part by or through the Department of Housing and Community Development.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as provided in this section:<section prefix="(1)">If a contractor has furnished 100% security to guarantee the performance of a contract and 100% security to guarantee payment for labor and materials, including leased equipment:<section prefix="(i)">The retention proceeds under the terms of a contract may not exceed 5% of the contract price; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The retention proceeds of any payment due under the terms of a contract from an owner to a contractor may not exceed 5% of the payment;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The retention proceeds of any payment due under the terms of a contract from a contractor to a subcontractor may not exceed the percentage of retention proceeds from the owner to the contractor; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The retention proceeds of any payment due under the terms of a contract from a subcontractor to another subcontractor may not exceed the percentage of retention proceeds from the contractor to the subcontractor.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section may not be construed to prohibit the withholding of any amount due:<section prefix="(1)">From the owner to the contractor if the owner reasonably determines that the contractor's performance under the contract provides reasonable grounds for withholding the additional amount;</section><section prefix="(2)">From the contractor to any subcontractor if the contractor reasonably determines that the subcontractor's performance under the subcontract provides reasonable grounds for withholding the additional amount; or</section><section prefix="(3)">From a subcontractor to another subcontractor if the subcontractor determines that the other subcontractor's performance under the subcontract provides reasonable grounds for withholding the additional amount.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
