<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-11B-113</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>113</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a homeowners association depository in the office of the clerk of the court in each county and the City of Baltimore.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Consistent with the duties of a clerk of a court as enumerated in &#xA7; 2-201 of the Courts and Judicial Proceedings Article, the clerk of the court shall establish and thereafter maintain a depository for the purpose of making available to the public upon request the information to be deposited by homeowners associations.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The depository shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be established and maintained in each county and the City of Baltimore as a document file separate from the land records of the county or City;</section><section prefix="(2)">Contain a record of the names of all homeowners associations for each county and the City of Baltimore;</section><section prefix="(3)">Contain all disclosures deposited by a homeowners association; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Be available to the public for viewing and for obtaining copies during the regular business hours of the office of the clerk.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The clerk of the court is authorized to regulate the form and manner of documents deposited into the depository and to collect fees for a deposit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The clerk of the court shall permit the deposit of copies of disclosures, however reproduced.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The clerk of the court may adopt regulations as necessary or desirable to implement the depository.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The State Court Administrator shall establish, so as to cover the reasonable and ordinary expenses of maintaining the depository, the amount of the fees that the clerk of the court may charge for deposits in the depository.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The clerk of the court shall maintain a depository index; and</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">All disclosures shall be filed under the name of the homeowners association.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Material contained in the depository may not be viewed as recordation under Title 3 of this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
