<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="grp" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-7-105.3</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "holder of a subordinate interest" includes any condominium council of unit owners ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>105.3</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "holder of a subordinate interest" includes any condominium council of unit owners or homeowners association that has filed a request for notice of sale under subsection (c) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The person authorized to make a sale in an action to foreclose a mortgage or deed of trust shall give written notice of any proposed foreclosure sale to the holder of any subordinate mortgage, deed of trust, or other subordinate interest, including a judgment, in accordance with &#xA7; 7-105.2 of this subtitle and the requirements of Maryland Rule 14-210.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The land records office of each county shall maintain a current listing of recorded requests for notice of sale by holders of subordinate mortgages, deeds of trust, or other subordinate interests.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The holder of a subordinate mortgage, deed of trust, or other subordinate interest may file a request for notice under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each request for notice of sale shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be recorded in a separate docket or book which shall be indexed under the name of the holder of the superior mortgage or deed of trust and under the book and page numbers where the superior mortgage or deed of trust is recorded;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Identify the property in which the subordinate interest is held;</section><section prefix="(iii)">State the name and address of the holder of the subordinate interest; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Identify the superior mortgage or deed of trust by stating:<section prefix="1.">The names of the original parties to the superior mortgage or deed of trust;</section><section prefix="2.">The date the superior mortgage or deed of trust was recorded; and</section><section prefix="3.">The office, docket or book, and page where the superior mortgage or deed of trust is recorded.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, failure of a holder of a subordinate mortgage, deed of trust, or other subordinate interest to record a request for notice under this subsection does not affect the duty of a holder of a superior interest to provide notice as required under this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A holder of a superior interest does not have a duty to provide notice to a condominium council of unit owners or homeowners association that has not filed a request for notice under this subsection.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The person giving notice under this section shall file in the action:<section prefix="(1)">The return receipt from the notice; or</section><section prefix="(2)">An affidavit that:<section prefix="(i)">The notice provisions of this section have been complied with; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The address of the holder of the subordinate interest is not reasonably ascertainable.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The person authorized to make a sale in an action to foreclose a mortgage or deed of trust is not required to give notice to the holder of a subordinate mortgage, deed of trust, or other subordinate interest if:<section prefix="(1)">The existence of the mortgage, deed of trust, or other subordinate interest is not reasonably ascertainable;</section><section prefix="(2)">The identity or address of the holder of the mortgage, deed of trust, or other subordinate interest is not reasonably ascertainable;</section><section prefix="(3)">With respect to a recorded or filed subordinate mortgage, deed of trust, or other recorded or filed subordinate interest, the recordation or filing occurred after the later of:<section prefix="(i)">30 days before the day on which the foreclosure sale was actually held; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The date the action to foreclose the mortgage or deed of trust was filed;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">With respect to an unrecorded or unfiled subordinate mortgage, deed of trust, or other unrecorded or unfiled subordinate interest, the subordinate interest was created after the later of:<section prefix="(i)">30 days before the day on which the foreclosure sale was actually held; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The date the action to foreclose the mortgage or deed of trust was filed; or</section></section><section prefix="(5)">With respect to a condominium council of unit owners or homeowners association, the condominium council of unit owners or homeowners association has not filed a request for notice under subsection (c) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The right of a holder of a subordinate mortgage, deed of trust, or other subordinate interest to file an action for the failure of the person authorized to make a sale in an action to foreclose a mortgage or deed of trust to comply with the provisions of this section shall expire 3 years after the date of the order ratifying the foreclosure sale.</section>
  </text>
</law>
