<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-10-705</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>705</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Conservation easement" means an easement, covenant, restriction, or condition on real property, including an amendment to an easement, covenant, restriction, or condition, as provided for in &#xA7; 2-118 of this article that is:<section prefix="(i)">Owned by:<section prefix="1.">The Maryland Environmental Trust;</section><section prefix="2.">The Maryland Historical Trust;</section><section prefix="3.">The Maryland Agricultural Land Preservation Foundation;</section><section prefix="4.">The Maryland Department of Natural Resources;</section><section prefix="5.">A county or municipal corporation and is funded by the Maryland Department of Natural Resources, the Rural Legacy Program, or a local agricultural preservation program; or</section><section prefix="6.">A land trust; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Required by a permit issued by the Department of the Environment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Land trust" means an organization that:<section prefix="(i)">Is a qualified organization under &#xA7; 170(h)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code and regulations adopted under that section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has executed a cooperative agreement with the Maryland Environmental Trust.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section applies to the sale of property encumbered by a conservation easement.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not apply to the sale of property in an action to foreclose a mortgage or deed of trust.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A vendor of real property encumbered by one or more conservation easements shall, on or before entering into a contract for the sale of the property, deliver to each purchaser:<section prefix="(1)">The notice described in subsection (d) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A copy of all conservation easements encumbering the property.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The notice required under subsection (c)(1) of this section shall be in a form substantially the same as the following:</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A purchaser who receives the notice and copies of the easements required under subsection (c) of this section on or before entering into a contract of sale does not have the right to rescind the contract of sale based on the information received from the vendor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A purchaser who does not receive the notice and copies of the easements required under subsection (c) of this section on or before entering into a contract of sale, on written notice to the vendor or the vendor's agent:<section prefix="(i)">Has the unconditional right to rescind the contract at any time before, or within 5 days after, receipt of the notice and copies of the easements; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is entitled to the immediate return of any deposits made in accordance with the contract.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 30 calendar days after a sale of property encumbered by a conservation easement, the purchaser shall notify the owner of a conservation easement of the sale.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notification shall include, to the extent reasonably available:<section prefix="(i)">The name and address of the purchaser;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The name of the vendor;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The address of the property; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The date of the sale.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In satisfying the requirements of subsection (c) of this section, the vendor and purchaser shall be entitled to rely on the conservation easement recorded in the land records of the county where the property is located.</section>
  </text>
</law>
