<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-11A-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Time-shares may be created in any unit in existence before January 1, 1985 unless prohibited by a project instrument. If time-shares are not prohibited by the project instrument, the owners of at least 34 percent of the units in the project may sign and record a document among the land records of the county where the project is located, stating an intent to limit time-shares in the project, and referring to this section. Thereafter, no person or other entity may become a developer with respect to more than 1 unit in the project, but this limitation will not apply to units of which the developer was owner of record prior to the recording of the aforementioned document.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this paragraph, "recorded covenants and restrictions" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 11B-101 of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The owners of property in a residential community governed by recorded covenants and restrictions may prohibit time-shares on any property subject to the recorded covenants and restrictions by amending the recorded covenants and restrictions by a vote of the owners in accordance with the majority requirements of the recorded covenants and restrictions.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The provisions of subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph do not apply to an existing time-share unit in a project.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The limitations on time-shares created by the recording of a document as provided in subsection (a) of this section may be removed by the recordation among the land records of the county where the project is located of a document removing time-share limitations signed by owners of at least 80 percent of the units in the project.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For the purposes of signing a document provided for in subsection (a) or subsection (b) of this section, any person designated by the owners of a majority of the time-shares in a unit may sign as the owner of that unit unless the relevant time-share instrument provides otherwise.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">All documents provided for in this section shall be under oath or affirmed under penalty of perjury.</section>
  </text>
</law>
