<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-15-102</section_number>
  <catch_line>Unless otherwise specifically provided in this article, the provisions of this article are applicabl...</catch_line>
  <order_by>102</order_by>
  <text>Unless otherwise specifically provided in this article, the provisions of this article are applicable on the effective date. In addition,<section prefix=""><section prefix="(1)">Section 3-101(a) of this article applies to all deeds whether executed before or after the effective date.</section><section prefix="(2)">Section 3-102 of this article applies to all instruments whether recorded before or after the effective date.</section><section prefix="(3)">Section 3-104(f)(1) of this article applies only to documents executed on or after May 31, 1966.</section><section prefix="(4)">Section 3-104(f)(2) of this article applies only to all deeds recorded after June 1, 1967.</section><section prefix="(5)">Section 3-104(f)(6) of this article applies only to all deeds recorded after June 1, 1965.</section><section prefix="(6)">Sections 4-101 and 4-103 of this article apply only to all deeds executed on or after the effective date.</section><section prefix="(7)">Section 4-106(e) of this article applies only to all mortgages and deeds of trust executed on or after the effective date.</section><section prefix="(8)">Section 2-113 of this article applies only to all deeds executed after April 7, 1886.</section><section prefix="(9)">Section 2-114 of this article applies to all inter vivos instruments executed on or after the effective date and to all testamentary instruments where the testator died after the effective date.</section><section prefix="(10)">Section 7-101 of this article applies only to mortgages and mortgage assignments executed on or after the effective date.</section><section prefix="(11)">Section 7-102 of this article applies only to mortgages and deeds of trust executed on or after the effective date.</section><section prefix="(12)">Section 7-103(b) of this article applies only to payments made on or after the effective date.</section><section prefix="(13)">Section 7-105.4 of this article applies to all mortgages or deeds of trust whether executed before or after the effective date.</section><section prefix="(14)">Section 7-106(a) of this article applies only to deeds of trust executed on or after the effective date.</section><section prefix="(15)">Section 7-106(c) of this article applies to all proceedings instituted on or after the effective date, whether the mortgage or deed of trust was executed before or after the effective date.</section><section prefix="(16)">Section 8-203(b) of this article applies only to those leases entered into, renegotiated, or renewed after July 1, 1972.</section><section prefix="(17)">Section 8-203(d) of this article applies to all security deposits held by a landlord before July 1, 1972, with interest accruing from July 1, 1972, and to all security deposits received by the landlord on or after July 1, 1972, with interest accruing from the date of receipt.</section><section prefix="(18)">Section 8-402(a) of this article applies to all leases whose terms expire on or after the effective date, whether or not the lease term commenced before the effective date.</section><section prefix="(19)">Section 10-401 of this article applies to all contracts whether recorded before or after the effective date.</section><section prefix="(20)">Section 10-402 of this article applies to all options whether recorded before or after the effective date.</section><section prefix="(21)">Section 14-103 of this article applies to all sales mentioned in that section which occur on or after the effective date.</section><section prefix="(22)">Section 14-111 of this article applies to all proceedings commenced on or after the effective date.</section></section></text>
</law>
