<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-7-319.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>319.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commissioner may enforce the provisions of this subtitle by exercising any of the powers provided under &#xA7;&#xA7; 2-113 through 2-116 of the Financial Institutions Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner may seek an injunction to prohibit a person who has engaged or is engaging in a violation of this subtitle from engaging or continuing to engage in the violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court may enter any order or judgment necessary to:<section prefix="(i)">Prevent the use by a person of any prohibited practice;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Restore to a person any money or real or personal property acquired from the person by means of any prohibited practice; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Appoint a receiver in case of willful violation of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In any action brought by the Commissioner under this subsection, the Commissioner is entitled to recover the costs of the action for the use of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner may enforce the provisions of this subtitle by requiring a violator to take affirmative action to correct the violation including the restitution of money or property to any person aggrieved by the violation.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commissioner may:<section prefix="(1)">Investigate violations of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Aid any other unit of State government that has regulatory jurisdiction over the business activities of the violator.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commissioner may cooperate in the investigation and prosecution of any violation of this subtitle with the Office of the Attorney General, the State's Attorney, or any other unit of law enforcement.</section>
  </text>
</law>
