<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="grp" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-13-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>At any stage of a proceeding under this title, if an applicant dies or assigns his rights in the app...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At any stage of a proceeding under this title, if an applicant dies or assigns his rights in the application, warrant, certificate of survey, or land described in the application, the assignee, personal representative, heir, or legatee of the applicant may request that he be substituted for the applicant.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On filing a request for substitution in the proper form, the person making the request shall be substituted as the applicant for all purposes in the proceeding.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A request for substitution shall be in writing and contain:<section prefix="(1)">The name and address of the person requesting substitution;</section><section prefix="(2)">The name and address of each person, other than the person requesting substitution and those persons named in the original application, who would obtain a direct or indirect title interest in the land for which the patent is sought if the patent were issued to the person requesting substitution;</section><section prefix="(3)">A statement of the manner by which the person requesting substitution succeeded to the rights of the original applicant;</section><section prefix="(4)">The original or an officially certified copy of each document by which the succession of interest was effected;</section><section prefix="(5)">A description of all changes in and required corrections of any of the statements and facts contained in the original application;</section><section prefix="(6)">A statement that, except as described under item (5) of this subsection, the statements and facts contained in the original application are accurate and complete to the best of the knowledge, information, and belief of all persons signing the request; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Any other information the Commissioner requires under a rule or regulation adopted under &#xA7; 13-203 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The request for substitution shall be signed and verified by the person requesting substitution and by each person required to be named under subsection (b)(2) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
