<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="grp" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-13-107</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "claimant" means a person who claims legal title to abandoned land for which a cert...</catch_line>
  <order_by>107</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "claimant" means a person who claims legal title to abandoned land for which a certificate of reservation for public use has been issued.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If abandoned land was patented prior to the issuance of a certificate of reservation for public use by a unit of State government, a claimant may file a written claim for legal title to the land with the unit of State government that reserved the land for public use.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the unit of State government that reserved the land for public use determines that the claimant has legal title to the land, the unit of State government shall:<section prefix="(1)">Pay the claimant fair market value for the land, as determined by the lower of two independent appraisals of the land; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Notify the Commissioner that the land is no longer needed for public use.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Any action taken by a unit of State government under subsection (c) of this section is subject to approval by the Board of Public Works.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a unit of State government that reserved land for public use determines that a claimant does not have legal title to the land, the unit of State government shall issue a written denial of the claimant's claim.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A claimant who is aggrieved by the denial of a claim under this section may file an action in the circuit court of the jurisdiction in which the land is located to quiet title to the land.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A claim under this section is barred unless the claimant files the claim within 20 years after the date that the unit of State government obtains a certificate of reservation for public use of the land.</section>
  </text>
</law>
