<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-11-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated unless otherwise apparent from context.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Board of directors" means the persons to whom some or all of the powers of the council of unit owners have been delegated under this title or under the condominium bylaws.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Board of directors" includes any reference to "board".</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Common elements" means all of the condominium except the units.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Limited common elements" means those common elements identified in the declaration or on the condominium plat as reserved for the exclusive use of one or more but less than all of the unit owners.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"General common elements" means all the common elements except the limited common elements.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Common expenses and common profits" means the expenses and profits of the council of unit owners.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Condominium" means property subject to the condominium regime established under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Council of unit owners" means the legal entity described in &#xA7; 11-109 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Developer" means any person who subjects his property to the condominium regime established by this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Electronic transmission" means any form of communication, not directly involving the physical transmission of paper, that creates a record that:<section prefix="(1)">May be retained, retrieved, and reviewed by a recipient of the communication; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May be reproduced directly in paper form by a recipient through an automated process.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Governing body" means the council of unit owners, board of directors, or any committee of the council of unit owners or board of directors.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Housing agency" means a housing agency of a county or incorporated municipality or some other agency or entity of a county or incorporated municipality designated as such by law or ordinance.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Mortgagee" means the holder of any recorded mortgage, or the beneficiary of any recorded deed of trust, encumbering one or more units.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Moving expenses" means costs incurred to:<section prefix="(1)">Hire contractors, labor, trucks, or equipment for the transportation of personal property;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pack and unpack personal property;</section><section prefix="(3)">Disconnect and install personal property;</section><section prefix="(4)">Insure personal property to be moved; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Disconnect and reconnect utilities such as telephone service, gas, water, and electricity.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Occupant" means any lessee or guest of a unit owner.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Percentage interests" means the interests, expressed as a percentage, fraction or proportion, established in accordance with &#xA7; 11-107 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Property" means unimproved land, land together with improvements thereon, improvements without the underlying land, or riparian or littoral rights associated with land. Property may consist of noncontiguous parcels or improvements.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Rental facility" means property containing dwelling units intended to be leased to persons who occupy the dwellings as their residences.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Unit" means a three-dimensional space identified as such in the declaration and on the condominium plat and shall include all improvements contained within the space except those excluded in the declaration, the boundaries of which are established in accordance with &#xA7; 11-103(a)(3) of this title. A unit may include 2 or more noncontiguous spaces.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Unit owner" means the person, or combination of persons, who hold legal title to a unit. A mortgagee or a trustee designated under a deed of trust, as such, may not be deemed a unit owner.</section>
  </text>
</law>
