<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="grp" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-3-108.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>108.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Appendix plat" means a plat of a single lot or parcel of land that:<section prefix="(i)">Is produced on a single page not larger than 8.5 inches by 14 inches;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is presented for recordation as part of a deed or other instrument; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Does not require subdivision approval.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Plat" includes any diagram that purports to represent the boundaries of any land.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Plat" does not include a plat or microfilm aperture card that:<section prefix="1.">Meets archival standards for permanent records; and</section><section prefix="2.">Depicts property or rights-of-way to be acquired or granted by the State Highway Administration.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Subdivision approval" means approval required under subdivision regulations adopted in Queen Anne's County in accordance with Title 5 of the Land Use Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The provisions of this section apply only in Queen Anne's County.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Clerk of the Circuit Court for Queen Anne's County may not accept for record any plat that does not comply with the provisions of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The provisions of this subsection do not apply to appendix plats.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who is recording a plat shall deliver a set of 3 copies of each page of the plat at the time of recordation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each copy of a page of a plat shall conform to all of the provisions of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The fee for recording each set of plats is $25.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In accordance with the provisions of &#xA7; 3-304 of this title, the Clerk of the Circuit Court of Queen Anne's County shall maintain and distribute any plat that the Clerk records.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for the provisions relating to legibility and scale, the provisions of this subsection do not apply to appendix plats.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each page of a plat shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be legible;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be drawn to a stated scale;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Be 18 inches by 24 inches in size, including a one and one-half inch unused margin for binding along the left edge of the page; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Be prepared in black ink on transparent mylar or by another process comparable to original quality that conforms to the archival standards established by the Maryland Hall of Records.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A plat consisting of more than 1 page shall include an index page that includes and delineates each area shown on all other pages.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person who is recording a plat shall submit, along with the plat, a written certificate that is signed by:<section prefix="(1)">A person authorized to certify subdivision approval under regulations concerning subdivisions adopted by the county or a municipal corporation under Title 5 of the Land Use Article, and which states that:<section prefix="(i)">Subdivision approval has been given; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Subdivision approval is not required; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Each owner of the property, and which states that the plat does not require subdivision approval.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A certificate under subsection (f) of this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be in writing; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Contain the actual signature of the person who makes the certificate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A person who willfully executes or presents for recordation a plat that contains a certificate required by subsection (f) of this section and that is false is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $500 or imprisonment not exceeding 6 months or both.</section>
  </text>
</law>
