<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-310" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-7-310</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to any other right under law to rescind a contract, the homeowner of a residence in default has the right to rescind a contract for the sale or transfer of the residence in default within 5 days after the execution of the contract.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Any provision in a contract or other agreement concerning a sale or transfer of a residence in default that attempts or purports to waive the homeowner's rights under this title, consent to jurisdiction for litigation or choice of law in a state other than Maryland, consent to venue in a county other than the county in which the property is located, or impose any costs or filing fees greater than the fees required to file an action in a circuit court, is void.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except when a primary mortgage lender takes a deed in lieu of foreclosure, a sale or transfer of a residence in default may not be executed using a quitclaim deed.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A notice of rescission under this section:<section prefix="(1)">Shall be in writing but need not take any particular form specified in this subtitle or any form contained in any agreement with the purchaser or transferee; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is effective, however expressed, if it indicates the intention of the homeowner to rescind the contract.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The right to rescind may not be conditioned on the repayment of any funds, provided however that any debt existing prior to a rescission shall continue to exist.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Within 10 days after receipt of a notice of rescission, the purchaser or transferee shall return, without condition, any original deed, title, contract, and any other document signed by the homeowner.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">During the 5-day rescission period, a deed or other document affecting title to the homeowner's residence in default may not be recorded.</section>
  </text>
</law>
