<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-14-128</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>128</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The provisions of this section shall apply to any residential property, including property that is subject to the provisions of:<section prefix="(1)">Title 8, Title 8A, Title 11, Title 11A, or Title 11B of this article; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Title 5, Subtitle 6B of the Corporations and Associations Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Regardless of the terms of any contract, deed, covenant, restriction, instrument, declaration, rule, bylaw, lease agreement, rental agreement, or any other document concerning the display of flags or decorations by a homeowner or tenant on residential property, a homeowner or tenant may not be prohibited from displaying on the premises of the property in which the homeowner or tenant is entitled to reside one portable, removable flag of the United States in a respectful manner, consistent with 4 U.S.C. &#xA7;&#xA7; 4 through 10, as amended, and subject to reasonable rules and regulations adopted pursuant to subsection (d) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The terms of any contract, deed, covenant, restriction, instrument, declaration, rule, bylaw, lease agreement, rental agreement, or any other document concerning the display of flags or decorations by a homeowner or tenant on residential property may not prohibit or unduly restrict the right of a homeowner or tenant to display on the premises of the property in which the homeowner or tenant is entitled to reside one portable, removable flag of the United States in a respectful manner, consistent with 4 U.S.C. &#xA7;&#xA7; 4 through 10, as amended, and subject to reasonable rules and regulations adopted under subsection (d) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the board of directors of a condominium, homeowners association, or housing cooperative, or a landlord may adopt reasonable rules and regulations regarding the placement and manner of display of the flag of the United States and a flagpole used to display the flag of the United States on the premises of the property in which the homeowner or tenant is entitled to reside.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before adopting any rules or regulations under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the board of directors of the condominium, homeowners association, or housing cooperative, or the landlord shall:<section prefix="(i)">Hold an open meeting on the proposed rules and regulations for the purpose of providing affected homeowners and tenants an opportunity to be heard; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provide advance notice of the time and place of the open meeting by publishing the notice in a community newsletter, on a community bulletin board, by means provided in the documents governing the condominium, homeowners association, or housing cooperative, or in the lease, or by other means reasonably calculated to inform the affected homeowners and tenants.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
