<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="grp" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-8A-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>A park owner shall establish reasonable rules related to the order, peace, health, safety, and quali...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A park owner shall establish reasonable rules related to the order, peace, health, safety, and qualification standards of mobile homes, residents, and the operation of the park.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A rule established under paragraph (1) of this subsection may not be enforced unless it is in writing and is delivered to each resident in the park.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A park owner shall prescribe reasonable, written standards for the mobile homes to be placed or retained in the park, their size, quality, appearance, material specification, construction and safety condition.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A rule adopted pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection setting a standard for the size, quality, material specification, or construction of mobile homes may not be enforced against any individual:<section prefix="(i)">Who, at the time the standard is adopted, is the owner or tenant of a mobile home in the park, as to that mobile home; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Who purchases a mobile home from the individual who owned the home at the time the standard was adopted.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A park owner shall prescribe reasonable, written maintenance standards for any mobile home in the park or immediate area surrounding the mobile home, in accordance with the State or county health laws or regulations.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">All rules and standards shall be fair and reasonable and, except as provided in paragraph (b)(2) of this section, shall apply uniformly to all residents in the park.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A rule or standard is not enforceable unless the park owner:<section prefix="(1)">Delivers a copy of the rule or standard to each resident affected thereby; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Posts a copy of the rule or standard in a conspicuous place in the park.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An amendment to a rule or standard is not effective until the later of:<section prefix="(1)">The date specified in the amendment; or</section><section prefix="(2)">30 days after the park owner delivers to each resident written notice of the proposed amendment.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
