<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-309" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-13-309</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the surveyor to whom a warrant is directed is unable or unwilling to perform the duties set out in the warrant, the applicant may request the Commissioner in writing for issuance of a substitute warrant to another surveyor chosen by the applicant. The request shall set forth in detail the reasons for requesting the substitute warrant.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On receipt of the request, the Commissioner may issue a substitute warrant to the successor surveyor. If notice of the original warrant was published under &#xA7; 13-308 of this subtitle, further publication is not required.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The issuance of a substitute warrant does not extend the time for filing the certificate of survey. However, a request for extension may be filed under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the surveyor to whom an original or substitute warrant is directed is able and willing to perform the duties set out in the warrant but is unable to return his certificate in the time otherwise required by this subtitle, the applicant or the surveyor may request the Commissioner in writing for an extension of that time. The request shall set forth in detail the reasons for requesting the extension.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On receipt of the request, the Commissioner:<section prefix="(i)">May extend the time for the return of the certificate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall advise the applicant, the surveyor, and each objector in writing of his decision and the period of any extension granted.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
