<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-111" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-11-111</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The council of unit owners or the body delegated in the bylaws of a condominium to carry out the responsibilities of the council of unit owners may adopt rules for the condominium if:<section prefix="(1)">Each unit owner is mailed or delivered:<section prefix="(i)">A copy of the proposed rule;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Notice that unit owners are permitted to submit written comments on the proposed rule; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Notice of the proposed effective date of the proposed rule;</section></section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">Before a vote is taken on the proposed rule, an open meeting is held to allow each unit owner or tenant to comment on the proposed rule;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The meeting held under this paragraph may not be held unless:</section></section><section prefix="(3)">After notice has been given to unit owners as provided in this subsection, the proposed rule is passed at a regular or special meeting by a majority vote of those present and voting of the council of unit owners or the body delegated in the bylaws of the condominium to carry out the responsibilities of the council of unit owners.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The vote on the proposed rule shall be final unless:<section prefix="(i)">Within 15 days after the vote, to adopt the proposed rule, 15 percent of the council of unit owners sign and file a petition with the body that voted to adopt the proposed rule, calling for a special meeting;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A quorum of the council of unit owners attends the meeting; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">At the meeting, 50 percent of the unit owners present and voting disapprove the proposed rule, and the unit owners voting to disapprove the proposed rule are more than 33 percent of the total votes in the condominium.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">During the special meetings held under paragraph (1) of this subsection, unit owners, tenants, and mortgagees may comment on the proposed rule.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A special meeting held under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be held:<section prefix="(i)">After the unit owners and any mortgagees have at least 15 days' written notice of the meeting; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Within 30 days after the day on which the petition is received by the body.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each unit owner or tenant may request an individual exception to a rule adopted while the individual was the unit owner or tenant of the condominium.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The request for an individual exception under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be:<section prefix="(i)">Written;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Filed with the body that voted to adopt the proposed rule; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Filed within 30 days after the effective date of the rule.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each rule adopted under this section shall state that the rule was adopted under the provisions of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A rule may not be adopted under this section after July 1, 1984 if the rule is inconsistent with the condominium declaration or bylaws.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This section does not apply to rules adopted before July 1, 1984.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
