<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="grp" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-11-113</section_number>
  <catch_line>Unless the declaration or bylaws state otherwise, the dispute settlement mechanism provided by this ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>113</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Unless the declaration or bylaws state otherwise, the dispute settlement mechanism provided by this section is applicable to complaints or demands formally arising on or after January 1, 1982.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The council of unit owners or board of directors may not impose a fine, suspend voting, or infringe upon any other rights of a unit owner or other occupant for violations of rules until the following procedure is followed:<section prefix="(1)">Written demand to cease and desist from an alleged violation is served upon the alleged violator specifying:<section prefix="(i)">The alleged violation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The action required to abate the violation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">A time period, not less than 10 days, during which the violation may be abated without further sanction, if the violation is a continuing one, or a statement that any further violation of the same rule may result in the imposition of sanction after notice and hearing if the violation is not continuing.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Within 12 months of the demand, if the violation continues past the period allowed in the demand for abatement without penalty or if the same rule is violated subsequently, the board serves the alleged violator with written notice of a hearing to be held by the board in session. The notice shall contain:<section prefix="(i)">The nature of the alleged violation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The time and place of the hearing, which time may be not less than 10 days from the giving of the notice;</section><section prefix="(iii)">An invitation to attend the hearing and produce any statement, evidence, and witnesses on his or her behalf; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The proposed sanction to be imposed.</section></section><section prefix="(3)">A hearing occurs at which the alleged violator has the right to present evidence and present and cross-examine witnesses. The hearing shall be held in executive session pursuant to this notice and shall afford the alleged violator a reasonable opportunity to be heard. Prior to the effectiveness of any sanction hereunder, proof of notice and the invitation to be heard shall be placed in the minutes of the meeting. This proof shall be deemed adequate if a copy of the notice, together with a statement of the date and manner of delivery, is entered by the officer or director who delivered the notice. The notice requirement shall be deemed satisfied if the alleged violator appears at the meeting. The minutes of the meeting shall contain a written statement of the results of the hearing and the sanction, if any, imposed.</section><section prefix="(4)">A decision pursuant to these procedures shall be appealable to the courts of Maryland.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If any unit owner fails to comply with this title, the declaration, or bylaws, or a decision rendered pursuant to this section, the unit owner may be sued for damages caused by the failure or for injunctive relief, or both, by the council of unit owners or by any other unit owner. The prevailing party in any such proceeding is entitled to an award for counsel fees as determined by court.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The failure of the council of unit owners to enforce a provision of this title, the declaration, or bylaws on any occasion is not a waiver of the right to enforce the provision on any other occasion.</section>
  </text>
</law>
