<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-11B-117</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>117</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">As provided in the declaration, a lot owner shall be liable for all homeowners association assessments and charges that come due during the time that the lot owner owns the lot.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to any other remedies available at law, a homeowners association may enforce the payment of the assessments and charges provided in the declaration by the imposition of a lien on a lot in accordance with the Maryland Contract Lien Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not limit or affect the priority of:<section prefix="(i)">A lien for the annual charge provided first priority over a deed of trust or mortgage by the deed, agreement, and declaration of covenants, easements, charges, and liens dated December 13, 1966, and recorded in the land records of Howard County (the Columbia Association Declaration); or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any lien, secured interest, or other encumbrance with priority that is held by or for the benefit of, purchased by, assigned to, or securing any indebtedness to:<section prefix="1.">The State or any county or municipal corporation in the State;</section><section prefix="2.">Any unit of State government or the government of any county or municipal corporation in the State; or</section><section prefix="3.">An instrumentality of the State or any county or municipal corporation in the State.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the case of a foreclosure of a mortgage or deed of trust on a lot in a homeowners association, a portion of the homeowners association's liens on the lot, as prescribed in paragraph (3) of this subsection, shall have priority over a claim of the holder of a first mortgage or a first deed of trust that is recorded against the lot on or after October 1, 2011.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The portion of the homeowners association's liens that has priority under paragraph (2) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">Shall consist solely of not more than 4 months, or the equivalent of 4 months, of unpaid regular assessments for common expenses that are levied by the homeowners association in accordance with the requirements of the declaration or bylaws of the homeowners association;</section><section prefix="(ii)">May not include:<section prefix="1.">Interest;</section><section prefix="2.">Costs of collection;</section><section prefix="3.">Late charges;</section><section prefix="4.">Fines;</section><section prefix="5.">Attorney's fees;</section><section prefix="6.">Special assessments; or</section><section prefix="7.">Any other costs or sums due under the declaration or bylaws of the homeowners association or as provided under any contract, law, or court order; and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">May not exceed a maximum of $1,200.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, at the request of the holder of a first mortgage or first deed of trust on a lot in a homeowners association, the governing body shall provide to the holder written information about the portion of any lien filed under the Maryland Contract Lien Act that has priority as prescribed under paragraph (3) of this subsection, including information that is sufficient to allow the holder to determine the basis for the portion of the lien that has priority.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">At the time of making a request under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the holder shall provide the governing body of the homeowners association with the written contact information of the holder.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If the governing body of the homeowners association fails to provide written information to the holder under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph within 30 days after the filing of the statement of lien among the land records of each county in which the homeowners association is located, the portion of the homeowners association's liens does not have priority as prescribed under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
