<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-3-105.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>105.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "lien instrument" means:<section prefix="(1)">A lien created under the Maryland Contract Lien Act;</section><section prefix="(2)">An instrument creating or authorizing the creation of a lien in favor of a homeowners' association, a condominium council of unit owners, a property owners association, or a community association;</section><section prefix="(3)">A security agreement; or</section><section prefix="(4)">A vendor's lien.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A mortgage, deed of trust, or lien instrument may be released validly in accordance with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">When the debt secured by a mortgage, deed of trust, or lien instrument is paid fully or satisfied by a settlement agent licensed by the Maryland Insurance Administration as a title insurance producer under Title 10, Subtitle 1 of the Insurance Article, a title insurer, or a lawyer admitted to the Maryland Bar, and the party satisfied fails to provide a release suitable for recording, the settlement agent, title insurer, or lawyer may prepare and record a statutory release affidavit that:<section prefix="(1)">May be received by the clerk and indexed and recorded as any other instrument in the nature of a release or certificate of satisfaction; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Has the same effect as a release of the property for which the mortgage, deed of trust, or lien instrument is the security, as if a release were executed by the mortgagee, named trustees, or secured party.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Before the settlement agent, title insurer, or lawyer may record a statutory release affidavit under this section, that person shall:<section prefix="(1)">Allow at least a 60-day waiting period from the date the mortgage, deed of trust, or lien instrument is paid fully or satisfied for the party satisfied to provide a release suitable for recording;</section><section prefix="(2)">Send by certified mail, with or without a return receipt, to the party satisfied:<section prefix="(i)">A copy of this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A copy of the proposed statutory release affidavit that the person intends to record; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">A notice that unless a release suitable for recording is provided within 30 days, the person will obtain a release in accordance with the provisions of this section;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">After the mailing of the notice under item (2) of this subsection, allow an additional waiting period of at least 30 days for the party satisfied to provide a release suitable for recording.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A statutory release affidavit recorded under this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be in substantially the following form:</section><section prefix="(1)">On (insert date), I caused to be paid off the debt secured by the mortgage, deed of trust, or lien instrument, found in Liber/Book _____, at Folio/Page _____, in the land records of __________ County/Baltimore City, Maryland.</section><section prefix="(2)">I obtained a written payoff statement from the person to whom the debt was owed or the person's agent, the funds paid to the person or the person's agent were sufficient to pay off the debt in full, and, as authorized by the obligor on the account, I instructed the person or the person's agent to close the account.</section><section prefix="(3)">On (insert date), I sent the notice required under &#xA7; 3-105.2(d)(2) of the Real Property Article to the person satisfied by certified mail.</section><section prefix="(4)">The person satisfied has failed to provide a release suitable for recording.</section><section prefix="(5)">I am:</section><section prefix="(6)">The payoff of the debt was accomplished by:</section><section prefix="(2)">Be accompanied by:<section prefix="(i)">The canceled check evidencing final payment, which shall contain the name of the party whose debt is being satisfied, the debt account number, if any, and words indicating that the check is intended as payment in full of the debt being satisfied;</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the canceled check is unavailable, a check facsimile, as defined in &#xA7; 5-513 of the Financial Institutions Article, that contains the information required under item (i) of this item, accompanied by a certification from an authorized agent of the institution on which the check was drawn stating the check facsimile is a true and genuine image of the original check; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">If the debt securing the mortgage, deed of trust, or lien instrument was paid off by a wire transfer, the wire transfer remittance advice, which shall:<section prefix="1.">Be accompanied by a certification from an authorized agent of the institution from which the wire transfer was initiated stating that the document is a true and genuine image of the original wire transfer confirmation order issued by the institution; and</section><section prefix="2.">Contain the name of the person for whom the payoff was made, the name of the institution that was paid the money, a truncated version of the number of the account from which the funds were transferred, a truncated version of the number of the account to which the funds were transferred, the Federal Reserve Bank's reference numbers for the wire transfer, the loan number for the note that was paid off, the amount of the payoff made by the wire transfer, and the date and time of the wire transfer.</section></section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
