<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-110" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-11-110</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">All common profits shall be disbursed to the unit owners, be credited to their assessments for common expenses in proportion to their percentage interests in common profits and common expenses, or be used for any other purpose as the council of unit owners decides.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Funds for the payment of current common expenses and for the creation of reserves for the payment of future common expenses shall be obtained by assessments against the unit owners in proportion to their percentage interests in common expenses and common profits.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Where provided in the declaration or the bylaws, charges for utility services may be assessed and collected on the basis of usage rather than on the basis of percentage interests.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If provided by the declaration, assessments for expenses related to maintenance of the limited common elements may be charged to the unit owner or owners who are given the exclusive right to use the limited common elements.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Assessments for charges under this paragraph may be enforced in the same manner as assessments for common expenses.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A unit owner shall be liable for all assessments, or installments thereof, coming due while he is the owner of a unit. In a voluntary grant the grantee shall be jointly and severally liable with the grantor for all unpaid assessments against the grantor for his share of the common expenses up to the time of the voluntary grant for which a statement of lien is recorded, without prejudice to the rights of the grantee to recover from the grantor the amounts paid by the grantee for such assessments. Liability for assessments may not be avoided by waiver of the use or enjoyment of any common element or by abandonment of the unit for which the assessments are made.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Payment of assessments, together with interest, late charges, if any, costs of collection and reasonable attorney's fees may be enforced by the imposition of a lien on a unit in accordance with the provisions of the Maryland Contract Lien Act.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Suit for any deficiency following foreclosure may be maintained in the same proceeding, and suit to recover any money judgment for unpaid assessments may also be maintained in the same proceeding, without waiving the right to seek to impose a lien under the Maryland Contract Lien Act.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any assessment, or installment thereof, not paid when due shall bear interest, at the option of the council of unit owners, from the date when due until paid at the rate provided in the bylaws, not exceeding 18 percent per annum, and if no rate is provided, then at 18 percent per annum.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The bylaws also may provide for a late charge of $15 or one tenth of the total amount of any delinquent assessment or installment, whichever is greater, provided the charge may not be imposed more than once for the same delinquent payment and may only be imposed if the delinquency has continued for at least 15 calendar days.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the declaration or bylaws provide for an annual assessment payable in regular installments, the declaration or bylaws may further provide that if a unit owner fails to pay an installment when due, the council of unit owners may demand payment of the remaining annual assessment coming due within that fiscal year. A demand by the council is not enforceable unless the council, within 15 days of a unit owner's failure to pay an installment, notifies the unit owner that if the unit owner fails to pay the monthly installment within 15 days of the notice, full payment of the remaining annual assessment will then be due and shall constitute a lien on the unit as provided in this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not limit or affect the priority of any lien, secured interest, or other encumbrance with priority that is held by or for the benefit of, purchased by, assigned to, or securing any indebtedness to:<section prefix="(i)">The State or any county or municipal corporation in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any unit of State government or the government of any county or municipal corporation in the State; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">An instrumentality of the State or any county or municipal corporation in the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the case of a foreclosure of a mortgage or deed of trust on a unit in a condominium, a portion of the condominium's liens on the unit, as prescribed in paragraph (3) of this subsection, shall have priority over a claim of the holder of a first mortgage or a first deed of trust that is recorded against the unit on or after October 1, 2011.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The portion of the condominium's liens that has priority under paragraph (2) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">Shall consist solely of not more than 4 months, or the equivalent of 4 months, of unpaid regular assessments for common expenses that are levied by the condominium in accordance with the requirements of the declaration or bylaws of the condominium;</section><section prefix="(ii)">May not include:</section><section prefix="(iii)">May not exceed a maximum of $1,200.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, at the request of the holder of a first mortgage or first deed of trust on a unit in a condominium, the governing body shall provide to the holder written information about the portion of any lien filed under the Maryland Contract Lien Act that has priority as prescribed under paragraph (3) of this subsection, including information that is sufficient to allow the holder to determine the basis for the portion of the lien that has priority.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">At the time of making a request under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the holder shall provide the governing body of the condominium with the written contact information of the holder.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If the governing body of the condominium fails to provide written information to the holder under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph within 30 days after the filing of the statement of lien among the land records of each county in which the condominium is located, the portion of the condominium's liens does not have priority as prescribed under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
