<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="grp" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-14-117</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>117</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Ground lease" means a residential lease or sublease for a term of years renewable forever subject to the payment of a periodic ground rent.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">
          <section prefix="1.">"Ground lease holder" means the holder of the reversionary interest under a ground lease.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">"Ground lease holder" includes an agent of the ground lease holder.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">"Ground rent" means a rent issuing out of, or collectible in connection with, the reversionary interest under a ground lease.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">"Leasehold interest" means the tenancy in real property created under a ground lease.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">"Leasehold tenant" means the holder of the leasehold interest under a ground lease.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This subsection applies to residential property that was or is used, intended to be used, or authorized to be used for four or fewer dwelling units.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">This subsection does not apply to property:<section prefix="1.">Leased for business, commercial, manufacturing, mercantile, or industrial purposes, or any other purpose that is not primarily residential;</section><section prefix="2.">Improved or to be improved by any apartment, condominium, cooperative, or other building for multifamily use of greater than four dwelling units; or</section><section prefix="3.">Leased for dwellings or mobile homes that are erected or placed in a mobile home development or mobile home park.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A contract for the sale of real property subject to a ground rent shall contain the following notice in boldface type, at least as large as 14 point, in substantially the following form:</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "water and sewer authority" includes a person to which the duties and responsibilities of the Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission have been delegated by a written agreement or in accordance with a local ordinance.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A contract for the initial sale of improved, residential real property to a member of the public who intends to occupy or rent the property for residential purposes shall disclose the estimated cost, as established by the appropriate water and sewer authority, of any deferred water and sewer charges for which the purchaser may become liable. If the appropriate water and sewer authority has not established a schedule of charges for the water and sewer project that benefits the property or if a local jurisdiction has adopted a plan to benefit the property in the future, the contract of sale shall disclose that fact.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Violation of subsection (b) of this section entitles the initial purchaser to recover from the seller:<section prefix="(1)">Two times the amount of deferred charges the purchaser would be obligated to pay during the 5 years of payments following the sale;</section><section prefix="(2)">No amount greater than actually paid thereafter; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Any deposit moneys actually paid by the purchaser that were lost as a result of violation of subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A contract for use in the sale of residential property used as a dwelling place for one or two single-family units shall contain, in the manner provided under paragraph (2) of this subsection, the following statement:</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The statement required under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be printed in conspicuous type or handwritten in the contract or an addendum to the contract.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A contract or an addendum to the contract for the sale of real property shall contain in conspicuous type the following statement:</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A contract of sale shall also comply with the following provisions, if applicable:<section prefix="(1)">Section 17-405 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article (notice of purchaser's protection by the Real Estate Guaranty Fund in an amount not to exceed $25,000);</section><section prefix="(2)">Section 17-504 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article (notice by real estate broker pertaining to deposit in noninterest bearing account);</section><section prefix="(3)">Section 17-523 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article (notice by real estate broker about recordation and transfer taxes);</section><section prefix="(4)">Section 17-524 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article (notice of purchaser's right to select title company, settlement company, escrow company, mortgage lender, or financial institution);</section><section prefix="(5)">Section 8A-605 of this article (notice of park rules to be given to buyer pertaining to sales of mobile homes);</section><section prefix="(6)">Section 10-103 of this article (notices and disclosures pertaining to land installment contracts);</section><section prefix="(7)">Sections 10-301 and 10-306 of this article (requirements and disclosures pertaining to deposits on new homes);</section><section prefix="(8)">Sections 10-505 and 10-506 of this article (requirements and disclosures pertaining to contracts between custom home builders and buyers);</section><section prefix="(9)">Sections 10-602, 10-603, 10-604(b), and 10-605 of this article (notices, disclosures, and requirements pertaining to new home warranties);</section><section prefix="(10)">Section 10-701 of this article (notice pertaining to sale of real property in Prince George's County creating subdivision);</section><section prefix="(11)">Section 10-702 of this article (disclosure or disclaimer statements pertaining to single-family residential real property);</section><section prefix="(12)">Section 10-703 of this article (notice pertaining to land use in county land-use plans in Anne Arundel County);</section><section prefix="(13)">Section 11-126 of this article (notice pertaining to initial sale of condominium unit);</section><section prefix="(14)">Section 11-135 of this article (notice pertaining to resale of condominium unit);</section><section prefix="(15)">Sections 11A-112, 11A-115, and 11A-118 of this article (statements and requirements pertaining to time-shares);</section><section prefix="(16)">Section 11B-105 of this article (notice pertaining to initial sale of lot in development containing more than 12 lots);</section><section prefix="(17)">Section 11B-106 of this article (notice pertaining to resale of any lot or initial sale of lot in development containing 12 or fewer lots);</section><section prefix="(18)">Section 11B-107 of this article (notice pertaining to initial sale of lot not intended to be occupied or rented for residential purposes);</section><section prefix="(19)">Section 5-6B-02 of the Corporations and Associations Article (notice pertaining to initial sale of cooperative interests);</section><section prefix="(20)">Section 13-308 of the Tax - Property Article (notice of liability for agricultural land transfer tax);</section><section prefix="(21)">Section 13-504 of the Tax - Property Article (notice of liability for agricultural land transfer tax in Washington County); and</section><section prefix="(22)">Section 6-824 of the Environment Article (disclosure pertaining to obligations to perform risk reduction).</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Unless otherwise specifically provided, a contract of sale is not rendered invalid by the omission of any statement referred to in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to Prince George's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A contract for the sale of real property on which a development impact fee has been imposed shall contain a notice to the purchaser stating:<section prefix="(i)">That a development impact fee has been imposed on the property;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The total amount of the impact fee that has been imposed on the property; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The amount of the impact fee, if any, that is unpaid on the date of the contract for the sale of the property.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Violation of paragraph (2) of this subsection entitles the initial purchaser to recover from the seller:<section prefix="(i)">Two times the amount of development impact fees the purchaser would be obligated to pay following the sale;</section><section prefix="(ii)">No amount greater than actually paid thereafter; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any deposit moneys actually paid by the purchaser that were lost as a result of violation of paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to St. Mary's and Charles counties.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A contract for the sale of agriculturally assessed real property shall include the following information:</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Omission of the notice required under paragraph (2) of this subsection may not be a basis for invalidation of the contract for sale.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to Baltimore City and all other counties except Montgomery County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A contract for the initial sale of a new home, as defined in the Maryland Home Builder Registration Act, shall include the following:<section prefix="(i)">The builder registration number of the seller of the new home;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A provision stating that the new home shall be constructed in accordance with all applicable building codes in effect at the time of the construction of the new home;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A provision referencing all performance standards or guidelines:<section prefix="1.">That the seller shall comply with in the construction of the new home; and</section><section prefix="2.">That shall prevail in the performance of the contract and any arbitration or adjudication of a claim arising from the contract; and</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">A provision detailing the purchaser's right to receive a consumer information pamphlet as provided under the Home Builder Registration Act.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The performance standards or guidelines described in paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be:<section prefix="(i)">The performance standards or guidelines adopted at the time of the contract:<section prefix="1.">By the National Association of Home Builders; or</section><section prefix="2.">Under the federal National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety Standards Act, to the extent applicable;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Any performance standards or guidelines adopted by the home builder and incorporated into the contract that are equal to or more stringent than the performance standards or guidelines adopted at the time of the contract:<section prefix="1.">By the National Association of Home Builders; or</section><section prefix="2.">Under the federal National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety Standards Act, to the extent applicable; or</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">Any performance standards or guidelines adopted at the time of the contract by a county or municipal corporation that are equal to or more stringent than the performance standards or guidelines adopted at the time of the contract:<section prefix="1.">By the National Association of Home Builders; or</section><section prefix="2.">Under the federal National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety Standards Act, to the extent applicable.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The information required by paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be printed in conspicuous type.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j-1)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A contract for the initial sale of a new home, as defined in the Maryland Home Builder Registration Act, shall be contingent on the purchaser obtaining a written commitment for a loan secured by the property, unless the contract contains a provision expressly stating that it is not contingent.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the contract is contingent on the purchaser obtaining a written commitment for a loan secured by the property, the contract shall state the maximum loan interest rate the purchaser is obligated to accept.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply in Allegany, Carroll, Frederick, Garrett, Howard, Montgomery, and Washington counties.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A contract for the sale of residential real property shall contain the following statement:</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">All local laws requiring a statement or notice substantially similar to the statement required under paragraph (2) of this subsection prevail over the requirements of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to Anne Arundel County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, if Anne Arundel County or the State has initiated enforcement action for a violation of a local law described in &#xA7; 5-106(aa)(1) of the Courts and Judicial Proceedings Article, a contract for sale of the real property where the violation occurred shall disclose:<section prefix="(i)">The nature of the violation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The status of any ongoing proceedings to enforce the violation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any actions the buyer of the real property may be required to take with respect to the property in order to cure the violation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a violation of a local law described in &#xA7; 5-106(aa)(1) of the Courts and Judicial Proceedings Article is cured and a buyer of the real property where the violation occurred would not have any obligation to cure the violation, paragraph (2) of this subsection does not apply.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
