<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11B-102" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-11B-102</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as expressly provided in this title, the provisions of this title apply to all homeowners associations that exist in the State after July 1, 1987.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The provisions of &#xA7;&#xA7; 11B-105 and 11B-108 of this title do not apply to the initial sale of lots within the development to members of the public if on July 1, 1987:<section prefix="(1)">More than 50 percent of the lots included within or to be included within the development have been sold under a bona fide arm's length contract to members of the public who intend to occupy or rent the lots for residential purposes; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Less than 100 lots included within or to be included within the development have not been sold under a bona fide arm's length contract to members of the public who intend to occupy or rent the lots for residential purposes.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The provisions of &#xA7; 11B-110 of this title do not apply to common area improvements substantially completed before July 1, 1987.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The provisions of &#xA7; 11B-105 of this title do not apply to developments containing 12 or fewer lots or in which 12 or fewer lots remain to be sold as of July 1, 1987.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 11B-101(f) of this title, this title does not apply to any property which is:<section prefix="(1)">Part of a condominium regime governed by Title 11 of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">Part of a cooperative housing corporation; or</section><section prefix="(3)">To be occupied and used for nonresidential purposes.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">For any contract for the sale of a lot that is entered into before July 1, 1987, the provisions of &#xA7;&#xA7; 11B-105, 11B-106, 11B-107, and 11B-108 of this title do not apply.</section>
  </text>
</law>
