<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-8A-201</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Before a current or prospective resident signs a rental agreement or occupies the premises, a park owner shall:<section prefix="(1)">Provide the prospective resident with a written notice identifying the availability, capacity, and connection fee of all utility services at the proposed site in order to assure the proper and adequate installation of the mobile home. The prospective resident shall furnish to the park owner a written acknowledgment of this notification and acceptance of the site as proposed.</section><section prefix="(2)">Deliver a copy of the rules and an explanation of any provision for amendment of the rule.</section><section prefix="(3)">Deliver a copy of the rental agreement which shall contain the following:<section prefix="(i)">A specific identification of the site to be leased;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A term of tenancy of at least 1 year;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A stipulation of:<section prefix="1.">The total amount of annual rental for the site;</section><section prefix="2.">The term of payment, whether monthly, quarterly, semiannually, or annually;</section><section prefix="3.">The amount due for each installment;</section><section prefix="4.">The amount of any late payment fee; and</section><section prefix="5.">All park fees, in a manner that identifies the service to be provided for each park fee;</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">A description of each general obligation of the resident and park owner;</section><section prefix="(v)">A description of each service, facility, and utility service that the park owner will provide;</section><section prefix="(vi)">A description of any termination and renewal option;</section><section prefix="(vii)">The text of &#xA7; 8A-202(c) of this subtitle, which defines "qualified resident"; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">A specific reference to this title as the law that governs the relationships between the resident and park owner.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A rental agreement may not require an annual payment of rent for a site.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A prospective resident may request and a park owner may agree that the resident make an annual payment of rent for the site.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
