<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="grp" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-11B-106</section_number>
  <catch_line>A contract for the resale of a lot within a development, or for the initial sale of a lot within a d...</catch_line>
  <order_by>106</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A contract for the resale of a lot within a development, or for the initial sale of a lot within a development containing 12 or fewer lots, to a member of the public who intends to occupy or rent the lot for residential purposes, is not enforceable by the vendor unless:<section prefix="(1)">The purchaser is given, on or before entering into the contract for the sale of such lot, or within 20 calendar days of entering into the contract, the disclosures set forth in subsection (b) of this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">The purchaser is given any changes in mandatory fees and payments exceeding 10 percent of the amount previously stated to exist and any other substantial and material amendment to the disclosures after they become known to the vendor; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The contract of sale contains a notice in conspicuous type, which shall include bold and underscored type, in a form substantially the same as the following:</section><section prefix="(1)">Architectural changes, design, color, landscaping, or appearance;</section><section prefix="(2)">Occupancy density;</section><section prefix="(3)">Kind, number, or use of vehicles;</section><section prefix="(4)">Renting, leasing, mortgaging, or conveying property;</section><section prefix="(5)">Commercial activity; or</section><section prefix="(6)">Other matters.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The vendor shall provide the purchaser the following information in writing:<section prefix="(1)">A statement as to whether the lot is located within a development;</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">The current monthly fees or assessments imposed by the homeowners association upon the lot;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The total amount of fees, assessments, and other charges imposed by the homeowners association upon the lot during the prior fiscal year of the homeowners association; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">A statement of whether any of the fees, assessments, or other charges against the lot are delinquent;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">The name, address, and telephone number of the management agent of the homeowners association, or other officer or agent authorized by the homeowners association to provide to members of the public, information regarding the homeowners association and the development, or a statement that no agent or officer is presently so authorized by the homeowners association;</section><section prefix="(4)">A statement as to whether the owner has actual knowledge of:<section prefix="(i)">The existence of any unsatisfied judgments or pending lawsuits against the homeowners association; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any pending claims, covenant violations actions, or notices of default against the lot; and</section></section><section prefix="(5)">A copy of:<section prefix="(i)">The articles of incorporation, the declaration, and all recorded covenants and restrictions of the primary development, and of other related developments to the extent reasonably available, to which the purchaser shall become obligated on becoming an owner of the lot, including a statement that these obligations are enforceable against an owner's tenants, if applicable; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The bylaws and rules of the primary development, and of other related developments to the extent reasonably available, to which the purchaser shall become obligated on becoming an owner of the lot, including a statement that these obligations are enforceable against an owner and the owner's tenants, if applicable.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 30 calendar days of any resale transfer of a lot within a development, the transferor shall notify the homeowners association for the primary development of the transfer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notification shall include, to the extent reasonably available, the name and address of the transferee, the name and forwarding address of the transferor, the date of transfer, the name and address of any mortgagee, and the proportionate amount of any outstanding homeowners association fee or assessment assumed by each of the parties to the transaction.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The requirements of subsection (b) of this section shall be deemed to have been fulfilled if the information required to be disclosed is provided to the purchaser in writing in a clear and concise manner. The disclosures may be summarized or produced in any collection of documents, including plats, the declaration, or the organizational documents of the homeowners association, provided those documents effectively convey the required information to the purchaser.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In satisfying the requirements of subsection (b) of this section, the vendor shall be entitled to rely upon the disclosures contained in the depository after June 30, 1989.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The provisions of subsections (a), (b), (d), and (e) of this section do not apply to the sale of a lot in an action to foreclose a mortgage or deed of trust.</section>
  </text>
</law>
