<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-10-601</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>601</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Appliances, fixtures, and items of equipment" means furnaces, boilers, oil tanks and fittings, air purifiers, air handling equipment, ventilating fans, air conditioning equipment, water heaters, pumps, stoves, refrigerators, garbage disposals, compactors, dishwashers, automatic door openers, washers and dryers, bathtubs, sinks, toilets, faucets and fittings, lighting fixtures, circuit breakers, and other similar items.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Builder" means any person, corporation, partnership or other legal entity:<section prefix="(1)">That is engaged in the business of erecting or otherwise constructing a new home; or</section><section prefix="(2)">That purchases a completed new home for resale in the course of its business.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Division" means the Consumer Protection Division of the Office of the Attorney General.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Electrical systems" means all wiring, electrical boxes, switches, outlets and connections up to the public utility connection.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Heating, cooling, and ventilating systems" means all duct work, steam, water and refrigerant lines, registers, convectors, radiation elements and dampers.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Load-bearing portions of the home" means the load-bearing portions of the:<section prefix="(1)">Foundation system and footings;</section><section prefix="(2)">Beams;</section><section prefix="(3)">Girders;</section><section prefix="(4)">Lintels;</section><section prefix="(5)">Columns;</section><section prefix="(6)">Walls and partitions;</section><section prefix="(7)">Floor systems; and</section><section prefix="(8)">Roof framing system.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Local jurisdiction" means any county and any municipal corporation in Maryland subject to the provisions of Article XI-E of the Constitution.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"New home" means every newly constructed private dwelling unit in the State and the fixtures and structure that are made a part of a newly constructed private dwelling unit at the time of construction.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"New home" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">Outbuildings, including detached garages and detached carports, except outbuildings that contain plumbing, electrical, heating, cooling, or ventilation systems serving the new home;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Driveways;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Walkways;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Patios and decks;</section><section prefix="(v)">Boundary walls;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Retaining walls not necessary for the structural stability of the new home;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Landscaping;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Fences;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Off-site improvements;</section><section prefix="(x)">Appurtenant recreational facilities; and</section><section prefix="(xi)">Other similar items as determined by the Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"New home warranty" means a series of written promises made by a builder that meets the requirements of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"New home warranty security plan" means a plan that meets the requirements of &#xA7; 10-606 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Owner" means the purchaser of a new home who uses the home primarily for residential purposes during the warranty period.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Plumbing systems" means:<section prefix="(1)">Gas supply lines and fittings;</section><section prefix="(2)">Water supply, waste, and vent pipes and their fittings;</section><section prefix="(3)">Septic tanks and their drain fields; and</section><section prefix="(4)"><section prefix="(i)">Water, gas, and sewer service piping and their extensions to the tie-in of a public utility connection; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">On-site wells and sewage disposal systems.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Structural defect" means any defect in the load-bearing portions of a new home that adversely affects its load-bearing function to the extent that the home becomes or is in serious danger of becoming unsafe, unsanitary, or otherwise uninhabitable.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Structural defect" includes damage due to subsidence, expansion, or lateral movement of soil that has been located or relocated by the builder.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Structural defect" does not include damage caused by movement of the soil:<section prefix="(i)">Resulting from a flood or earthquake; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">For which compensation has been provided.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Warranty date" means the first day that the owner occupies the new home, settles on the new home, makes the final contract payment on the new home, or obtains an occupancy permit for the new home if the home is built on the owner's property, whichever is earlier.</section>
  </text>
</law>
