<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-7-105.6</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>105.6</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, any purchaser at a foreclosure sale of a mortgage or deed of trust has the same rights and remedies against the tenants of the mortgagor or grantor as the mortgagor or grantor had, and the tenants have the same rights and remedies against the purchaser as they would have had against the mortgagor or grantor on the date the mortgage or deed of trust was recorded.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For purposes of this subsection, a lease or tenancy shall be considered "bona fide" only if:<section prefix="(i)">The mortgagor or grantor or the child, spouse, or parent of the mortgagor or grantor under the contract is not the tenant;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The lease or tenancy was the result of an arm's length transaction; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The lease or tenancy requires the receipt of rent that is not substantially less than fair market rent for the property or the unit's rent is reduced or subsidized due to a federal, State, or local subsidy.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the case of a foreclosure on any residential property, an immediate successor in interest who has acquired legal title to the property under the foreclosure shall assume the interest subject to:<section prefix="(i)">The provision by the successor in interest of a notice to vacate to any bona fide tenant at least 90 days before the effective date of the notice; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The rights of any bona fide tenant as of the date of transfer of legal title under the foreclosure:<section prefix="1.">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, under a bona fide lease entered into before the transfer of legal title, to occupy the premises until the end of the remaining term of the lease; or</section><section prefix="2.">Without a lease or with a lease terminable at will under State law, subject to the receipt by the tenant of the notice required under item (i) of this paragraph.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to the receipt by the tenant of the notice to vacate under paragraph (2)(i) of this subsection, a successor in interest may terminate a lease effective on the date of the sale of the residential property to a purchaser who will occupy the property as the purchaser's primary residence.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The notice required under paragraph (2)(i) of this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be in writing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be sent by first-class and certified mail, return receipt requested;</section><section prefix="(iii)">State the date on which the notice is being given;</section><section prefix="(iv)">State the date on which the termination of the tenancy is effective; and</section><section prefix="(v)">State whether the basis for termination of the tenancy is:<section prefix="1.">Expiration of the term of the lease;</section><section prefix="2.">Sale of the property to a purchaser who will occupy the property as the purchaser's primary residence; or</section><section prefix="3.">Termination of a month-to-month or other terminable-at-will tenancy.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">This section does not affect the requirements for termination of any federal- or State-subsidized tenancy or of any State or local law that provides longer time periods or additional protection for tenants.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the required advertisement of sale so discloses, a foreclosure sale shall be made subject to one or more of the tenancies entered into subsequent to the recording of the mortgage or deed of trust or otherwise subordinated thereto.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any lease so continuing is unaffected by the sale, except the purchaser shall become the landlord, as of the date of the sale, on ratification of the sale.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
