<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-103" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-11-103</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The declaration shall express at least the following particulars:<section prefix="(1)">The name by which the condominium is to be identified, which name shall include the word "condominium" or be followed by the phrase "a condominium".</section><section prefix="(2)">A description of the condominium sufficient to identify it with reasonable certainty together with a statement of the owner's intent to subject the property to the condominium regime established under this title.</section><section prefix="(3)">A general description of each unit, including its perimeters, location, and any other data sufficient to identify it with reasonable certainty. As to condominiums created on or after July 1, 1981, except as provided by the declaration or the plat and subject to paragraph (4)(ii) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">If walls, floors, or ceilings are designated as boundaries of a unit, all lath, furring, wallboard, plasterboard, plaster, paneling, tiles, wallpaper, paint, finished flooring, and any other materials constituting any part of the finished surfaces thereof are a part of the unit, and all other portions of the walls, floors, or ceilings are a part of the common elements.</section><section prefix="(ii)">If any chute, flue, duct, wire, conduit, or any other fixture lies partially within and partially outside the designated boundaries of a unit, any portion thereof serving only that unit is a part of that unit, and any portion thereof serving more than one unit or any portion of the common elements is a part of the common elements.</section><section prefix="(iii)">Subject to the provisions of subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, all spaces, interior partitions, and other fixtures and improvements within the boundaries of a unit are a part of the unit.</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any shutters, awnings, window boxes, doorsteps, stoops, porches, balconies, patios, and all exterior doors and windows or other fixtures designed to serve a single unit, but located outside the unit's boundaries, are limited common elements allocated exclusively to that unit.</section></section><section prefix="(4)"><section prefix="(i)">A general description of the common elements together with a designation of those portions of the common elements that are limited common elements and the unit to which the use of each is restricted initially.</section><section prefix="(ii)"/></section><section prefix="(5)">The percentage interests appurtenant to each unit as provided in &#xA7; 11-107 of this title.</section><section prefix="(6)">The number of votes at meetings of the council of unit owners appurtenant to each unit.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The information required by subsection (a)(2) through (4) of this section may be incorporated in the declaration by reference to the condominium plat.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for a corrective amendment under &#xA7; 11-103.1 of this title or as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the declaration may be amended only with the written consent of 80 percent of the unit owners listed on the current roster. Amendments under this section are subject to the following limitations:<section prefix="(i)">Except to the extent expressly permitted or expressly required by other provisions of this title, an amendment to the declaration may not change the boundaries of any unit, the undivided percentage interest in the common elements of any unit, the liability for common expenses or rights to common profits of any unit, or the number of votes in the council of unit owners of any unit without the written consent of every unit owner and mortgagee.</section><section prefix="(ii)">An amendment to the declaration may not modify in any way rights expressly reserved for the benefit of the developer or provisions required by any governmental authority or for the benefit of any public utility.</section><section prefix="(iii)">Except to the extent expressly permitted by the declaration, an amendment to the declaration may not change residential units to nonresidential units or change nonresidential units to residential units without the written consent of every unit owner and mortgagee.</section><section prefix="(iv)">Except as otherwise expressly permitted by this title and by the declaration, an amendment to the declaration may not redesignate general common elements as limited common elements without the written consent of every unit owner and mortgagee.</section><section prefix="(v)">No provision of this title shall be construed in derogation of any requirement in the declaration or bylaws that all or a specified number of the mortgagees of the condominium units approve specified actions contemplated by the council of unit owners.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The council of unit owners may petition the circuit court in equity for the county in which the condominium is located to correct:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The petition may be brought only if:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The court may reform the declaration to correct the error or omission as the court considers appropriate, if:</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">A final order of reformation may be appealed by any party within 30 days of its issuance. An order of reformation may not be recorded until the appeal period has lapsed or all appeals have been completed.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An amendment or order of reformation becomes effective on recordation in the same manner as the declaration. If the condominium is registered with the Secretary of State, the council of unit owners shall file a copy of the order of reformation with the Secretary of State within 15 days of recordation.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
