<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="grp" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-11B-113.5</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section establishes the process for the annexation of parcels of land that are subject to the d...</catch_line>
  <order_by>113.5</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section establishes the process for the annexation of parcels of land that are subject to the deed, agreement, and declaration establishing any of the villages or town center in Columbia in Howard County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notwithstanding any provision of law or contract, a parcel of land located in that area of land in Howard County that is subject to the deed, agreement, and declaration of covenants, easements, charges, and liens dated December 13, 1966, and recorded in the land records of Howard County in Liber W.H.H. 463, Folio 158, et seq. (the Columbia Association Declaration) that is not part of the village or town center in which the land is located may be annexed into the village or town center if:<section prefix="(1)">The owner or developer of the land makes an application for annexation to the village or town center community association; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The Columbia Association or its successor and the village or town center community association approve the annexation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An instrument that consolidates a parcel of land into the village or town center in which the land is located shall be executed and filed for recordation in the land records of Howard County.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A parcel of land that is annexed into a village or town center in accordance with this section shall be subject to the recorded covenants and restrictions of the village or town center in which the parcel of land is located.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An annexation completed in accordance with this section may not abrogate or in any other way affect any approval previously granted or condition previously imposed under a recorded covenant or contract regarding improvements constructed on the annexed property.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
