<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="grp" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-14-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated unless the context requires otherwi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated unless the context requires otherwise.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Broker" means:<section prefix="(1)">An individual licensed as, or otherwise authorized to act as, a real estate broker under Title 17 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A corporation or partnership authorized to provide real estate brokerage services under Title 17 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Broker's lien" means a lien established in accordance with this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Claimant" means a broker claiming a broker's lien under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Commercial lease" means a lease of building floor space intended to be used by the tenant for a nonresidential use whether or not the lease expressly sets forth a use.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Commercial leasing brokerage agreement" or "brokerage agreement" means a written agreement between a broker and the owner of commercial property that provides for the payment of a commercial leasing commission by the owner to the broker for services in obtaining a commercial tenant regardless as to whether the broker acted as the agent for the owner or the commercial tenant.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Commercial leasing brokerage agreement" or "brokerage agreement" includes a written unilateral offer from an owner of commercial property to one or more brokers, including the broker claiming a lien under this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Commercial leasing commission" or "commission" means the compensation payable by the owner of commercial property to a broker for obtaining a commercial tenant under a commercial leasing brokerage agreement.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Commercial property" means land, and any improvements on the land, used or intended to be used for a nonresidential purpose.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Commercial tenant" means a tenant under a commercial lease.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Lien property" means the commercial property against which a broker's lien is claimed or against which a broker's lien has attached under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Owner" means the owner of the commercial property.</section>
  </text>
</law>
