<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-116" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-11-116</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The council of unit owners shall keep books and records in accordance with good accounting practices on a consistent basis.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On the request of the unit owners of at least 5 percent of the units, the council of unit owners shall cause an audit of the books and records to be made by an independent certified public accountant, provided an audit shall be made not more than once in any consecutive 12-month period. The cost of the audit shall be a common expense.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, all books and records, including insurance policies, kept by the council of unit owners shall be maintained in Maryland or within 50 miles of its borders and shall be available at some place designated by the council of unit owners for examination or copying, or both, by any unit owner, a unit owner's mortgagee, or their respective duly authorized agents or attorneys, during normal business hours, and after reasonable notice.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a unit owner requests in writing a copy of financial statements of the condominium or the minutes of a meeting of the board of directors or other governing body of the condominium to be delivered, the board of directors or other governing body of the condominium shall compile and send the requested information by mail, electronic transmission, or personal delivery:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Books and records required to be made available under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall first be made available to a unit owner not later than 15 business days after a unit is conveyed from a developer and the unit owner requests to examine or copy the books and records.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Books and records kept by or on behalf of a council of unit owners may be withheld from public inspection, except for inspection by the person who is the subject of the record or the person's designee or guardian, to the extent that they concern:<section prefix="(i)">Personnel records, not including information on individual salaries, wages, bonuses, and other compensation paid to employees;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An individual's medical records;</section><section prefix="(iii)">An individual's personal financial records, including assets, income, liabilities, net worth, bank balances, financial history or activities, and creditworthiness;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Records relating to business transactions that are currently in negotiation;</section><section prefix="(v)">The written advice of legal counsel; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">Minutes of a closed meeting of the board of directors or other governing body of the council of unit owners, unless a majority of a quorum of the board of directors or governing body that held the meeting approves unsealing the minutes or a recording of the minutes for public inspection.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for a reasonable charge imposed on a person desiring to review or copy the books and records or who requests delivery of information, the council of unit owners may not impose any charges under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A charge imposed under paragraph (1) of this subsection for copying books and records may not exceed the limits authorized under Title 7, Subtitle 2 of the Courts Article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
