<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-107" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-11-107</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each unit owner shall own an undivided percentage interest in the common elements equal to that set forth in the declaration. Except as specifically provided in this title, the common elements shall remain undivided. Except as provided in this title, no unit owner, nor any other person, may bring a suit for partition of the common elements, and any covenant or provision in any declaration, bylaws, or other instrument to the contrary is void.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each unit owner shall have a percentage interest in the common expenses and common profits equal to that set forth in the declaration.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The percentage interest provided in subsections (a) and (b) of this section may be identical or may vary. The percentage interests shall have a permanent character and, except as specifically provided by this title, may not be changed without the written consent of all of the unit owners and their mortgagees. Any change shall be evidenced by an amendment to the declaration, recorded among the appropriate land records. The percentage interests may not be separated from the unit to which they appertain. Any instrument, matter, circumstance, action, occurrence, or proceeding in any manner affecting a unit also shall affect, in like manner, the percentage interests appurtenant to the unit.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, but subject to any provision in the declaration or bylaws, a unit owner may:<section prefix="(i)">Grant by deed part of a unit and incorporate it as part of another unit if a portion of the percentage interests of the grantor is granted to the grantee and the grant is evidenced by an amendment to the declaration specifically describing the part granted, the percentage interests reallocated and the new percentage interest of the grantor and the grantee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Subdivide his unit into 2 or more units if the original percentage interests and votes appurtenant to the original unit are allocated to the resulting units and the subdivision is evidenced by an amendment to the declaration describing the resulting units and the percentage interests and votes allocated to each unit.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When appropriate, a plat may be attached to the amendment. The transfer or subdivision may be made without the consent of all of the unit owners if the amendment to the declaration is executed by the unit owners and mortgagees of the units involved and by the council of unit owners or its authorized designee.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the unit owner of 2 or more adjacent units or the unit owner of a unit and an adjacent part of another unit transferred in accordance with this subsection desires to consolidate them, the council of unit owners or its authorized designee may authorize the unit owner to remove all or part of any walls separating the units or portions of them if the removal does not violate any applicable statute or regulation.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
