<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-14-125.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>125.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Local code violation" means a violation under the following provisions of the Harford County Code as amended from time to time or under any applicable code relating to the following provisions incorporated in the Harford County Code by reference, or comparable provisions within the codes of the incorporated municipalities of Aberdeen, Havre de Grace, and Bel Air:<section prefix="(i)">Chapter 64 - Animals;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Chapter 82 - Building Construction;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Chapter 84 - Buildings, General;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Chapter 109 - Environmental Control;</section><section prefix="(v)">Chapter 157 - Licenses and Permits;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Chapter 162 - Livability Code;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Chapter 173 - Mobile Homes and Trailers; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">Chapter 179 - Nuisances and Public Health.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Nuisance" means:<section prefix="(i)">An act or condition created, performed, or maintained on private property that constitutes a local code violation and that:<section prefix="1.">Negatively impacts the well-being of other residents; and</section><section prefix="2."/></section><section prefix="(ii)">A property where the tenant, owner, or other occupant has been convicted of violations of &#xA7; 10-201 or &#xA7; 10-202 of the Criminal Law Article for conduct occurring on, in, or in relation to the property;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A property to which police or other law enforcement agencies have responded to complaints or calls for service 4 or more times within any 30-day period and that:<section prefix="1.">Negatively impacts the well-being of other residents; and</section><section prefix="2."/></section><section prefix="(iv)">A property where the tenant, owner, or other occupant has been convicted of violations of any criminal law occurring on, in, or in relation to the property and is related to the activities of a criminal gang as defined in &#xA7; 9-801 of the Criminal Law Article; or</section><section prefix="(v)">A building, structure, dwelling, dwelling unit, or accessory structure that:<section prefix="1.">Contains defects due to inadequate maintenance, obsolescence, or abandonment that increase the hazard of fire, accident, or other calamity; or</section><section prefix="2.">Is unsafe, unsanitary, dangerous, or detrimental to the health, safety, or general welfare of the community due to lack of maintenance, inadequate ventilation, light, sanitary facilities, or other conditions.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section only applies to a nuisance located within the boundaries of Harford County.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An action to abate a nuisance may be brought under this section and &#xA7; 4-401 of the Courts Article by the State's Attorney for Harford County.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney may seek injunctive and other equitable relief in the District Court for abatement of a nuisance upon showing:<section prefix="(i)">The notice requirements under paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection have been satisfied; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The nuisance has not been abated.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An action may not be brought under this section based on a nuisance until 60 days after the State's Attorney gives notice of the violation and of the State's Attorney's intent to bring an  action under this section by certified mail, return receipt requested, to the applicable local enforcement agency.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An action may not be brought under this section if the applicable code enforcement agency has filed an action for equitable relief from the nuisance.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An action may not be brought under this section until 60 days after the tenant, if any, and owner of record receive notice from the State's Attorney that a nuisance exists and that legal action may be taken if the nuisance is not abated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The notice shall specify:<section prefix="1.">The nature of the alleged nuisance;</section><section prefix="2.">The date and time of day the nuisance was first discovered;</section><section prefix="3.">The location on the property where the nuisance is allegedly occurring; and</section><section prefix="4.">The relief sought.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The notice shall indicate:<section prefix="1.">The nature of the proceedings;</section><section prefix="2.">The time and place of the hearing; and</section><section prefix="3.">The name and telephone number of the person to contact for additional information.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In filing a suit under this section, the State's Attorney shall certify to the court:<section prefix="(i)">What steps the State's Attorney has taken to satisfy the notice requirements under this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">That each condition precedent to the filing of an action under this section has been met.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A political subdivision of the State or any agency of a political subdivision may not be subject to any action brought under this section or an action resulting from an action brought under this section against a private property owner.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, and in addition to or as a component of any remedy ordered under subsection (d) of this section, the court, after a hearing, may order a tenant who knew or should have known of the existence of the nuisance to vacate the property within 72 hours.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court, after a hearing, may grant a judgment of restitution or the possession of rental property to the owner if:<section prefix="(i)">The owner and tenant are parties to the action; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A tenant has failed to obey an order under subsection (d) of this section or paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the court orders restitution or the possession of the property under paragraph (2) of this subsection, the court shall immediately issue its warrant to the sheriff or constable commanding execution of the warrant within 5 days after issuance of the warrant.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In addition to or as a part of any injunction, restraining order, or other relief ordered, the court may order the owner of the property to submit for court approval a plan of correction to ensure, to the extent reasonably possible, that the property will not again be used for a nuisance if:<section prefix="(i)">The owner is a party to the action; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The owner knew or should have known of the existence of the nuisance.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If an owner fails to comply with an order to abate a nuisance, after a hearing, the court may, in addition to any other relief granted, order that the property be demolished if the property is unfit for habitation and the estimated cost of rehabilitation significantly exceeds the estimated market value of the property after rehabilitation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">This section may not be construed to abrogate any equitable or legal right or remedy otherwise available under the law to abate a nuisance.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Provisions of this article or public local laws applicable to actions between a landlord and a tenant are not applicable to actions brought against a landlord or a tenant under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
