<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="grp" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-7-314</section_number>
  <catch_line>Each foreclosure surplus acquisition shall be in the form of a written contract....</catch_line>
  <order_by>314</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each foreclosure surplus acquisition shall be in the form of a written contract.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each foreclosure surplus acquisition contract shall:<section prefix="(1)">Contain the entire agreement of the parties;</section><section prefix="(2)">Be printed in at least 12 point type, in the same language that is used by the homeowner and was used by the foreclosure surplus purchaser and the homeowner to negotiate the sale of the residence in foreclosure;</section><section prefix="(3)">Be fully completed, dated, and personally signed by the homeowner and the foreclosure surplus purchaser before the statement of account has been referred to the auditor; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Include:<section prefix="(i)">The name, business address, and telephone number of the foreclosure surplus purchaser;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The address of the residence in foreclosure;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The total consideration to be given by the foreclosure surplus purchaser in connection with or incident to the transaction;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A complete description of the terms of payment or other consideration, including any services of any nature that the foreclosure surplus purchaser represents the foreclosure surplus purchaser will perform for the homeowner before or after the sale; and</section><section prefix="(v)">The following notice, which shall be printed in at least 14 point boldface type, completed with the name of the foreclosure surplus purchaser, and located in immediate proximity to the space reserved for the homeowner's signature:</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The contract shall be accompanied by a completed form in duplicate, captioned "Notice of Rescission".</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Notice of Rescission shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be on a separate sheet of paper attached to the contract;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be easily detachable; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Contain the following statement printed in at least 15 point type:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The foreclosure surplus purchaser shall provide the homeowner with a copy of the contract and the attached Notice of Rescission at the time the contract is executed by all parties.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The contract required by this section survives delivery of any instrument of conveyance of the residence in foreclosure, is binding in the audit, and has no effect on persons other than the parties to the contract.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Any provision in a contract that attempts or purports to waive any of the rights specified in this title, consent to jurisdiction or choice of law in a state other than Maryland, consent to venue in a county other than the county in which the property is located, or impose any costs or filing fees greater than the fees required to file an action in a circuit court, is void.</section>
  </text>
</law>
