<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="grp" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-11B-111.5</section_number>
  <catch_line>If a homeowners association fails to fill vacancies on the governing body sufficient to constitute a...</catch_line>
  <order_by>111.5</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If a homeowners association fails to fill vacancies on the governing body sufficient to constitute a quorum in accordance with the bylaws, three or more owners of lots may petition the circuit court for the county where the condominium is located to appoint a receiver to manage the affairs of the homeowners association.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 30 days before petitioning the circuit court, the lot owners acting under the authority granted by subsection (a) of this section shall mail to the governing body a notice describing the petition and the proposed action.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The lot owners shall mail a copy of the notice to the owner of each lot in the development.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the governing body fails to fill vacancies sufficient to constitute a quorum within the notice period, the lot owners may proceed with the petition.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A receiver appointed by a court under this section may not reside in or own a lot in the development governed by the homeowners association.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A receiver appointed under this section shall have all powers and duties of a duly constituted governing body.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The receiver shall serve until the homeowners association fills vacancies on the governing body sufficient to constitute a quorum.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The salary of the receiver, court costs, and reasonable attorney's fees are expenses of the homeowners association.</section>
  </text>
</law>
