<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="grp" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-7-311</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies to a contract for the sale or transfer of a residence in default that is includ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>311</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to a contract for the sale or transfer of a residence in default that is included in a foreclosure consulting contract or arranged by a foreclosure consultant.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to any other requirement under law, the purchaser of a residence in default shall provide the homeowner with a document entitled "Notice to Homeowner".</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The document entitled "Notice to Homeowner" shall:<section prefix="(1)">Contain the total sales price of the residence in default and an explanation of the distribution of the proceeds of the sale, including any payments to any parties, including the foreclosure consultant;</section><section prefix="(2)">Be printed in 12 point type and written in the same language that is used by the homeowner and was used in discussions to describe the foreclosure consultant's or purchaser's services or to negotiate the transfer or sale of the property;</section><section prefix="(3)">Be dated and personally signed by the homeowner and the purchaser and witnessed and acknowledged by a notary public appointed and commissioned by the State;</section><section prefix="(4)">Describe in detail the terms of any sale or transfer including:<section prefix="(i)">The name, business address, telephone number, and facsimile number of the person to whom the deed or title will be sold or transferred;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The address of the residence in default;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The total consideration to be given or received, directly or indirectly, by the homeowner, purchaser, and the foreclosure consultant;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The time at which title is to be sold or transferred to the purchaser; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Any financial or legal obligations to which the homeowner may remain subject; and</section></section><section prefix="(5)">Contain the following statement printed in at least 14 point boldface type and located in immediate proximity to the space reserved for the homeowner's signature:</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The purchaser shall provide the homeowner with a document entitled "NOTICE OF RIGHT TO RESCIND CONTRACT FOR THE SALE OR TRANSFER OF DEED OR TITLE".</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The document entitled "NOTICE OF RIGHT TO RESCIND CONTRACT FOR THE SALE OR TRANSFER OF DEED OR TITLE" shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be a separate document and not printed on the back of any other document; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Contain the following statement printed in at least 14 point type:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The purchaser shall provide the homeowner with a copy of the Notice of Right to Rescind Contract for the Sale or Transfer of Deed or Title immediately on execution of any document that includes an agreement to sell or transfer.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The time during which the homeowner may rescind the contract for the sale or transfer does not begin to run until the purchaser has complied with this part.</section>
  </text>
</law>
