<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-7-401</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>401</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(a-1)">"Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Financial Regulation in the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Document" includes applications, appraisal reports, HUD-1 settlement statements, W-2 forms, verifications of income or employment, bank statements, tax returns, payroll stubs, and any required disclosure.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Homeowner" means:<section prefix="(1)">A record owner of residential real property; or</section><section prefix="(2)">An individual occupying the residential real property under a use and possession order issued under Title 8, Subtitle 2 of the Family Law Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Mortgage fraud" means any action by a person made with the intent to defraud that involves:<section prefix="(1)">Knowingly making any deliberate misstatement, misrepresentation, or omission during the mortgage lending process with the intent that the misstatement, misrepresentation, or omission be relied on by a mortgage lender, borrower, or any other party to the mortgage lending process;</section><section prefix="(2)">Knowingly creating or producing a document for use during the mortgage lending process that contains a deliberate misstatement, misrepresentation, or omission with the intent that the document containing the misstatement, misrepresentation, or omission be relied on by a mortgage lender, borrower, or any other party to the mortgage lending process;</section><section prefix="(3)">Knowingly using or facilitating the use of any deliberate misstatement, misrepresentation, or omission during the mortgage lending process with the intent that the misstatement, misrepresentation, or omission be relied on by a mortgage lender, borrower, or any other party to the mortgage lending process;</section><section prefix="(4)">Receiving any proceeds or any other funds in connection with a mortgage closing that the person knows resulted from a violation of item (1), (2), or (3) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(5)">Conspiring to violate any of the provisions of item (1), (2), (3), or (4) of this subsection; or</section><section prefix="(6)">Filing or causing to be filed in the land records in the county where a residential real property is located, any document relating to a mortgage loan that the person knows to contain a deliberate misstatement, misrepresentation, or omission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Mortgage lending process" means the process by which a person seeks or obtains a mortgage loan.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Mortgage lending process" includes:<section prefix="(i)">The solicitation, application, origination, negotiation, servicing, underwriting, signing, closing, and funding of a mortgage loan; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The notarizing of any document in connection with a mortgage loan.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Mortgage loan" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 11-501 of the Financial Institutions Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Pattern of mortgage fraud" means two or more incidents of mortgage fraud that:<section prefix="(1)">Involve two or more residential real properties; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Have similar intents, results, accomplices, victims, or methods of commission or otherwise are interrelated by distinguishing characteristics.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Residential real property" means real property improved by four or fewer single family dwelling units.</section>
  </text>
</law>
