<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-11-102</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>102</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The fee simple owner or lessee under a lease that exceeds 60 years of any property in the State may subject the property to a condominium regime by recording among the land records of the county where the property is located, a declaration, bylaws, and condominium plat that comply with the requirements specified in this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (1) of this subsection, a leasehold estate may not be subjected to a condominium regime if it is used for residential purposes unless the State, a county that has adopted charter home rule under Article XI-A of the Maryland Constitution, a municipal corporation, or, subject to the provisions of subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority is the owner of the reversionary fee simple estate.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority may establish a leasehold estate for a condominium regime that is used for residential purposes under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph if, when the initial term of the lease expires, there is a provision in the lease that allows the lessee to automatically renew the lease for another term.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding paragraph (2) of this subsection or any declaration, rule, or bylaw, a developer or any other person may not be prohibited from granting a leasehold estate in an individual unit used for residential purposes.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If any property lying partly in one county and partly in any other county is subjected to a condominium regime, the declaration, bylaws, and condominium plat shall be recorded in all counties where any portion of the property is located. Subsequent instruments affecting the title to a unit which is physically located entirely within a single county shall be recorded only in that county, notwithstanding the fact that the common elements are not physically located entirely within that county.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">All instruments affecting title to units shall be recorded and taxed as in other real property transactions. However, no State or local tax may be imposed by reason of the execution or recordation of the declaration, bylaws, condominium plat, or any statement of condominium lien recorded pursuant to the provisions of &#xA7; 11-110 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The declaration, bylaws, and condominium plat shall be indexed in the grantor index under the name of the developer and under the name of the condominium. Subsequent amendments shall be indexed under the name of the condominium.</section>
  </text>
</law>
