<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-7-105.11</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>105.11</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Certificate of property unfit for human habitation" means:<section prefix="(i)">In Baltimore City, a certificate of substantial repair; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A certificate for residential property issued by a unit of a county or municipal corporation indicating that the county or municipal corporation has determined that the residential property is unfit for human habitation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Certificate of vacancy" means a certificate for a residential property issued by a unit of a county or municipal corporation indicating that the residential property is vacant.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only to a county or municipal corporation that issues a certificate of vacancy or a certificate of property unfit for human habitation.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a mortgage or deed of trust on residential property is in default, a person with a secured interest in the residential property may request that a county or municipal corporation issue a certificate of vacancy or a certificate of property unfit for human habitation.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The county or municipal corporation shall issue to a secured party a certificate of vacancy for a residential property if the county or municipal corporation determines that the residential property is vacant.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The county or municipal corporation shall issue to a secured party a certificate of property unfit for human habitation for a residential property if the county or municipal corporation determines in accordance with requirements of local, county, or State housing codes, that the residential property is unfit for human habitation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A certificate of vacancy or certificate of property unfit for human habitation issued under this subsection is valid for 60 days after the date the certificate is issued.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A county or municipal corporation may charge a fee not exceeding $100 to a secured party to issue a certificate of vacancy or a certificate of property unfit for human habitation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except as provided in subsection (f) of this section, if a certificate of vacancy or certificate of property unfit for human habitation is valid at the time of filing an order to docket or complaint to foreclose, &#xA7; 7-105.1 of this subtitle does not apply to an action to foreclose a mortgage or deed of trust on the property for which the certificate was issued.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The record owner or occupant of a property may challenge the certificate of vacancy or certificate of property unfit for human habitation under this section by notifying the circuit court of the challenge.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A secured party filing an order to docket or complaint to foreclose based on a certificate of vacancy or a certificate of property unfit for human habitation under this section shall serve the foreclosure documents in accordance with &#xA7; 7-105.1(h)(1) of this subtitle along with a description of the procedure to challenge the certificate and the form to be used to make the challenge.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a challenge under paragraph (1) of this subsection is upheld, the secured party shall comply with the requirements of &#xA7; 7-105.1 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A county or municipal corporation may establish procedures governing the issuance of a certificate of vacancy or certificate of property unfit for human habitation under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
