<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="grp" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-11A-108.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>An association by a two-thirds majority vote of the members present at any regular or special meetin...</catch_line>
  <order_by>108.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An association by a two-thirds majority vote of the members present at any regular or special meeting may amend its time-share instrument to provide that the time-shares in a time-share project will not terminate at the end of the term of the time-share plan as provided in &#xA7; 11A-108 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In determining that the time-shares will not terminate at the end of the term of the time-share plan, an association may:<section prefix="(1)">Establish a later termination date or decide that there will be no termination date; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide that on or after the original termination date as set forth in the time-share instrument, a time-share owner shall continue to:<section prefix="(i)">Have exclusive rights to use, occupy, sell, convey, assign, mortgage, exchange, or pass by will or inheritance, any time-shares owned by the person;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Use and enjoy all the common elements of the time-share project; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Have the previously existing rights and duties in the association including the right to vote and the duty to pay charges and assessments.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person to whom a time-share is transferred by sale, conveyance, assignment, mortgage, devise, bequest, or inheritance shall have the rights and duties of the person from whom the time-share was transferred.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The provisions of this section apply even if, under the terms of a time-share deed or time-share instrument, the time-share owners have or will become owners as tenants in common of a time-share unit or project.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An association may not take an action provided for in subsection (a) of this section unless the notice of the meeting sent to the time-share owners expressly states that the action may be considered at the meeting.</section>
  </text>
</law>
