<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-2-122</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>122</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section, "trust" means an express inter vivos or testamentary trust.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Trust" includes the following instruments or funding arrangements in the nature of a trust:<section prefix="(i)">A profit sharing plan;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A retirement plan;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A liquidating or liquidation plan; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">An unincorporated foundation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Trust" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">A real estate investment trust as defined in &#xA7; 8-101 of the Corporations and Associations Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A statutory trust as defined in &#xA7; 12-101 of the Corporations and Associations Article; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A trust, formed under the law of another state or a foreign country, that authorizes a trust to take, hold, and dispose of title to property in the name of the trust.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A grant of property by deed to a grantee designated in the deed as a trust has the same effect as if the grantor had granted the property to the trustee or trustees appointed and acting for the trust on the effective date of the deed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If executed by the trustee or trustees appointed and acting for the trust on the effective date of the deed, a grant of property by deed from a grantor designated in the deed as a trust has the same effect as if the grantee had received the property from the trustee or trustees appointed and acting for the trust on the effective date of the deed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A grant of property by deed to a grantee designated in the deed as an estate of a decedent, including the estate of a nonresident decedent, has the same effect as if the grantor had granted the property to:<section prefix="(i)">The personal representative or personal representatives appointed by a register of wills or orphans' court in the State for the estate and acting as the personal representative on the effective date of the deed; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A foreign personal representative exercising the powers of the office for the estate of a nonresident decedent on the effective date of the deed.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If executed by the person or persons indicated in item (i) or (ii) of this paragraph as applicable, a grant of property by deed from a grantor designated in the deed as an estate of a decedent, including the estate of a nonresident decedent, has the same effect as if the grantee had received the property from:<section prefix="(i)">The personal representative or personal representatives appointed by a register of wills or orphans' court in the State for the estate and acting as the personal representative on the effective date of the deed; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A foreign personal representative exercising the powers of the office for the estate of a nonresident decedent on the effective date of the deed.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
