<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-11-131</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>131</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The implied warranties provided in this section may not be excluded or modified.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The warranties provided in &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-202 and 10-203 of this article apply to all sales by developers under this title. For the purposes of this article, a newly constructed dwelling unit means a newly constructed or newly converted condominium unit and its appurtenant undivided fee simple interest in the common areas.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a developer grants an improvement to an intermediate purchaser to evade any liability to a purchaser imposed by the provisions of this section, or by &#xA7; 10-202 or &#xA7; 10-203 of this article, the developer is liable on the subsequent sale of the improvement by the intermediate purchaser as if the subsequent sale had been effectuated by the developer without regard to the intervening grant.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In addition to the implied warranties set forth in &#xA7; 10-203 of this article there shall be an implied warranty on an individual unit from a developer to a unit owner. The warranty on an individual unit commences with the transfer of title to that unit and extends for a period of 1 year. The warranty shall provide:<section prefix="(1)">That the developer is responsible for correcting any defects in materials or workmanship in the construction of walls, ceilings, floors, and heating and air conditioning systems in the unit; and</section><section prefix="(2)">That the heating and any air conditioning systems have been installed in accordance with acceptable industry standards and:<section prefix="(i)">That the heating system is warranted to maintain a 70&#xB0;F temperature inside with the outdoor temperature and winds at the design conditions established by the Energy Conservation Building Standards Act, Title 7, Subtitle 4 of the Public Utilities Article, or those established by the political subdivision as provided in Title 7, Subtitle 4 of the Public Utilities Article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">That the air conditioning system is warranted to maintain a 78&#xB0;F temperature inside with the outdoor temperature at the design conditions established by Title 7, Subtitle 4 of the Public Utilities Article, or those established by the political subdivision as provided in Title 7, Subtitle 4 of the Public Utilities Article.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to the implied warranties set forth in &#xA7; 10-203 of this article there shall be an implied warranty on common elements from a developer to the council of unit owners. The warranty shall apply to: the roof, foundation, external and supporting walls, mechanical, electrical, and plumbing systems, and other structural elements.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The warranty shall provide that the developer is responsible for correcting any defect in materials or workmanship, and that the specified common elements are within acceptable industry standards in effect when the building was constructed.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The warranty on common elements commences with the first transfer of title to a unit owner.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The warranty of any common elements not completed at the first transfer of title to a unit owner shall commence with the completion of that element or with its availability for use by all unit owners, whichever occurs later.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The warranty extends for a period of 3 years from commencement under subparagraph (i) or (ii) of this paragraph or 2 years from the date on which the unit owners, other than the developer and its affiliates, first elect a controlling majority of the members of the board of directors for the council of unit owners, whichever occurs later.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A suit for enforcement of the warranty on general common elements shall be brought only by the council of unit owners. A suit for enforcement of the warranty on limited common elements may be brought by the council of unit owners or any unit owner to whose use it is reserved.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Notice of defect shall be given within the warranty period and suit for enforcement of the warranty shall be brought within 1 year of the warranty period.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Warranties shall not apply to any defects caused through abuse or failure to perform maintenance by a unit owner or the council of unit owners.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The provisions of this section do not apply to a condominium that is occupied and used solely for nonresidential purposes.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
