<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-501" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-14-501</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Affordable housing land trust" means an entity that:<section prefix="(1)">Provides affordable housing to low-income families and moderate-income families through an affordable housing land trust agreement; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is organized or managed by:<section prefix="(i)">A nonprofit organization exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 501(c)(2), (3), or (4) of the United States Internal Revenue Code; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A unit or instrumentality of the State or a political subdivision of the State.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Affordable housing land trust agreement" means an agreement between an affordable housing land trust and a purchaser of real property owned by the affordable housing land trust, or for which the affordable housing land trust has a proprietary or reversionary interest, that:<section prefix="(1)">Grants the affordable housing land trust a preemptive right to purchase or repurchase the property, including any improvements on the property;</section><section prefix="(2)">Contains language restricting the transfer, lease, sublease, assignment, or occupancy of the property with regard to:<section prefix="(i)">Potential transferees, sublessees, assignees, or occupants; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The price at which the property may be transferred; or</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Imposes other conditions on the use or transfer of the property that would trigger a reversionary interest and that are designed to ensure that the property remains available and affordable to low-income families and moderate-income families.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Family" means a household consisting of one or more individuals.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Low-income family" means a household with an income that does not exceed 80% of the area median income for a household of the same size.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Moderate-income family" means a household with an income that does not exceed 140% of the area median income for a household of the same size.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Nonprofit status" means the recognition by the Internal Revenue Service that an affordable housing land trust is exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 501(c)(2), (3), or (4) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
  </text>
</law>
