<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-8-110.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>110.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Ground lease" means a residential lease or sublease for a term of years renewable forever subject to the payment of a periodic ground rent.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Ground lease holder" means the holder of the reversionary interest under a ground lease.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Ground lease holder" includes an agent of the ground lease holder.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Ground rent" means a rent issuing out of, or collectible in connection with, the reversionary interest under a ground lease.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Irredeemable ground rent" means a ground rent created under a ground lease executed before April 9, 1884, that does not contain a provision allowing the leasehold tenant to redeem the ground rent.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Leasehold interest" means the tenancy in real property created under a ground lease.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Leasehold tenant" means the holder of the leasehold interest under a ground lease.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Redeemable ground rent" means a ground rent that may be redeemed in accordance with this section or redeemed or extinguished in accordance with &#xA7; 8-110(f) of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section applies to residential property that is or was used, intended to be used, or authorized to be used for four or fewer dwelling units.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not apply to property:<section prefix="(i)">Leased for business, commercial, manufacturing, mercantile, or industrial purposes, or any other purpose that is not primarily residential;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Improved or to be improved by any apartment, condominium, cooperative, or other building for multifamily use of greater than four dwelling units; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Leased for dwellings or mobile homes that are erected or placed in a mobile home development or mobile home park.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An irredeemable ground rent shall be converted to, and become, a redeemable ground rent, unless within the time specified in subsection (f) of this section, a notice of intention to preserve irredeemability is recorded.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The conversion of an irredeemable ground rent to a redeemable ground rent occurs on the day following the end of the period in which the notice may be recorded.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A disability or lack of knowledge of any kind does not prevent the conversion of an irredeemable ground rent to a redeemable ground rent if no notice of intention to preserve irredeemability is filed within the time specified in subsection (f) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any ground lease holder of an irredeemable ground rent may record a notice of intention to preserve irredeemability among the land records of the county where the land is located.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice may be recorded by:<section prefix="(i)">The person claiming to be the ground lease holder; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the ground lease holder is under a disability or otherwise unable to assert a claim on the ground lease holder's own behalf, any other person acting on the ground lease holder's behalf.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To be effective and to be entitled to be recorded, the notice shall be executed by the ground lease holder, acknowledged before a notary public, and contain substantially the following information:<section prefix="(i)">An accurate description of the leasehold interest affected by the notice, including, if known, the property improvement address;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The name of every ground lease holder of an irredeemable ground rent;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The name of every leasehold tenant as of the time the notice is filed according to the land records or the records of the State Department of Assessments and Taxation;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The recording reference of the ground lease;</section><section prefix="(v)">The recording reference of every leasehold tenant's leasehold deed, as of the time the notice is filed, according to the land records or the records of the State Department of Assessments and Taxation;</section><section prefix="(vi)">The recording reference of every irredeemable ground rent ground lease holder's deed; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">The block number for the leasehold interest if the property is located in Baltimore City.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A notice that substantially meets the requirements of this section shall be accepted for recording among the land records on payment of the same fees as are charged for the recording of deeds.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The filing of a notice is exempt from the imposition of a State or local excise tax.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The notice shall be indexed as "Notice of Intention to Preserve Irredeemability":<section prefix="(i)">In the grantee indices of deeds under the name of every ground lease holder of an irredeemable ground rent;</section><section prefix="(ii)">In the grantor indices of deeds under the name of every leasehold tenant as of the time the notice is filed according to the land records or the records of the State Department of Assessments and Taxation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">In the block index in Baltimore City.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To preserve the irredeemability of an irredeemable ground rent, a notice of intention to preserve shall be recorded on or before December 31, 2010.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a notice of intention to preserve is not recorded on or before December 31, 2010, the ground rent becomes a redeemable ground rent.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a notice is recorded on or before December 31, 2010, the ground rent shall remain irredeemable for a period of 10 years from January 1, 2011, to December 31, 2020, both inclusive.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The effectiveness of a filed notice to preserve irredeemability shall lapse on January 1, 2021, and the ground rent shall become a redeemable ground rent, unless a renewal notice containing substantially the same information as the notice of intention to preserve irredeemability is recorded within 6 months before the expiration of the 10-year period set forth in paragraph (3) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The effectiveness of any subsequently filed renewal notice shall lapse after the expiration of the applicable 10-year period and the ground rent shall become a redeemable ground rent, unless further renewal notices are recorded within 6 months before the expiration of the applicable 10-year period.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A ground rent made redeemable in accordance with this section:<section prefix="(1)">Is redeemable at any time following the date of conversion of the irredeemable ground rent to a redeemable ground rent; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall be redeemable for a sum equal to the annual rent reserved multiplied by 16.66, which is capitalization at 6 percent.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
