<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="grp" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-14-126.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>126.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Department" means the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Foreclosed Property Registry" means the Foreclosed Property Registry established by the Department under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Foreclosure purchaser" means the person identified as the purchaser on the report of sale required by Maryland Rule 14-305 for a foreclosure sale of residential property.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Fund" means the Foreclosed Property Registry Fund established by the Department under subsection (i) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Local jurisdiction" means:<section prefix="(i)">A county; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A municipal corporation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Residential property" means real property improved by four or fewer dwelling units that are designed principally and are intended for human habitation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department shall establish and maintain an Internet-based Foreclosed Property Registry for information relating to foreclosure sales of residential property.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">At the time of a foreclosure sale of residential property, the person responsible for conducting the foreclosure shall obtain from the foreclosure purchaser a written acknowledgment of the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 30 days after a foreclosure sale of residential property, a foreclosure purchaser shall submit an initial registration to the Foreclosed Property Registry.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The initial registration shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be in the form the Department requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Contain the following information:<section prefix="1.">The name, telephone number, and address of the foreclosure purchaser;</section><section prefix="2.">The street address of the property that is the subject of the foreclosure sale;</section><section prefix="3.">The date of the foreclosure sale;</section><section prefix="4.">Whether the property is a single-family or multifamily property;</section><section prefix="5.">The name and address of the person, including a substitute purchaser, who is authorized to accept legal service for the foreclosure purchaser;</section><section prefix="6.">To the best of the foreclosure purchaser's knowledge at the time of registration:</section><section prefix="7.">Whether the foreclosure purchaser has possession of the property.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Within 30 days after a deed transferring title to the residential property has been recorded, the foreclosure purchaser shall submit a final registration to the Foreclosed Property Registry.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The final registration shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be in the form the Department requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Contain the following information as of the date of final registration:<section prefix="1.">The name, telephone number, and address of the owner on the deed;</section><section prefix="2.">The date of the ratification of the sale; and</section><section prefix="3.">The date the deed was recorded.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The filing fees for registering a residential property are:<section prefix="(i)">$50 for an initial registration filed within the time period required under subsection (d)(1) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">$100 for an initial registration filed after the time period required under subsection (d)(1) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">There is no fee for a final registration.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A filing fee paid under paragraph (1) of this subsection is nonrefundable.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A local jurisdiction may enact a local law that imposes a civil penalty for failure to register under this section in an amount not exceeding $1,000.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, a local jurisdiction that, in accordance with any applicable building code or local ordinance, abates a nuisance on a residential property registered under this section or takes action to maintain a residential property registered under this section may collect the cost associated with the abatement or other action as a charge included on the residential property's property tax bill. 	</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The cost associated with an abatement or other action taken under paragraph (1) of this subsection may not be included as a charge on the residential property's property tax bill unless the local jurisdiction provides advance written notice in accordance with subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph to:<section prefix="1.">The person identified in the registry who is authorized to accept legal service for the foreclosure purchaser; and</section><section prefix="2.">The person identified in the registry who is responsible for the maintenance of the property.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The notice described in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph shall:<section prefix="1.">Describe the intended abatement or other action the local jurisdiction intends to take; and</section><section prefix="2.">Be provided:</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Foreclosed Property Registry:<section prefix="(i)">Is not a public record as defined by &#xA7; 10-611 of the State Government Article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is not subject to Title 10, Subtitle 6 of the State Government Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department may authorize access to the Foreclosed Property Registry only to local jurisdictions, their agencies, and representatives and State agencies.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection, the Department or a local jurisdiction may provide information for a specific property in the Foreclosed Property Registry to:<section prefix="(i)">A person who owns property on the same block; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A homeowners association or condominium in which the property is located.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Revenue collected from the filing fees required under subsection (e)(1) of this section shall be distributed to the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Foreclosed Property Registry Fund in the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The purpose of the Fund is to support the development, administration, and maintenance of the Foreclosed Property Registry established under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department shall administer the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The State Treasurer shall hold the Fund separately, and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(i)">Revenue distributed to the Fund under subsection (h) of this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Investment earnings of the Fund;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Money appropriated in the State budget to the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any other money from any other source accepted for the benefit of the Fund.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The State Treasurer shall invest the money of the Fund in the same manner as other State money may be invested.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Any investment earnings of the Fund shall be paid into the Fund.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, only the State may enact a law requiring a notice to be filed with a unit of government to register residential properties that are subject to foreclosure.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection does not restrict or otherwise affect the ability of a unit of government to require a registration or notice to be filed for a purpose other than one relating to foreclosure, even if a property to be identified in the registration or notice is subject to foreclosure.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
