<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="grp" order_by="" level="1">Real Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>grp-14-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A party seeking to create a lien as the result of a breach of contract shall, within 2 years of a breach of contract, give written notice to the party against whose property the lien is intended to be imposed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, notice under this subsection shall be served by:<section prefix="(i)">Certified or registered mail, return receipt requested, addressed to the owner of the property against which the lien is sought to be imposed at the owner's last known address; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Personal delivery to the owner by the party seeking a lien or the party's agent.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a party seeking to create a lien is unable to serve an owner under paragraph (2) of this subsection, notice under this subsection shall be served by:<section prefix="(i)">The mailing of a notice to the owner's last known address; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Posting notice in a conspicuous manner on the property by the party seeking to create a lien or the party's agent in the presence of a competent witness. In the instance of a contractual lien on a building, the notice shall be posted in a conspicuous manner on the door or other front part of the building.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A notice under subsection (a) of this section shall include:<section prefix="(1)">The name and address of the party seeking to create the lien;</section><section prefix="(2)">A statement of intent to create a lien;</section><section prefix="(3)">An identification of the contract;</section><section prefix="(4)">The nature of the alleged breach;</section><section prefix="(5)">The amount of alleged damages;</section><section prefix="(6)">A description of the property against which the lien is intended to be imposed sufficient to identify the property, and stating the county or counties in which the property is located; and</section><section prefix="(7)">A statement that the party against whose property the lien is intended to be imposed has the right to a hearing under subsection (c) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A party to whom notice is given under subsection (a) of this section may, within 30 days after the notice is served on the party, file a complaint in the circuit court for the county in which any part of the property is located to determine whether probable cause exists for the establishment of a lien.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A complaint filed under this subsection shall include:<section prefix="(i)">The name of the complainant and the name of the party seeking to establish the lien;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A copy of the notice served under subsection (a) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">An affidavit containing a statement of facts that would preclude establishment of the lien for the damages alleged in the notice.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A party filing a complaint under this subsection may request a hearing at which any party may appear to present evidence.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a complaint is filed, the party seeking to establish the lien has the burden of proof.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The clerk of the circuit court shall docket the proceedings under this section, and all process shall issue out of and all pleadings shall be filed in a single action.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Before any hearing held under subsection (c) of this section, the party seeking to establish a lien may supplement, by means of an affidavit, any information contained in the notice given under subsection (a) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a complaint is filed under subsection (c) of this section, the court shall review any pleadings filed, including any supplementary affidavit filed under subsection (f) of this section, and shall conduct a hearing if requested under subsection (c)(3) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the court determines that probable cause exists to establish a lien, it shall order the lien imposed.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The order to impose a lien shall state that the owner of the property against which the lien is imposed may file a bond of a specified amount to have the lien against the property removed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the court orders a lien to be imposed under subsection (g) of this section, or if the owner of the property against which a lien is intended to be imposed fails to file a complaint under subsection (c) of this section the party seeking to create the lien may file a statement of lien among the land records of each county in which any portion of the property is located.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The party seeking to create the lien may file the lien statement in the county land records:<section prefix="(i)">If a complaint was filed under subsection (c) of this section, 30 days after the date of the court order allowing the creation of the lien; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If a complaint was not filed under subsection (c) of this section, 30 days after the owner was served under subsection (a)(2) or (3) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Unless the party seeking to create the lien and the owner agree otherwise, if the party seeking to create the lien fails to file the lien statement within 90 days after the expiration of the applicable time period described in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the party seeking to create the lien may:<section prefix="(i)">Not file the lien statement in the county land records; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">File for a new lien by complying with the requirements of subsections (a) through (h) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A lien imposed under this subtitle has priority from the date the statement of lien is filed.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Until an order imposing a lien is entered by the court, the owner of the property against which the lien is imposed may have the lien removed at any time by filing with the clerk of the circuit court a bond in the amount specified by the court under subsection (g)(3) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Until an order is entered by the court either establishing or denying a lien, the action shall proceed to trial on any matter at issue.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court may award costs and reasonable attorney's fees to any party under this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, a statement of lien is sufficient for purposes of this subtitle if it is in substantially the following form:</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies only to a lien that is subject to &#xA7; 11-110(f) or &#xA7; 11B-117(c) of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In addition to satisfying the requirements of paragraph (1) of this subsection, a statement of lien is sufficient for purposes of this subtitle if the statement includes specific information about the amount of the regular monthly assessments, or the equivalent of the regular monthly assessments, for common expenses in substantially the following form:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">If an order is entered under subsection (i) of this section denying a lien, or if a bond is filed under subsection (h) of this section, the clerk of the circuit court shall enter a notation in the land records releasing the lien.</section>
  </text>
</law>
