<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-5-7B-03</section_number>
  <catch_line>The governing body of a county or of a municipal corporation may designate priority funding areas as...</catch_line>
  <order_by>03</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of a county or of a municipal corporation may designate priority funding areas as provided in this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing bodies of two or more adjoining counties, two or more municipal corporations, or any combination of adjoining counties and municipal corporations may designate, as provided in this section and in accordance with the regulations adopted by the Department of Planning, a priority funding area that combines two or more contiguous areas located in each of the local governments.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An area zoned or, if applicable, classified by January 1, 1997 principally for industrial use may be designated as a priority funding area.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An area zoned or, if applicable, classified after January 1, 1997, as industrial may be designated as a priority funding area if the area is served by a public or community sewer system.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An area where the principal uses of the area are for employment may be designated as a priority funding area if:<section prefix="(i)">the area is served by public or community sewer systems; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">public or community sewer systems are planned in the approved 10-year water and sewer plan.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An area zoned or, if applicable, classified after January 1, 1997 as industrial, or where the principal uses are for employment, in addition to meeting the criteria set forth in paragraph (1) of this subsection, shall be located within a locally designated growth area.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A community in existence prior to January 1, 1997 that is within a locally designated growth area may be designated as a priority funding area if the community:<section prefix="(i)">is served by a public or community sewer system and in that part of the community designated by the local government for residential use or development:<section prefix="1.">there is an average density of at least 2.0 units per acre; or</section><section prefix="2.">if a portion of the community is undeveloped, the permitted average density is not less than 2.0 units per acre; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, is served by a public or community water system and in that part of the community designated by the local government for residential use or development there is an average density of at least 2.0 units per acre.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The provisions of paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection do not apply to mobile home parks or communities with less than 10 units.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Funding for a growth-related project under paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection is to be provided only if the project serves to maintain the character of the community and does not serve to increase the growth capacity of the community except for limited peripheral or in-fill development.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If an existing community receives a public or community sewer system, an area beyond the periphery of the developed portion of the existing community may be designated as a priority funding area if the development of the area beyond the periphery:<section prefix="1.">has a permitted average density of at least 3.5 units per acre; and</section><section prefix="2.">the area is served by a public or community sewer system.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Department of the Environment may provide funding for a sewer system in an existing community beyond the periphery of the developed portion of the community if the expansion has a permitted average density of at least 3.5 units per acre.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An area, other than an existing community under subsection (d) of this section, may be designated as a priority funding area if:<section prefix="(1)">the area:<section prefix="(i)">is within a locally designated growth area of the local government; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is planned to be served under the approved 10-year water and sewer plan;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the designation represents a long-term development policy for promoting an orderly expansion of growth and an efficient use of land and public services; and</section><section prefix="(3)">in that part of the area designated by the local government for residential use or development, there is permitted an average density of not less than 3.5 units per acre.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A rural village may be designated as a priority funding area under this section if:<section prefix="(i)">the village is designated in the county comprehensive plan as of July 1, 1998; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the boundary of the priority funding area is the periphery of the developed portion of the village as of July 1, 1998.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Funding for a growth-related project under this subtitle is to be provided only if the project serves to maintain the character of the community and does not serve to increase the growth capacity of the village except for limited peripheral or in-fill development.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The designation by a county, municipal corporation, or multiple local governments as provided in subsection (a)(2) of this section, of a priority funding area under this section shall be based on:<section prefix="(1)">an analysis of the capacity of land areas available for development, including in-fill and redevelopment; and</section><section prefix="(2)">an analysis of the land area needed to satisfy demand for development at densities consistent with the master plan.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">For the purposes of this section, average density shall be calculated based on the total acreage of all parcels in the area for which the principal permitted use is residential, excluding land:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">dedicated for public use by easement in perpetuity or fee acquisition; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">dedicated recreational use;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">subject to an agricultural easement under &#xA7; 2-508 of the Agriculture Article;</section><section prefix="(3)">subject to an agricultural easement under a county agricultural land preservation program certified under &#xA7; 5-408 of this title;</section><section prefix="(4)">used for cemetery purposes;</section><section prefix="(5)">identified by a local government as:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">streams and their buffers;</section><section prefix="2.">100-year flood plains;</section><section prefix="3.">habitats of threatened and endangered species; and</section><section prefix="4.">steep slopes; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">on which development is prohibited by local law or ordinance; or</section></section><section prefix="(6)">identified by a local government as delineated nontidal wetlands on which development is prohibited by State or local law or ordinance.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
