<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-301" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-14-301</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL JULY 1, 2016 PER CHAPTER 154 OF 2012 //<section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section><section prefix="(b)">"Certification" means the determination that a legal entity is a minority business enterprise for the purposes of this subtitle.</section><section prefix="(c)">"Certification agency" means the agency designated by the Board of Public Works under &#xA7; 14-303(b) of this subtitle to certify and decertify minority business enterprises.</section><section prefix="(d)">"Certified minority business enterprise" means a minority business enterprise that holds a certification.</section><section prefix="(e)">"Economically disadvantaged individual" means a socially disadvantaged individual whose ability to compete in the free enterprise system has been impaired due to diminished capital and credit opportunities as compared to others in the same or similar line of business who are not socially disadvantaged.</section><section prefix="(f)"><section prefix="(1)">"Minority business enterprise" means any legal entity, except a joint venture, that is:<section prefix="(i)">organized to engage in commercial transactions;</section><section prefix="(ii)">at least 51% owned and controlled by 1 or more individuals who are socially and economically disadvantaged; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">managed by, and the daily business operations of which are controlled by, one or more of the socially and economically disadvantaged individuals who own it.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">"Minority business enterprise" includes a not for profit entity organized to promote the interests of physically or mentally disabled individuals.</section></section><section prefix="(g)">"Minority business enterprise participation schedule" means a schedule included in the submission of a bid or offer that identifies:<section prefix="(1)">the certified minority business enterprises that a bidder or offeror agrees to use in the performance of the contract; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the percentage of contract value attributed to each certified minority business enterprise.</section></section><section prefix="(h)"><section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, "personal net worth" means the net value of the assets of an individual remaining after total liabilities are deducted.</section><section prefix="(2)">"Personal net worth" includes the individual's share of assets held jointly or as community property with the individual's spouse.</section><section prefix="(3)">"Personal net worth" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">the individual's ownership interest in the applicant or a certified minority business enterprise;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the individual's equity in his or her primary place of residence; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">up to $500,000 of the cash value of any qualified retirement savings plans or individual retirement accounts.</section></section></section><section prefix="(i)">"Race-neutral measure" means a method that is or can be used to assist all small businesses.</section><section prefix="(j)"><section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, and in accordance with the State's most recent disparity study, "socially and economically disadvantaged individual" means a citizen or lawfully admitted permanent resident of the United States who is:<section prefix="(i)">in any of the following minority groups:</section><section prefix="(ii)">otherwise found by the certification agency to be a socially and economically disadvantaged individual.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">There is a rebuttable presumption that an individual who is a member of a minority group under paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection is socially and economically disadvantaged.</section><section prefix="(3)">An individual whose personal net worth exceeds $1,500,000, as adjusted annually for inflation according to the Consumer Price Index, may not be found to be economically disadvantaged.</section></section><section prefix="(k)">"Socially disadvantaged individual" means an individual who has been subjected to racial or ethnic prejudice or cultural bias within American society because of membership in a group and without regard to individual qualities. Social disadvantage must stem from circumstances beyond the control of the individual.</section></text>
</law>
