<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-17-605</section_number>
  <catch_line>A contractor or subcontractor that elects to make payments to the Fund in accordance with this subti...</catch_line>
  <order_by>605</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A contractor or subcontractor that elects to make payments to the Fund in accordance with this subtitle shall make payments, as determined by the Secretary, not to exceed 25 cents per hour for each employee in each covered craft who is employed by the contractor or subcontractor on the covered project.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the prevailing wage determination for a covered craft includes a fringe benefit contribution for apprenticeship programs that exceeds 25 cents, the contractor or subcontractor shall pay the difference to the employees in the covered craft in wages.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Payments made under this section fulfill any obligations of the contractor or subcontractor regarding contributions for apprenticeship programs included in the prevailing wage determination under &#xA7; 17-208 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Payments made under paragraph (1) of this section are permissible deductions under &#xA7; 17-215(b) of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Payments made to the Fund in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be made on a monthly basis.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Secretary determines that a contractor or subcontractor for a covered project has made contributions to an apprenticeship training program at rates lower than those required by this subtitle, the contractor or subcontractor shall make payments to the Fund for the difference between its contribution and the contribution rate required by this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Payments made to the Fund in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be made on a monthly basis.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A contractor shall report all apprenticeship payments made under this subtitle on prevailing wage payroll records required by &#xA7; 17-220 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A contractor or subcontractor that makes contributions to the Fund, a registered apprenticeship program, or an organization that has registered apprenticeship programs may request that its contributions be directed to a specific preapprenticeship or workforce development program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary shall make a good-faith effort to accommodate requests received in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
