<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="17-203" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-17-203</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Advisory Council" means the Advisory Council on Prevailing Wage Rates.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is an Advisory Council on Prevailing Wage Rates in the Division of Labor and Industry.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Advisory Council consists of the following 6 members:<section prefix="(1)">2 individuals from management in the building and construction industry;</section><section prefix="(2)">2 individuals from labor in the building and construction industry; and</section><section prefix="(3)">2 individuals from the general public.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor shall appoint each member with the advice of the Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The 2 members from management shall be selected from a list submitted by management organizations in the building and construction industry.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The 2 members from labor shall be selected from a list submitted by labor organizations in the building and construction industry.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Before taking office, each appointee to the Advisory Council shall take the oath required by Article I, &#xA7; 9 of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">From among the Advisory Council members, the Governor shall appoint a chairman.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The chairman of the Advisory Council:<section prefix="(i)">shall serve for 1 year from the day of appointment; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is not eligible for reappointment as chairman for the following year.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Advisory Council on October 1, 1988.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If a vacancy occurs, the Governor shall appoint a new member with the advice of the Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Governor may remove a member for incompetence or misconduct.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Advisory Council shall advise and submit recommendations to the Commissioner on the Commissioner's functions under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner may ask other units of the State government or units of local governments to provide statistical data, reports, and other information to help the Advisory Council to carry out its duties.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The Advisory Council shall meet at least twice a year and on other days the Commissioner requests, at the times and places that it determines.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">Each member of the Advisory Council is entitled to:<section prefix="(1)">compensation in accordance with the State budget; and</section><section prefix="(2)">reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">Subject to the evaluation and reestablishment provisions of the Maryland Program Evaluation Act, this section shall terminate and be of no effect after July 1, 2014.</section>
  </text>
</law>
