<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-13-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>Competitive sealed proposals may be used if:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Competitive sealed proposals may be used if:<section prefix="(1)">the procurement is for human, social, cultural, or educational services;</section><section prefix="(2)">with the approval of the head of a unit, the procurement officer determines that specifications cannot be prepared that allow an award based on the lowest bid price, the lowest evaluated bid price or, if the procurement is subject to &#xA7; 11-202(3) of this article, the bid most favorable to the State; or</section><section prefix="(3)">the head of the unit determines that:<section prefix="(i)">the need to use a method other than competitive sealed bids is sufficiently compelling to override the general public policy that favors awarding procurement contracts on the basis of competitive sealed bids; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the use of competitive sealed bidding for that procurement contract is not practicable or not advantageous to the State.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whenever procurement is based on competitive sealed proposals, a procurement officer shall seek proposals by issuing a request for proposals.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A request for proposals shall include a statement of:<section prefix="(i)">the scope of the procurement contract, including the expected degree of minority business enterprise participation, as provided in &#xA7; 14-303(b) of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the factors, including price, that will be used in evaluating proposals; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the relative importance of each factor.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A unit shall publish a request for proposals in the same manner as required for an invitation for bids.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After receipt of proposals but before the procurement officer awards the procurement contract, a unit may conduct discussions with an offeror to:<section prefix="(i)">obtain the best price for the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">ensure full understanding of:<section prefix="1.">the requirements of the State, as set forth in the request for proposals; and</section><section prefix="2.">the proposal submitted by the offeror.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If discussions are conducted, the unit:<section prefix="(i)">shall conduct the discussions in accordance with regulations adopted under this Division II;</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall provide an opportunity to participate to each responsible offeror who submits a proposal that, in the judgment of the procurement officer, is reasonably susceptible of being selected for award;</section><section prefix="(iii)">shall treat all of those responsible offerors fairly and equally;</section><section prefix="(iv)">may allow all of those responsible offerors to revise their initial proposals by submitting best and final offers, if discussions indicate that it would be in the best interests of the State to do so;</section><section prefix="(v)">may conduct more than 1 series of discussions and requests for best and final offers; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">may not disclose to an offeror any information derived from a proposal of or discussions with a competing offeror.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">a proposal is irrevocable for the period specified in the request for proposals; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a best and final offer is irrevocable for the period specified in the request for best and final offers.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A procurement officer may allow an offeror to correct or withdraw a proposal or best and final offer if correction or withdrawal is:<section prefix="(i)">allowed under regulations adopted under this Division II; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">approved in writing by the Office of the Attorney General.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">After obtaining any approval required by law, the procurement officer shall award the procurement contract to the responsible offeror who submits the proposal or best and final offer determined to be the most advantageous to the State considering the evaluation factors set forth in the request for proposals.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A unit shall publish notice of a contract in excess of $25,000 awarded under this section, or a lower amount set by the Board by regulation in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 1 of the State Government Article as follows:<section prefix="(1)">until July 1, 2006, in the Contract Weekly and in eMaryland Marketplace; and</section><section prefix="(2)">on and after July 1, 2006, in eMaryland Marketplace.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
