<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-14-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Community service provider" means an entity that:<section prefix="(1)">is organized under the laws of the United States or this State;</section><section prefix="(2)">is accredited by the Division of Rehabilitation Services of the State Department of Education for participation in the Employment Works Program;</section><section prefix="(3)">is operated in the interest of individuals who have a mental or physical disability, including blindness, that:<section prefix="(i)">constitutes a substantial barrier to employment; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">prevents the individual from engaging in competitive employment; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">does not inure net income wholly or partly to the benefit of any shareholder or other individual.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Individual with disability owned business" means a business:<section prefix="(1)">that is organized under the laws of the United States or the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">that is majority owned by an individual or individuals determined by the Division of Rehabilitation Services in the State Department of Education to have a disability, as defined by Title 21, Subtitle 3 of the Education Article;</section><section prefix="(3)">whose majority owner or owners are directly and significantly engaged in the daily operation of the business;</section><section prefix="(4)">whose workforce includes individuals with disabilities comprising a percentage of the workforce that is at or above the minimum required under the policies or guidelines established by the Pricing and Selection Committee for the Employment Works Program;</section><section prefix="(5)">whose total gross revenues for contracts assigned under the Program at the time of assignment do not exceed the maximum allowed under policies or guidelines established by the Pricing and Selection Committee for the Employment Works Program; and</section><section prefix="(6)">that continues to meet all other eligibility criteria established by the Pricing and Selection Committee for the Employment Works Program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"State aided or controlled entity" means any public or quasi-public institution that receives aid from the State or that is owned, controlled, or managed by the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
