<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-18-102</section_number>
  <catch_line>This title applies to an employee of an employer for the duration of a contract subject to this titl...</catch_line>
  <order_by>102</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This title applies to an employee of an employer for the duration of a contract subject to this title if at least one-half of the employee's time during any workweek relates to a State contract for services or a subcontract for services under a State contract.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This title does not apply to an employee of an employer if the employee:<section prefix="(i)">is 17 years of age or younger for the duration of a contract subject to this title; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">works less than 13 consecutive weeks for the duration of a contract subject to this title and during that period works full time.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This title does not apply to a contract:<section prefix="(1)">for services needed immediately to prevent or respond to an imminent threat to public health or safety;</section><section prefix="(2)">with a public service company;</section><section prefix="(3)">with a nonprofit organization;</section><section prefix="(4)">between units; or</section><section prefix="(5)">between a unit and a county or Baltimore City.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the unit responsible for a State contract determines that application of this title would conflict with any applicable federal program requirement, this title does not apply to the contract or program.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The head of the unit responsible for a State contract  subject to this title shall determine if contract services valued at  50% or more of the total value of the contract will be performed in  the Tier 1 area or the Tier 2 area and shall provide that  determination on the invitation for a bid.</section>
  </text>
</law>
