<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-7-312</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Maryland Stadium Facilities Fund....</catch_line>
  <order_by>312</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Maryland Stadium Facilities Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Fund is:<section prefix="(1)">a special, nonlapsing fund that consists of moneys that may be appropriated, transferred, credited, or paid to it from any source; and</section><section prefix="(2)">not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Treasurer shall separately hold, and the Comptroller shall account for, the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund shall be invested and reinvested in the same manner as other State funds.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any investment earnings shall be retained to the credit of the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Moneys credited to the Maryland Stadium Facilities Fund may be used, in accordance with approved comprehensive financing plans, to:<section prefix="(1)">pay rent to the Maryland Stadium Authority;</section><section prefix="(2)">with the approval of the Board of Public Works, make grants or loans, not exceeding $1 million in any fiscal year, to the Authority for its corporate purposes;</section><section prefix="(3)">with the approval of the Board of Public Works, finance capital construction in lieu of issuing bonds; or</section><section prefix="(4)">financially support, through equity investment, loan, guarantee, or otherwise, full or partial private financing of any element of the facility.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At the end of the fiscal year, a transfer to the Dedicated Purpose Fund of the State Reserve Fund shall be made to the extent that the balance of revenues in the Fund exceeds:<section prefix="(i)">$24 million; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Debt Service Reserve Fund being held by or on behalf of the Maryland Stadium Authority for payment of debt service on revenue bonds issued by the Authority.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Any revenues transferred to the State Reserve Fund in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be dedicated for use by the Maryland Stadium Authority and may be transferred from the State Reserve Fund by an appropriation in the budget bill or, with the approval of the Legislative Policy Committee, by budget amendment.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The unspent balance of any revenues for the Maryland Stadium Authority in the State Reserve Fund shall revert to the General Fund 2 years after the end of the fiscal year in which the transfer was made.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
