<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-111" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-12-111</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Public employer" means:<section prefix="(i)">a unit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a county;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a municipality;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a county board of education; or</section><section prefix="(v)">a special taxing district.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, "services" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 11-101(t) of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Services" includes:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to a procurement contract with an estimated value of $2,000,000 or more.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In response to a solicitation for a procurement contract issued by a public employer, a bidder shall disclose to the public employer the following:<section prefix="(1)">whether the bidder or any contractor that the bidder will subcontract with to perform the contract has plans, at the time the bid is submitted, to perform any services required under the contract outside the United States; and</section><section prefix="(2)">if services required under the contract are anticipated to be performed outside the United States:<section prefix="(i)">where the services will be performed; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the reasons why it is necessary or advantageous to perform the services outside the United States.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a public employer may not knowingly contract for the following services unless the services are to be provided in the United States:<section prefix="(i)">architectural services;</section><section prefix="(ii)">construction services;</section><section prefix="(iii)">engineering services; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">energy performance contract services.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A public employer may contract for services listed in paragraph (1) of this subsection that are provided outside the United States, if:<section prefix="(i)">the services are not available in the United States;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the price of the services in the United States exceeds by an unreasonable amount the price of services provided outside the United States; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the quality of the services in the United States is substantially less than the quality of comparably priced services provided outside the United States.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board shall adopt regulations defining the following terms for the purposes of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">"unreasonable amount"; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">"substantially less".</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
