<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-5-805</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>805</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department has primary responsibility for preparing proposed amendments to the Plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For the purpose of updating the Plan, the Department and the Commission shall together consider draft amendments to the Plan at least once every 5 years starting with October 1, 1995.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In preparing a proposed amendment, the Department shall consult with local jurisdictions and appropriate units of the State government, who shall:<section prefix="(i)">provide the Department with pertinent information, including information on implementation of the Plan; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">cooperate with and assist the Department in preparing the proposed amendment.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Before the Department presents a proposed amendment to the Plan to local jurisdictions for their approval, the Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">review and comment on the proposed amendment and work with the Department in making any modifications to the proposed amendment that the Commission considers necessary;</section><section prefix="(2)">distribute copies of the proposed amendment to the Governor, appropriate members of the General Assembly, the local jurisdictions entitled to voting representation on the Commission, other affected local jurisdictions, and appropriate units of the State government, for their information and comments; and</section><section prefix="(3)">conduct at least 1 public hearing on the proposed amendment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">After a proposed amendment to the Plan has been acted on by the Commission, the Department may present the proposed amendment to the governing bodies of the local jurisdictions entitled to voting representation on the Commission, for their approval, by resolution. The Department shall include any comments made by the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the governing bodies of 6 of the 8 local jurisdictions entitled to voting representation on the Commission approve the proposed amendment, the Department shall present the proposed amendment to the General Assembly. The Department shall include any comments made by the Commission or by the governing bodies.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the General Assembly, by joint resolution, approves the proposed amendment, the effective date of the amendment is immediate, unless otherwise specified in the amendment.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
