<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="17-220" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-17-220</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each contractor required to pay the prevailing wage rate shall:<section prefix="(1)">keep payroll records covering work performed directly at the work site in accordance with regulations adopted by the Commissioner; and</section><section prefix="(2)">allow the Commissioner or the public body to inspect the records at any reasonable time and as often as necessary.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each contractor shall submit a complete copy of the payroll records of the contractor and, for work performed at the work site, of the subcontractors in the form that the Commissioner specifies by regulation to:<section prefix="(i)">the public body; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Commissioner.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner and the public body shall make payroll records available for public inspection during regular business hours.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each copy of the payroll records shall be accompanied by a statement that is signed by the contractor or, for the subcontractor's records, by the subcontractor and indicates that:<section prefix="(1)">the payroll records are correct;</section><section prefix="(2)">the wage rates paid are not less than those established by the Commissioner as set forth in the public work contract;</section><section prefix="(3)">the classification set forth for each employee conforms with the work performed by that employee; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the contractor or subcontractor has complied with each requirement of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a contractor is late in submitting copies of the payroll records required under subsection (b) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">the public body may postpone the processing of partial payment estimates under the public work contract pending receipt of the copies; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the contractor shall be liable to the public body for liquidated damages of $10 for each calendar day the records are late.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
