<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-108" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-13-108</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 11-205 ("Collusion"), &#xA7; 10-204 ("Approval for designated contracts"), &#xA7; 13-219 ("Required clauses - Nondiscrimination clause"), &#xA7; 13-221 ("Disclosures to Secretary of State"), Title 16 ("Suspension and Debarment of Contractors"), or Title 17 ("Special Provisions - State and Local Subdivisions") of this article, with the approval of the head of a unit, its procurement officer may make an emergency procurement by any method that the procurement officer considers most appropriate to avoid or mitigate serious damage to public health, safety, or welfare.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The procurement officer shall:<section prefix="(i)">obtain as much competition as possible under the circumstances;</section><section prefix="(ii)">limit the emergency procurement to the procurement of only those items, both in type and quantity, necessary to avoid or to mitigate serious damage to public health, safety, or welfare; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">after awarding the procurement contract, submit to the Board a written report that gives the justification for use of the emergency procurement procedure.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 11-205 ("Collusion"), &#xA7; 10-204 ("Approval for designated contracts"), &#xA7; 13-219 ("Required clauses - Nondiscrimination clause"), &#xA7; 13-221 ("Disclosures to Secretary of State"), Title 16 ("Suspension and Debarment of Contractors"), or Title 17 ("Special Provisions - State and Local Subdivisions") of this article, with the approval of the head of the unit and the Board, the Maryland Port Commission or the Maryland Aviation Administration may make a procurement on an expedited basis if the head of the unit and the Board find that:<section prefix="(i)">urgent circumstances require prompt action;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an expedited procurement best serves the public interest; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the need for the expedited procurement outweighs the benefits of making the procurement on the basis of competitive sealed bids or competitive sealed proposals.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The procurement officer shall attempt to obtain as much competition as reasonably possible.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Not more than 30 days after the execution and approval of a procurement contract awarded under this section, a unit shall publish in eMaryland Marketplace notice of the award.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For real property leases procured under this section, the term of the lease shall be for the minimum period of time practicable.</section>
  </text>
</law>
