<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-19-108</section_number>
  <catch_line>In determining whether to proceed further with an investigation and in making findings, Commission s...</catch_line>
  <order_by>108</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In determining whether to proceed further with an investigation and in making findings, Commission staff may consider any evidence provided by the complainant or the respondent business entity as to the following factors:<section prefix="(1)">whether there was an intent to discriminate on the part of the respondent business firm;</section><section prefix="(2)">whether there was a pattern and practice of discrimination on the part of the respondent business entity;</section><section prefix="(3)">any actions taken by the respondent business entity to remedy the alleged discrimination;</section><section prefix="(4)">the effectiveness of any prior attempts by the respondent business entity to remedy the discrimination;</section><section prefix="(5)">whether the respondent business entity has procured goods or services from or otherwise engaged in business with persons or entities of the same protected class as the complainant to an extent sufficient to demonstrate that the respondent business entity has not discriminated against such protected class in the overall context of its business; and</section><section prefix="(6)">any other evidence deemed relevant by the Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Based on a review and investigation consistent with &#xA7; 20-1005 of the State Government Article, Commission staff shall make an initial finding of each allegation stated in the complaint, that either:<section prefix="(1)">the investigation produced sufficient evidence to find that the alleged discrimination or retaliation did take place ("probable cause");</section><section prefix="(2)">the investigation failed to produce sufficient evidence to find that the alleged discrimination or retaliation took place ("no probable cause");</section><section prefix="(3)">the investigation produced sufficient evidence to establish that the complainant knowingly made one or more false or frivolous allegations, and further investigation did not appear likely to produce sufficient evidence that the alleged discrimination or retaliation did take place ("false or frivolous");</section><section prefix="(4)">the allegation has been settled or otherwise resolved with the agreement of the respondent business entity, the complainant, and the State ("settled"); or</section><section prefix="(5)">the allegation has been withdrawn ("withdrawn").</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Commission staff shall make the initial findings under subsection (b) of this section based on a preponderance of the evidence.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">On completion of its initial investigation, Commission staff shall recommend to the Commission the appropriate action to be taken, including:<section prefix="(1)">additional investigation of the complaint;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Commission's adoption of the initial findings rendered by Commission staff;</section><section prefix="(3)">imposition of sanctions;</section><section prefix="(4)">imposition of remedies; or</section><section prefix="(5)">other action consistent with this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In determining appropriate action on a discrimination claim, the Commission may take into account any evidence provided or uncovered in the course of the investigation regarding:<section prefix="(1)">the impact of the discrimination on affected parties;</section><section prefix="(2)">the impact of any authorized remedy on the State or any other party;</section><section prefix="(3)">actions taken by the respondent business entity to remedy the alleged discrimination;</section><section prefix="(4)">the effectiveness of any prior attempts by the respondent business entity to remedy the discrimination;</section><section prefix="(5)">whether the respondent business entity has procured goods or services from or otherwise engaged in business with persons or entities of the same protected class as the complainant to an extent sufficient to demonstrate that the respondent business entity has not discriminated against such protected class in the overall context of its business;</section><section prefix="(6)">the number and scope of prior violations of this policy by the respondent business entity; and</section><section prefix="(7)">any other evidence determined to be relevant by the Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Commission shall make the initial findings and issue recommendations for appropriate action within 120 calendar days of the receipt of the complaint.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission may extend the time limit set forth in paragraph (1) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">for good cause; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the parties agree to mediate a settlement to the complaint.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Commission shall notify the complainant and the business entity within 5 business days of the issuance of the initial findings and recommendations, including an explanation of the reasons justifying the initial findings.</section>
  </text>
</law>
