<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-8-209</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>209</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the limitations in this section, with the approval of the Board of Public Works, a State unit authorized to issue bonds may issue new bonds to refund its outstanding bonds.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The power to issue bonds under this section is in addition to any other power to borrow.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A State unit may issue bonds under this section only for:<section prefix="(1)">the public purpose of realizing for the State unit a savings in the total cost of debt service on a direct comparison or present value basis;</section><section prefix="(2)">the public purpose of debt restructuring that reduces the total cost of debt service; or</section><section prefix="(3)">the public purpose of debt restructuring that the State unit determines:<section prefix="(i)">is in its best interests;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is consistent with its long term financial plan; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">realizes a financial objective of the State unit, including improvement of the relationship of debt service to any source of payment such as taxes, assessments, or other charges.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A State unit may:<section prefix="(1)">provide that bonds under this section be in 1 or more series; and</section><section prefix="(2)">vary the amount of the series.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The total principal amount of the bonds issued under this section may exceed the total principal amount of the bonds that are being refunded.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To determine whether the bonds under this section are within any limit on debt that applies to the State unit:<section prefix="(i)">the amount of the bonds that are being refunded shall be subtracted from its total outstanding debt; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the amount of the bonds issued under this section shall be added to the difference.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a State unit shall issue bonds under this section in accordance with the procedures that applied to issuance of the bonds that are being refunded.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If, at a public meeting, the State unit determines that it would be in the public interest, the State unit may sell bonds issued under this section at a private sale, without soliciting bids.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Bonds that are being refunded and that are subject to redemption before their stated dates of maturity may be called for redemption:<section prefix="(1)">on the earliest redemption date; or</section><section prefix="(2)">at a later date that the State unit determines.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A State unit shall invest and apply proceeds of a sale of bonds issued under this section to ensure that the principal and redemption premium of, and interest on, the bonds that are being refunded will be paid in full when due.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State unit may deposit any part of the proceeds of the sale of bonds issued under this section in a trust fund with a trust company or other banking institution, in the name of the State unit.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The trustee may invest and reinvest money in the trust fund in:<section prefix="(i)">obligations of the United States;</section><section prefix="(ii)">obligations guaranteed by the United States;</section><section prefix="(iii)">certificates of deposit or time deposits secured by an obligation of the United States; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">certificates of deposit or time deposits secured by an obligation guaranteed by the United States.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Interest, income, and profits on the investment may be:<section prefix="(i)">considered to be revenue of a revenue project; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">applied in any lawful manner, including to the payment of:<section prefix="1.">the bonds that are being refunded; and</section><section prefix="2.">the bonds issued under this section.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The trustee shall make money in the trust fund available, as the State unit requires, for the payment of:<section prefix="(i)">the principal and redemption premium of, and interest on, the bonds that are being refunded;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the principal and redemption premium of, and interest on, the bonds issued under this section; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">any other related costs.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">All or any part of the bonds issued under this section may be made payable from and secured by:<section prefix="(1)">money in the trust fund; or</section><section prefix="(2)">other money or security that the State unit provides.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
