<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-3A-308</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section does not apply to a public institution of higher education....</catch_line>
  <order_by>308</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to a public institution of higher education.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In submitting its information technology project requests, a unit of State government shall designate projects which are major information technology development projects.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In reviewing information technology project requests, the Secretary may change a unit's designation of a major information technology development project.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary shall review and, with the advice of the Secretary of Budget and Management, approve major information technology development projects and specifications for consistency with all statewide plans, policies, and standards, including a systems development life cycle plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Secretary shall be responsible for overseeing the implementation of major information technology development projects, regardless of fund source.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">With the advice of the Secretary of Budget and Management, expenditures for major information technology development projects shall be subject to the approval of the Secretary who shall approve expenditures only when those projects are consistent with statewide plans, policies, and standards.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall approve funding for major information technology development projects only when those projects are supported by an approved systems development life cycle plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An approved systems development life cycle plan shall include submission of:<section prefix="(i)">a project planning request that details initial planning for the project, including:<section prefix="1.">the project title, appropriation code, and summary;</section><section prefix="2.">a description of:</section><section prefix="3.">an estimate of:</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">a project implementation request to begin full design, development, and implementation of the project after the completion of planning, including:<section prefix="1.">the project title, appropriation code, and summary;</section><section prefix="2.">a description of:</section><section prefix="3.">an estimate of:</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary may approve funding incrementally, consistent with the systems development life cycle plan.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
