<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-8-125</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>125</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Fund" means the State and Local Facilities Loan Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For bonds issued under &#xA7; 8-122 of this subtitle, the Comptroller shall establish:<section prefix="(1)">the State and Local Facilities Loan Fund;</section><section prefix="(2)">a premium and expense account in the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(3)">for accounting purposes only:<section prefix="(i)">a capital project account for each enabling act; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">separate subaccounts for each project included in enabling acts authorizing multiple projects.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Comptroller shall credit the proceeds of the sale of State bonds to the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Comptroller shall credit to the premium and expenses account:<section prefix="(i)">any part of the proceeds of a bond sale that is a premium; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any additional part of the proceeds necessary to pay the expenses of that bond sale.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On approval by the Board, the Comptroller may expend money from the Fund for any expenditure authorized by an enabling act, regardless of whether bonds have been sold to specifically fund that enabling act.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To ensure compliance with &#xA7; 8-127 of this subtitle, the Comptroller shall account for all expenditures from the Fund on a project-specific basis.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An expenditure made under this subsection may not reduce the amount of bonds authorized under an enabling act for which bonds have not been sold.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless payment of expenses otherwise has been provided, the expenses of each bond sale shall be paid from the proceeds of that bond sale credited to the premium and expense account.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After the expenses of each sale of State bonds have been paid, the remaining premium credited to the premium and expense account from that bond sale shall be transferred to the Annuity Bond Fund to pay debt service on State bonds.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
