<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-5A-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Business entity" means:<section prefix="(i)">a person conducting or operating a trade or business in the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an organization operating in Maryland that is exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Certified heritage area" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 13-1101 of the Financial Institutions Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Certified historic structure" means a structure that is located in the State and is:<section prefix="1.">listed in the National Register of Historic Places;</section><section prefix="2.">designated as a historic property under local law and determined by the Director to be eligible for listing on the National Register of Historic Places;</section><section prefix="3."/><section prefix="4.">located in a certified heritage area and certified by the Maryland Heritage Areas Authority as contributing to the significance of the certified heritage area.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Certified historic structure" does not include a structure that is owned by the State, a political subdivision of the State, or the federal government.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Certified rehabilitation" means a completed rehabilitation of:<section prefix="(i)">a certified historic structure that the Director certifies is a substantial rehabilitation in conformance with the rehabilitation standards of the United States Secretary of the Interior; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a qualified rehabilitated structure.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Commercial rehabilitation" means a rehabilitation of a structure other than a single-family, owner-occupied residence.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Director" means the Director of the Maryland Historical Trust.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Financial assistance" means action by the State or a State unit to award grants, loans, loan guarantees, or insurance to a public or private entity to finance, wholly or partly, a project that involves or may result in building construction, building alteration, or land disturbance.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">"High performance building" means a building that:<section prefix="(i)">meets or exceeds the current version of the U.S. Green Building Council's LEED (Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design) green building rating system gold rating; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">achieves at least a comparable numeric rating according to a nationally recognized, accepted, and appropriate numeric sustainable development rating system, guideline, or standard approved by the Secretaries of Budget and Management and General Services under &#xA7; 3-602.1 of this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(10)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Historic property" means a district, site, building, structure, monument, or object significant to:<section prefix="1.">the prehistory or history of the State; or</section><section prefix="2.">the upland or underwater archeology, architecture, engineering, or culture of the State.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Historic property" includes related artifacts, records, and remains.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(11)">"Local historic district" means a district that the governing body of a county or municipal corporation, or the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore, has designated under local law as historic.</section>
      <section prefix="(12)">"Main Street Maryland community" means:<section prefix="(i)">a commercial area in a local jurisdiction designated by the Secretary of Housing and Community Development as a Main Street Maryland community under the Main Street Maryland Program on or before January 1, 2010; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a commercial area in Baltimore City designated as a Main Street by the Mayor of Baltimore City on or before January 1, 2010.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(13)">"Main Street Maryland Program" means the Maryland Main Street designation program for local jurisdictions established in the Code of Maryland Regulations (COMAR).</section>
      <section prefix="(14)">"National register structure" means a structure that is:<section prefix="(i)">listed on the National Register of Historic Places; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">located in a historic district listed on the National Register of Historic Places and certified by the Director as contributing to the significance of the district.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(15)">"Political subdivision" means a county or municipal corporation of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(16)">"Qualified rehabilitation expenditure" means any amount that:<section prefix="(i)">is properly chargeable to a capital account;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is expended in the rehabilitation of a structure that by the end of the calendar year in which the certified rehabilitation is completed is a certified historic structure or a qualified rehabilitated structure;</section><section prefix="(iii)">is expended in compliance with a plan of proposed rehabilitation that has been approved by the Director; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">is not funded, financed, or otherwise reimbursed by any:<section prefix="1.">State or local grant;</section><section prefix="2.">grant made from the proceeds of tax-exempt bonds issued by the State, a political subdivision of the State, or an instrumentality of the State or of a political subdivision of the State;</section><section prefix="3.">State tax credit other than the tax credit under this section; or</section><section prefix="4.">other financial assistance from the State or a political subdivision of the State, other than a loan that must be repaid at an interest rate that is greater than the interest rate on general obligation bonds issued by the State at the most recent bond sale prior to the time the loan is made.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(17)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Qualified rehabilitated structure" means a building, other than a single-family, owner-occupied residence, that:<section prefix="1."/><section prefix="2.">will be substantially rehabilitated; and</section><section prefix="3.">meets the requirements set forth in subsection (b)(7) of this section.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Qualified rehabilitated structure" does not include a certified historic structure.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(18)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Single-family, owner-occupied residence" means a structure or a portion of a structure occupied by the owner and the owner's immediate family as their primary or secondary residence.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Single-family, owner-occupied residence" includes a residential unit in a cooperative project owned by or leased to a cooperative housing corporation, as defined in &#xA7; 5-6B-01 of the Corporations and Associations Article, and leased for exclusive occupancy to, and occupied by, a member of the corporation and the member's immediate family under a proprietary lease.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(19)">"Smart Growth Subcabinet" means the Smart Growth Subcabinet established under Title 9, Subtitle 14 of the State Government Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(20)">"State unit" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 11-101 of the State Government Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(21)">"Substantial rehabilitation" means rehabilitation of a structure for which the qualified rehabilitation expenditures, during the 24-month period selected by the individual or business entity ending with or within the taxable year, exceed:<section prefix="(i)">for single-family, owner-occupied residential property, $5,000;</section><section prefix="(ii)">for a qualified rehabilitated structure located in a Main Street Maryland community, the greater of:<section prefix="1.">50% of the adjusted basis of the structure; or</section><section prefix="2.">$25,000; or</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">for all other property, the greater of:<section prefix="1.">the adjusted basis of the structure; or</section><section prefix="2.">$25,000.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(22)">"Sustainable community" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 6-201 of the Housing and Community Development Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Director, in consultation with the Smart Growth Subcabinet, shall adopt regulations to:<section prefix="(i)">establish procedures and standards for certifying historic structures and rehabilitations under this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">for commercial rehabilitations, establish an application process for the award of initial credit certificates for Maryland sustainable communities tax credits consistent with the requirements of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(iii)">for commercial rehabilitations, establish criteria, consistent with the requirements of this subsection, for evaluating, comparing, and rating plans of proposed rehabilitation that have been determined by the Director:<section prefix="1.">for certified historic structures, to conform with the rehabilitation standards of the United States Secretary of the Interior;</section><section prefix="2.">for rehabilitations of the exteriors of qualified rehabilitated structures, to be compatible with the rehabilitation standards of the United States Secretary of the Interior if the structure is located in, or adversely affects:</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">for commercial rehabilitations, establish a competitive award process for the award of initial credit certificates for Maryland sustainable communities tax credits that favors the award of tax credits for rehabilitation projects that:<section prefix="1.">are located in jurisdictions that have been historically underrepresented in the award of tax credits for commercial rehabilitations, based on the number of national register structures in each jurisdiction;</section><section prefix="2.">are consistent with and promote current growth and development policies and programs of the State;</section><section prefix="3.">are located in areas targeted by the State for additional revitalization and economic development opportunities due to the focusing of State resources and incentives;</section><section prefix="4.">beginning in fiscal 2012, are located in sustainable communities;</section><section prefix="5.">are located in areas where the political subdivision has implemented regulatory streamlining or other development incentives that foster redevelopment and revitalization in priority funding areas, as defined in Title 5, Subtitle 7B of this article, and the appropriate local governing body or the planning board or commission, if designated by the local governing body, has certified to the Smart Growth Subcabinet those regulatory streamlining or other development incentives;</section><section prefix="6.">include affordable and workforce housing options; and</section><section prefix="7.">are qualified rehabilitated structures more than 50 years old;</section></section><section prefix="(v)">for commercial rehabilitations, determine whether the certified rehabilitation is a high performance building;</section><section prefix="(vi)">for commercial rehabilitations, establish a required external marker or, at a minimum, an internal marker for the rehabilitation projects that identifies that the rehabilitation was funded by Maryland sustainable communities tax credits; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">as provided in paragraph (6) of this subsection, charge a reasonable fee to certify historic structures and qualified rehabilitated structures under this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Director may not certify that a rehabilitation is a certified rehabilitation eligible for a tax credit provided under this section unless the individual or business entity seeking certification states under oath the amount of the individual's or business entity's qualified rehabilitation expenditures.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each year, the Director may accept applications for approval of plans of proposed commercial rehabilitations and for the award of initial credit certificates for the fiscal year that begins July 1 of that year.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">For commercial rehabilitations, the Director may not accept an application for approval of plans of proposed rehabilitation if:<section prefix="1.">any substantial part of the proposed rehabilitation work has begun; or</section><section prefix="2.">the applicant for a commercial rehabilitation has previously submitted three or more applications for commercial rehabilitations with total proposed rehabilitations exceeding $500,000 in that year.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For commercial rehabilitations, the Director may accept an application for approval of plans of a proposed rehabilitation for which a substantial part of the proposed rehabilitation work has begun if the rehabilitation work has been approved under the federal historic tax credit.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subsection (d)(3)(iii) of this section, not more than 75% of the total credit amounts under initial credit certificates issued for any fiscal year may be issued for projects in a single county or Baltimore City.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Not more than 10% of the total credit amounts under initial credit certificates issued for any fiscal year may be issued for projects that are qualified rehabilitated structures.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Director shall adopt regulations to charge a reasonable fee to certify historic structures and rehabilitations under this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Director shall set the level of the fee so that the projected proceeds from the fee will cover the costs to the Trust of administering the credit under this section and the federal historic tax credit.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The fee charged may not exceed 3% of the amount of the initial credit certificate issued for a commercial rehabilitation project or the amount of the credit for which a single-family, owner-occupied rehabilitation would be eligible based on the greater of the estimated or final qualified rehabilitation expenditures for the rehabilitation.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">If the fee charged for a commercial rehabilitation is not received by the Trust within 120 days after the Trust sends notice that the fee is due, the initial credit certificate for the rehabilitation shall expire.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The proceeds from the fee shall be deposited in a special fund, to be used only for the purposes of paying the costs of administering the credit under this section and the federal historic tax credit.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">Any unused balance of the fund at the end of each fiscal year shall be transferred to the Reserve Fund established under subsection (d) of this section and shall increase the amount of the initial credit certificates that the Trust may issue for the following fiscal year.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">For a building to be a qualified rehabilitated structure, after the rehabilitation process:<section prefix="(i)">50% or more of the existing external walls of the building must be retained in place as external walls;</section><section prefix="(ii)">75% or more of the existing external walls of the building must be retained in place as internal or external walls; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">75% or more of the internal structural framework of the building must be retained in place.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, for the taxable year in which a certified rehabilitation is completed, an individual or business entity may claim a tax credit in an amount equal to 20% of the individual's or business entity's qualified rehabilitation expenditures for the rehabilitation.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For commercial rehabilitations, an individual or business entity may claim a tax credit in an amount equal to 25% of the individual's or business entity's qualified rehabilitation expenditures if the certified rehabilitation is a certified historic structure and a high performance building.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">For commercial rehabilitations, an individual or business entity may claim a tax credit in an amount equal to 10% of the individual's or business entity's qualified rehabilitation expenditures if the certified rehabilitation is a qualified rehabilitated structure.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">For any commercial rehabilitation, the State tax credit allowed under this section may not exceed the lesser of:<section prefix="1.">$3,000,000; or</section><section prefix="2.">the maximum amount specified under the initial credit certificate issued for the rehabilitation.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For a rehabilitation other than a commercial rehabilitation, the State tax credit allowed under this section may not exceed $50,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">For the purposes of the limitation under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the following shall be treated as a single commercial rehabilitation:<section prefix="1.">the phased rehabilitation of the same structure or property;</section><section prefix="2.">the separate rehabilitation of different components of the same structure or property; or</section><section prefix="3.">the rehabilitation of multiple structures that are functionally related to serve an overall purpose.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the initial credit certificate for a proposed commercial rehabilitation shall expire and the credit under this section may not be claimed if:<section prefix="1.">within 18 months after the initial credit certificate was issued, the applicant has not notified the Trust, in writing, that the commercial rehabilitation has begun; or</section><section prefix="2.">the commercial rehabilitation is not completed within 30 months after the initial credit certificate was issued.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For reasonable cause, the Director may postpone the 30-month expiration date for an initial credit certificate for a commercial rehabilitation.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the tax credit allowed under this section in any taxable year exceeds the total tax otherwise payable by the business entity or the individual for that taxable year, the individual or business entity may claim a refund in the amount of the excess.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The State credit allowed under this section may be allocated among the partners, members, or shareholders of an entity in any manner agreed to by those persons in writing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "Reserve Fund" means the Sustainable Communities Tax Credit Reserve Fund established under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Sustainable Communities Tax Credit Reserve Fund that is a continuing, nonlapsing special fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The money in the Fund shall be invested and reinvested by the Treasurer, and interest and earnings shall be credited to the General Fund.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If the fees paid in any fiscal year are less than the directly related administrative costs of operating the Sustainable Communities Tax Credit Program, funds in the Reserve Fund shall be used for the directly related administrative costs of the Program.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to the provisions of this subsection, the Director shall issue an initial credit certificate for each commercial rehabilitation for which a plan of proposed rehabilitation is approved.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An initial credit certificate issued under this subsection shall state the maximum amount of credit under this section for which the commercial rehabilitation may qualify.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">
          <section prefix="1.">Except as otherwise provided in this subparagraph and in subsection (b)(6)(vi) of this section, for any fiscal year, the Director may not issue initial credit certificates for credit amounts in the aggregate totaling more than the amount appropriated to the Reserve Fund for that fiscal year in the State budget as approved by the General Assembly.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">If the aggregate credit amounts under initial credit certificates issued in a fiscal year total less than the amount appropriated to the Reserve Fund for that fiscal year as a result of the limitation under subsection (b)(5)(i) of this section, any excess amount may be issued under initial credit certificates for projects in a county or Baltimore City in the same fiscal year, without regard to the limitation under subsection (b)(5)(i) of this section.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">Subject to subsubparagraph 2 of this subparagraph, if the aggregate credit amounts under initial credit certificates issued in a fiscal year total less than the amount appropriated to the Reserve Fund for that fiscal year, any excess amount shall remain in the Reserve Fund and may be issued under initial credit certificates for the next fiscal year.</section>
          <section prefix="4.">For any fiscal year, if funds are transferred from the Reserve Fund under the authority of any provision of law other than paragraph (4) of this subsection, the maximum credit amounts in the aggregate for which the Director may issue initial credit certificates shall be reduced by the amount transferred.</section>
          <section prefix="5.">In each fiscal year, the Director shall estimate the amount of fees to be collected based on the amount appropriated to the Reserve Fund and reserve the difference between the estimated fees and estimated directly related administrative costs of the Program to be used to administer the Program.</section>
          <section prefix="6.">If the reservation of funds to administer the Program under subsubparagraph 5 of this subparagraph is not necessary to cover the directly related administrative costs of the Program, any excess amount shall remain in the Reserve Fund and may be issued under initial credit certificates for the next fiscal year.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">For each of fiscal years 2011, 2012, 2013, and 2014, the Governor shall include in the budget bill an appropriation to the Reserve Fund.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">Notwithstanding the provisions of &#xA7; 7-213 of this article, the Governor may not reduce an appropriation to the Reserve Fund in the State budget as approved by the General Assembly.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The Director may not issue an initial credit certificate for any fiscal year after fiscal year 2014.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in this paragraph, money appropriated to the Reserve Fund shall remain in the Fund.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">Within 15 days after the end of each calendar quarter, the Trust shall notify the Comptroller as to each commercial rehabilitation completed and certified during the quarter:</section>
          <section prefix="2.">On notification that a project has been certified, the Comptroller shall transfer an amount equal to the maximum credit amount stated in the initial credit certificate for the project from the Reserve Fund to the General Fund.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">
          <section prefix="1.">On or before October 1 of each year, the Trust shall notify the Comptroller as to the maximum credit amount stated in the initial credit certificate for each commercial rehabilitation for which the initial credit certificate has expired under subsection (c)(3) of this section as of the end of the prior fiscal year.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">On notification that the initial credit certificate for a project has expired under subsection (c)(3) of this section, the Comptroller shall transfer an amount equal to the maximum credit amount stated in the initial credit certificate for the project from the Reserve Fund to the General Fund.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">"Dispose of" means to transfer legal title or, in the case of a leasehold, the leasehold interest.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">"Dispose of" includes to sell in a sale-and-leaseback transaction, to transfer on the foreclosure of a security interest, or to transfer by gift.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">"Dispose of" does not include to transfer title or the leasehold interest to a creditor on creation of a security interest.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Disqualifying work" means work that:<section prefix="1.">is performed on a certified rehabilitation; and</section><section prefix="2.">if performed as part of the rehabilitation certified under this section, would have made the rehabilitation ineligible for certification.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The credit allowed under this section shall be recaptured as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection if, during the taxable year in which a certified rehabilitation is completed or any of the 4 taxable years succeeding the taxable year in which the certified rehabilitation is completed:<section prefix="(i)">any disqualifying work is performed on the certified rehabilitation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">for a commercial rehabilitation, the certified rehabilitation is complete and has been disposed of.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">
          <section prefix="1.">If the disqualifying work is performed or the certified rehabilitation is disposed of during the taxable year in which the certified rehabilitation was completed, 100% of the credit shall be recaptured.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">If the disqualifying work is performed or the certified rehabilitation is disposed of during the first full year succeeding the taxable year in which the certified rehabilitation was completed, 80% of the credit shall be recaptured.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">If the disqualifying work is performed or the certified rehabilitation is disposed of during the second full year succeeding the taxable year in which the certified rehabilitation was completed, 60% of the credit shall be recaptured.</section>
          <section prefix="4.">If the disqualifying work is performed or the certified rehabilitation is disposed of during the third full year succeeding the taxable year in which the certified rehabilitation was completed, 40% of the credit shall be recaptured.</section>
          <section prefix="5.">If the disqualifying work is performed or the certified rehabilitation is disposed of during the fourth full year succeeding the taxable year in which the certified rehabilitation was completed, 20% of the credit shall be recaptured.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The individual or business entity that claimed the tax credit shall pay the amount to be recaptured as determined under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph as taxes payable to the State for the taxable year in which the disqualifying work is performed or the certified rehabilitation is disposed of.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Comptroller may determine, under the process for return examination and audit under &#xA7;&#xA7; 13-301 and 13-302 of the Tax - General Article:<section prefix="(i)">the amount of rehabilitation expenditures used in calculating the credit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">whether such expenditures are qualified rehabilitation expenditures under this section; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">whether the credit is allowable as claimed.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The authority of the Comptroller to examine and audit a tax return does not limit the authority of the Director to determine whether a rehabilitation qualifies as a certified rehabilitation or whether a certificate of certified rehabilitation has been properly issued.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Comptroller may adopt regulations to require that an entity other than a corporation claim the tax credit on the tax return filed by that entity.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as otherwise provided in this paragraph, the credit under this section may be claimed for the year a certified rehabilitation is completed, only if the Director has, by the time the return is filed, issued a certificate of completion for the certified rehabilitation.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A taxpayer claiming the credit may amend a return for the year the certified rehabilitation was completed to account for a certificate issued subsequent to the filing of the original return.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">An amended return shall be filed within the period allowed under the Tax - General Article for filing refund claims.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The provisions of this paragraph do not extend the period in which a certified rehabilitation must be completed to be eligible for a tax credit under this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">An amended return may account for an amended certification issued by the Director for a certified rehabilitation.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A refund payable under subsection (c) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">operates to reduce the income tax revenue from corporations if the person entitled to the refund is a corporation subject to the income tax under Title 10 of the Tax - General Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">operates to reduce insurance premium tax revenues if the person entitled to the refund is subject to taxation under Title 6 of the Insurance Article; and</section><section prefix="(3)">operates to reduce the income tax revenue from individuals if the person entitled to the refund is:<section prefix="(i)">an individual subject to the income tax under Title 10 of the Tax - General Article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an organization exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before December 15 of each fiscal year, the Director shall report to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly, on:<section prefix="(i)">the initial credit certificates awarded for commercial rehabilitations under this section for that fiscal year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the tax credits awarded for certified rehabilitations completed in the preceding fiscal year;</section><section prefix="(iii)">whether the tax credits awarded for certified rehabilitations completed in the preceding fiscal year were located in:<section prefix="1.">a Main Street Maryland community;</section><section prefix="2.">beginning in fiscal 2012, a sustainable community;</section><section prefix="3.">a local historic district; or</section><section prefix="4.">a national register district; and</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">the estimated amount of directly related administrative costs reserved in the Reserve Fund, the estimated amount of fees to be collected, the actual directly related administrative costs, and the actual amount of fees collected.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The report required under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall include for each initial credit certificate awarded for the fiscal year for a commercial rehabilitation:<section prefix="(i)">the name of the owner or developer of the commercial rehabilitation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the name and address of the proposed or certified rehabilitation and the county where the project is located;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the dates of receipt and approval by the Director of all applications regarding the project, including applications:<section prefix="1.">for certification that a structure or property will qualify as a certified historic structure or a qualified rehabilitated structure; and</section><section prefix="2.">for approval of the proposed rehabilitation; and</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">the maximum amount of the credit stated in the initial credit certificate for the project and the estimated rehabilitation expenditures stated in the application for approval of the plan of proposed rehabilitation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The report required under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall include for each certified commercial rehabilitation completed during the preceding fiscal year:<section prefix="(i)">the name of the owner or developer of the commercial rehabilitation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the name and address of the certified rehabilitation and the county where the project is located;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the dates of receipt and approval by the Director of all applications regarding the project; and</section><section prefix="(iv)"><section prefix="1.">the maximum amount of the credit stated in the initial credit certificate for the project and the estimated rehabilitation expenditures stated in the application for approval of the plan of proposed rehabilitation; and</section><section prefix="2.">the actual qualified rehabilitation expenditures and the final amount of the credit for which the project qualified.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The report required under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall summarize for each category of certified rehabilitations:<section prefix="(i)">the total number of applicants for:<section prefix="1.">certification that a structure or property will qualify as a certified historic structure or a qualified rehabilitated structure;</section><section prefix="2.">approval of plans of proposed rehabilitations; or</section><section prefix="3.">certification of the completed rehabilitations;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">the number of proposed projects for which plans of proposed rehabilitation were approved; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the total estimated rehabilitation expenditures stated in approved applications for approval of plans of proposed rehabilitation and the total qualified rehabilitation expenditures for completed rehabilitations certified.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The information required under paragraph (4) of this subsection shall be provided in the aggregate and separately for each of the following categories of certified rehabilitations:<section prefix="(i)">owner-occupied single family residential structures; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">commercial rehabilitations.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of this subsection, the provisions of this section and the tax credit authorized under this section shall terminate as of July 1, 2014.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On and after July 1, 2014:<section prefix="(i)">the tax credit authorized under this section may be claimed for:<section prefix="1.">a rehabilitation project, other than a commercial rehabilitation, for which an application for approval of a plan of proposed rehabilitation was received by the Director on or before June 30, 2014; or</section><section prefix="2.">a commercial rehabilitation for which an initial credit certificate has been awarded under subsection (d) of this section; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">the Director shall continue to report to the Governor and the General Assembly as required under subsection (h) of this section for as long as any rehabilitation project for which the tax credit may be claimed remains incomplete.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
