<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-3-304</section_number>
  <catch_line>In carrying out its responsibilities, the Central Collection Unit may:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In carrying out its responsibilities, the Central Collection Unit may:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">institute, in its name, any action that is available under State law for collection of a debt or claim; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">without suit, settle the debt or claim;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">for all debts or claims collected on or after June 1, 1992:<section prefix="(i)">in addition to the outstanding principal and interest, assess and collect from the debtor a fee, which may not exceed 20% of the outstanding principal and interest, sufficient to cover all collection and administrative costs; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">prior to crediting any amount to any agency which refers a debt for any purpose, withhold a fee sufficient to cover all collection and administrative costs;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">waive or reduce any fee assessed under paragraph (2) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(4)">certify a debt or claim and the debtor responsible for the debt or claim to:<section prefix="(i)">the Comptroller for income tax refund interception in accordance with Title 13, Subtitle 9 of the Tax - General Article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the State Lottery Agency for State lottery prize interception in accordance with &#xA7; 3-307 of this subtitle.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to the authority provided under subsection (a) of this section, and notwithstanding that the Central Collection Unit is a unit of the State government and that assistant Attorneys General represent the Unit, the Unit may enforce a statutory or written contractual obligation of a debtor to pay costs in addition to principal, including collection costs, counsel fees, or interest penalties.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Central Collection Unit may report any account referred to it under this section to a consumer reporting agency.</section>
  </text>
</law>
