<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-4-808</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>808</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To determine life-cycle costs, the Department, in cooperation with the Maryland Energy Administration, shall establish standards that require at least:<section prefix="(1)">an evaluation of:<section prefix="(i)">the amount and type of glass used in the building and the directions of exposure;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the effect of insulation incorporated into the design of the building;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the effect of the use of active and passive solar energy systems;</section><section prefix="(iv)">if wind or solar energy is used, the orientation and integration of the building with respect to its site; and</section><section prefix="(v)">the variable occupancy and operating conditions of the building and its parts;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">an energy consumption analysis of each major piece of equipment in any of the following systems serving the building:<section prefix="(i)">the cooling system;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the heating system;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the hot water system;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the lighting system;</section><section prefix="(v)">the ventilation system; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">any other major energy-using system; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">a comparison of possible alternative energy systems:<section prefix="(i)">that would use the most plentiful and available energy resources in combinations that would result in maximum energy efficiency, both in the building and at the source; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">with respect to the projected annual energy consumption of the major energy-using equipment of each system over the life of the building.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To evaluate life-cycle costs, the Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">adopt and uniformly apply a definition of the "life of the building"; and</section><section prefix="(2)">provide defending criteria for the definition adopted.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
