<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-7-406</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>406</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Department" means the Department of Budget and Management.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Grantee" means a for profit or nonprofit entity or association that receives State aid during a fiscal year.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Grantee" does not include a unit of State or local government.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Grantor" means a unit of State government or other State entity that provides State aid to a grantee.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"State aid" means a contribution, grant, or subsidy of $50,000 or more provided through the State operating or capital budget or by the action of a unit of State government from State funds appropriated to that unit.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"State aid" does not include reimbursements to providers participating in a State program.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A grantor shall submit a report as provided in this subsection to the Department on or before September 1 after the close of each fiscal year in which the grantor provided State aid to a grantee.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The report shall contain:<section prefix="1.">the name, address, and zip code of each grantee that received State aid from the grantor during the previous fiscal year;</section><section prefix="2.">the amount of any State aid provided to the grantee; and</section><section prefix="3.">a description of the State aid provided to the grantee.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The reports required under this subsection shall be in the form and format, including electronic format, that the Department, after consultation with the Department of Information Technology, requires.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department of Information Technology, in consultation with the Department of Budget and Management, shall develop and operate a searchable website, accessible to the public at no cost through the Internet.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The searchable website shall contain:<section prefix="(i)">the name of the grantor that provided the State aid;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the name of the grantee that received the State aid;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the amount of the State aid that was provided to the grantee;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the zip code of the grantee that received the State aid; and</section><section prefix="(v)">a description of the State aid that was provided to the grantee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The searchable website shall allow a user to search by the following data fields:<section prefix="(i)">the grantee that received the State aid;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the grantor that provided the State aid; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the zip code of any grantee that received State aid.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Office of Legislative Audits may conduct an audit or review of a grantee in accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 2-1221 through 2-1227 of the State Government Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
