<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5A-305" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-5A-305</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To preserve the architectural and scenic integrity and beauty of the State House and other nearby real properties owned or used by the State or a State unit, the Board of Public Works may acquire architectural easements in the following areas in the City of Annapolis:<section prefix="(i)">around State Circle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">on School Street opposite the Executive Mansion; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">on the easterly side of North Street, between State Circle and College Avenue.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The areas listed in paragraph (1) of this subsection include:<section prefix="(i)">the bed of the street and outer sidewalk areas to the building line on the outer perimeter; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">an area extending outward 50 feet from that building line.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board of Public Works may acquire architectural easements by purchase, gift, exchange, or condemnation under Title 12 of the Real Property Article, with any available money.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board of Public Works may:<section prefix="(1)">agree or contract with the owner or user of real property in the specified area to prohibit the owner or user from making any structural or other physical change in the property that the Board of Public Works determines would harm the architectural and scenic integrity and beauty of the property and the specified area; and</section><section prefix="(2)">give the owner or user cash or other consideration, including a promise not to acquire an architectural easement by condemnation over part or all of the property while the owner or user complies with the agreement or contract.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
