<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-5-7B-09</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>09</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Infill development" means new development in a priority funding area on vacant, bypassed, and underutilized lands within existing developed areas.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Smart neighborhood development" means a comprehensively planned, compact mixed use development within a priority funding area that integrates residential, commercial, open space, and public uses.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department of Planning shall:<section prefix="(1)">establish a process for the review of projects by the appropriate State agencies and the Department of Planning for compliance with this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">provide to each State agency and unit of State government the location of priority funding areas; and</section><section prefix="(3)">make available to each county, and to the public for review, copies of maps illustrating:<section prefix="(i)">priority funding areas certified by the local governments; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any comments by the Department of Planning on the areas certified.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">By October 1, 1998, the Department of Planning shall complete surveys of municipal, county, and State governments for infrastructure needs and shall maintain a list of needed projects that includes information relating to the financial capacity of the affected unit of government to undertake such projects.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A copy of this list of projects shall be made available upon request to members of the General Assembly, local government officials, and the general public.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Department of Planning shall:<section prefix="(1)">draft model land-use codes for infill development and smart neighborhood development;</section><section prefix="(2)">draft guidelines to provide local governments with information on innovative planning and implementation techniques to encourage and facilitate infill development and smart neighborhood development;</section><section prefix="(3)">circulate the models and guidelines to other State agencies and departments; and</section><section prefix="(4)">work with local governments, State agencies, and departments to develop incentives to encourage the voluntary adoption and implementation by local governments of models and guidelines implementing the intent of the models and guidelines required to be developed by the Department of Planning under this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Each State agency subject to this subtitle shall report annually to the Department of Planning on the implementation of this subtitle in a form approved by the Department of Planning.</section>
  </text>
</law>
