<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-6-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Treasurer shall give 15% of the weight of the decision to the standards established in this section in deciding whether to:<section prefix="(1)">designate a financial institution as a depositary for State money under &#xA7; 6-205 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">make an agreement with a financial institution for a banking service under &#xA7; 6-229 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Treasurer shall consider whether the financial institution received a rating of "needs improvement" or "substantial noncompliance" in its most recent examination under the federal Community Reinvestment Act of 1977, P.L. Number 95-128.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a financial institution operates in a state other than Maryland, the Treasurer shall consider Maryland-specific information that is provided within the assessment area section of the Community Reinvestment Act report.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Treasurer shall consider whether, during the previous 5 years, a court in Maryland has found, in a final adjudication, that a financial institution has violated any antidiscrimination statute or regulation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Treasurer may consider whether, during the previous 5 years, a court outside Maryland has found, in a final adjudication, that a financial institution has violated any antidiscrimination statute or regulation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Treasurer may determine how to assess a violation under paragraph (1) or (2) of this subsection if the violation was committed by:<section prefix="(i)">an affiliate of the financial institution; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an entity acquired by the financial institution.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Treasurer shall consider whether the financial institution has demonstrated that during the previous 5 years, the financial institution has:<section prefix="(1)">successfully made loans in Maryland through State or federal lending programs designed to assist small and minority-owned businesses;</section><section prefix="(2)">had an active outreach program to assist small and minority-owned businesses through which the financial institution has made efforts in Maryland; and</section><section prefix="(3)">established strategic partnerships in Maryland with entities whose mission is to provide technical assistance to small and minority-owned businesses.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
