<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-2-106</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>106</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Bond" means any evidence of debt.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Official" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a comptroller;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a chief financial officer; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">a treasurer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Public body" means:<section prefix="(i)">a unit of the State government; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a county, municipal corporation, public corporation, special authority, or other political subdivision of the State.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a public body is authorized to incur debt to be redeemed from the proceeds of any tax or levy, an authorized official of the public body shall submit to the State Treasurer:<section prefix="(1)">on or before January 1 of each year, a report on bonds anticipated to be issued during the next 7-month period; and</section><section prefix="(2)">on or before July 1 of each year, a report on bonds anticipated to be issued during the next 7-month period.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A report under this section shall be in the form the State Treasurer requires.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The report shall include:<section prefix="(i)">a statement of the amount of bonds that the public body expects to issue during the period that the report covers; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">for each issue of bonds, a statement of:<section prefix="1.">the month and part of the month during which the bonds will be issued;</section><section prefix="2.">the term for which the bonds will be outstanding; and</section><section prefix="3.">whether the bonds will be sold at a public or private sale.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Treasurer shall prepare:<section prefix="(i)">on or before January 31 of each year, a compilation of the information in the reports submitted for the current January 1 to July 31 period; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">on or before July 31 of each year, a compilation of the information in the reports submitted for the current July 1 to January 31 period.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The compilation shall include any additions or corrections to the information in the reports.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The State Treasurer shall send a copy of the compilation to each official who submitted a report included in the compilation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The State Treasurer shall:<section prefix="(1)">make the reports and compilations available for inspection during normal business hours; and</section><section prefix="(2)">provide a copy of a report or compilation to any person who first pays to the State Treasurer a fee to cover costs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An official is not personally liable for failure to submit a report under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Failure to submit the report or to comply with other requirements of this section does not affect:<section prefix="(i)">the authority of a public body to incur debt; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the validity of any debt that the public body incurs.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
