<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-7B-08" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-5-7B-08</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To be eligible for funding for growth-related projects, a local government or two or more county governments shall certify to the Department of Planning any area designated by the local government or county governments as a priority funding area under &#xA7; 5-7B-03 of this subtitle, which shall be consistent with the local comprehensive plan and the criteria set forth in &#xA7; 5-7B-03 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Prior to certification of a priority funding area or areas, the local government or county governments may submit the proposed priority funding areas and any relevant information to the Department of Planning for:<section prefix="(1)">technical assistance, review, and comment; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the opportunity for public review.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Upon certification of a priority funding area, the local government or county governments shall provide to the Department of Planning all information necessary to demonstrate the precise location of the area, including a map of the area showing planning and zoning characteristics, and existing and planned water and sewer services as appropriate.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department of Planning, as appropriate, shall provide to each State agency that funds growth-related projects copies of maps illustrating:<section prefix="(1)">priority funding areas certified by the local government or county governments; and</section><section prefix="(2)">any comments by the Department of Planning on the areas certified.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Prior to funding a growth-related project, the State funding agency shall obtain from the affected local government or county governments a written statement that the proposed growth-related project is located within a certified priority funding area.</section>
  </text>
</law>
