<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-1002" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-3-1002</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department shall review and update as necessary:<section prefix="(1)">the goals developed in the managing for results State comprehensive plan; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the plan's objectives and performance measures.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, on or before July 1 of each year an agency, in conjunction with the Department, shall select no more than six agency goals that are:<section prefix="(1)">compatible with the managing for results State comprehensive plan; or</section><section prefix="(2)">consistent with the agency's mission if the goals identified in the managing for results State comprehensive plan do not apply to the agency.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, with its annual budget submission to the Department, an agency shall develop and submit to the Department as part of the budget process a managing for results agency strategic plan that shall include:<section prefix="(1)">a mission statement;</section><section prefix="(2)">a description of the agency's goals;</section><section prefix="(3)">a description of the objectives and performance measures implemented at the program level to achieve the agency's goals, including:<section prefix="(i)">performance measure statistics for at least the 2 most recently completed fiscal years; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">performance measure estimates for the current year appropriation and budget request year;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">a discussion of the agency's progress in meeting its goals and performance measures and any challenges the agency has faced in working toward its goals;</section><section prefix="(5)">a description of the internal controls established to ensure reliability of the data collected for each performance measure; and</section><section prefix="(6)">an identification of the customers and stakeholders served.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An agency subject to this subtitle shall maintain documentation of the internal controls established to evaluate performance measures that shall be subject to review by the State, including the Office of Legislative Audits.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall provide a report to the Senate Budget and Taxation Committee and House Appropriations Committee in January of each year on the contents of the State comprehensive plan and the State's progress toward the goals outlined in the plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The report shall include details on each agency's progress.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Senate Budget and Taxation Committee and House Appropriations Committee may hold hearings after receiving the report.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The first report shall be submitted on or before January 31, 2005 and shall include a presentation of the first managing for results State comprehensive plan.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
