<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3A-301" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-3A-301</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Development" means all expenditures for a new information technology system or an enhancement to an existing system including system:<section prefix="(i)">planning;</section><section prefix="(ii)">procurement;</section><section prefix="(iii)">creation;</section><section prefix="(iv)">installation;</section><section prefix="(v)">testing; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">initial training.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Development" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">ongoing operating costs, software or hardware maintenance, routine upgrades, or modifications that merely allow for a continuation of the existing level of functionality; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">expenditures made after a new or enhanced system has been legally accepted by the user and is being used for the business process for which it was intended.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Fund" means the Major Information Technology Development Project Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Information technology" means all electronic information processing hardware and software, including:<section prefix="(1)">maintenance;</section><section prefix="(2)">telecommunications; and</section><section prefix="(3)">associated consulting services.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Information technology services" means information provided by electronic means by or on behalf of a unit of State government.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Major information technology development project" means any information technology development project that meets one or more of the following criteria:<section prefix="(1)">the estimated total cost of development equals or exceeds $1,000,000;</section><section prefix="(2)">the project is undertaken to support a critical business function associated with the public health, education, safety, or financial well-being of the citizens of Maryland; or</section><section prefix="(3)">the Secretary determines that the project requires the special attention and consideration given to a major information technology development project due to:<section prefix="(i)">the significance of the project's potential benefits or risks;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the impact of the project on the public or local governments;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the public visibility of the project; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">other reasons as determined by the Secretary.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Master plan" means the statewide information technology master plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Nonvisual access" means the ability, through keyboard control, synthesized speech, Braille, or other methods not requiring sight to receive, use, and manipulate information and operate controls necessary to access information technology.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Resource sharing" means the utilization of a State resource by private industry in exchange for the provision to the State of a communication service or other consideration.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Systems development life cycle plan" means a plan that defines all actions, functions, or activities to be performed by a unit of State government in the definition, planning, acquisition, development, testing, implementation, operation, enhancement, and modification of information technology systems.</section>
  </text>
</law>
