<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-13-207</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>207</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, a procurement officer may not require a bidder or offeror to provide bid security on a procurement contract if the procurement officer expects the price to be $100,000 or less.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A procurement officer shall require a bidder or offeror to provide bid security on a procurement contract for construction if:<section prefix="(i)">the price is expected to exceed $100,000; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the price is expected to be $100,000 or less but federal law or a condition of federal assistance requires the security.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The amount of bid security required for a procurement contract for construction shall be:<section prefix="(i)">at least 5% of the bid or price proposal; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the bid or price proposal states a rate but not a total price, an amount determined by the procurement officer.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A procurement officer may require a bidder or offeror to provide bid security on a procurement contract for services, supplies, or construction related services if the price of the procurement contract is expected to exceed $50,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A procurement officer shall require a bidder or offeror to provide bid security on a procurement contract for services, supplies, or construction related services if federal law or a condition of federal assistance requires the security.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The amount of bid security required for a procurement contract for services, supplies, or construction related services shall be an amount determined by the procurement officer. If a bid or proposal states a rate but not a total price, the procurement officer shall determine the dollar amount of the bid security.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Bid security under this section shall be:<section prefix="(1)">a bond provided by a surety company authorized to do business in the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">cash; or</section><section prefix="(3)">another form of security allowed by regulation.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
