<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5A-301" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-5A-301</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Director" means the Director of the Maryland Historical Trust.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Financial assistance" means action by the State or a State unit to award grants, loans, loan guarantees, or insurance to a public or private entity to finance, wholly or partly, an undertaking.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Governmental unit" means an agency, authority, board, commission, council, office, or other unit or instrumentality of the government of the State or of a political subdivision of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Historic property" means a district, site, building, structure, monument, or object significant to:<section prefix="(i)">the prehistory or history of the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the upland and underwater archaeology, architecture, engineering, or culture of the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Historic property" includes related artifacts, records, and remains.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Nonprofit organization" means a corporation, foundation, or other legal entity, no part of the net earnings of which inures to the benefit of a private shareholder or individual holding an interest in the entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Political subdivision" means a county or municipal corporation of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Preservation" or "historic preservation" means the identification, evaluation, recordation, documentation, curation, acquisition, protection, management, rehabilitation, restoration, stabilization, maintenance, and reconstruction of a historic property.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"State Historic Preservation Officer" means the individual who administers the State Historic Preservation Program under the National Historic Preservation Act of 1966, 16 U.S.C. &#xA7;&#xA7; 470-470mm.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"State unit" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 11-101 of the State Government Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Submerged" means beneath or substantially beneath water.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Terrestrial" means relating to land above the mean high tide line and above nontidal waters.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Trust" means the Maryland Historical Trust.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Undertaking" means a project that involves or may result in building construction, building alteration, or land disturbance.</section>
  </text>
</law>
