<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-13-210</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>210</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a procurement officer decides to conduct a pre-bid conference to explain the requirements of a procurement that is expected to exceed $100,000, as soon as practicable after the conference concludes, the procurement officer shall have written minutes of the conference prepared.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The minutes of a pre-bid conference are public records and shall be open to public inspection during ordinary business hours.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to Title 10, Subtitle 6, Part III of the State Government Article:<section prefix="(i)">a summary of the final evaluation of a proposal shall be open to public inspection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">after an award, all proposals shall be open to public inspection; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">at and after bid opening, the contents of a bid and any document submitted with the bid shall be open to public inspection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, Title 10, Subtitle 6, Part III of the State Government Article shall govern any request for the disclosure of information related to a procurement.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A procurement officer may deny public access to the advisory or deliberative records of an evaluator of a proposal if the records would not be available by law to a private party in litigation with the unit.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before bid opening:<section prefix="(i)">bids shall remain sealed; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the State may not disclose the name of a bidder.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before the closing date for proposals, a procurement officer may not disclose the name of a person who has submitted a proposal.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Before awarding a procurement contract based on competitive sealed proposals, the State may not disclose the contents of a proposal to any person other than a person responsible for evaluating or reviewing the proposal.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Subsections (b)(1), (c), and (d) of this section do not affect the authority of the Board of Contract Appeals or a court of competent jurisdiction to:<section prefix="(1)">decide that information is discoverable in an administrative or judicial proceeding; and</section><section prefix="(2)">compel disclosure.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
