<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-5A-334</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>334</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is an Archaeology Office in the Trust.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Archaeology Office includes a research unit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The research unit shall:<section prefix="(i)">engage in and direct fundamental archaeological research;</section><section prefix="(ii)">synthesize existing research information; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">encourage archaeological research and investigation by museums, institutions of higher education, and scientific and historical institutions and organizations in the State.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Director shall employ a Chief Archaeologist, a State Terrestrial Archaeologist, and a State Underwater Archaeologist in accordance with &#xA7; 5A-316 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each archaeologist employed under this subsection shall have an advanced degree in archaeology or a closely related field from an accredited college or university.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Chief Archaeologist shall be a professional archaeologist.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Chief Archaeologist is the administrative head of the Archaeology Office.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Archaeology Office includes all staff members of the Trust who are archaeologists or hired to perform archaeological work, including those who may be assigned archaeological-related functions in other units of the Trust.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Archaeology Office does not include individuals specifically assigned to a park, museum, or other site-specific facility under the jurisdiction of the Trust.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
