<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-6-105</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "Group" means the Consensus Revenue Monitoring and Forecasting Group established un...</catch_line>
  <order_by>105</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Group" means the Consensus Revenue Monitoring and Forecasting Group established under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Consensus Revenue Monitoring and Forecasting Group.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Group consists of:<section prefix="(1)">the Chief and staff of the Bureau as designated by the Chief;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Deputy Comptroller with responsibility for tax administration and staff as designated by the Deputy Comptroller with responsibility for tax administration;</section><section prefix="(3)">staff of the Office of the Treasurer as designated by the Treasurer;</section><section prefix="(4)">staff of the Department of Budget and Management as designated by the Secretary of Budget and Management;</section><section prefix="(5)">staff of the Department of Transportation as designated by the Secretary of Transportation; and</section><section prefix="(6)">staff of the Office of Policy Analysis of the Department of Legislative Services as designated by the Director of the Office.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Chief shall chair the Group.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Group and its constituent units shall:<section prefix="(1)">review and analyze attainment of revenues on a monthly basis; and</section><section prefix="(2)">advise and collaborate with the Bureau:<section prefix="(i)">in the development of revenue forecasts and any necessary revisions to those forecasts; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">in the performance of any pertinent studies or analyses as requested by the Chief or as directed by the Board.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">To assist the Group in performing its function, the Comptroller and the Bureau shall:<section prefix="(1)">within 7 calendar days after the end of each month, provide to members of the Group detailed data on revenue collections; and</section><section prefix="(2)">before any document relating to the work of the Bureau is published, provide a draft of the document to the members of the Group for review and comment.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
