<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-10-501</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>501</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to subsection (b) of this section, the Board of Public Works may grant to an individual erroneously convicted, sentenced, and confined under State law for a crime the individual did not commit an amount commensurate with the actual damages sustained by the individual, and may grant a reasonable amount for any financial or other appropriate counseling for the individual, due to the confinement.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In making a grant under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Board of Public Works shall use money in the General Emergency Fund or money that the Governor provides in the annual budget.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An individual is eligible for a grant under subsection (a) of this section only if the individual has received from the Governor a full pardon stating that the individual's conviction has been shown conclusively to be in error.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board of Public Works may pay the grant determined under subsection (a) of this section in a lump sum or in installments.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of Public Works may not pay any part of a grant made under this section to any individual other than the pardoned individual.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An individual may not pay any part of a grant received under this section to another person for services rendered in connection with the collection of the grant.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An obligation incurred in violation of this paragraph is void.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A payment made in violation of this paragraph shall be forfeited to the State.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This section does not prohibit an individual from contracting for services to:<section prefix="(1)">determine the individual's innocence;</section><section prefix="(2)">obtain a pardon; or</section><section prefix="(3)">obtain the individual's release from confinement.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
