<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-3A-404</section_number>
  <catch_line>The General Assembly declares that:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>404</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The General Assembly declares that:<section prefix="(1)">it is the policy of the State to foster telecommunication and computer networking among State and local governments, their agencies, and educational institutions in the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">there is a need to improve access, especially in rural areas, to efficient telecommunication and computer network connections;</section><section prefix="(3)">improvement of telecommunication and computer networking for State and local governments and educational institutions promotes economic development, educational resource use and development, and efficiency in State and local administration;</section><section prefix="(4)">rates for the intrastate inter-LATA telephone communications needed for effective integration of telecommunication and computer resources are prohibitive for many smaller governments, agencies, and institutions; and</section><section prefix="(5)">the use of improved State telecommunication and computer networking under this section is intended not to compete with commercial access to advanced network technology, but rather to foster fundamental efficiencies in government and education for the public good.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall establish a telecommunication and computer network in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The network shall consist of:<section prefix="(i)">one or more connection facilities for telecommunication and computer connection in each local access transport area (LATA) in the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">facilities, auxiliary equipment, and services required to support the network in a reliable and secure manner.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The network shall be accessible through direct connection and through local intra-LATA telecommunications to State and local governments and public and private educational institutions in the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
