<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="17-704" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-17-704</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>** CONTINGENCY - IN EFFECT - CHAPTERS 446 AND 447 OF 2012 **<section prefix="(a)"><section prefix="(1)">On or before December 31, 2012, the Board shall use credible information available to the public to create a list of persons that the Board determines to be engaged in investment activities in Iran as described in &#xA7; 17-702 of this subtitle.</section><section prefix="(2)">The Board shall update the list at least every 180 days.</section><section prefix="(3)">Before the Board includes a person on the list, the Board shall provide the person with 90 days' written notice that:<section prefix="(i)">the Board intends to include the person on the list; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">inclusion on the list would make the person ineligible to bid on, submit a proposal for, or enter into or renew a contract with a public body for goods or services.</section></section><section prefix="(4)">The notice required under paragraph (3) of this subsection shall specify that if the person ceases engagement in investment activities in Iran as described in &#xA7; 17-702 of this subtitle, the person may become eligible for a future contract or contract renewal with a public body for goods or services on removal from the list.</section></section><section prefix="(b)"><section prefix="(1)">The Board shall provide a person with an opportunity to comment in writing to the Board that the person is not engaged in investment activities in Iran.</section><section prefix="(2)">If the person demonstrates to the Board that the person is not engaged in investment activities in Iran as described in &#xA7; 17-702 of this subtitle, the Board may not include the person on the list.</section></section><section prefix="(c)">The Board shall remove a person from the list if the person demonstrates to the Board that the person no longer is engaged in investment activities in Iran as described in &#xA7; 17-702 of this subtitle.</section><section prefix="(d)">The Board shall make every reasonable effort to avoid erroneously including a person on the list.</section><section prefix="(e)">The Board shall publish the list on the Internet.</section></text>
</law>
