<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-5A-323</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>323</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Trust shall compile a Maryland Inventory of Historic Properties that consists of districts, sites, buildings, structures, and other objects of known or potential value to the prehistory, history, upland and underwater archaeology, architecture, engineering, and culture of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Trust shall compile a Historic Register to include all properties in the State that are listed in or eligible for listing in the National Register of Historic Places of the United States Department of the Interior.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Trust shall adopt regulations specifying procedures and eligibility standards for including properties in the Historic Register.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Director shall determine whether a property is eligible to be listed in the National Register of Historic Places.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Director's determination may be appealed to the Governor's Consulting Committee on the National Register of Historic Places, which reviews nominations to the National Register under the National Historic Preservation Act.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The determination of the Governor's Consulting Committee is final.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The location and character of a historic property included in the Maryland Inventory of Historic Properties or the Historic Register shall be confidential if the Director determines that disclosure would create a substantial risk of theft of the property or damage to the property or to the area where the property is located.</section>
  </text>
</law>
