<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-12-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to capital expenditures by the Department of Transportation or the Maryland Transportation Authority, in connection with State roads, bridges, or highways.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Before execution, a contract for a capital expenditure other than in connection with a State correctional facility, St. Mary's College of Maryland, Morgan State University, or the University System of Maryland shall be:<section prefix="(1)">reviewed by the Secretary of General Services; and</section><section prefix="(2)">except as provided in &#xA7; 12-203 of this subtitle and &#xA7; 13-108 of this article, after that review, approved by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before execution, a contract for a capital expenditure in connection with a State correctional facility shall be:<section prefix="(1)">reviewed by the Secretary of Public Safety and Correctional Services; and</section><section prefix="(2)">except as provided in &#xA7; 12-203 of this subtitle, after that review, approved by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Before execution, a contract for a capital expenditure in connection with the University System of Maryland shall be:<section prefix="(1)">subject to the provisions of Title 4, Subtitle 4 of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">approved by the Board of Regents of the University System of Maryland; and</section><section prefix="(3)">approved by the Board of Public Works.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Before execution, a contract for a capital expenditure in connection with St. Mary's College of Maryland shall be:<section prefix="(1)">subject to the provisions of Title 4, Subtitle 4 of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">approved by the Board of Trustees of St. Mary's College of Maryland; and</section><section prefix="(3)">approved by the Board of Public Works.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Before execution, a contract for a capital expenditure in connection with Morgan State University shall be:<section prefix="(1)">subject to the provisions of Title 4, Subtitle 4 of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">approved by the Board of Regents of Morgan State University; and</section><section prefix="(3)">approved by the Board of Public Works.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Board shall supervise the expenditure of any money that the General Assembly appropriates for:<section prefix="(1)">buildings;</section><section prefix="(2)">equipment;</section><section prefix="(3)">new construction; or</section><section prefix="(4)">any other capital expenditure.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
