<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-3A-506</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>506</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The programs under &#xA7; 3A-504(a) of this subtitle and &#xA7; 3A-602(a) of this title shall be funded as provided in the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Universal Service Trust Fund created for the purpose of paying the costs of maintaining and operating the program under &#xA7; 3A-504(a) of this subtitle subject to the limitations and controls provided in this subtitle, and the program under &#xA7; 3A-602(a) of this title subject to the limitations and controls provided in Subtitle 6 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Moneys in the Universal Service Trust Fund shall be held in the State Treasury.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Money in the Universal Service Trust Fund may only be used:<section prefix="(i)">to fund the costs of the programs specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">to pay for the administration of the Universal Service Trust Fund.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The costs of the programs under &#xA7; 3A-504(a) of this subtitle and &#xA7; 3A-602(a) of this title shall be funded by revenues generated by:<section prefix="(i)">a surcharge to be paid by the subscribers to a communications service; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">other funds as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The surcharge may not exceed 18 cents per month for each account and shall be applied to all current bills rendered for a communications service in the State.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The surcharge is payable at the time the bills for a communications service are due.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The surcharge to be collected under this section only applies to a communications service for which charges are billed by, or on behalf of, a communications company to a subscriber of the communications service.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall annually certify to the Public Service Commission the costs of the programs under &#xA7; 3A-504(a) of this subtitle and &#xA7; 3A-602(a) of this title to be paid by the Universal Service Trust Fund for the following fiscal year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">	The Public Service Commission shall determine the surcharge for the following fiscal year necessary to fund the programs under &#xA7; 3A-504(a) of this subtitle and &#xA7; 3A-602(a) of this title.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">In accordance with subsection (c)(2) and subsubparagraph 2 of this subparagraph, the Public Service Commission shall set the surcharge for the following fiscal year at an amount that is no higher than necessary to generate sufficient revenues to fund the costs of the programs for the following fiscal year, as certified under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">In setting the surcharge under subsubparagraph 1 of this subparagraph, the Public Service Commission shall take into account whether the surcharge may be adjusted as a result of any uncommitted funds in the Universal Service Trust Fund at the end of the fiscal year that may be used to fund the costs of the programs for the following fiscal year.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary shall, on 60 days' notice, direct the affected communications companies to add the surcharge determined by the Public Service Commission under paragraph (2) of this subsection to all current bills rendered for communications service in the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The affected communications companies shall act as collection agents for the Universal Service Trust Fund and shall remit all proceeds monthly to the Comptroller for deposit to the Universal Service Trust Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The communications companies shall be entitled to credit against these proceeds in an amount equal to 1 1/2 percent of these proceeds to cover the expenses of billing, collecting, and remitting the surcharge and any additional charges.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall administer the Universal Service Trust Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The income derived from investment of money in the Universal Service Trust Fund shall accrue to the Universal Service Trust Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any funds remaining at the end of a fiscal year in the Universal Service Trust Fund shall be carried forward within the Universal Service Trust Fund for the maintenance and operation of the programs specified under subsection (b) of this section in the following fiscal year.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Legislative Auditor shall conduct postaudits of a fiscal and compliance nature of the Universal Service Trust Fund and the expenditures made for purposes of &#xA7; 3A-504(a) of this subtitle and &#xA7; 3A-602(a) of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The cost of the fiscal portion of the postaudit examination shall be paid from the Universal Service Trust Fund as an administrative cost.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
