<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-8-211</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>211</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Code" means the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and includes regulations and rulings issued under that Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Financial officer" means the Controller, the director of finance or similar official of a unit of the State government or a political instrumentality of the State that has authority to issue bonds. "Financial officer" includes, to the extent necessary, the Treasurer and the Comptroller.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Proceeds" means moneys received from the sale of bonds, and includes any moneys deemed to be proceeds of bonds under the Code.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The financial officer may establish and maintain funds and accounts for the administration, management, investment and accounting of proceeds, including any investment earnings on proceeds, that may be necessary or appropriate from time to time to comply with the Code and to establish or maintain the exclusion from gross income for federal income tax purposes of interest on the bonds.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The financial officer may manage and invest proceeds, including any investment earnings on proceeds, in a manner so as to maintain the exclusion from gross income for federal income tax purposes of interest on the bonds. The financial officer may restrict the yields on investments of proceeds if and to the extent necessary to maintain the exclusion from gross income for federal income tax purposes of interest on the bonds.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The financial officer may prepare and maintain records of the receipt, deposit, investment, management, disbursement and application of proceeds, including any investment earnings on proceeds, that may be necessary or appropriate from time to time to comply with the Code and to maintain or verify the exclusion from gross income for federal income tax purposes of interest on the bonds.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The financial officer may establish a separate rebate fund to be used to make any payments to the United States with respect to investment earnings on proceeds that may be required from time to time by the Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">There may be separate accounts within the rebate fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Amounts deposited to the rebate fund shall be used only for the purpose of making rebate payments to the United States.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The financial officer may make payments from the rebate fund as may be required from time to time in order to:<section prefix="(i)">comply with the Code; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">maintain the exclusion from gross income for federal income tax purposes of interest on the bonds.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Any excess moneys held in the rebate fund with respect to an issue of bonds after all required rebate payments for that issue have been made, as certified by the financial officer, shall be applied in a manner consistent with the Code.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The financial officer may prepare and file from time to time with the appropriate agency of the United States any forms, information, and reports with respect to the bonds and the expenditure and investment of proceeds that may be required under the Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The financial officer and other officers of a State unit may:<section prefix="(1)">take any other or further actions;</section><section prefix="(2)">enter into any agreement or covenant regarding the use of proceeds, including any investment earnings on proceeds, the deposit of moneys to the rebate fund and the making of rebate payments; and</section><section prefix="(3)">provide certifications of facts and estimates, that may be necessary or appropriate from time to time to comply with the Code and to establish or maintain the exclusion from gross income for federal income tax purposes of interest on the bonds.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Nothing in this section shall prevent the State unit from authorizing the issuance and sale of bonds the interest on which is not excludable from gross income for federal income tax purposes.</section>
  </text>
</law>
