<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-809" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-4-809</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Maryland Green Building Council.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Council shall include:<section prefix="(1)">the Secretary of General Services, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Secretary of Budget and Management, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(3)">the Secretary of the Environment, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(4)">the Secretary of Housing and Community Development, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(5)">the Secretary of Natural Resources, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(6)">the Secretary of Planning, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(7)">the Secretary of Transportation, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(8)">the Director of the Maryland Energy Administration, or the Director's designee;</section><section prefix="(9)">the Director of the Interagency Committee on Public School Construction, or the Director's designee;</section><section prefix="(10)">the Chancellor of the University System of Maryland, or the Chancellor's designee; and</section><section prefix="(11)">six members appointed by the Governor to represent environmental, business, and citizen interests, one of whom has expertise in energy conservation or green building design standards.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member appointed by the Governor is 2 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of appointed members are staggered.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the remainder of that term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Governor may remove an appointed member for incompetence, misconduct, or failure to perform the duties of the position.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A member appointed by the Governor may not receive compensation, but is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor shall appoint a chair from among the Council members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Council may act with an affirmative vote of nine members.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Staff support to the Council shall be provided by the Department of General Services, with assistance as necessary to be furnished by other involved agencies and units of State government.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Maryland Green Building Council shall:<section prefix="(1)">evaluate current high performance building technologies;</section><section prefix="(2)">provide recommendations concerning the most cost-effective green building technologies that the State might consider requiring in the construction of State facilities, including consideration of the additional cost associated with the various technologies;</section><section prefix="(3)">provide recommendations concerning how to expand green building in the State; and</section><section prefix="(4)">develop a list of building types for which green building technologies should not be applied, taking into consideration the operational aspects of facilities evaluated, and the utility of a waiver process where appropriate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">On or before November 1 of each year, the Council shall report to the Governor and the General Assembly, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, as to recommendations for the implementation plan for a higher performance building program in the State and any progress that has been made during the preceding year.</section>
  </text>
</law>
