<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-13-105</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>105</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A request for proposals for a lease of real property shall include:<section prefix="(1)">a work statement that shall be used as a basis for the evaluation of proposals;</section><section prefix="(2)">a statement of the factors, including price, that will be used in evaluating proposals; and</section><section prefix="(3)">a statement of the relative importance of each factor.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to the requirements of Title 4, Subtitle 3, Part III of this article, a unit shall publish a request for proposals in the same manner as required for an invitation for bids.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">After proposals have been opened, the procurement officer shall reject any proposal that is unacceptable.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If more than three proposals are submitted, the procurement officer may conduct negotiations with the offerors who, based on a preliminary evaluation in accordance with the evaluation factors, have submitted the three best proposals.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Negotiations are not required if the request for proposals:<section prefix="(i)">notified all offerors that negotiations would not be conducted; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">requested best and final offers.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The procurement officer:<section prefix="(i)">may establish a maximum fair market rental rate for each premises offered;</section><section prefix="(ii)">during negotiations, may not disclose to an offeror any information derived from the proposal of a competing offeror, except price and information directly related to price; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">after negotiations, may reject a proposal that exceeds the maximum fair market rate.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After receiving best and final offers:<section prefix="(i)">a procurement officer may conduct further negotiations with the successful offeror to obtain for the State the best price, conditions, and services; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any modification of a successful offer must be in the best interests of the State.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">By direct solicitation and without republication of notice, the procurement officer may acquire other offers if:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">negotiations and best and final offers fail to produce a lease for real property with terms comparable to market rental rates in the boundaries in which the unit must obtain the lease; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the final offeror did not accept a lease with terms comparable to the market rental rates; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the public notice of requests for proposals fails to produce a response or offer of a lease for real property.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If a procurement officer determines that renewal of an existing lease is in the best interests of the State, the procurement officer may negotiate the renewal without soliciting other offers.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">After obtaining any approval required by law, the procurement officer shall award the procurement contract to the responsible offeror who submits the proposal or best and final offer determined to be the most advantageous to the State considering:<section prefix="(1)">the price and evaluation factors set forth in the request for proposals; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the modifications to those factors under the negotiation process.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
