<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-408" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-5-408</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is within the Department a program for certification of effective county agricultural land preservation programs.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A county may apply to the Department and the Maryland Agricultural Land Preservation Foundation for certification under this section only if the county agricultural preservation advisory board and the governing body of the county both:<section prefix="(1)">approve the program established at the county level as being an effective approach to agricultural land preservation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">approve the county's application for certification.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A county may apply for certification under this section if the county has established programs to encourage participation of farmers in agricultural land preservation efforts at the county level, including purchase of development rights or financial enhancements related to purchase of development rights, outside of the State Agricultural Land Preservation Foundation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">County programs shall include:<section prefix="(i)">any program that the Department and the Foundation:</section><section prefix="(ii)">beginning in fiscal year 2009, a priority preservation area element established in accordance with &#xA7; 2-518 of the Agriculture Article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To apply for certification under this section, a county shall file with the Maryland Agricultural Land Preservation Foundation and the Department an application in the form that the Department and the Foundation jointly require by regulation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 60 days after notification of an application for certification:<section prefix="(i)">the Foundation shall advise the Department as to whether it approves the application; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Department shall notify the county as to whether the county's application for certification has been approved.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Department and the Foundation may not certify a county under this section unless the Department and the Foundation determine that:<section prefix="(1)">the proposed county program for the purchase of development rights or financial enhancements related to the purchase of development rights is likely to be successful;</section><section prefix="(2)">the county has committed to spend additional local funds for the purchase of development rights or enhancements related to the purchase of development rights in an amount equal to or exceeding the amount of the additional funds that will be available as a result of certification; and</section><section prefix="(3)">beginning in fiscal year 2009:<section prefix="(i)">the county's priority preservation area has been established in accordance with &#xA7; 2-518 of the Agriculture Article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the county's priority preservation area element in the comprehensive plan meets the requirements set forth in subsection (f) of this section.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department and the Foundation may not certify a priority preservation area of a county under this section unless the Department and the Foundation agree that the county's comprehensive plan:<section prefix="(1)">establishes appropriate goals for the amount and types of agricultural resource land to be preserved in the priority preservation area;</section><section prefix="(2)">describes:<section prefix="(i)">the county's strategy to support normal agricultural and forestry activities in conjunction with the amount of development permitted in the priority preservation area; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the ordinances, regulations, and procedures the county is using in the priority preservation area to support the ability of working farms to engage in normal agricultural and forestry activities;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">includes maps showing the county's priority preservation area;</section><section prefix="(4)">describes the priority preservation area in the context of the county's growth management plans;</section><section prefix="(5)">describes the way in which preservation goals will be accomplished in the priority preservation area, including the county's strategy to:<section prefix="(i)">protect land from development through zoning;</section><section prefix="(ii)">preserve the desired amount of land with permanent easements; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">maintain a rural environment capable of supporting normal agricultural and forestry activities;</section></section><section prefix="(6)">includes an evaluation of the ability of the county's zoning and other land use management practices to:<section prefix="(i)">limit the impact of subdivision and development;</section><section prefix="(ii)">allow time for easement purchase; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">achieve the Foundation's goals before development excessively compromises the agricultural and forest resource land;</section></section><section prefix="(7)">identifies shortcomings in the abilities of the county's zoning and land management practices and identifies current or future actions to correct the shortcomings; and</section><section prefix="(8)">describes the methods the county will use to concentrate preservation funds and other supporting efforts in the priority preservation area to achieve the goals of the Foundation and the county's acreage preservation goal.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In certifying a county's priority preservation area, the Department and the Foundation shall ensure that:<section prefix="(1)">the county has included all the information required by subsection (f) of this section in the county's comprehensive plan; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the size of the county's priority preservation area is appropriate in relation to the county's acreage preservation goal.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A county that has been certified under this section as having established an effective county agricultural land preservation program is eligible for:<section prefix="(i)">the additional funds available to certified counties under &#xA7; 2-508.1 of the Agriculture Article and &#xA7; 13-306 of the Tax - Property Article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">as of July 1, 2008, funds provided for the Maryland Agricultural Land Preservation Foundation over and above the funding the Foundation receives in accordance with &#xA7; 2-508.1 of the Agriculture Article and &#xA7;&#xA7; 13-209 and 13-306 of the Tax - Property Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A county that has been certified under this section may use the additional funds available as a result of certification:<section prefix="(i)">for the purposes stated under &#xA7; 2-508.1 of the Agriculture Article and &#xA7; 13-306 of the Tax - Property Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">to purchase easements in its priority preservation area;</section><section prefix="(iii)">for a Critical Farms Program approved by the Foundation;</section><section prefix="(iv)">for an installment purchase agreement program approved by the Foundation; or</section><section prefix="(v)">for the Next Generation Farmland Acquisition Program approved by the Foundation.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A certification under this section is effective for 3 years and the decision by the Department and the Foundation as to certification is final with no right to appeal.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the request of the county, the Department and the Foundation shall recertify under this section a county agricultural land preservation program if:<section prefix="(i)">the county has maintained a successful program of purchase of development rights or financial enhancements related to purchase of development rights during the period of certification;</section><section prefix="(ii)">conditions in the county priority preservation area remain in accordance with the requirements of &#xA7; 2-518 of the Agriculture Article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the county provides an update on the method, evaluation, shortcomings, and future actions that the county is using or will use to achieve preservation goals, as required under subsection (f)(6) through (8) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the update demonstrates significant progress toward achievement of preservation goals in the priority preservation area.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The Department and the Foundation shall jointly adopt regulations for administration of the certification program.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">In accordance with the requirements of &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the Department and the Foundation shall report on the certification program on or before January 15 of each year to:<section prefix="(1)">the Governor;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of Planning;</section><section prefix="(3)">the Senate Budget and Taxation Committee and the Senate Education, Health, and Environmental Affairs Committee; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the House Appropriations Committee, the House Environmental Matters Committee, and the House Committee on Ways and Means.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
