<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-5-402</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>402</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">harmonize its planning activities with the planning activities of other units of the State government;</section><section prefix="(2)">coordinate the plans and programs of all units of the State government;</section><section prefix="(3)">cooperate with and assist other units of the State government in the execution of their planning functions, to harmonize their planning activities with the State Development Plan; and</section><section prefix="(4)">promote the State's Economic Growth, Resource Protection, and Planning Policy set forth in Subtitle 7A of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">harmonize its planning activities with the planning activities of local governments; and</section><section prefix="(2)">cooperate with and assist local governments in the execution of their planning functions, to harmonize their planning activities with the State Development Plan.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">coordinate State programs with the federal government;</section><section prefix="(2)">cooperate with and assist units of the federal government in the execution of their planning functions, to harmonize their planning activities with the State Development Plan; and</section><section prefix="(3)">cooperate with, confer with, and, on request, provide information to:<section prefix="(i)">units of the federal government; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">local or regional agencies that are created under federal programs or that receive federal support.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">As far as possible, the Department shall cooperate with and confer with planning agencies of other states or of regional groupings of states.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Department shall cooperate with and assist regional and private planning agencies in the execution of their planning functions, to harmonize their planning activities with the State Development Plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department shall exercise authority as the lead agency in coordinating the State's land preservation efforts and focus its planning efforts on targeted land preservation.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Department shall plan for the efficient use of inactive railroad corridors by:<section prefix="(1)">examining all opportunities, both present and future, for acquisition or use of inactive railroad corridors;</section><section prefix="(2)">coordinating and working with the Departments of Natural Resources, Transportation, Business and Economic Development, and the State Railroad Administration and other agencies to determine the suitability and feasibility of acquiring or using inactive railroad corridors for recreational trails, public utilities, or future transportation purposes; and</section><section prefix="(3)">taking part in United States Interstate Commerce Commission proceedings regarding the abandonment or the discontinuance of use of railroad corridors on behalf of the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">review transportation plans and programs prepared by the Department of Transportation and regional planning agencies and make recommendations regarding the relationship between transportation and planned land use; and</section><section prefix="(2)">evaluate proposed transportation improvements and policies to assure consistency between transportation investments and the State Economic Growth, Resource Protection, and Planning Policy.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Department may provide advice to local governments regarding the impact on growth and development of:<section prefix="(1)">transportation components of local plans;</section><section prefix="(2)">aspects of local land use regulation affecting transportation; and</section><section prefix="(3)">local transportation improvements.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
