<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-12-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Board may adopt regulations that allow a unit of the State government to enter into a contract o...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may adopt regulations that allow a unit of the State government to enter into a contract or make a change order related to a capital project without approval.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">These regulations shall:<section prefix="(i)">comply with this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">be subject to the approval of the Joint Committee on Administrative, Executive, and Legislative Review.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Regulations adopted under this section shall:<section prefix="(i)">establish an expenditure or use classification to determine which contracts or change orders may be made without Board approval;</section><section prefix="(ii)">set an amount for each classification and require a unit of the State government to obtain approval of the Board if the annual dollar value of a contract and its change orders exceeds that amount; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">require a unit of the State government to establish a reporting system approved by the Board to inform the Board about contracts or change orders entered into without Board approval.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The amount established by the Board under paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection shall be an amount that:<section prefix="(i)">frees the Board from direct review of relatively insignificant items; but</section><section prefix="(ii)">does not impair the strong public policy favoring direct review by the Board for items that have a substantial fiscal impact.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
