<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-3-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>With the approval of the Governor, the Secretary shall appoint a Deputy Secretary....</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With the approval of the Governor, the Secretary shall appoint a Deputy Secretary.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Deputy Secretary:<section prefix="(i)">is in the executive service of the State Personnel Management System and serves at the pleasure of the Secretary;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is entitled to the salary provided in the State budget; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">has the duties provided by law or delegated by the Secretary.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall appoint 1 or more budget analysts.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each budget analyst must:<section prefix="(i)">have at least 3 years' experience in personnel and other subjects that are related to the operation of a business organization;</section><section prefix="(ii)">be a graduate of a recognized school of business administration or have the additional experience that the Secretary requires; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">meet any other qualifications that the Secretary sets.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The budget analysts shall:<section prefix="(i)">continually conduct studies of all budget expenditures of units of the Executive Branch of the State government;</section><section prefix="(ii)">make recommendations to the Secretary for greater efficiency and economy in those units; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">perform any other duties that the Secretary assigns.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary may employ a staff in accordance with the State budget.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each assistant secretary and professional consultant is in the executive service, management service, or is a special appointment in the State Personnel Management System and is appointed by and serves at the pleasure of the Secretary.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in this section or otherwise by law, the Secretary shall appoint and remove all other staff in accordance with the provisions of the State Personnel and Pensions Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The appointment or removal of staff of any unit in the Department is subject to the approval of the Secretary.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
