<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-407" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-4-407</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The General Assembly finds that:<section prefix="(1)">units of the State government are under pressure to delay or eliminate needed physical facility maintenance and repair because of fiscal constraints;</section><section prefix="(2)">lack of regular maintenance and repair results in deterioration of public improvements and increased costs for repair or construction of entirely new replacement facilities; and</section><section prefix="(3)">a specific set of procedures is necessary to ensure that all units of the State government perform regular maintenance and repair.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department of General Services shall establish general policies and standards for maintenance and repair of public improvements.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On or before December 31 of each year, the Department of General Services shall send any changes to these general policies and standards to:<section prefix="(i)">the Board of Public Works; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Department of Budget and Management.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">establish and supervise a comprehensive and continuing program of maintenance and repair of all public improvements; and</section><section prefix="(2)">review maintenance and operation of public improvements to the extent that any engineering question is involved.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each unit of the State government shall carry out a maintenance and repair program for each public improvement under the jurisdiction of the unit. In carrying out the program, the unit shall:<section prefix="(1)">conform to the policies and standards established by the Department; and</section><section prefix="(2)">allocate sufficient funds and personnel.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
