<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-4-406</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>406</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall advise the Board of Public Works and any unit of the State government in connection with any engineering question or matter concerning a public improvement.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall supervise any engineering question or matter concerning a public improvement.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any contract, plan, or specification for any public improvement that involves an engineering question:<section prefix="(i)">shall be submitted to the Department; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is subject to the approval of the Department.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">At the request of the Board of Public Works, the Department shall advise the Board of Public Works on any contract that exceeds $500,000 if the contract involves an engineering question or a matter concerning a public improvement undertaken by the University System of Maryland, Morgan State University, or St. Mary's College of Maryland.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">represent the Board of Public Works at the opening of bids for a public improvement;</section><section prefix="(2)">tabulate and record the bids; and</section><section prefix="(3)">advise the Board of Public Works on the bids.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department shall supervise each appraisal related to a public improvement.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall collect and maintain a complete and accurate file of drawings and plats of the location of all public improvements.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall collect and maintain records of construction costs and progress on each public improvement.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department shall adequately store and protect any original drawing, plat, record, or specification.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Department shall examine and approve or disapprove each plan and specification prepared in connection with the preparation or execution of a contract for a public improvement.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall inspect and approve or disapprove any material, equipment, and methods used in making public improvements and shall inspect each public improvement during the course of construction or repair.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The duty of the Department under this subsection does not relieve an architect or engineer of any supervisory responsibility for which the architect or engineer is employed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The provisions of subsections (a), (b), (e), and (f) of this section do not apply to State correctional facilities as defined in &#xA7; 11-101 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-102 through 10-105 of the Correctional Services Article, the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services shall perform the duties specified in subsections (a), (b), (e), and (f) of this section for State correctional facilities.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
