<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-13-314</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Selection Board shall waive the requirements of &#xA7;&#xA7; 13-304(b), 13-308, 13-309, 13-311, 13-312(b...</catch_line>
  <order_by>314</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Selection Board shall waive the requirements of &#xA7;&#xA7; 13-304(b), 13-308, 13-309, 13-311, 13-312(b), and 13-313 of this subtitle if:<section prefix="(1)">the Selection Board determines that:<section prefix="(i)">the architectural services or engineering services cannot be defined so completely as to carry out those requirements; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the specifications require architectural services or engineering services that are available only from a bona fide single source or a proprietary product or process;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the Governor declares an emergency;</section><section prefix="(3)">after a natural disaster, public health and safety are endangered; or</section><section prefix="(4)">on the recommendation of the Secretary of General Services or the Secretary of Transportation and a finding by the Governor that extraordinary circumstances exist, the Board of Public Works determines that:<section prefix="(i)">for a particular project, urgent circumstances require the selection of a contractor on an expedited basis;</section><section prefix="(ii)">expedited selection best serves the public interest; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the need for an expedited selection outweighs the benefits of carrying out those requirements.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A waiver and the reasons for it shall be documented and:<section prefix="(1)">immediately reported to eMaryland Marketplace for publication; and</section><section prefix="(2)">reported to the Legislative Policy Committee within 30 days after the waiver occurs.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
