<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3A-313" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-3A-313</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Payee" means any party who receives from the State an aggregate payment of $25,000 in a fiscal year.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Payee" does not include:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Searchable website" means a website created in accordance with this section that displays and searches State payment data.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On or before January 1, 2009, the Department shall develop and operate a single searchable website, accessible to the public at no cost through the Internet.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The searchable website shall contain State payment data, including:<section prefix="(1)">the name of a payee receiving a payment;</section><section prefix="(2)">the location of a payee by postal zip code;</section><section prefix="(3)">the amount of a payment; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the name of an agency making a payment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The searchable website shall allow the user to:<section prefix="(1)">search data for fiscal year 2008 and each year thereafter; and</section><section prefix="(2)">search by the following data fields:<section prefix="(i)">a payee receiving a payment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an agency making a payment; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the zip code of a payee receiving a payment.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">State agencies shall provide appropriate assistance to the Secretary to ensure the existence and ongoing operation of the single website.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">This section may not be construed to require the disclosure of information that is confidential under State or federal law.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">This section shall be known and may be cited as the "Maryland Funding Accountability and Transparency Act of 2008".</section>
  </text>
</law>
