<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-3A-503</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Board shall be composed of 12 individuals appointed by the Governor, who shall designate the cha...</catch_line>
  <order_by>503</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board shall be composed of 12 individuals appointed by the Governor, who shall designate the chair, including:<section prefix="(1)">five representatives of the deaf or hard of hearing community;</section><section prefix="(2)">one representative of the mobility-impaired community who requires the use of specialized customer telephone equipment;</section><section prefix="(3)">one representative of the speech-impaired community who requires the use of specialized customer telephone equipment;</section><section prefix="(4)">one representative of the senior citizen community who requires the use of specialized customer telephone equipment;</section><section prefix="(5)">one representative of the deaf-blind community; and</section><section prefix="(6)">three representatives of government, one of whom is a representative of the Public Service Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Board on June 30, 2008.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Governor may remove a member for incompetence or misconduct.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The members of the Board shall serve without compensation, but shall be reimbursed for all reasonable expenses incurred in the performance of their duties.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">By January 1 of each year, the Board shall file an annual report on its activities to the General Assembly in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board shall advise the Department with regard to the program's:<section prefix="(1)">level of access to program participants; and</section><section prefix="(2)">quality of service.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
