<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-19-107</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>107</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Commission staff shall be responsible for directing and conducting investigations of discrimination and retaliation complaints filed under this title in a manner consistent with &#xA7;&#xA7; 20-208, 20-1005, 20-1006, 20-1008, 20-1009, and 20-1010 of the State Government Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission may request assignment of additional State personnel or outside consultants as may be reasonably necessary or appropriate to conduct an investigation.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Commission staff shall exercise reasonable judgment in seeking relevant evidence from the complainant, the respondent business entity and, as necessary, external sources.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This title may not be construed to require the State to fund the cost of:<section prefix="(i)">having State staff or other individuals travel outside the State to investigate any claim under this title; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">having witnesses travel to the State for the purpose of investigating a claim or testifying at a hearing or proceeding under this title.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Consistent with &#xA7; 20-1101 of the State Government Article, the Public Information Act, and the Open Meetings Act, the Commission shall protect the confidential character of information relating to an investigation and may issue protective orders for good cause to limit, or otherwise impose conditions on, access by any person to any document in the possession of a party.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A protective order issued under paragraph (1) of this subsection may include:<section prefix="(i)">a document in the possession of the State or otherwise in the record that is not a public record; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">information disclosed in accordance with &#xA7; 19-116 of this title.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commission shall exercise reasonable discretion in determining the extent of the investigation required to support Commission staff's initial findings and recommendations.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may investigate and adjudicate a claim of discrimination under this title only if the claim alleges that:<section prefix="(i)">the discrimination was committed by a business entity within the limitations period set forth in &#xA7; 19-101(c) of this title; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the discrimination occurred in the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Discrimination is deemed to have occurred in the State only if:<section prefix="(i)">each party operated a place of business in, or resided in, the State at the time of the discrimination; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the discriminatory act was committed in the State.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
