<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-8-128</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>128</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If, within 2 years after the date of an authorization of State debt, evidence that a required matching fund will be provided has not been presented to the Board or no part of the project or program for which the enabling act authorized the State debt is under contract and the Board has not encumbered money for any part of the project or program, the authorization terminates unless:<section prefix="(1)">the enabling act provides otherwise; or</section><section prefix="(2)">in an emergency, the Board unanimously grants a temporary exception for a period of 1 year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Unless otherwise provided in an enabling act, an authorization of State debt for a project or program shall terminate no later than 1 year after the abandonment, completion, or acceptance of the project or program, as determined by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except to the extent that money authorized by an enabling act for a State project or program has been encumbered by the Board, an authorization of State debt shall automatically terminate 7 years after the date of the authorization, unless:<section prefix="(1)">the enabling act provides otherwise; or</section><section prefix="(2)">in an emergency, the Board unanimously grants a temporary exception for 1 year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If bonds have not been issued, the amount of any unissued bonds from a terminated authorization shall be canceled and be of no further effect.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If bonds have been issued, the amount of any unspent bond proceeds from a terminated authorization shall be disposed of as provided in &#xA7; 8-129 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall enforce the provisions of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A failure to comply with or give effect to the provisions of this section may not affect the validity or enforceability of State debt.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Board shall submit for publication in the Maryland Register a notice of any authorization of State debt that has been terminated or extended under this section; the notice shall include the chapter number and year of enactment of the enabling act and each amendment to the enabling act.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A termination or extension under this section may become effective only after the publication of notice in the Maryland Register.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Treasurer, in consultation with the Comptroller, shall submit a report on January 1 each year to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The report shall list all projects or programs for which authorization would be terminated in the upcoming year under the provisions in this section or &#xA7; 7-305 of this article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
