<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-314" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-7-314</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Account" means the Economic Development Opportunities Program Account.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Executive agency" means an executive department or agency in the Executive Branch of State government, including all offices of the Executive Department or agency directly responsible to the Governor.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Extraordinary economic development opportunity" means the:<section prefix="(i)">attraction of a new private sector enterprise to the State or retention or expansion of an existing private sector enterprise in the State that:</section><section prefix="(ii)">retention or expansion of an existing public institution, private institution, or federal research and development institute that:</section><section prefix="(iii)">establishment or attraction of a public institution, a private institution, or a federal research and development institute new to the State that:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Performance requirement" means a contractual agreement between an executive agency and an Account recipient that requires the Account recipient to meet minimum economic development outcomes in exchange for a grant or a loan under this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Performance requirement" includes claw-back, penalty, rescission, and recalibration clauses that utilize job creation, capital investment, and other measures of economic development.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Private sector enterprise" means any commercial, industrial, educational, or research organization which is not a part of or controlled by a federal, State, or local government agency.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to the provisions of this section, the Economic Development Opportunities Program Account is established to maximize extraordinary economic development opportunities.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Governor may provide an appropriation in the budget bill to the Account for a specific or general purpose or purposes.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">After notice to and approval by the Legislative Policy Committee, the Governor may transfer funds by budget amendment from the Economic Development Opportunities Program Account to the expenditure account of the appropriate executive agency.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Account is a continuing, nonlapsing fund which is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Treasurer shall separately hold, and the Comptroller shall account for, the Account.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Account shall be invested and reinvested in the same manner as other State funds.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Except as provided in paragraph (5) of this subsection, any investment earnings shall be subject to &#xA7; 7-311(d) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Any investment earnings on moneys transferred from the Account to a second continuing, nonlapsing fund may be retained to the credit of the second fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Moneys appropriated or credited to the Account do not revert to the Revenue Stabilization Account.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, repayments of principal or interest on any loan from the Account shall be retained to the credit of the Account.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Repayments of principal or interest on any loan made from moneys transferred from the Account to a second continuing, nonlapsing fund may be retained to the credit of the second fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department of Business and Economic Development shall report to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly before January 1 of each year:<section prefix="(i)">the financial status of the program and a summary of its operations for the preceding fiscal year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">for the previous 3 fiscal years, the status of Account disbursements for economic development projects reviewed by the Legislative Policy Committee under this section; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">for the previous 3 fiscal years, the status of job creation, capital investment, and other measures of economic development for each economic development project reviewed by the Legislative Policy Committee under this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the job creation, capital investment, and other measures of economic development described in paragraph (1) of this subsection are lower than negotiated according to subsection (h)(1) of this section, the report shall contain an explanation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Upon receipt of the report, the Legislative Policy Committee shall have 60 days to review and comment on the report, during which time the Department of Business and Economic Development shall provide any additional information regarding the Account as requested by the Legislative Policy Committee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection and in subsection (i) of this section, any funds transferred from the Economic Development Opportunities Program Account shall be used only for extraordinary economic development opportunities that:<section prefix="(i)">meet the criteria provided in this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">include performance requirements; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">in addition to the performance requirements under item (ii) of this paragraph, include a performance requirement that utilizes a claw-back provision.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Account may pay an executive agency for administrative, legal, or actuarial expenses incurred by the agency in connection with transactions funded by transfers of moneys to the agency from the Account.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Legislative Policy Committee may approve an economic development opportunity that is not an extraordinary economic development opportunity if the executive agency requesting the transfer of funds offers a detailed justification for the exception. The Legislative Policy Committee shall give particular consideration to an exception that would provide a significant economic development opportunity for an area of the State that has a relatively high unemployment rate or relatively low per capita income.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department of Business and Economic Development shall submit to the Legislative Policy Committee by January 1 of each year a list of guidelines for the kinds of performance requirements that may be negotiated with a loan or grant applicant.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department of Business and Economic Development may modify these guidelines as needed, upon approval of the Legislative Policy Committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An executive agency may depart from these guidelines as needed, upon approval of the Legislative Policy Committee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">Subject to the provisions of this subtitle, funds transferred from the Economic Development Opportunities Program Account, to an executive agency, may be loaned, granted, or invested for:<section prefix="(1)">assisting in the retention or expansion of existing private sector enterprises, public or private institutions, or federal research and development institutes;</section><section prefix="(2)">assisting in the establishment or attraction of private sector enterprises, public or private institutions, or federal research and development institutes new to this State; or</section><section prefix="(3)">providing assistance where existing State or local programs lack sufficient resources or are constrained by timing or program design from being utilized.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">Upon submission to the Legislative Policy Committee of a proposed budget amendment to transfer money from the Account, the Governor shall provide, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the Legislative Policy Committee:<section prefix="(1)">a detailed description of:<section prefix="(i)">the proposed use of the funds;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the manner in which the proposed use meets the criteria as set forth in this section;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the degree to which the proposed use of funds will advance statewide or local economic development strategies and objectives; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the degree to which available sources of federal, State, local, and private financial support have been sought and will be utilized;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the terms, conditions, and performance requirements of any grant or loan for which the funds are to be used;</section><section prefix="(3)">a comprehensive economic analysis of the proposed use of the funds which estimates:<section prefix="(i)">the economic impact to the State and the local jurisdictions affected;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a minimum level of net economic benefits to the public sector;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the number of jobs expected to be created as a result of the proposed economic development project and the percentage of those jobs that are expected to be held by Maryland residents;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the wage rates and benefit packages for the jobs expected to be created as a result of the proposed economic development project; and</section><section prefix="(v)">any other appropriate financial or economic benefits;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">any other analysis or information that is requested by the Legislative Policy Committee; and</section><section prefix="(5)">the date on which the executive agency expects to disburse the funds to the proposed recipient.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">If an executive agency fails to disburse transferred funds to a recipient within 1 year after the expected disbursement date presented to the Legislative Policy Committee under subsection (l) of this section, the funds will revert back to the Account and the Governor shall:<section prefix="(1)">resubmit the proposed budget amendment to transfer money from the Account to the Legislative Policy Committee; and</section><section prefix="(2)">provide the Legislative Policy Committee with the information required under subsection (l) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(n)">Funds appropriated to the Economic Development Opportunities Program Account may not be loaned, granted, or invested for:<section prefix="(1)">substituting for funds from other State or local programs for which a project may be eligible and sufficient resources exist;</section><section prefix="(2)">projects which are not likely to attract or retain employment opportunities;</section><section prefix="(3)">funding projects located outside the State;</section><section prefix="(4)">construction or land acquisition by the Maryland Stadium Authority; or</section><section prefix="(5)">funding for any sports activity or facility.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(o)">In the case of an economic development opportunity located outside a priority funding area as established under Title 5, Subtitle 7B of this article, the Department shall first comply with the provisions of that subtitle before making a request for approval by the Legislative Policy Committee under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">An executive agency may approve changes to a transaction approved by the Legislative Policy Committee as long as the changes do not materially and adversely affect the overall position of the executive agency in the transaction or the economic development benefits to be derived by the State in the transaction.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Financial assistance" means a grant, loan, or investment provided under this subsection that exceeds $100,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Political subdivision" includes an agency or other instrumentality of the political subdivision.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection does not apply to financial assistance used solely for the purpose of acquiring real property or structures on real property.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">With respect to financial assistance under this section to a political subdivision:<section prefix="(i)">if the political subdivision has a program for promoting procurement opportunities among minority businesses that is acceptable to the Department of Business and Economic Development, the political subdivision shall apply the requirements of that program to the procurement of goods or services made with the proceeds from the financial assistance; but</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the political subdivision does not have a program that is acceptable to the Department of Business and Economic Development under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the political subdivision is subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this paragraph, "minority business enterprise" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 14-301 of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">With respect to financial assistance under this section to an entity other than a political subdivision, the entity shall agree to include in the agreement providing the financial assistance a provision acceptable to the Department of Business and Economic Development that would encourage the procurement from minority business enterprises of goods or services purchased with the proceeds from the financial assistance.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">In negotiating the provision required under subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the Department of Business and Economic Development shall take into account relevant factors, including:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Department of Business and Economic Development may require that a recipient of financial assistance under this section submit to the Department of Business and Economic Development a list, or an updated list, of the minority business enterprises from which goods or services were procured and the nature and dollar amount of the goods or services.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
