<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-8-206</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section does not apply if the total principal amount of the authorized issue is $25,000 or less...</catch_line>
  <order_by>206</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section does not apply if the total principal amount of the authorized issue is $25,000 or less.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not apply to a bond that:<section prefix="(i)">matures within 1 year after the date of issue and is issued:<section prefix="1.">in anticipation of tax receipts;</section><section prefix="2.">to meet current expenses; or</section><section prefix="3.">to meet an emergency;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">is sold to the United States or a unit or instrumentality of the United States;</section><section prefix="(iii)">is issued under a plan of composition approved in a proceeding under Chapter IX of the United States Bankruptcy Act; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">is issued under any other plan to refund or refinance in exchange, bond for bond, an outstanding maturing debt, other than:<section prefix="1.">a current or floating debt; or</section><section prefix="2.">a bond under item (i) of this paragraph.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This section does not apply if:<section prefix="(i)">the proceeds of the sale of bonds are to be used with a grant from the United States or a unit or instrumentality of the United States to finance public works; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">in the opinion of the Attorney General, the agreement or other writing referring to the grant conditions the grant on the prior execution, by the State unit and a prospective buyer, of a contract for the sale of the bonds when issued.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">This section does not apply to bond or grant anticipation notes issued under Part III of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">This section does not apply to bonds issued under an enabling act that specifically states that this section does not apply or that provides a different method for the sale of the bonds.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A State unit shall offer bonds at a public sale.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A State unit shall give notice of a public sale of bonds at least twice in at least 1 newspaper with a general circulation in the State. The 1st publication shall appear at least 10 days before the date of sale.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice shall:<section prefix="(i)">be in the form required in the resolution that authorizes the issuance of the bonds;</section><section prefix="(ii)">state the date, time, and place of the public sale;</section><section prefix="(iii)">describe the bonds by reference to the enabling act under which they are authorized;</section><section prefix="(iv)">state the date of issue;</section><section prefix="(v)">state the total principal amount;</section><section prefix="(vi)">state the schedule of maturities;</section><section prefix="(vii)">state the interest payable or the manner of determining the interest;</section><section prefix="(viii)">state the purpose for which the proceeds will be used;</section><section prefix="(ix)">describe the general form of the bonds, including:<section prefix="1.">whether the bonds will be in coupon or registered form; and</section><section prefix="2.">whether the principal or interest or both will be registrable;</section></section><section prefix="(x)">state that each bid must be made in writing by sealed proposal; and</section><section prefix="(xi)">state the amount of the good faith deposit that the State unit has determined must accompany the bid.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The notice may reserve to the State unit the right to reject any or all bids.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section and &#xA7; 8-207 of this subtitle, the State unit shall sell the bonds to the highest bidder or bidders at the public sale.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the State unit has reserved the right to reject bids and does reject all bids, the State unit, within 30 days after rejecting all the bids, may sell the bonds at a private sale for not less than the highest amount bid by an acceptable bidder at the public sale.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the State unit has reserved the right to reject all bids and does reject all bids and fails to sell the bonds at a private sale within the 30-day period under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the State unit may sell the bonds only at another public sale after notice as required in subsection (c) of this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
