<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-7-310</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>310</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Account" means the Dedicated Purpose Account.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Dedicated Purpose Account is established:<section prefix="(1)">to retain appropriations for major, multi-year expenditures where the magnitude and timing of cash needs are uncertain; and</section><section prefix="(2)">beginning in fiscal year 1996, to meet specific expenditure requirements.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Governor may provide an appropriation in the budget bill to the Account for a specific purpose or purposes.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For each appropriation to the Account, the Governor may:<section prefix="(1)">include the funds in the State budget subject to appropriation by the General Assembly; or</section><section prefix="(2)">transfer the funds by budget amendment from the Account to the expenditure account of the appropriate unit of State government only after the proposed budget amendment has been:<section prefix="(i)">submitted to the Senate Budget and Taxation Committee and the House Appropriations Committee of the General Assembly; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">approved by the Legislative Policy Committee.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Account is a continuing, nonlapsing fund which is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The unspent balance of an appropriation to the Account reverts to the Revenue Stabilization Account 4 years after the end of the fiscal year for which the appropriation was made.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Governor determines that certain funds in the Account are no longer needed for the purpose for which they were originally appropriated, those funds may be transferred by budget amendment to the Revenue Stabilization Account after the proposed budget amendment has been:<section prefix="(i)">submitted to the Senate Budget and Taxation Committee and the House Appropriations Committee of the General Assembly; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">approved by the Legislative Policy Committee.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
