<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-11-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>A unit may not enter into a procurement contract except as allowed under this Division II....</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A unit may not enter into a procurement contract except as allowed under this Division II.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this Division II, if a procurement violates this Division II, the procurement contract is void.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Whenever a procurement contract is void under this subsection, the contractor shall be awarded compensation for actual expenses reasonably incurred under the procurement contract, plus a reasonable profit, if the contractor:<section prefix="(i)">acted in good faith;</section><section prefix="(ii)">did not directly contribute to a violation of this Division II; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">had no knowledge of the violation before the procurement contract was awarded.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whenever a procurement violates this Division II, the Board may determine that the procurement contract is voidable, rather than void, if the Board determines that:<section prefix="(i)">all parties acted in good faith;</section><section prefix="(ii)">ratification of the procurement contract would not undermine the purposes of this Division II; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the violation or series of violations was insignificant or otherwise did not prevent substantial compliance with this Division II.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Whenever a procurement contract is voidable under this subsection and the contractor has not acted in violation of this Division II, the unit may:<section prefix="(i)">ratify the procurement contract if the unit determines that ratification is in the best interests of the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">void the procurement contract and award the contractor compensation for actual expenses reasonably incurred under the contract, plus a reasonable profit.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Whenever a procurement contract is voidable under this subsection and the contractor has acted in violation of this Division II, the unit:<section prefix="(i)">may void the procurement contract; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">without prejudice to the State's right to appropriate damages, may ratify the procurement contract if the unit determines that ratification is in the best interests of the State.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
