<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-108" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-15-108</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to any procurement contract funded with tax-exempt financing.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the requirements of this section, a contractor under a procurement contract that a unit awards for construction is entitled to have retainage under the procurement contract placed in an escrow account if the contractor:<section prefix="(i)">elects that procedure in the procurement contract in the space provided for that election; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">submits to the unit an escrow agreement that meets the requirements of subsection (c) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The procurement contract shall identify the escrow agent.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The escrow agreement shall:<section prefix="(1)">be on a form that the unit provides;</section><section prefix="(2)">include the complete address of both the escrow agent and the surety;</section><section prefix="(3)">authorize the unit to pay retainage to the escrow agent; and</section><section prefix="(4)">be signed by:<section prefix="(i)">the contractor;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the surety for the contractor; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the escrow agent.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">On compliance with the requirements of subsection (b) of this section, the unit shall pay the retainage to the escrow agent unless:<section prefix="(1)">federal money is involved and application of this section would jeopardize timely recovery of that federal money; or</section><section prefix="(2)">retainage is withheld for:<section prefix="(i)">lack of progress on the part of the contractor; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">other violations by the contractor.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In accordance with the escrow agreement, a contractor may require an escrow agent:<section prefix="(1)">to invest the retainage placed in the escrow account; and</section><section prefix="(2)">to the extent the contractor is entitled to retainage under subsection (f)(2)(ii) of this section, to pay the earnings on the investment to the contractor.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Retainage may be released to the contractor only as directed by the unit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the time of final payment, the unit shall direct the escrow agent to settle the escrow account by distributing money in the escrow account in the following order:<section prefix="(i)">to the unit for any claim it may have against the contractor under the procurement contract;</section><section prefix="(ii)">unless waived by the Board, to the Comptroller for any claim exceeding $50 against the contractor by the State, a unit, or a State controlled governmental entity; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">to the contractor.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
