<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-224" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-13-224</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Children of current or former recipients" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 5-304 of the Human Services Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Department" means the Department of Human Resources.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Eligible contract" means a procurement contract designated by the Board as appropriate for the execution of a hiring agreement.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"FIP" means the Family Investment Program established under Title 5, Subtitle 3 of the Human Services Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Former recipient" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 5-304 of the Human Services Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Foster youth" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 5-304 of the Human Services Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Hiring agreement" means an agreement entered into by the Department or a local department and an entity doing business with the State under which the Department or the local department and the entity agree to work cooperatively in endeavoring to identify and hire current and former FIP recipients, children of current or former recipients, foster youth, and obligors to fill job openings of the entity.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">"Local department" means a local department of social services in a county or in Baltimore City created or continued under &#xA7; 3-201(a) of the Human Services Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(10)">"Obligor" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 10-101 of the Family Law Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On or before October 1, 1998, the Board, in consultation with the Department, shall designate the types of procurement contracts that are eligible contracts.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before December 1, 1998, the Department shall develop a model hiring agreement form that shall be completed by the Department or a local department and an entity in conjunction with the award of an eligible contract.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The model hiring agreement form shall include the following provisions:<section prefix="(i)">the entity will:</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Department or the local department, as appropriate, will assign an account representative to the entity who will:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each year, the Department and any local departments that have entered into hiring agreements shall submit a report to the Board, the Joint Committee on Welfare Reform, and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly on:<section prefix="(1)">the number of hiring agreements executed;</section><section prefix="(2)">the number of current and former FIP recipients, children of current or former recipients, foster youth, and obligors hired by an entity with which a hiring agreement was executed; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the effectiveness of each hiring agreement in obtaining employment for current and former FIP recipients, children of current or former recipients, foster youth, and obligors.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
