<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-7B-01" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-5-7B-01</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Funding" includes any form of assurance, guarantee, grant payment, credit, tax credit, or other assistance, including a loan, loan guarantee, or reduction in the principal obligation of, or rate of interest payable on, a loan or a portion of a loan.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Growth-related project" means only the items set forth below:<section prefix="(i)">any major capital project as defined in &#xA7; 2-103.1(a)(4) of the Transportation Article, except existing transportation facilities projects as defined in &#xA7; 4-101(h) of the Transportation Article, project planning as defined in &#xA7; 8-610(i) of the Transportation Article, or initial project planning as defined in &#xA7; 8-610(e) of the Transportation Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">funding by the Department of Housing and Community Development for:</section><section prefix="(iii)">funding by the Department of Business and Economic Development under any of the following:</section><section prefix="(iv)">funding by the Department of the Environment, for any project under:</section><section prefix="(v)">except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, procurement or funding of projects by the Department of General Services for:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Growth-related project" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">projects by the Department of General Services for maintenance, repair, additions, or renovations to existing facilities, acquisition of land for telecommunications towers, parks, conservation and open space, and acquisition of agricultural, conservation, and historic easements;</section><section prefix="(ii)">funding by the Department of Housing and Community Development for any project financed with federal moneys used to purchase or rehabilitate existing single or multifamily housing or project financed with the proceeds of revenue bonds issued by the Community Development Administration if:</section><section prefix="(iii)">acquisition of land by the Department of Natural Resources under Title 1, Subtitle 1 of the Natural Resources Article; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">any other project, funding, or other State assistance not listed under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Limited peripheral development" means development that is contiguous to an existing community and does not increase the size of the existing community or village by more than 10% of the existing number of dwelling units.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Locally designated growth area" means an area determined by the county to be suitable for development in compliance with Title 1, Subtitle 4 or Title 3 of the Land Use Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Rural village" means a rural village, village center, or other unincorporated area that is primarily residential, including an area with historic qualities, that is located in an otherwise rural or agricultural area and for which new growth, if any, would derive primarily from in-fill development or limited peripheral expansion.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Technical assistance" means the provision of advice, consultation, training, information, or design, or architectural, organizational, or management assistance.</section>
  </text>
</law>
