<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-2-206</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>206</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Board" means the Maryland Agricultural Education and Rural Development Assistance Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Council" means the Rural Maryland Council established under Title 13, Subtitle 4 of the Economic Development Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Fund" means the Maryland Agricultural Education and Rural Development Assistance Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The General Assembly finds and declares that:<section prefix="(1)">many nonprofit organizations that serve the needs of the rural areas of the State experience fiscal difficulties in addressing the areas of economic and community development and agriculture and forestry education because of the inadequacy of funding resources for them;</section><section prefix="(2)">these organizations do not have the access to private and public sources of funding that are generally more available to nonprofit groups that serve the needs of the metropolitan areas of the State; and</section><section prefix="(3)">as a result, the rural areas of the State face a serious deficit of resources where the need, in many instances, is greatest.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Maryland Agricultural Education and Rural Development Assistance Fund that shall be administered by the Council.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The purpose of the Fund is to provide funding:<section prefix="(i)">to rural regional planning and economic development organizations and rural community development programs whose missions and work have statewide implications and merit State support; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">to augment the efforts of advanced technology centers and similar programs that serve agricultural and natural resources based small businesses in rural areas through community colleges.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Fund is a continuing, nonlapsing fund which is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Treasurer shall separately hold and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Treasurer may invest moneys in the Fund in the same manner as other State money may be invested.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Expenditures from the Fund may only be made:<section prefix="(i)">pursuant to an appropriation approved by the General Assembly in the annual State budget; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">by the budget amendment procedure provided for in &#xA7; 7-209 of this article, provided that:<section prefix="1.">the budget amendment and supporting information have been submitted to the budget committees for their review and comment; and</section><section prefix="2.">at least 45 days have elapsed from the time the budget amendment and supporting information were submitted to the budget committees.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Council shall award grants on the basis of the binding recommendations of the Maryland Agricultural Education and Rural Development Assistance Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Maryland Agricultural Education and Rural Development Assistance Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall consist of:<section prefix="(i)">the Secretary of Agriculture or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Secretary of Business and Economic Development or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Secretary of Housing and Community Development or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(v)">the Secretary of Natural Resources or the Secretary's designee; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">the Chairman of the Council or the Chairman's designee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The agencies listed in paragraph (2)(i) through (v) of this subsection may assist the Council with administering individual grant awards.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">establish procedures for applications for grants;</section><section prefix="(ii)">review applications for grants; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">make binding recommendations to the Council regarding the recipients of grants and the amount of the grants.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Board shall give funding priority to organizations described in subsection (c)(2)(i) of this section that have:<section prefix="(i)">obtained an equal matching amount of funding from a source other than the State in the immediate prior fiscal year; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">sufficient evidence of a commitment of a third party funding source to provide an equal matching amount of funding in the current fiscal year.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A grant recipient shall submit to the Council written documentation of how the grant recipient spent or otherwise used the grant.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On or before June 30 of each year, the Council shall submit to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly, a written report that includes:<section prefix="(i)">the number of grants made during the fiscal year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the names of the recipients of the grants;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the specific purpose of each grant awarded; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">documentation of how the grant recipient spent or otherwise used the grant.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
