<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-105" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-12-105</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Council" means the Procurement Advisory Council.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Procurement Advisory Council.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Council consists of the following ten members:<section prefix="(i)">the State Treasurer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Chancellor of the University System of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Secretary of Budget and Management;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Secretary of General Services;</section><section prefix="(v)">the Secretary of Transportation;</section><section prefix="(vi)">the Secretary of the Board;</section><section prefix="(vii)">the Special Secretary for the Office of Minority Affairs;</section><section prefix="(viii)">a representative of local government who has expertise in local procurement matters, appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">two members of the general public, at least one of whom has expertise in State procurement matters, appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the State Treasurer is unable to attend a meeting of the Procurement Advisory Council, the Treasurer may designate the Deputy Treasurer to attend the meeting.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a member of the Council listed in paragraph (1) (ii) through (v) of this subsection is unable to attend a meeting of the Procurement Advisory Council, the member may designate the Chief Procurement Officer of the agency to attend the meeting.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary of the Board is Chairman of the Council.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Council shall meet at least quarterly each year.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Procurement Advisor is the principal staff of the Council and the Council shall have any additional staff that the Board authorizes in accordance with the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Council shall:<section prefix="(1)">ensure that the State's procurement system is utilizing the most advanced procurement methods and management techniques;</section><section prefix="(2)">effect and enhance communication between State units on procurement matters, with an emphasis on disseminating information on current developments and advances in procurement methods and management;</section><section prefix="(3)">provide a forum for the discussion of specific procurement issues and problems that arise;</section><section prefix="(4)">advise the Board on problems in the procurement process and make recommendations for improvement of the process; and</section><section prefix="(5)">review existing procurement regulations to:<section prefix="(i)">determine whether they fulfill the intent and purpose of the law, especially as it relates to fostering broad-based competition; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">make recommendations on the regulations, if revising and restructuring them will result in easier understanding and use.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
