<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-13-111</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies to the procurement of supplies, with an estimated contract value of $1,000,000 ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>111</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to the procurement of supplies, with an estimated contract value of $1,000,000 or more, by a primary procurement unit.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whenever the head of a primary procurement unit or designee determines that it is in the best interest of the State for a procurement contract to be based on auction bids, a procurement officer shall seek bids by issuing an invitation for auction bids.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to subsection (c) of this section, an invitation for auction bids shall include:<section prefix="(i)">the specifications of the procurement contract;</section><section prefix="(ii)">whether the procurement contract will be awarded based on the lowest bid price or the lowest evaluated bid price;</section><section prefix="(iii)">if the procurement contract will be based on evaluated bid price, the objective measurable criteria by which the lowest evaluated bid price will be determined;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the small business preference, if designated under &#xA7; 13-103 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(v)">the date and time when bidding will commence and the date and time when bidding will end or the event upon which bidding will end.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In the discretion of the procurement officer, the invitation for auction bids may:<section prefix="(i)">include a request for unpriced technical offers or samples;</section><section prefix="(ii)">direct bidders to submit price bids after the unit evaluates the technical offers or samples and finds they are acceptable under the criteria set forth in the invitation for auction bids; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">inform all bidders who submitted technical offers or samples of the identity of each bidder who submitted an acceptable technical offer or sample.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Price bids may not be received until after the unit has completed evaluation of the technical offers or samples.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A price bid may not be received at any time if the bid is submitted by a bidder whose technical offer or sample has been evaluated as unacceptable to the unit.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A unit shall give public notice of an invitation for auction bids in the same manner as required for an invitation for bids.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Multiple price bids are permitted in response to an invitation for auction bids.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">When a bidder submits multiple bids, each bid shall be judged independently and shall not revoke previous bids of that bidder.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A procurement officer shall:<section prefix="(i)">receive bids in public at the time and place designated in the invitation for auction bids; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">record and post the amount of each bid at the time it is received.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The amount of a price bid shall be available for public inspection from the time it is received.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The identity of the bidder submitting a price bid shall not be available for public inspection until bidding has ended.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Except as provided in paragraph (5) of this subsection, a bid is irrevocable, after receipt, for the period specified in the invitation for auction bids.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A procurement officer may allow a bidder to correct or withdraw a bid if correction or withdrawal is:<section prefix="(i)">allowed under regulations adopted under this Division II applicable to an invitation for bids; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">approved in writing by the Office of the Attorney General.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After obtaining any approval required by law, the procurement officer shall award the procurement contract to the responsible bidder who submits the responsive bid that:<section prefix="(i)">is the lowest bid price; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the invitation for auction bids so provides, is the lowest evaluated bid price.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If, after bids have been received, a procurement officer determines that only one responsible bidder has submitted a responsive bid, the unit may negotiate the procurement contract with that one bidder under the procedure for sole source procurement.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">After bids have been received, a procurement officer may award a procurement contract on the basis of revised bids if:<section prefix="1.">all bids are rejected under &#xA7; 13-206(b) of this title;</section><section prefix="2.">all bid prices exceed the funds available for the procurement; or</section><section prefix="3.">with the approval of the head of a primary procurement unit or a designee, the procurement officer determines that all bids are unreasonable as to at least one requirement and the delay that would result from issuing a new invitation for auction bids with revised specifications or quantities would be fiscally disadvantageous or otherwise not in the best interests of the State.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If there is more than one bidder, discussions about revised specifications or quantities shall be conducted with all responsible bidders who submitted responsive bids. The bidders shall be treated fairly and equally with respect to any discussions.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If one of the conditions set forth under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph exists, as promptly as possible, the procurement officer shall:<section prefix="1.">issue an invitation for revised auction bids, which shall state whether the award will be made without competitive negotiations; and</section><section prefix="2.">require a prompt response to that invitation.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">An invitation for revised auction bids is not subject to the notice requirements in subsection (d) of this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">After revised bids have been submitted, negotiations with bidders may not be conducted unless the procurement officer determines that there is a compelling reason to negotiate.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">After revised bids have been received and any approval required by law has been obtained, the procurement officer shall award the procurement contract to the responsible bidder who submits a responsive bid that:<section prefix="1.">is the lowest bid price; or</section><section prefix="2.">if the invitation for revised bids so provides, is the lowest evaluated bid price.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Not more than 30 days after the execution and approval of a procurement contract awarded under this section, a unit shall publish notice of the award:<section prefix="(1)">until July 1, 2006, in the Contract Weekly and eMaryland Marketplace; and</section><section prefix="(2)">on and after July 1, 2006, in eMaryland Marketplace.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
