<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-230" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-7-230</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Fund" means the Unpresented Checks Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is an Unpresented Checks Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">At the end of each fiscal year, the Treasurer shall:<section prefix="(1)">identify each check that:<section prefix="(i)">has been issued against the money of the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">has remained unpresented for 2 years; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">request the Comptroller to credit the aggregate amount of the checks to the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">At the end of each fiscal year, the Treasurer shall:<section prefix="(1)">determine a reasonable minimum balance to retain in the Fund that will be needed to honor each check that is presented after its amount has been credited to the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(2)">request the Comptroller to transfer the balance in the Fund to the General Fund of the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">After the amount of a check has been credited to the Fund, on a warrant charged against the Fund, the Treasurer, the Chief Deputy Treasurer, or a deputy treasurer may reissue a check that is presented for payment.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">As required by State or federal law, or as considered proper by the Treasurer, the Treasurer, the Chief Deputy Treasurer, or a deputy treasurer shall:<section prefix="(1)">void an unpresented check; and</section><section prefix="(2)">request the Comptroller to transfer the amount of the voided check to:<section prefix="(i)">the original source of the money; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">another fund or account.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Unpresented checks credited to the Fund are not subject to Title 17 of the Commercial Law Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Notwithstanding &#xA7; 10-617 of the State Government Article, at the end of each fiscal year, the Treasurer may electronically publish on the Treasurer's website the names of payees of checks that have remained unpresented for 2 years or more.</section>
  </text>
</law>
