<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-18-107</section_number>
  <catch_line>Within 30 days after a complaint is filed, the Commissioner shall investigate the complaint in accor...</catch_line>
  <order_by>107</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Within 30 days after a complaint is filed, the Commissioner shall investigate the complaint in accordance with this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A written or oral complaint or statement made by an employee under this title is confidential and may not be disclosed to the employer without the consent of the employee.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An employer subject to this title shall allow the Commissioner or the Commissioner's designee access to a work site and payroll records, and allow an opportunity to interview employees for purposes of enforcing this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 30 days after completing an investigation, the Commissioner shall issue an order for a hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 30 days before the hearing, the Commissioner shall serve, personally or by mail, written notice of the hearing on all interested parties.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The notice shall include:<section prefix="(i)">a statement of facts disclosed in the investigation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the time and place of the hearing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In conducting a hearing, the Commissioner may:<section prefix="(i)">subpoena witnesses;</section><section prefix="(ii)">administer oaths; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">compel the production of records, books, papers, and other evidence.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 30 days after the conclusion of the hearing, the Commissioner shall:<section prefix="(i)">issue a determination; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">serve, personally or by mail, each interested party with a copy of the determination.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Commissioner finds a violation of this title, the Commissioner shall determine the amount of restitution and liquidated damages to be assessed under &#xA7; 18-108 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On receipt of the determination, the employer shall pay the affected employees the amount due in accordance with the Commissioner's determination.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
