<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-7-324</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "Account" means the Catastrophic Event Account....</catch_line>
  <order_by>324</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Account" means the Catastrophic Event Account.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to the provisions of this section, the Account is established to enable the State to respond without undue delay to a natural disaster or other catastrophic situation that cannot be taken care of within the resources of existing appropriations.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Governor may provide an appropriation in the budget bill to the Account.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">After notice to and approval by the Legislative Policy Committee, the Governor may transfer funds by budget amendment from the Account to the expenditure accounts of the appropriate unit of State government.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Funds appropriated to the Catastrophic Event Account:<section prefix="(1)">may not be used to offset operating deficiencies in regular programs of State government; but</section><section prefix="(2)">may be expended to assist a unit of State government in funding costs in connection with a natural disaster or catastrophic situation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Account is a continuing, nonlapsing fund which is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Treasurer shall separately hold, and the Comptroller shall account for, the Account.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Account shall be invested and reinvested in the same manner as other State funds.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Any investment earning shall be subject to &#xA7; 7-311(d) of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Moneys appropriated to the Account do not revert to the Revenue Stabilization Account.</section>
  </text>
</law>
