<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-8-131</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to the limitations in this section, the Board of Public Works may issue new bonds to refund ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>131</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the limitations in this section, the Board of Public Works may issue new bonds to refund its outstanding bonds.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The power to issue bonds under this section is in addition to any other power to borrow.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board may issue bonds under this section only for:<section prefix="(1)">the public purpose of realizing for the State a savings in the total cost of debt service on a direct comparison or present value basis; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the public purpose of debt restructuring that reduces the total cost of debt service.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board may:<section prefix="(1)">provide that bonds under this section be in 1 or more series; and</section><section prefix="(2)">vary the amount of the series.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The total principal amount of the bonds issued under this section may exceed the total principal amount of the bonds that are being refunded.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Bonds that are being refunded and that are subject to redemption before their stated dates of maturity may be called for redemption:<section prefix="(1)">on the earliest redemption date; or</section><section prefix="(2)">at a later date that the Board determines.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Treasurer shall invest and apply proceeds of a sale of bonds issued under this section to ensure that the principal and redemption premium of, and interest on, the bonds that are being refunded will be paid in full when due.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Treasurer may deposit any part of the proceeds of the sale of bonds issued under this section in a trust fund with a trust company or other banking institution, in the name of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The trustee may invest and reinvest money in the trust fund in:<section prefix="(i)">obligations of the United States;</section><section prefix="(ii)">obligations guaranteed by the United States;</section><section prefix="(iii)">certificates of deposit or time deposits secured by an obligation of the United States;</section><section prefix="(iv)">certificates of deposit or time deposits secured by an obligation guaranteed by the United States; or</section><section prefix="(v)">any obligation or other investment described in &#xA7; 6-222(a) of this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Interest, income, and profits on the investment may be applied in any lawful manner, including to the payment of:<section prefix="(i)">the bonds that are being refunded; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the bonds issued under this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The trustee shall make money in the trust fund available, as the Board requires, for the payment of:<section prefix="(i)">the principal and redemption premium of, and interest on, the bonds that are being refunded;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the principal and redemption premium of, and interest on, the bonds issued under this section; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">any other related costs.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Comptroller shall account for the proceeds of a sale of bonds issued under this section as nonbudgeted funds.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">All or any part of the bonds issued under this section may be made payable from and secured by:<section prefix="(1)">money in the Annuity Bond Fund established under &#xA7; 8-132 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">other money or security that the State provides.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Nothing in this section shall prevent issuance and sale of refunding bonds the interest on which is not excludable from gross income for federal income tax purposes.</section>
  </text>
</law>
