<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-5-407</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>407</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Commission" means the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To provide regional planning in the area of the State subject to the jurisdiction of the Commission, and except as otherwise provided in this section, the Department may include in the annual budget of the Department the amount the Secretary considers appropriate as the State's share of the cost of regional planning projects programmed by the Commission for the following fiscal year.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The amount included in the annual budget under subsection (b) of this section may not exceed $100,000 in any single year.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary shall determine which regional planning projects programmed by the Commission qualify for State assistance.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall provide the Secretary with any information the Secretary requires to determine which regional planning projects programmed by the Commission qualify for State assistance.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On or before August 1 of each year, the Commission shall provide the Secretary with a copy of the proposed budget of the Commission for the following fiscal year. After the copy of the proposed budget is provided to the Secretary, the Commission shall promptly notify the Secretary and obtain the approval of the Secretary for any changes in the proposed budget for regional projects funded under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Secretary may require an annual audit of the operations of the Commission that relate to any project financed wholly or partly by payments to the Commission from the Department.</section>
  </text>
</law>
