<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-13-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>After a solicitation is issued and until a recommendation is made by a procurement officer, a procur...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">After a solicitation is issued and until a recommendation is made by a procurement officer, a procurement officer may disclose to a person outside the Executive Department only:<section prefix="(1)">whether a decision has been made regarding a solicitation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">information that is available to the public under &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-611 through 10-628 of the State Government Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">After a solicitation is issued, a procurement officer shall record and include in the procurement file the following information from an inquiry from a source outside the Executive Department:<section prefix="(1)">the date and time of the inquiry;</section><section prefix="(2)">the name and affiliation of the person making the inquiry; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the substance and nature of the inquiry.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A procurement officer shall maintain a file on each procurement that includes:<section prefix="(1)">a record of all inquiries required to be recorded under subsection (b) of this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">all written solicitations by an agency or unit;</section><section prefix="(3)">all offers received;</section><section prefix="(4)">all internal and external correspondence regarding the procurement;</section><section prefix="(5)">written documentation from the procurement officer describing efforts to confirm the information in the affidavits submitted by the successful bidder or offeror; and</section><section prefix="(6)">the final contract.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
