<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-8-121</section_number>
  <catch_line>By resolution, the Board may specify the form in which State bonds are to be issued, including:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>121</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">By resolution, the Board may specify the form in which State bonds are to be issued, including:<section prefix="(1)">a coupon form;</section><section prefix="(2)">a capital appreciation form;</section><section prefix="(3)">a variable interest rate form;</section><section prefix="(4)">a form that qualifies for tax credits, interest subsidies, or other federal tax benefits;</section><section prefix="(5)">a form that qualifies as a registered form under &#xA7;&#xA7; 54A, 103, and 149 of the Internal Revenue Code or a regulation proposed or adopted under those sections; and</section><section prefix="(6)">any other registered form.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whenever the Board provides for the sale of State bonds in registered form, the Board may establish procedures for the registration and transfer of the State bonds.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may exercise any other power that relates to issuance of State bonds in registered form and that is not conferred on the Treasurer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Whenever the Board provides for the sale of State bonds in registered form, the Treasurer may:<section prefix="(1)">appoint any agent, including an authenticating trustee, corporate trustee, paying agent, registrar, or transfer agent, or use the agent appointed under &#xA7; 8-135 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">specify the rights, duties, and compensation of the agent; and</section><section prefix="(3)">in connection with the establishment and maintenance of a central depository system for the transfer or pledge of the State bonds, make agreements with:<section prefix="(i)">custodian banks and their nominees; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">financial intermediaries and their nominees.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Whenever the Board provides for the sale of State bonds in variable interest rate form, the Treasurer may:<section prefix="(1)">appoint any agent or other contracting party, including an underwriter, remarketing agent, dealer, tender agent, insurer, liquidity provider, or similar entity; and</section><section prefix="(2)">specify the rights, duties, and compensation of and make agreements with the agent or other contracting party.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
