<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-505" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-14-505</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL SEPTEMBER 30, 2016 PER CHAPTER 22 OF 2010 //<section prefix="(a)">Within 90 days after the end of each fiscal year, each designated procurement unit shall submit a report on the operation and effectiveness of the Small Business Reserve Program that complies with subsection (d)(2) of this section to the Board of Public Works.</section><section prefix="(b)">Within 60 days after receipt of all reports required under subsection (a) of this section, the Board of Public Works shall compile the information and report on the operation and effectiveness of the entire Small Business Reserve Program to the Legislative Policy Committee, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article.</section><section prefix="(c)">Within 60 days after the enactment of the budget bill by the General Assembly, each designated procurement unit shall submit a report to the Governor's Office of Minority Affairs that complies with the reporting requirements set forth in COMAR 21.11.01.06.</section><section prefix="(d)"><section prefix="(1)">Within 90 days after the end of each fiscal year, each unit shall submit a report to the Governor's Office of Minority Affairs that complies with the requirements of paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section><section prefix="(2)">For the preceding fiscal year, the report shall:<section prefix="(i)">state the total number and the dollar value of payments the unit made to small businesses under designated small business reserve contracts;</section><section prefix="(ii)">state the total number and the dollar value of payments the unit made to small businesses under nondesignated small business reserve contracts, including purchase card procurements;</section><section prefix="(iii)">state the total dollar value of payments the unit made under procurement contracts; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">contain other such information as required by the Governor's Office of Minority Affairs.</section></section></section><section prefix="(e)">On or before December 31 of each year, the Governor's Office of Minority Affairs shall submit to the Board of Public Works and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the Legislative Policy Committee a report summarizing the information the Office receives under subsection (b) of this section.</section></text>
</law>
