<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-8-135</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>135</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "financial institution" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 6-201 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Treasurer may appoint any financial institution as a fiscal agent.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">During its agency, the fiscal agent shall be covered by a surety bond in the form and amount required by law.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In accordance with the procedures that the Treasurer sets, a fiscal agent shall pay at the financial institution, from money advanced to the agent, the interest on State debt and, as the principal matures, the principal.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The fiscal agent shall keep a receipt for each payment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each fiscal agent shall:<section prefix="(1)">allow the Treasurer to inspect the agent's accounts at any time; and</section><section prefix="(2)">provide copies of the accounts on request of:<section prefix="(i)">the Senate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the House of Delegates;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Comptroller; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Treasurer.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">At least once every 6 months, each fiscal agent shall send to the Treasurer:<section prefix="(1)">an accounting of the State bonds and coupons that the agent has redeemed since the last accounting or transmittal under this subsection;</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">a certificate that states the total number of those State bonds and coupons and that attests to the destruction of all of them by a method satisfactory to the Treasurer; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the Treasurer requires, the State bonds and coupons that the agent has redeemed since the last accounting or transmittal under this subsection;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">an accounting of the State bonds and coupons that have not been redeemed during any allowed redemption period that expired since the prior accounting provided under this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the total unredeemed principal and interest on any State bonds and coupons for which the redemption period has expired since the prior accounting provided under this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Treasurer shall examine, count, and record each State bond and coupon that a fiscal agent returns.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Once every 2 years, after the Legislative Auditor verifies the records of the Treasurer, the Comptroller and the Treasurer or their deputies shall destroy all State bonds and coupons that the fiscal agents returned before the close of the last fiscal year.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The State bonds and coupons shall be destroyed in the presence of the Legislative Auditor or a designee of the Auditor.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Comptroller, Treasurer, and Legislative Auditor shall execute a certificate that states the total number of State bonds and coupons destroyed and that attests to the destruction of all of them.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Treasurer shall:<section prefix="(1)">keep all certificates of destruction; and</section><section prefix="(2)">send copies of each certificate to the presiding officers of the General Assembly.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Treasurer shall:<section prefix="(1)">deposit unredeemed principal and interest into an unpresented bond and coupon account; and</section><section prefix="(2)">dispose of unredeemed principal and interest as provided in Title 17 of the Commercial Law Article.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
