<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-2-207</section_number>
  <catch_line>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL JUNE 30, 2020 PER CHAPTER 621 OF 2006 //...</catch_line>
  <order_by>207</order_by>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL JUNE 30, 2020 PER CHAPTER 621 OF 2006 //<section prefix="(a)"><section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section><section prefix="(2)">"Agriculture" means the commercial production, storage, processing, marketing, distribution, or export of an agronomic, aquacultural, equine, floricultural, horticultural, ornamental, silvicultural, or viticultural crop, including:<section prefix="(i)">farm products;</section><section prefix="(ii)">livestock and livestock products;</section><section prefix="(iii)">poultry and poultry products;</section><section prefix="(iv)">milk and dairy products;</section><section prefix="(v)">timber and forest products;</section><section prefix="(vi)">fruit and horticultural products; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">seafood and aquacultural products.</section></section><section prefix="(3)">"Board" means the Maryland Agricultural Education and Rural Development Assistance Board established under &#xA7; 2-206(e) of this subtitle.</section><section prefix="(4)">"Council" means the Rural Maryland Council established under Title 13, Subtitle 4 of the Economic Development Article.</section><section prefix="(5)">"Fund" means the Rural Maryland Prosperity Investment Fund established under this section.</section><section prefix="(6)">"Regional councils" means:<section prefix="(i)">the Mid-Shore Regional Council;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Lower Eastern Shore Regional Council;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Tri-County Council for Southern Maryland;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Tri-County Council for Western Maryland; and</section><section prefix="(v)">the Upper Shore Regional Council.</section></section><section prefix="(7)">"Rural area" means:<section prefix="(i)">the following counties:<section prefix="1.">Allegany;</section><section prefix="2.">Calvert;</section><section prefix="3.">Caroline;</section><section prefix="4.">Carroll;</section><section prefix="5.">Cecil;</section><section prefix="6.">Charles;</section><section prefix="7.">Dorchester;</section><section prefix="8.">Frederick;</section><section prefix="9.">Garrett;</section><section prefix="10.">Harford;</section><section prefix="11.">Kent;</section><section prefix="12.">Queen Anne's;</section><section prefix="13.">St. Mary's;</section><section prefix="14.">Somerset;</section><section prefix="15.">Talbot;</section><section prefix="16.">Washington;</section><section prefix="17.">Wicomico; and</section><section prefix="18.">Worcester; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">portions of other counties in close proximity to agricultural activity.</section></section><section prefix="(8)">"Rural community" means an incorporated or unincorporated area of a county or group of counties in a rural area.</section></section><section prefix="(b)">The General Assembly finds that:<section prefix="(1)">many rural communities in the State face a host of difficult challenges relating to persistent unemployment and poverty, changing technological and economic conditions, an aging population and an out-migration of youth, inadequate access to quality housing, health care and other services, and deteriorating or inadequate transportation, communications, sanitation, and economic development infrastructure;</section><section prefix="(2)">Maryland's agricultural and resource-based industries continue to underpin the local economies of rural communities but are increasingly under threat from national and international market competition, urban encroachment and land development pressure, and environmental and regulatory influences;</section><section prefix="(3)">local governments, regional organizations, educational institutions, and private sector service providers have been unable to meet all the economic development, community development, and human services needs of Maryland residents in the rural counties and municipal corporations because of a lack of adequate available capacity and resources;</section><section prefix="(4)">the objective of the Rural Maryland Prosperity Investment Fund is to help raise the overall standard of living in rural areas to a level that meets or exceeds statewide benchmark averages by 2020, while preserving the best aspects of a pastoral heritage and rural way of life;</section><section prefix="(5)">resources provided to the Fund are designed to facilitate significant targeted investments in important economic and community development programs and promote regional and intergovernmental cooperation;</section><section prefix="(6)">these investments will also enable local and regional public and nonprofit organizations to leverage additional nonstate financial and human resources to facilitate the realization of sustainable rural development objectives while the program is in effect; and</section><section prefix="(7)">the Fund will serve the interests of the entire State by:<section prefix="(i)">encouraging the increase of entrepreneurial activity and commerce and a balanced economy in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">relieving conditions of unemployment and underemployment in rural areas;</section><section prefix="(iii)">assisting in the retention of valuable farm and forest land for productive use by present and future generations;</section><section prefix="(iv)">promoting intergovernmental cooperation and public sector/private sector partnerships in and between rural and other areas;</section><section prefix="(v)">enhancing the deployment of housing, transportation, water, wastewater, and broadband communications infrastructure and services in rural areas;</section><section prefix="(vi)">supporting rural commercial center redevelopment and community revitalization efforts; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">generally promoting the health, happiness, safety, employment opportunity, and general welfare of the residents of each of the rural counties and municipal corporations of the State.</section></section></section><section prefix="(c)"><section prefix="(1)">There is a Rural Maryland Prosperity Investment Fund.</section><section prefix="(2)">The Fund is administered by the Rural Maryland Council with the assistance of the Board.</section><section prefix="(3)">The purpose of the Fund is to provide funding to rural regional and statewide planning and development organizations, institutions of higher education serving rural communities, rural community development organizations, and local governments acting in partnership with one another to promote the quality of life in rural areas.</section></section><section prefix="(d)">Each year, beginning in fiscal year 2008 and continuing through fiscal year 2020, the Governor may include an appropriation in the budget bill for the Fund.</section><section prefix="(e)"><section prefix="(1)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to reversion under &#xA7; 7-302 of this article.</section><section prefix="(2)">The Treasurer shall separately hold and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section><section prefix="(3)">The Treasurer may invest money in the Fund in the same manner as other State money may be invested.</section></section><section prefix="(f)">Disbursements of money appropriated to the Fund shall be allocated equally among the following categories:<section prefix="(1)">rural regional planning and development assistance, by targeting support to the:<section prefix="(i)">regional councils serving rural areas; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">multicounty efforts serving rural communities in areas not served by the regional councils;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">regional infrastructure projects that directly involve two or more units of local government, not to exceed one-fourth of the total cost of any particular project;</section><section prefix="(3)">rural entrepreneurship development, including programs and activities serving rural communities undertaken by nonprofit organizations and institutions of higher education; and</section><section prefix="(4)">rural community development, programmatic assistance, and education, with money to be divided equally between the Council and the Maryland Agricultural Education and Rural Development Assistance Fund.</section></section><section prefix="(g)"><section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Board shall award grants from the Fund on a competitive basis in accordance with the procedures in &#xA7; 2-206(e) of this subtitle.</section><section prefix="(2)">Any money received by the Council under subsection (f) of this section shall be used to help administer the Fund and perform other functions that benefit rural areas as the Council determines.</section><section prefix="(3)">A grant recipient shall submit to the Council written documentation of how the grant recipient spent or otherwise used the grant.</section></section><section prefix="(h)">The Board may reallocate money from one category listed in subsection (f) of this section to another category only if there is a lack of sufficient applications requesting use of money in a particular category.</section><section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="(1)">On or before October 1 of each year, the Council shall submit a report to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly.</section><section prefix="(2)">The report shall summarize the activities of the Fund during the preceding fiscal year, including:<section prefix="(i)">the number of grants made during the fiscal year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the names of the recipients of the grants;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the specific purpose of each grant awarded; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">documentation of how the grant recipient spent or otherwise used the grant.</section></section></section></text>
</law>
