<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-8-123</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>123</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, the Board shall offer State bonds at a public sale.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 10 days before the date of a public sale, the Board shall give public notice of the sale.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice shall state the date, time, and place of the public sale.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, at a public sale, the Board shall sell State bonds for cash to the responsible bidder who:<section prefix="(i)">offers the lowest net interest cost to the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">meets other terms or conditions of sale or issuance that the Board has set.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Whenever the Board determines that no bid is satisfactory and that it is in the best interests of the State to reject all bids, the Board may reject the bids.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By resolution, the Board may postpone the time for receipt of proposals for the bonds without republishing the form of advertisement for the bonds.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Treasurer shall provide notice of the new date and time of sale not less than 24 hours prior to the time proposals are to be submitted, which date may not be more than 30 days after the originally scheduled date of sale.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The notice may be given by Munifacts News Service or a similar service or such other method as the Treasurer deems appropriate.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
