<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-14-308</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person may not:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>308</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not:<section prefix="(i)">fraudulently obtain, hold, or attempt to obtain or hold certification;</section><section prefix="(ii)">aid another person in performing an act prohibited under item (i) of this paragraph;</section><section prefix="(iii)">willfully obstruct, impede, or attempt to obstruct or impede a State official or employee investigating the qualifications of a business entity that has requested certification;</section><section prefix="(iv)">fraudulently obtain, attempt to obtain, or aid another person in fraudulently obtaining or attempting to obtain, public moneys to which the person is not entitled under this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(v)">in any minority business enterprise matter administered under this subtitle:<section prefix="1.">willfully falsify, conceal, or cover up a material fact by any scheme or device;</section><section prefix="2.">make a false or fraudulent statement or representation; or</section><section prefix="3.">use a false writing or document that the person knows to contain a false or fraudulent statement or entry.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided by law, a contractor may not identify a certified minority business enterprise in a bid or proposal and:<section prefix="(i)">fail to request, receive, or otherwise obtain authorization from the certified minority business enterprise to identify the certified minority business enterprise in its bid or proposal;</section><section prefix="(ii)">fail to notify the certified minority business enterprise before execution of the contract of its inclusion of the bid or proposal;</section><section prefix="(iii)">fail to use the certified minority business enterprise in the performance of the contract; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">pay the certified minority business enterprise solely for the use of its name in the bid or proposal.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">	A person who violates any provision of this subsection is guilty of a felony and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $20,000 or imprisonment not exceeding 5 years or both.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not make a false statement about whether an entity has certification.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who violates this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $2,500 or imprisonment not exceeding 1 year or both.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Governor's Office of Minority Affairs shall make available a fraud hotline for reporting violations of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
