<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-5A-326</section_number>
  <catch_line>In cooperation with the Trust and subject to available resources, each State unit shall:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>326</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In cooperation with the Trust and subject to available resources, each State unit shall:<section prefix="(1)">establish a program to identify, document, and nominate to the Trust each property owned or controlled by the State unit that appears to qualify for the Historic Register;</section><section prefix="(2)">ensure that no property listed in or eligible to be listed in the Historic Register is inadvertently transferred, sold, demolished, destroyed, substantially altered, or allowed to deteriorate significantly; and</section><section prefix="(3)">use any available historic building under its control to the extent prudent and practicable before acquiring, constructing, or leasing a building to carry out its responsibilities.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If it is prudent, practicable, and in the State's best interest to do so, a State unit that transfers a surplus property listed in or eligible to be listed in the Historic Register shall ensure that the transfer provides for the preservation or enhancement of the property.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a historic property is to be altered substantially or destroyed by State action or with financial assistance from a State unit, the State unit shall cause timely steps to be taken to:<section prefix="(1)">make appropriate investigations and records;</section><section prefix="(2)">salvage appropriate objects and materials; and</section><section prefix="(3)">deposit with the Trust the results of the investigations, the records, and the recovered objects and materials.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A State unit that issues permits or licenses or provides financial assistance shall cooperate with the Trust by:<section prefix="(1)">giving notice to the Trust, on request, of each application for a permit, a license, or financial assistance; and</section><section prefix="(2)">requiring that, where appropriate, an applicant for a permit, a license, or financial assistance consult with the Trust before the State unit takes final action on the application.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After consulting with the Trust, and to avoid, mitigate, or satisfactorily reduce any significant adverse effect on a property listed in or eligible to be listed in the Historic Register, a State unit may put reasonable conditions on a license, permit, or award of financial assistance.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A State unit may seek guidance from the Council before imposing conditions on a license, permit, or award of financial assistance.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A person may appeal the reasonableness of a condition imposed on a license or permit in accordance with the Administrative Procedure Act.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">By regulation, the Trust shall establish professional standards, guidelines, and procedures to preserve historic properties owned, controlled, regulated, or assisted by State units, to minimize the need for Trust review, and to avoid duplication and delays.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">This section may be applied to any undertaking that is subject to the National Historic Preservation Act, 16 U.S.C. &#xA7; 470f.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Failure by a State unit to comply with this section does not create a private cause of action under State law.</section>
  </text>
</law>
