<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-110" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-13-110</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Cooperative entity" means one or more State or local entities that enter into an agreement for the cooperative or joint administration of programs.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Governmental entity" means:<section prefix="(i)">the federal government or an agency or other instrumentality of the federal government;</section><section prefix="(ii)">another state or an agency or other instrumentality of another state;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a bistate or multistate agency;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a county, municipal corporation, or other political subdivision of the State or of another state, or an agency or other instrumentality of the political subdivision;</section><section prefix="(v)">a bicounty or multicounty agency;</section><section prefix="(vi)">a primary procurement unit; or</section><section prefix="(vii)">an affiliation, alliance, consortium, or group composed solely of governmental entities that is established for purposes of promoting intergovernmental cooperative purchasing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Intergovernmental cooperative purchasing agreement" means a contract:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">between a primary procurement unit and a person who, at the time the intergovernmental cooperative purchasing agreement is awarded, has a contract with the federal government or an agency or other instrumentality of the federal government, and who agrees to provide the unit with identical prices, terms, and conditions as stipulated in the federal contract.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Local entity" means a county, municipal corporation, bicounty or multicounty agency, public authority, special taxing district, or other political subdivision or unit of a political subdivision of this State.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Local entity" includes boards of education and library boards that receive funding from the State.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Not-for-profit entity" means a corporation incorporated in the State, or otherwise qualified to do business in the State that has been determined by the Internal Revenue Service to be exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 501(c)(3), (4), or (6) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"State entity" means a department, board, commission, agency, or a subunit in the Executive branch of State government.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to &#xA7; 12-107 of this article, whenever a primary procurement unit procurement officer determines that it is in the best interest of the State to sponsor or participate in an intergovernmental cooperative purchasing agreement, with the approval of the unit head and subject to any other approval required by law, the primary procurement unit may become a party to or participate under the agreement.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A determination under this subsection shall be in writing and include a statement that the intergovernmental cooperative purchasing agreement:<section prefix="(i)">will provide cost benefits to the State, promote administrative efficiencies, or promote intergovernmental cooperation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is not intended to evade the purposes of this Division II.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a primary procurement unit sponsors an intergovernmental cooperative purchasing agreement:<section prefix="(i)">the contract shall be awarded in the same manner as the contract would be awarded under this Division II if the unit was the sole participant under the contract; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">all procedures under this Division II, including procedures governing contract claims and protests, shall apply.			</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If a primary procurement unit participates in an intergovernmental cooperative purchasing agreement, any protest or contract claim involving the agreement shall be handled in accordance with the terms of the agreement.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, each procurement contract for supplies or services entered into by a State or local entity shall include a provision that facilitates other State and local entities and not-for-profit entities to participate in the contract.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This subsection does not apply to:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">This subsection does not apply if the State or local entity determines that including the provision would:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A State or local entity may enter into an agreement for the cooperative or joint administration of programs with one or more other State or local entities.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A cooperative entity established under this section may administer the programs and exercise the powers and duties specifically delegated to the cooperative entity by the agreement that established the cooperative entity.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An agreement described under this subsection does not relieve a State or local entity or other participant of the agreement from any obligation or responsibility imposed on the entity by law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Notwithstanding any other law, a local entity may participate in an existing State or local contract drafted in accordance with this section, if the governing body of the entity determines that participation would:<section prefix="(1)">provide a cost savings in purchase price or administrative burden; or</section><section prefix="(2)">further other policy goals including operational and energy-efficiency goals related to the purchase, operation, or maintenance of the supply or service.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
