<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-5A-327</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>327</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"MHT Loan Fund" means the Historic Preservation Loan Fund of the Trust.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"MHT Loan Program" means the Historic Preservation Loan Program of the Trust.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is an MHT Loan Program in the Trust.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The purpose of the MHT Loan Program is to implement and encourage the preservation of historic properties.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Trust shall administer the MHT Loan Program and coordinate the MHT Loan Program with federal and State programs that complement or facilitate carrying out the MHT Loan Program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">There is an MHT Loan Fund in the Trust.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The MHT Loan Fund may be used:<section prefix="(1)">to pay administrative costs directly related to the MHT Loan Program;</section><section prefix="(2)">to pay for the Trust to acquire historic properties or interests in historic properties for its authorized purposes or for resale or lease subject to appropriate preservation covenants;</section><section prefix="(3)">to pay costs, including preparation costs, to restore or rehabilitate historic properties owned by the Trust for:<section prefix="(i)">the Trust's authorized purposes; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">resale or lease subject to appropriate preservation covenants; or</section></section><section prefix="(4)">to make loans to nonprofit organizations, political subdivisions, business entities, and individuals to:<section prefix="(i)">acquire, rehabilitate, restore, or refinance historic properties; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">provide short-term financing for costs, including preparation costs, directly related to work that the Trust or the State Historic Preservation Officer requires or recommends to be undertaken before a construction project financed with federal or State money is begun or continued.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The MHT Loan Fund is a continuing, nonlapsing special fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Treasurer shall hold and the Comptroller shall account for the MHT Loan Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The MHT Loan Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">money appropriated in the State budget to the MHT Loan Program;</section><section prefix="(2)">money received as interest or repayment of principal on loans made under the MHT Loan Program or the Capital Revolving Fund for Historic Preservation;</section><section prefix="(3)">the proceeds from the resale or lease of property originally acquired by the Trust with money from the MHT Loan Fund or the Capital Revolving Fund for Historic Preservation;</section><section prefix="(4)">money received from other public or private sources for the benefit of the MHT Loan Fund; and</section><section prefix="(5)">money received from the sale of general obligation bonds.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Money in the MHT Loan Fund shall be invested in the same manner as other State money.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall adopt regulations to carry out the purposes of the MHT Loan Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The regulations shall include:<section prefix="(i)">application procedures;</section><section prefix="(ii)">procedures to give adequate notice to the public of assistance available under the MHT Loan Program;</section><section prefix="(iii)">provisions for the review of plans and specifications;</section><section prefix="(iv)">provisions for the inspection of projects during construction; and</section><section prefix="(v)">selection criteria the Trust must consider in evaluating loan applications, including:<section prefix="1.">the relative historical or cultural significance of, and the urgency of need for, the project to be financed by the loan;</section><section prefix="2.">any proposed contribution by the appropriate political subdivision to the project;</section><section prefix="3.">the geographic distribution of loan assistance from the MHT Loan Fund; and</section><section prefix="4.">other relevant factors.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With the approval of the Secretary, for each loan the Trust may set:<section prefix="(i)">the principal amount;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the maturity;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the repayment terms; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">an interest rate that complies with applicable federal regulations governing State borrowing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A loan from the MHT Loan Fund may be granted at an interest rate lower than rates on other loans from the MHT Loan Fund if:<section prefix="(i)">the loan recipient is a nonprofit organization or a political subdivision; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Secretary of Housing and Community Development determines under &#xA7; 4-212 of the Housing and Community Development Article that after restoration or rehabilitation, the historic property will be wholly or partly occupied by individuals or families of limited income.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A loan from the MHT Loan Program may be secured by:<section prefix="(i)">a mortgage lien, which may be subordinate to other mortgage liens;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a guarantee of repayment; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">another form of collateral acceptable to the Trust.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Without approval or execution by the Board of Public Works, the Trust may take title to a mortgaged property by foreclosure or by deed in lieu of foreclosure and:<section prefix="(i)">convey title to a buyer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">obtain and seek enforcement of a deficiency judgment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">An individual or business entity may receive a loan only if the recipient can document that private financing is unavailable.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Trust shall ensure that no loan is made under the MHT Loan Program to acquire, restore, or rehabilitate a historic property unless the historic property is listed in or eligible to be listed in the Historic Register.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Trust shall require the recipient of a loan from the MHT Loan Program to enter into an agreement to preserve and maintain the property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the property is real property, the agreement shall be a recordable historic preservation easement.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary may waive the agreement requirement if the Secretary finds that an agreement is impracticable.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The trustees shall review and make recommendations to the Secretary about loans and expenditures from the MHT Loan Fund, and the Secretary shall approve each loan and expenditure from the MHT Loan Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To the extent required by regulations adopted by the Secretary and approved by the Board of Public Works, the Secretary shall submit to the Board of Public Works for approval a proposed loan or expenditure from the MHT Loan Fund that will be financed through the sale of State general obligation bonds.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except for an expenditure under subsection (d)(2) or (3) of this section, a loan or expenditure from the MHT Loan Fund is not subject to Titles 4 and 5 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">On or before December 31 of each year, the Trust shall report to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly on the financial status and the activities of the MHT Loan Program for the preceding fiscal year.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not knowingly make or cause to be made a material false statement of fact, including an understatement or overstatement of financial condition, in a statement or report in or regarding an application for a loan or affecting an existing loan.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who violates this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 2 years or a fine not exceeding $5,000 or both.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
