<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-5-814</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Commission consists of the following 34 voting members appointed by the Governor:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>814</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission consists of the following 34 voting members appointed by the Governor:<section prefix="(1)">7 individuals, 1 from each of the following 7 counties, on the recommendation of the governing body of that county:<section prefix="(i)">Anne Arundel County;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Calvert County;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Charles County;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Howard County;</section><section prefix="(v)">Montgomery County;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Prince George's County; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">St. Mary's County;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">1 individual representing the Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission;</section><section prefix="(3)">1 individual from each of the following regional planning agencies:<section prefix="(i)">the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission, Montgomery County;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission, Prince George's County; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Tri-County Council for Southern Maryland;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">1 individual, representing a municipality in the watershed, on the recommendation of the corresponding governing body of that municipality;</section><section prefix="(5)">1 individual representing a large federal facility in the watershed;</section><section prefix="(6)">as far as possible, the following individuals appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate, shall be selected to represent broad geographic, economic, and social interests within the watershed:<section prefix="(i)">2 individuals representing farming interests;</section><section prefix="(ii)">1 individual representing business interests;</section><section prefix="(iii)">4 individuals representing environmental and citizen interests;</section><section prefix="(iv)">2 individuals representing developer interests;</section><section prefix="(v)">2 individuals representing academic interests;</section><section prefix="(vi)">2 individuals, 1 each, representing 2 soil conservation districts;</section><section prefix="(vii)">1 individual representing the University of Maryland Cooperative Extension Service; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">1 individual representing watermen interests; and</section></section><section prefix="(7)">as ex officio members:<section prefix="(i)">the Secretary of Agriculture or a designee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Secretary of the Environment or a designee;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Secretary of Natural Resources or a designee;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Secretary of Planning or a designee;</section><section prefix="(v)">the Secretary of Transportation or a designee; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">the Chief of the Planning Division, U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, Baltimore District or a designee.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for ex officio members or their designees, the term of a member appointed under subsection (a)(1) of this section is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the end of a term, a member appointed under subsection (a)(1) of this section continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member who is appointed under subsection (a)(1) of this section after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The terms of the members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Commission on October 1, 1995.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may establish and abolish nonvoting memberships.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A nonvoting member shall be appointed by the Commission for a term set by the Commission.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
