<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-14-106</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "Committee" means the Pricing and Selection Committee for the Employment Works Prog...</catch_line>
  <order_by>106</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Committee" means the Pricing and Selection Committee for the Employment Works Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Pricing and Selection Committee for the Employment Works Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Committee consists of the following 6 members:<section prefix="(1)">the Secretary of Transportation or a designee;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Secretary of General Services or a designee;</section><section prefix="(3)">the Secretary of Public Safety and Correctional Services or a designee;</section><section prefix="(4)">the President of Blind Industries and Services of Maryland or a designee;</section><section prefix="(5)">the Assistant Secretary for Vocational Rehabilitation within the State Department of Education or a designee; and</section><section prefix="(6)">the Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation or a designee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A member of the Committee:<section prefix="(1)">may not receive compensation; but</section><section prefix="(2)">is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Committee shall:<section prefix="(1)">establish procedures to govern procurement of supplies and services from community service providers and individual with disability owned businesses;</section><section prefix="(2)">from the State procurement list, choose appropriate supplies and services for community service providers and individual with disability owned businesses to offer for procurement;</section><section prefix="(3)">provide that the State procure those supplies and services from a community service provider or an individual with disability owned business;</section><section prefix="(4)">if supplies or services are not available for procurement from a unit of the State government, determine whether supplies or services are available from a community service provider or an individual with disability owned business;</section><section prefix="(5)">determine the fair market price of supplies and services that community service providers and individual with disability owned businesses provide;</section><section prefix="(6)">in accordance with market conditions, adjust prices for the supplies and services that community service providers and individual with disability owned businesses provide; and</section><section prefix="(7)">at the request of a community service provider or an individual with disability owned business, review and, if appropriate, change the price of a supply or service.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In addition to the duties specified under subsection (e) of this section, the Committee shall:<section prefix="(1)">establish and periodically review eligibility policies or guidelines for participating community service providers and individual with disability owned businesses;</section><section prefix="(2)">maintain a current list of community service providers and individual with disability owned businesses;</section><section prefix="(3)">periodically review and revise its list of community service providers and individual with disability owned businesses; and</section><section prefix="(4)">send any revised list to the Secretary of General Services who shall make the list available to each person responsible for buying supplies or services for the State or a State aided or controlled entity.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
