<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-13-221</section_number>
  <catch_line>The provisions of this section are broadly applicable and apply to all contracts, leases, or other a...</catch_line>
  <order_by>221</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The provisions of this section are broadly applicable and apply to all contracts, leases, or other agreements entered into by the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section, "beneficial ownership" means:<section prefix="(i)">any ownership interest of 5% or more in a business;</section><section prefix="(ii)">any ownership interest of 5% or more in 1 or more entities in a chain of parent and subsidiary entities, any 1 of which participates in at least 5% of the capital or profits of a business; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">possession of an interest that exists under an agreement, contract, relationship, understanding, or other arrangement and entitles a person to benefits substantially equivalent to an ownership interest of 5% or more of a business.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In this section, unless there are special circumstances, an individual is deemed to hold an ownership interest that is held by the individual's spouse, the individual's child, or other relative of the individual who lives in the individual's home.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If, during a calendar year, a business enters into contracts, leases, or other agreements, with the State or its units or both, under which the business is to receive from the State or its units or both a total of $100,000 or more, the business shall file with the Secretary of State a list that contains the name and address of:<section prefix="(i)">any resident agent of the business;</section><section prefix="(ii)">each officer of the business; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">if known, each person who has beneficial ownership of the business.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The list shall be filed within 30 days of the date when the total value of the contracts, leases, or other agreements entered into during the calendar year reaches $100,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a person who has beneficial ownership is unknown to the business, it is sufficient for the business to disclose the legal ownership or the identity of the nominee who holds title for the unknown person.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A business or an officer of a business who violates any provision of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $10,000.</section>
  </text>
</law>
