<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-4-504</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>504</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary may dispose of excess personal property and surplus personal property as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whenever feasible, the Secretary shall dispose of excess personal property by transferring it to another unit of the State government.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The unit of the State government that receives the excess personal property shall pay any cost of the transfer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary:<section prefix="(1)">may dispose of any surplus personal property; and</section><section prefix="(2)">shall seek to gain the maximum value for the State in the disposition.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall dispose of surplus personal property:<section prefix="(i)">by dismantling it for recovery of valuable parts;</section><section prefix="(ii)">by trading it in;</section><section prefix="(iii)">by transferring it to a local jurisdiction, public school system, or nonprofit organization;</section><section prefix="(iv)">by auctioning or selling it, including selling it for scrap value; or</section><section prefix="(v)">if no value can be realized from it, by destroying it.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If surplus personal property is destroyed under this subsection, the unit of the State government that declared the item to be excess personal property shall pay any cost of destruction.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Secretary may delegate the authority to dispose of surplus personal property to a designee of the Secretary or, by regulation, to another unit of the State government.</section>
  </text>
</law>
