<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-2-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "block grant" means any federal grant-in-aid that:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "block grant" means any federal grant-in-aid that:<section prefix="(1)">contains consolidated funding for 1 or more programs; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is designated by Congress as a block grant.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">It is the policy of the State that the General Assembly and the Governor should consult before the Executive Branch of the State government adopts State policy on block grants.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section is in addition to and not in derogation of any other power or duty of the General Assembly.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section applies to the adoption of State policy to:<section prefix="(i)">participate in a block grant;</section><section prefix="(ii)">set a date on which the State will accept responsibility for a block grant; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">transfer money between block grants.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Governor shall send, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the Legislative Policy Committee each proposal for the adoption of State policy on a block grant.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Within 60 days after the Legislative Policy Committee receives the proposal or, if the Committee sets a shorter period, within that period, the Committee:<section prefix="(1)">may hold a public hearing on the proposal;</section><section prefix="(2)">may refer the proposal to another committee for review; and</section><section prefix="(3)">for the General Assembly, may send the Governor comments on the proposal.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Governor may act on the proposal only after the expiration of the 60-day period or any shorter period set under subsection (e) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
