<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-3-1003</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1003</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary shall review the strategic plans and the State comprehensive plan and may recommend appropriate changes to agency budgets.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a StateStat process that is managed by the Executive Branch.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">StateStat is an accountability process that involves:<section prefix="(i)">the adoption of a strategic plan and the establishment of goals by an agency;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the adoption of a comprehensive set of performance and citizen satisfaction measurements by an agency;</section><section prefix="(iii)">regular and frequent:<section prefix="1.">submission of timely and accurate data by an agency;</section><section prefix="2.">review and analysis of submitted data; and</section><section prefix="3.">accountability meetings to assess an agency's performance;</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">continuous review of the strategies and tactics used by an agency to meet the goals of the agency; and</section><section prefix="(v)">continuous assessment of the progress of an agency towards meeting the goals of the agency.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Governor may require an agency to participate in the StateStat process to help facilitate and accelerate the achievement of managing for results goals and objectives.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each agency that participates in the StateStat process shall submit a strategic plan and performance measurement report to the Secretary as part of its annual budget submission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The report submitted by each agency that participates in the StateStat process shall contain the information required in &#xA7; 3-1002(c) of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
