<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-310" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-5-310</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each unit of the State government shall notify the Department in writing of:<section prefix="(1)">any real property that is in excess of the needs of the unit; or</section><section prefix="(2)">any substantial change to any real property owned by the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to subsection (c) of this section, for any real property identified under subsection (a) of this section, the Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">study the proper disposition of the property;</section><section prefix="(2)">determine whether any local government or unit of the State government is interested in the property; and</section><section prefix="(3)">make an appropriate recommendation to the using unit of the State government and to the Board of Public Works.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, this subsection applies to the following categories of real property owned by the State in fee simple:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">This subsection does not apply to property declared excess for purposes of corrective disposal, including boundary or access corrections and minor road improvements for public safety.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When a unit notifies the Department under subsection (a) of this section, the unit shall include with the notification:<section prefix="(i)">the history of the acquisition of the property;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the rationale for the acquisition provided to the Board of Public Works at the time of the acquisition;</section><section prefix="(iii)">any future conservation plans for the property;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the environmental and ecological attributes of the property;</section><section prefix="(v)">the cultural and historical significance of the property;</section><section prefix="(vi)">the relationship of the property to surrounding and nearby real properties;</section><section prefix="(vii)">the actual cost savings, if any, that the unit anticipates will result from the disposal of the property;</section><section prefix="(viii)">any expected revenues that would be generated from the disposal of the property; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">any other justification or basis that the unit relied on in its determination that the property is in excess of its needs.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The information provided under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be made available by the unit or the Department on request.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">After the Department receives notice from a unit under subsection (a) of this section, the Department shall:<section prefix="(i)">notify:</section><section prefix="(ii)"/><section prefix="(iii)">in conjunction with the local governing body of the jurisdiction in which the property is located, determine whether any proposed disposition would conform to the local comprehensive plan; and</section><section prefix="(iv)"/></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">After review of the record created under paragraph (4) of this subsection, the using unit may rescind the notice of excess property submitted under subsection (a) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">If the using unit does not rescind the notice of excess property, the Department shall:<section prefix="(i)">based on all of the information collected by the Department, make an appropriate recommendation to the using unit and the Board of Public Works; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">notify the persons identified under paragraph (4)(i)1 and 2 of this subsection of the recommendation.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
