<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-317" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-7-317</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Cigarette Restitution Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund is a continuing, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7;  7-302 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">There shall be credited to the Fund all revenues consisting of funds  received by the State from any source resulting, directly or indirectly, from any  judgment against or settlement with tobacco product manufacturers, tobacco research  associations, or any other person in the tobacco industry relating to litigation,  administrative proceedings, or any other claims made or prosecuted by the State to  recover damages for violations of State law.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">There shall be credited to the Fund all moneys  collected under &#xA7; 24-508 of the Health - General Article or &#xA7; 5-608  of the Labor and Employment Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Treasurer shall:<section prefix="(1)">invest and reinvest the Fund in the same manner as other State funds; and</section><section prefix="(2)">credit any investment earnings to the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Expenditures from the Fund shall be made by an appropriation in the annual State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund shall be expended subject to any restrictions on its use or other limitations on its allocation that are:<section prefix="(i)">expressly provided by statute;</section><section prefix="(ii)">required as a condition of the acceptance of funds; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">determined to be necessary to avoid recoupment by the federal government of money paid to the Fund.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Disbursements from the Fund to programs funded by the State or with federal funds administered by the State shall be used solely to supplement, and not to supplant, funds otherwise available for the programs under federal or State law as provided in this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Cigarette Restitution Fund shall be used to fund:<section prefix="(i)">the Tobacco Use Prevention and Cessation Program established under Title 13, Subtitle 10 of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Cancer Prevention, Education, Screening, and Treatment Program established under Title 13, Subtitle 11 of the Health - General Article; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">other programs that serve the following purposes:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The provisions of this subsection may not be construed to affect the Governor's powers with respect to a request for an appropriation in the annual budget bill.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Amounts may only be expended from the Fund through appropriations in the State budget bill as provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Governor shall include in the annual budget bill appropriations from the Fund equivalent to the lesser of $100,000,000 or 90% of the funds estimated to be available to the Fund in the fiscal year for which the appropriations are made.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For each fiscal year for which appropriations are made, at least 50% of the appropriations shall be made for those purposes enumerated in subsection (f)(1)(i), (ii), and (iii)1 through 9 of this section subject to the requirement of subsection (e)(2) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">For each fiscal year for which appropriations are made, at least 30% of the appropriations shall be made for the purposes of the Maryland Medical Assistance Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">For each fiscal year for which appropriations are made, 0.15% of the Fund shall be appropriated for the purposes of enforcement of Title 16, Subtitle 5 of the Business Regulation Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Any additional appropriations, not subject to paragraph (3), paragraph (4), or paragraph (5) of this subsection, may be made for any lawful purpose.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">For each program, project or activity receiving funds appropriated under subsection (g)(3) of this section, the Governor shall:<section prefix="(1)">develop appropriate statements of vision, mission, key goals, key objectives, and key performance indicators and report these statements in a discrete part of the State budget submission, which shall also provide data for key performance indicators; and</section><section prefix="(2)">report annually, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly no later than October 1 on:<section prefix="(i)">total funds expended, by program and subdivision, in the prior fiscal year from the Fund established under this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the specific outcomes or public benefits resulting from that expenditure.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
