<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-13-222</section_number>
  <catch_line>For a State procurement contract for $10,000 or more, except as provided in subsection (c) of this s...</catch_line>
  <order_by>222</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">For a State procurement contract for $10,000 or more, except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, at the time a bid or proposal for any State procurement contract is submitted, the bidder or offeror shall certify to the procurement officer that:<section prefix="(1)">the bidder or offeror has paid all taxes, unemployment insurance contributions, reimbursement payments, and interest not barred by limitations and payable to the Comptroller, the Department of Assessments and Taxation, or the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation or has provided for payment in a manner satisfactory to the unit responsible for collection; and</section><section prefix="(2)">if the bidder or offeror is a vendor of tangible personal property, the bidder or offeror possesses a valid sales and use tax license under Title 11, Subtitle 7 of the Tax - General Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Before a unit awards any procurement contract for $100,000 or more, the unit shall verify through the Office of the Comptroller:<section prefix="(1)">that all taxes, unemployment insurance contributions, reimbursement payments, and interest not barred by limitations and payable by the contractor to the Comptroller, the Department of Assessments and Taxation, and the Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation are paid or that payment has been provided for in a manner satisfactory to the unit responsible for collection; and</section><section prefix="(2)">if the contractor is a vendor of tangible personal property, that the contractor possesses a valid sales and use tax license under Title 11, Subtitle 7 of the Tax - General Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board may waive the requirements of this section if the Board determines that:<section prefix="(1)">the procurement is essential or in the best interests of the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">there is no other known source for the procurement at a reasonable cost.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In any solicitation, a unit shall provide notice of the requirements of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
