<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-3-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Central Collection Unit in the Department....</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Central Collection Unit in the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">All employees and personnel of the Central Collection Unit shall:<section prefix="(i)">except for assistant Attorneys General assigned to the Central Collection Unit, be in the management service or special appointments in the State Personnel Management System who are appointed by and serve at the pleasure of the Secretary and are not subject to Title 11, Subtitle 2 of the State Personnel and Pensions Article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">receive such compensation as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except for employees in the Executive Pay Plan and any assistant Attorneys General assigned to the Central Collection Unit, a management service or special appointment of the skilled service or the professional service employee of the Central Collection Unit may not be permanently removed except for cause and until written charges have been filed and a hearing has been conducted in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article. This paragraph does not apply to the removal of a management service or special appointment employee because of a layoff that resulted from:<section prefix="(i)">a lack of work; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the lack of an appropriation.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary of Budget and Management may establish a performance incentive program to provide pay incentives for employees of the Central Collection Unit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Pay incentives provided to employees under this subsection shall be paid from the Central Collection Fund established under &#xA7; 3-306 of this subtitle as provided in the State budget.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Pay incentives may not be provided under this subsection if:<section prefix="(i)">the Central Collection Unit sustains an operating loss for the fiscal year in which the pay incentives were earned; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">funds are not available in the Central Collection Fund to pay the incentives.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
