<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-3A-309</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>309</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Major Information Technology Development Project Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The purpose of the Fund is to support major information technology development projects.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary:<section prefix="(1)">shall administer the Fund in accordance with this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">subject to the provisions of &#xA7; 2-201 of this article and &#xA7; 3A-307 of this subtitle, may receive and accept contributions, grants, or gifts of money or property.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Treasurer shall hold the Fund separately and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The State Treasurer shall invest and reinvest the money of the Fund in the same manner as other State money may be invested.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Any investment earnings of the Fund shall be paid into the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except as provided in subsection (f) of this section, the Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">money appropriated in the State budget to the Fund;</section><section prefix="(2)">money received from the sale, lease, or exchange of communication sites or communication frequencies for information technology purposes as approved by the Secretary;</section><section prefix="(3)">that portion of moneys earned from pay phone commissions to the extent that the commission rates exceed those in effect in December 1993;</section><section prefix="(4)">money received and accepted as contributions, grants, or gifts as authorized under subsection (c) of this section;</section><section prefix="(5)">general funds appropriated for major information technology development projects of any unit of State government other than a public institution of higher education that:<section prefix="(i)">are unencumbered and unexpended at the end of a fiscal year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">have been abandoned; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">have been withheld by the General Assembly or the Secretary;</section></section><section prefix="(6)">any investment earnings; and</section><section prefix="(7)">any other money from any source accepted for the benefit of the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Fund does not include any money:<section prefix="(1)">received by the Department of Transportation, Maryland Transportation Authority, or Maryland Public Broadcasting Commission;</section><section prefix="(2)">received by the Judicial or Legislative branches of State government; or</section><section prefix="(3)">generated from pay phone commissions that are credited to other accounts or funds in accordance with other provisions of law or are authorized for other purposes in the State budget or through an approved budget amendment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Governor shall submit with the State budget:<section prefix="(1)">a summary showing the unencumbered balance in the Fund as of the close of the prior fiscal year and a listing of any encumbrances;</section><section prefix="(2)">an estimate of projected revenue from each of the sources specified in subsection (e) of this section for the fiscal year for which the State budget is submitted; and</section><section prefix="(3)">a descriptive listing of projects reflecting projected costs for the fiscal year for which the State budget is submitted and any estimated future year costs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Expenditures from the Fund shall be made only:<section prefix="(1)">in accordance with an appropriation approved by the General Assembly in the annual State budget; or</section><section prefix="(2)">through an approved State budget amendment under Title 7, Subtitle 2, Part II of this article, provided that a State budget amendment for any project not requested as part of the State budget submission or for any project for which the scope or cost has increased by more than 5% or $250,000 shall be submitted to the budget committees allowing a 30-day period for their review and comment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Fund may be used:<section prefix="(1)">for major information technology development projects;</section><section prefix="(2)">as provided in subsection (j) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(3)">notwithstanding &#xA7; 3A-301(b)(2) of this subtitle, for the costs of the first 12 months of operation and maintenance of a major information technology development project.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">Notwithstanding subsection (b) of this section and except for the cost incurred in administering the Fund, each fiscal year up to $1,000,000 of this Fund may be used for:<section prefix="(1)">educationally related information technology projects;</section><section prefix="(2)">application service provider initiatives as provided for in Title 9, Subtitle 22 of the State Government Article; or</section><section prefix="(3)">information technology projects, including:<section prefix="(i)">pilots; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">prototypes.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">A unit of State government or local government may submit a request to the Secretary to support the cost of an information technology project with moneys under subsection (j) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before November 1 of each year, the Secretary shall report to the Governor, the Secretary of Budget and Management, and to the budget committees of the General Assembly and submit a copy of the report to the General Assembly, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The report shall include:<section prefix="(i)">the financial status of the Fund and a summary of its operations for the preceding fiscal year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an accounting for the preceding fiscal year of all moneys from each of the revenue sources specified in subsection (e) of this section, including any expenditures made from the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">for each project receiving moneys from the Fund in the preceding fiscal year and for each major information technology development project receiving funding from any source other than the Fund in the preceding fiscal year:<section prefix="1.">the status of the project;</section><section prefix="2.">a comparison of estimated and actual costs of the project;</section><section prefix="3.">any known or anticipated changes in scope or costs of the project;</section><section prefix="4.">an evaluation of whether the project is using best practices; and</section><section prefix="5.">a summary of any monitoring and oversight of the project from outside the agency in which the project is being developed, including a description of any problems identified by any external review and any corrective actions taken.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">On or before January 15 of each year, for each major information technology development project currently in development or for which operations and maintenance funding is being provided in accordance with subsection (i)(3) of this section, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the Secretary shall provide a summary report to the Department of Legislative Services with the most up-to-date project information including:<section prefix="(1)">project status;</section><section prefix="(2)">any schedule, cost, and scope changes since the last annual report;</section><section prefix="(3)">a risk assessment including any problems identified by any internal or external review and any corrective actions taken; and</section><section prefix="(4)">any change in the monitoring or oversight status.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
