<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-211" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-6-211</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL SEPTEMBER 30, 2021 PER CHAPTER 396 OF 2006 AND CHAPTER 740 OF 2009 //<section prefix="(a)"><section prefix="(1)">There is a Linked Deposit Program in the Department of Housing and Community Development.</section><section prefix="(2)">The purpose of the Linked Deposit Program is to stimulate opportunities for minority business enterprises to have access to credit by assisting these businesses in obtaining loans at lower than market interest rates.</section></section><section prefix="(b)">A loan qualifies under the Linked Deposit Program if the loan:<section prefix="(1)">satisfies the financial institution's lending criteria;</section><section prefix="(2)">has a term not exceeding 10 years;</section><section prefix="(3)">is made to a minority business enterprise certified under Title 14, Subtitle 3 of this article;</section><section prefix="(4)">has an interest rate that is 2 percentage points below the interest rate the financial institution would charge for a loan for a similar purpose and a similar term; and</section><section prefix="(5)">has points or fees charged at loan closing not exceeding 1 percent of the loan amount.</section></section><section prefix="(c)">The Department of Housing and Community Development shall:<section prefix="(1)">confirm with the certification agency designated under Title 14, Subtitle 3 of this article that each loan under the Linked Deposit Program is made to a business that is certified as a minority business enterprise;</section><section prefix="(2)">establish procedures for notification by the certification agency designated under Title 14, Subtitle 3 of this article if a business that has an outstanding balance of a loan under the Linked Deposit Program is no longer certified;</section><section prefix="(3)">require minority business enterprises and lenders to notify the Department concerning final loan disposition; and</section><section prefix="(4)">report annually to the Governor, the Treasurer, and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly on overall performance of the Linked Deposit Program.</section></section><section prefix="(d)">The Treasurer may establish the Linked Deposit Program for investment of deposits in any financial institution that:<section prefix="(1)">the Treasurer has designated as a depository for State money; and</section><section prefix="(2)">makes a loan in accordance with subsection (b) of this section.</section></section><section prefix="(e)"><section prefix="(1)">The Treasurer may make one or more interest bearing deposits that are equal to:<section prefix="(i)">the amount of the loan made by the financial institution in accordance with subsection (b) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the aggregate amount of two or more loans made by one or more financial institutions in accordance with subsection (b) of this section.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">In making an interest bearing deposit under this subsection, the Treasurer may accept a rate that is 2 percentage points below current market rates or an index selected by the Treasurer.</section><section prefix="(3)">The Treasurer may use up to $50,000,000 to make interest bearing deposits in an amount equivalent to the amount financial institutions loan to certified minority business enterprises.</section></section><section prefix="(f)"><section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, on notification by the Department of Housing and Community Development that a minority business enterprise participating in the Linked Deposit Program is no longer certified under Title 14, Subtitle 3 of this article, the Treasurer shall reduce the amount of the interest bearing deposit with the participating financial institution by the outstanding balance of the loan made under this section to the decertified minority business enterprise.</section><section prefix="(2)">A minority business enterprise that loses its certification due to revenue or employee growth may not be considered decertified for purposes of paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section></section><section prefix="(g)"><section prefix="(1)">A loan assisted by a linked deposit is not a debt of the State or a pledge of the credit of the State.</section><section prefix="(2)">The Treasurer and the State are not liable to any financial institution for payment of the principal or interest on a loan assisted by a linked deposit.</section></section><section prefix="(h)">The Department of Housing and Community Development and the Treasurer may adopt regulations to carry out this section.</section></text>
</law>
