<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-218" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-15-218</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided under &#xA7; 15-219 of this subtitle, a procurement officer who receives a protest or a contract claim from a contractor shall comply with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On receipt of a protest or contract claim from a contractor, a procurement officer:<section prefix="(i)">shall review the substance of the protest or contract claim;</section><section prefix="(ii)">may request additional information or substantiation through an appropriate procedure;</section><section prefix="(iii)">may discuss with interested parties and, if appropriate, may conduct negotiations with the person initiating the protest or contract claim; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">shall comply with any applicable regulations.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless clearly inappropriate, the procurement officer shall seek the advice of the Office of the Attorney General.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to subsection (b) of this section and consistent with the State budget and other applicable laws, the procurement officer shall:<section prefix="(i)">resolve the protest or contract claim by agreement of the parties;</section><section prefix="(ii)">wholly or partly deny the protest or contract claim; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">wholly or partly grant the relief sought by the person who submitted the protest or contract claim.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The procurement officer promptly shall send the decision in writing to the reviewing authority.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Unless otherwise provided by regulation, the decision of the procurement officer shall be reviewed promptly by:<section prefix="(1)">the head of the unit; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the head of the principal department or other equivalent unit of which the unit is a part.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided under paragraph (3) of this subsection, the reviewing authority shall approve, disapprove, or modify the decision of the procurement officer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The action of the reviewing authority under this subsection shall be the final action of the unit.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The reviewing authority may remand the proceeding with instructions to the procurement officer.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On remand, the procurement officer shall proceed under subsection (b) of this section in accordance with those instructions.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
