<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-6-222</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>222</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Treasurer may invest or reinvest unexpended or surplus money over which the Treasurer has custody in:<section prefix="(1)">an obligation for which the United States has pledged its faith and credit for the payment of the principal and interest;</section><section prefix="(2)">an obligation that a federal agency or a federal instrumentality has issued in accordance with an act of Congress;</section><section prefix="(3)">a repurchase agreement collateralized in an amount not less than 102% of the principal amount by an obligation of the United States, its agencies or instrumentalities, provided the collateral is held by a custodian other than the seller designated by the buyer;</section><section prefix="(4)">bankers' acceptances guaranteed by a financial institution with a short-term debt rating in the highest letter and numerical rating by at least one nationally recognized statistical rating organization as designated by either the United States Securities and Exchange Commission or the Treasurer;</section><section prefix="(5)">with respect to amounts treated by the Internal Revenue Service as bond sale proceeds only, bonds, notes, or other obligations of investment grade in the highest quality letter and numerical rating by at least one nationally recognized statistical rating organization as designated by the United States Securities and Exchange Commission issued by or on behalf of this or any other state or any agency, department, county, municipal or public corporation, special district, authority, or political subdivision thereof, or in any fund or trust that invests only in securities of the type described in this paragraph;</section><section prefix="(6)">commercial paper that has received the highest letter and numerical rating by at least two nationally recognized statistical rating organizations as designated by the United States Securities and Exchange Commission, provided that such commercial paper may not exceed 10% of the total investments made by the Treasurer under this subsection;</section><section prefix="(7)">money market mutual funds that:<section prefix="(i)">are registered with the Securities and Exchange Commission under the Investment Company Act of 1940, 15 U.S.C. &#xA7; 80a-1 et seq., as amended;</section><section prefix="(ii)">are operated in accordance with Rule 2A-7 of the Investment Company Act of 1940, 17 C.F.R. &#xA7; 270.2A-7, as amended; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">have received the highest possible rating from at least one nationally recognized statistical rating organization as designated by the United States Securities and Exchange Commission; and</section></section><section prefix="(8)">any investment portfolio created under the Maryland Local Government Investment Pool defined under Article 95, &#xA7; 22G of the Code that is administered by the Office of the State Treasurer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Treasurer may sell, redeem, or exchange an investment or reinvestment made under this section in accordance with the limitations of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the Treasurer shall report by January 3 of each year to the General Assembly on investment activities for unexpended or surplus money over which the Treasurer has custody which have been conducted during the previous fiscal year. At a minimum, the report shall specify for General Fund investments and all other investments:<section prefix="(1)">the inventory of investments with maturity dates and the book and market value as of June 30;</section><section prefix="(2)">the net income earned;</section><section prefix="(3)">the percentage share of each category of investment in the portfolio; and</section><section prefix="(4)">any sale of investments prior to the maturity date.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An investment made pursuant to this section shall be made:<section prefix="(1)">with the care, skill, prudence, and diligence under the circumstances then prevailing that a prudent person acting in a like capacity and familiar with such matters would use in the conduct of an enterprise of a like character and with like aims;</section><section prefix="(2)">in a manner designed to reasonably match the anticipated cash flow of the State so that sufficient funds are available to pay obligations upon proper presentation for payment;</section><section prefix="(3)">so that a reasonable amount of cash or cash equivalents is available for unanticipated cash needs;</section><section prefix="(4)">with due regard for minimizing risk while maximizing return;</section><section prefix="(5)">using competitive purchasing practices except when impractical;</section><section prefix="(6)">in accordance with a written investment policy;</section><section prefix="(7)">so that the securities and collateral may continue to be priced on a market to market basis; and</section><section prefix="(8)">to avoid the enhancement of the personal financial position of the Treasurer or any employee of the Treasurer who has responsibilities for such investments.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Consistent with minority business purchasing standards applicable to units of State government under this article and consistent with the fiduciary duties of the Treasurer, the Treasurer shall attempt to use to the greatest extent feasible minority business enterprises for brokerage and investment management services under this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For purposes of this subsection, brokerage and investment management services shall include services relating to all allocated asset classes as described in subsection (a) of this section.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">To assist the Treasurer in achieving the goal described under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Treasurer shall undertake measures to remove any barriers that limit full participation by minority business enterprises in brokerage and investment management services opportunities afforded under this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The measures undertaken by the Treasurer shall include the use of a wide variety of media, including the Treasurer's website, to provide notice to a broad and varied range of potential providers about the brokerage and investment management services opportunities afforded by the Treasurer.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In conjunction with the Governor's Office of Minority Affairs, the Treasurer shall develop guidelines to assist in identifying and evaluating qualified minority business enterprises in order to help the Treasurer achieve the objective for greater use of minority business enterprises for brokerage and investment management services under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On or before September 1 each year, the Treasurer shall submit a report to the Governor's Office of Minority Affairs and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly on:<section prefix="(i)">the identity of the minority business enterprise brokerage and investment management services firms used by the Treasurer in the immediately preceding fiscal year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the percentage and dollar value of the assets under the custody of the Treasurer that are under the investment control of minority business enterprise brokerage and investment management services firms for each allocated asset class; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the measures the Treasurer undertook in the immediately preceding fiscal year in accordance with paragraph (2)(ii) of this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
