<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-305" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-10-305</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to subsection (b) of this section, any real or personal property of the State or a unit of the State government may be sold, leased, transferred, exchanged, granted, or otherwise disposed of:<section prefix="(1)">to any person, to the United States or any of its units, or to any unit of the State government, for a consideration the Board decides is adequate; or</section><section prefix="(2)">to any county or municipal corporation in the State subject to any conditions the Board imposes.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided under subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, this subsection applies to the sale, transfer, grant, or exchange of:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">This subsection does not apply to the following dispositions of property identified in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may not approve the sale, transfer, exchange, or grant of property until:<section prefix="(i)">the Department of General Services or the Department of Natural Resources under Title 1, Subtitle 1 of the Natural Resources Article has submitted to the Board two independent appraisals of the property that:</section><section prefix="(ii)">the following information has been submitted, by electronic mail or facsimile and by certified mail, to the Senate Budget and Taxation Committee, the House Appropriations Committee, and, for property that meets both criteria of paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection, the Legislative Policy Committee:</section><section prefix="(iii)">45 days have elapsed since:</section><section prefix="(iv)">except for property sold under paragraph (4) of this subsection, for property that meets both criteria under paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection and for which the Board intends to approve a fee simple sale, transfer, exchange, or grant, the General Assembly has approved the proposed disposition as provided under paragraph (3) of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Within 45 days after receiving the information submitted under paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Legislative Policy Committee shall:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the Legislative Policy Committee fails to take any action under subparagraph (i)2 of this paragraph within the specified time period, the proposed disposition shall be deemed approved by the Committee.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)"/>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the Board has declared the property surplus, the Board shall sell the property to the federal government, a local government, or a unit of federal or local government for $1.00, if:<section prefix="(i)">the government or unit has indicated its interest in acquiring the land; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a restrictive covenant is placed on the deed of transfer, in accordance with &#xA7; 5-906(e)(7) and (8) of the Natural Resources Article, that requires the property to be maintained in a use that is consistent with its use at the time of transfer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Any revenues derived from the sale, transfer, exchange, or grant of property identified under paragraph (1)(i)1 of this subsection shall be deposited in the Advance Option and Purchase Fund under &#xA7; 5-904(b) of the Natural Resources Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as otherwise provided in this section:<section prefix="(1)">if any real or personal property disposed of under this section is not under the jurisdiction or control of any particular unit of the State government, the deed, lease, or other evidence of conveyance of the real or personal property shall be executed by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(2)">if any real or personal property disposed of under this section is under the jurisdiction or control of a unit of the State government, the deed, lease, or other evidence of conveyance of the real or personal property shall be executed by the highest official of the unit and by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whenever any unit of the State government leases any State-owned property under its jurisdiction and control to any State employee, agent, or servant, or to any other individual in State service, for the purpose of permitting the individual to maintain a residence on or in the property, the lease shall be:<section prefix="(i)">executed by the unit; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">approved by the Secretary of General Services.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The lease is not valid unless the Secretary of General Services approves it.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Whenever any unit of the State government leases any State-owned property under its jurisdiction and control to any lessee, the lease shall include a provision which prohibits the lessee from assigning or subleasing that property without the prior approval of the Board of Public Works.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Whenever the State Highway Administration leases any State-owned property under its jurisdiction and control to any person, the Administrator of the State Highway Administration may execute the lease if:<section prefix="(i)">the lease is entered into on a 30-day renewable basis; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the duration of the tenancy does not exceed 1 year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">At least twice each year, the Administrator of the State Highway Administration shall submit a report of the leases executed under the authority granted in paragraph (4) of this subsection to the Board of Public Works.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On the sale, lease, transfer, exchange, or other disposition of any real or personal property owned or controlled by the State Retirement and Pension System or the State of Maryland for the use of the Board of Trustees of the State Retirement and Pension System, any conveyancing document shall be executed in the manner provided in Division II of the State Personnel and Pensions Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any sale, lease, transfer, exchange or other disposition of any real or personal property owned or controlled by the State Retirement and Pension System or the State of Maryland for the use of the Board of Trustees of the State Retirement and Pension System by a conveyancing document executed by or for the Board of Trustees of the State Retirement and Pension System before October 1, 1994 in the manner provided under former Article 73B is ratified and confirmed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">All conveyances under this section shall be made in the name of the State of Maryland, acting through the executing authority provided for in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">This section does not apply to any lease or other temporary transfer, grant, or disposition of State real or personal property in connection with a procurement made subject to &#xA7; 11-202(3) of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Department of Budget and Management and Department of General Services, with the approval of the Board, shall adopt regulations in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 1 of the State Government Article to implement the provisions of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
