<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-5A-343</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies to all archaeological, prehistoric, and historic features found in any cave, in...</catch_line>
  <order_by>343</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section applies to all archaeological, prehistoric, and historic features found in any cave, including:<section prefix="(i)">all or any part of any burial grounds, historic or prehistoric ruins, and archaeological sites; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">relics, inscriptions, saltpeter workings, fossils, bones, and remains of historical human activity.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Without a permit issued under this section, a person may not excavate, remove, destroy, injure, deface, or disturb features found in a cave.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 5A-341 and 5A-342 of this subtitle, an individual trained in archaeology may apply for and be issued a permit to excavate or remove features described in subsection (a) of this section from or in a cave on land that the State owns or controls by rights under a lease, option contract, or purchase contract.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual may apply for a permit to excavate or remove archaeological, prehistoric, and historic features from a cave on privately owned land.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An applicant for a permit shall:<section prefix="(i)">be trained in archaeology;</section><section prefix="(ii)">give the Trust a detailed statement of the purposes and objectives of the proposed excavation or removal;</section><section prefix="(iii)">agree to provide the Trust with information from and results of any excavation, study, or collection in accordance with the terms of the permit;</section><section prefix="(iv)">obtain the prior written consent of the owner of the land on which the excavation or removal will be conducted; and</section><section prefix="(v)">agree to carry the permit while conducting the excavation or removal authorized by the permit.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A permit may be issued for a maximum term of 2 years and may be renewed.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A permit is not transferable, but a person working under the direct supervision of the permit holder need not obtain a separate permit.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Any object or material of archaeological, prehistoric, or historic value or interest found in a cave on privately owned land is the property of the owner of the land.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a person uses a cave for recreational or scientific purposes with the prior consent of and without a charge by the owner and sustains an injury, the owner and an authorized agent of the owner acting within the scope of the agent's authority are not liable for the injury.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Director and the Director's designee may enforce the provisions of this part relating to archaeological historic property found in caves in the same manner as provided in &#xA7; 5A-341(i) of this subtitle for submerged archaeological historic property.</section>
  </text>
</law>
