<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-7-208</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>208</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">While the General Assembly is in session the General Assembly may amend the appropriation for a program of the Legislative Branch of the State government by amendment to the budget bill.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">While the General Assembly is not in session, the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Delegates jointly may authorize an amendment of an appropriation for a program of the Legislative Branch of the State government.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An amendment of an appropriation for a program of the Legislative Branch of the State government:<section prefix="(1)">may not increase the sum of the appropriations from the General Fund of the State for all the programs of the Legislative Branch; and</section><section prefix="(2)">may authorize the expenditure of money from a special fund or the federal government as provided in &#xA7; 2-201 of this article or &#xA7; 7-217(a) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in this subsection, an amendment under this section may not increase a salary for a nonclassified position so that the salary exceeds the amount set by the most recently enacted State budget.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The limitation applies whether or not the most recently enacted budget is in effect.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">This subsection does not apply to salaries of positions that are included in an executive pay plan for the Legislative Branch.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">While the General Assembly is not in session, the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Delegates jointly may approve an amendment that increases a salary so that it exceeds the limitation in this subsection if:<section prefix="(i)">the President and the Speaker find that the salary increase is needed because an inability to obtain or to keep an essential career employee who is performing an administrative function or an essential professional or technical employee has created an acute emergency; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">their findings are documented.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A copy of each amended appropriation for a program shall be provided promptly to:<section prefix="(1)">the Comptroller; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the Secretary of Budget and Management.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
