<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-15-219</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>219</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except to the extent a shorter period is prescribed by regulation governing differing site conditions, a contractor shall file a written notice of a claim relating to a procurement contract for construction within 30 days after the basis for the claim is known or should have been known.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Unless extended by the unit, within 90 days after submitting a notice of a contract claim under a procurement contract for construction, a contractor shall submit to the unit a written explanation that states:<section prefix="(1)">the amount of the contract claim;</section><section prefix="(2)">the facts on which the contract claim is based; and</section><section prefix="(3)">all relevant data and correspondence that may substantiate the contract claim.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the head of the unit engaged in procurement of the construction shall review the contract claim.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the unit is part of a principal department or other equivalent unit, the Secretary of the principal department or the equivalent official shall review the contract claim, unless review has been delegated by regulation to the head of the unit.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The person who reviews a contract claim under subsection (c) of this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">investigate the contract claim; and</section><section prefix="(2)">give the contractor written notice of a resolution of the contract claim:<section prefix="(i)">within 90 days after receiving the contract claim or a longer period to which the parties agree, if the amount of the contract claim is not more than the amount under which the accelerated procedure may be selected before the Appeals Board; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">for any other contract claim, within 180 days after receiving the contract claim or a longer period to which the parties agree.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Recovery under a contract claim is not allowed for any expense incurred:<section prefix="(1)">more than 30 days before the required submission of a notice of a claim under subsection (a) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(2)">unless the time for submission of a claim is extended under subsection (b) of this section, more than 120 days before the required submission of the claim.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the unit determines that it is responsible for a portion but not all of the amount claimed by the contractor, subject to the terms of the contract, the unit shall pay the undisputed amount.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Payment of the undisputed amount:<section prefix="(i)">is not an admission of the liability of the unit on the claims; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">does not preclude recovery of the amount paid if it subsequently is determined that the determination of the unit was not correct.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A decision not to pay a contract claim is a final action for the purpose of appeal to the Appeals Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The failure to reach a decision within the time required under subsection (c) of this section may be deemed, at the option of the contractor, to be a decision not to pay the contract claim.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">At the time of final payment, the unit shall:<section prefix="(1)">release the retainage due to the contractor; and</section><section prefix="(2)">pay any interest that:<section prefix="(i)">has accrued on the retainage from the time of payment of the semifinal estimate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is due and payable to the contractor.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
