<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5A-313" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-5A-313</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board consists of 15 trustees.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Delegates are ex officio trustees.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">With the advice and consent of the Senate, the Governor shall appoint the other 12 trustees.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor may delegate any or all of the Governor's powers or duties as trustee to a member of the Executive Department of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The President of the Senate may delegate any or all of the President's powers or duties as trustee to a member of the Senate.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Speaker of the House of Delegates may delegate any or all of the Speaker's powers or duties as trustee to a member of the House of Delegates.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least two of the trustees appointed by the Governor shall have:<section prefix="(i)">an advanced degree in archaeology or a closely related field; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">experience in archaeology.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the trustees who qualify under paragraph (1) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">at least one shall have experience in submerged archaeology; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">at least one shall have experience in terrestrial archaeology.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary shall advise the Governor on the appointment of trustees qualified under paragraph (1) of this subsection after consulting with the Advisory Committee on Archaeology established under &#xA7; 5A-336 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of an appointed trustee is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of appointed trustees are staggered as required by the terms provided for trustees on October 1, 2005.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If an appointed trustee fails to serve or to complete a term, the Governor shall appoint a successor for the rest of the term.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">To the extent practicable and consistent with the purposes of the Trust, trustees shall be chosen, whether by delegation or appointment, to achieve a broad geographic distribution of trustees throughout the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
