<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-12-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>Before issuing a request for proposals for an energy performance contract, a primary procurement uni...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before issuing a request for proposals for an energy performance contract, a primary procurement unit shall consult with the Maryland Energy Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Maryland Energy Administration shall review the proposed request to ensure that it meets with the State energy standards, preserves the State's flexibility to investigate and use economically justifiable new technologies, and is in conformance with the unit's energy conservation plan that has been developed in accordance with &#xA7; 4-806 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law and subject to the approval and control of the Board of Public Works, a primary procurement unit of State government is authorized to enter into energy performance contracts of up to 15 years duration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Treasurer may enter into a capital lease to finance energy performance contracts as provided in Title 8, Subtitle 4 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The payments and the total contract amount due under an energy performance contract or, in the case of a capital lease used to finance energy performance contracts, the capital lease payments may not exceed the actual energy savings realized as a result of the contract's performance.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Before approval of an energy performance contract, the Board:<section prefix="1.">shall ensure that the projected annual energy savings attributable to the project will exceed the projected annual capital lease payments or payments to the contractor under the contract; and</section><section prefix="2.">based on the review of the Maryland Energy Administration, shall determine whether the proposed energy technology is appropriate for the time period provided in the contract.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Board may:<section prefix="1.">authorize the use of incentive contracts, including contracts that guarantee energy savings performance; and</section><section prefix="2.">require prospective contractors to furnish appropriate guarantees to ensure that projected savings are realized.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Any guarantees required under subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph may include a requirement that the contractor furnish a bond or other assurance to the State in an appropriate amount to guarantee projected performance and that the bond or other assurance be structured so that a failure to meet guaranteed performance savings will forfeit a portion of the bond or other assurance to match the shortfall in energy savings.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
