<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-13-302</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>302</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a General Professional Services Selection Board in the Department of General Services.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The General Selection Board consists of:<section prefix="(i)">4 permanent members; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">1 temporary member.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The permanent members shall be:<section prefix="(i)">the Secretary of General Services, ex officio, or a designee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">3 members who are appointed by the Governor and shall be:<section prefix="1.">1 appointee from the Department of General Services on recommendation of the Secretary of General Services; and</section><section prefix="2.">2 appointees from the general public, at least 1 of whom is not an architect or engineer.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The temporary member shall be the head of the unit whose request is under consideration.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On recommendation of the Secretary of General Services, the Governor may appoint an alternate member to serve in the absence of the appointee under paragraph (2)(ii)1 of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The appointee from the Department of General Services serves at the pleasure of the Governor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An appointee from the general public:<section prefix="(i)">serves a term of 5 years; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">at the end of the term, continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A temporary member serves only for the purpose of considering and acting on the request of the unit that the temporary member represents.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A permanent member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor may remove a member for incompetence, misconduct, neglect of duty, or other sufficient cause.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member may not participate in any matter before the General Selection Board in which the member:<section prefix="(i)">has an interest; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">is or, within the previous 12 months, has been associated with:<section prefix="1.">a transportation unit that has an interest in the matter; or</section><section prefix="2.">any other person who is not a unit and has an interest in the matter.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each appointee from the general public is entitled to:<section prefix="(1)">compensation in accordance with the State budget; and</section><section prefix="(2)">reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
