<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-13-215</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>215</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A unit may not enter into a cost-reimbursement contract unless the procurement officer determines that:<section prefix="(1)">a cost-reimbursement contract is likely to be less costly to the State than any other type of contract; or</section><section prefix="(2)">except for leases of real property, the kind or quality of procurement that the unit requires could not be obtained practicably under any other type of contract.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A unit may not enter into a procurement contract that is wholly or partly a cost-reimbursement contract unless the procurement officer determines that the accounting system of the contractor:<section prefix="(1)">will allow timely development of all necessary cost data in the form required by the specific type of procurement contract under consideration; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is adequate to allocate costs in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A cost-reimbursement contract shall provide that costs, including costs for subcontractors, will be reimbursed only if the costs are allowable and allocable under:<section prefix="(1)">the procurement contract; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the regulations of the Board on cost principles.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A contractor under a cost-reimbursement contract shall give notice to and, as required under the contract, obtain approval from a procurement officer before the contractor enters into:<section prefix="(1)">a cost-reimbursement subcontract; or</section><section prefix="(2)">any subcontract involving more than:<section prefix="(i)">$25,000; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">5% of the estimated cost of the procurement contract.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
