<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5A-330" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-5A-330</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL MAY 31, 2015 PER CHAPTERS 278 AND 279 OF 2010 //<section prefix="(a)"><section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section><section prefix="(2)">"Capital project" means the:<section prefix="(i)">acquisition of land or buildings for an African American heritage preservation project; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">construction or improvement of an African American heritage preservation project.</section></section><section prefix="(3)">"Commission" means the Commission on African American History and Culture.</section><section prefix="(4)">"Construction or improvement" means planning, design, engineering, alteration, construction, reconstruction, enlargement, expansion, extension, improvement, replacement, rehabilitation, renovation, upgrading, repair, or capital equipping.</section><section prefix="(5)">"Grantee" means a business entity, individual, nonprofit organization, or political subdivision.</section><section prefix="(6)">"Secretary" means the Secretary of Planning.</section></section><section prefix="(b)"><section prefix="(1)">There is an African American Heritage Preservation Program in the Trust.</section><section prefix="(2)">The purpose of the African American Heritage Preservation Program is to identify and preserve buildings, communities, and sites of historical and cultural importance to the African American experience in Maryland.</section></section><section prefix="(c)">The Trust shall develop and administer the African American Heritage Preservation Program in partnership with the Commission.</section><section prefix="(d)"><section prefix="(1)">On or before July 15 of each year, a grantee may submit an application to the joint partnership of the Trust and Commission to receive a grant for an African American heritage preservation capital project for the next fiscal year.</section><section prefix="(2)">An application shall include:<section prefix="(i)">a description of the scope and purpose of the project;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a building plan that includes the estimated total cost of the project; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">any other information required by the Trust and Commission.</section></section></section><section prefix="(e)">Grants under the Program to a business entity, individual, or political subdivision:<section prefix="(1)">require a matching fund from any combination of federal, county, municipal, or private sources; and</section><section prefix="(2)">may not exceed 50% of the total cost of an  African American heritage preservation capital project.</section></section><section prefix="(f)"><section prefix="(1)">The Trust and Commission shall review grant applications submitted in accordance with subsection (d) of this section and shall make recommendations for African American heritage preservation capital project grants for the next fiscal year.</section><section prefix="(2)">In making recommendations under this subsection, the Trust and Commission shall consider:<section prefix="(i)">the public necessity and urgency of a project;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the need for additional sources of funding for a project;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the estimated cost and timeliness of executing a project;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the viability of matching funds for a project; and</section><section prefix="(v)">geographic diversity.</section></section><section prefix="(3)">On or before November 1 of each year, the Trust and Commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">recommend African American heritage preservation capital projects for funding in the State capital budget for the next fiscal year; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">forward the list of recommended projects and grantees to the Department of Budget and Management.</section></section></section><section prefix="(g)">For fiscal year 2012 and each fiscal year thereafter, the Governor shall include in the annual capital budget submission $1,000,000 for African American heritage preservation capital projects.</section><section prefix="(h)">On or before October 1 of each year, the Trust and Commission shall report to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly, on State grants awarded for African American heritage preservation capital projects for the prior fiscal year.</section><section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, the Trust shall require a grantee under the African American Heritage Preservation Program to enter into an agreement to preserve and maintain the property.</section><section prefix="(2)">If the property is historic real property, the agreement shall be a recordable historic preservation easement.</section><section prefix="(3)">The Secretary may waive the easement requirement if the Secretary determines that an easement is impracticable or infeasible under the circumstances.</section></section><section prefix="(j)"><section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Secretary, in consultation with the Commission, shall adopt regulations to implement the African American Heritage Preservation Program.</section><section prefix="(2)">A proposed regulation that relates to approval by the Board of Public Works of grants to be financed through the sale of State general obligation bonds may not be adopted under paragraph (1) of this subsection unless the regulation is approved by the Board of Public Works.</section></section><section prefix="(k)">To the extent required by regulations adopted under subsection (j) of this section, the Trust and the Commission shall submit to the Board of Public Works for the Board's approval each recommended African American Heritage Preservation Program grant that is to be financed through the sale of State general obligation bonds.</section></text>
</law>
