<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-15-111</section_number>
  <catch_line>Within 90 days after the end of each fiscal year, each primary procurement unit shall submit to the ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>111</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Within 90 days after the end of each fiscal year, each primary procurement unit shall submit to the Governor and to the General Assembly a report on each procurement contract that was awarded during the preceding fiscal year and:<section prefix="(1)">was exempt from the notice requirements of &#xA7; 13-103(c) of this article because the procurement officer reasonably expected that the procurement contract would be performed entirely outside this State and the District of Columbia;</section><section prefix="(2)">cost more than $100,000 and was awarded for the procurement of services, construction related services, architectural services, or engineering services; or</section><section prefix="(3)">was awarded on the basis of:<section prefix="(i)">&#xA7; 13-107 of this article ("Sole source procurement");</section><section prefix="(ii)">&#xA7; 13-108(a) of this article ("Emergency procurement"); or</section><section prefix="(iii)">&#xA7; 13-108(b) of this article ("Expedited procurement").</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A report required under subsection (a)(2) or (3) of this section shall include:<section prefix="(i)">the name of each contractor;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the type and cost of the procurement contract; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">a description of the procurement.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A report required under subsection (a)(3) of this section also shall describe the basis for the award.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Within 90 days after the end of each fiscal year, the Governor shall submit to the General Assembly a report on each expedited procurement approved under &#xA7; 13-108(b) of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Within 90 days after the end of each fiscal year, the Department of Budget and Management shall submit to the Board and the General Assembly a report on each class of procurement for which the procedure for noncompetitive negotiated procurement has been approved under &#xA7; 13-106 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A report to the General Assembly under this section is subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
