<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-5A-328</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>328</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"MHT Grant Fund" means the Historic Preservation and Historical and Cultural Museum Assistance Grant Fund of the Trust.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"MHT Grant Program" means the Historic Preservation Grant Program of the Trust.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is an MHT Grant Program in the Trust.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The purposes of the MHT Grant Program are to:<section prefix="(i)">implement and encourage the preservation of historic properties; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">promote interest in and study of historic properties and their preservation.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Trust shall administer the MHT Grant Program and coordinate the MHT Grant Program with federal and State programs that complement or facilitate the MHT Grant Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Trust shall ensure that a grant awarded under the MHT Grant Program to acquire, restore, or rehabilitate a historic property is used only if the historic property is listed in or is eligible to be listed in the Historic Register.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Trust shall require a grantee under the MHT Grant Program to enter into an agreement to preserve and maintain the property.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the property is real property, the agreement shall be a recordable historic preservation easement.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Secretary may waive the agreement requirement if the Secretary determines that an agreement is impracticable.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall adopt regulations to carry out the purposes of the MHT Grant Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The regulations shall include:<section prefix="(i)">application procedures;</section><section prefix="(ii)">procedures to give adequate notice to the public of assistance available under the MHT Grant Program;</section><section prefix="(iii)">provisions for the review of plans and specifications;</section><section prefix="(iv)">provisions for the inspection of projects during construction; and</section><section prefix="(v)">selection criteria the Trust must consider when evaluating applications for grants, including:<section prefix="1.">the relative historical or cultural significance of, and the urgency of need for, the project to be financed by the grant;</section><section prefix="2.">any proposed contribution by the appropriate political subdivision to the project;</section><section prefix="3.">the geographic distribution of grant assistance from the MHT Grant Fund under subsection (e) of this section; and</section><section prefix="4.">other relevant factors.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is an MHT Grant Fund in the Trust.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The MHT Grant Fund may be used:<section prefix="(i)">for the purposes set forth in &#xA7; 5A-353 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">to make grants to nonprofit organizations, political subdivisions, business entities, and individuals to acquire, rehabilitate, or restore historic properties;</section><section prefix="(iii)">to make grants to nonprofit organizations and political subdivisions to pay costs, including preparation costs, that are directly related to a rehabilitation or restoration project;</section><section prefix="(iv)">to make grants to nonprofit organizations and political subdivisions for historic preservation education and promotion, including the research, survey, and evaluation of historic properties and the preparation of historic preservation planning documents and educational materials;</section><section prefix="(v)">to purchase or acquire historic properties or interests in historic properties for the Trust's authorized purposes or for resale or lease with appropriate preservation covenants;</section><section prefix="(vi)">to pay costs, including preparation costs, that are directly related to restoring or rehabilitating historic properties that the Trust owns for use in accordance with the Trust's authorized purposes or for resale or lease subject to appropriate preservation covenants; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">to pay for historic preservation education and promotion conducted by the Trust, and for the research, survey, and evaluation of historic properties and the preparation of historic preservation planning documents and educational materials.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Trust shall administer the MHT Grant Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The MHT Grant Fund is a continuing, nonlapsing special fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Treasurer shall hold and the Comptroller shall account for the MHT Grant Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The MHT Grant Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">money appropriated in the State budget to the MHT Grant Program or the Historical and Cultural Museum Assistance Program under &#xA7; 5A-352 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">the proceeds from the resale or lease of any properties originally acquired by the Trust from the MHT Grant Fund or the Capital Grant Fund for Historic Preservation;</section><section prefix="(3)">money received from other public or private sources for the benefit of the MHT Grant Fund; and</section><section prefix="(4)">money received from the sale of State general obligation bonds.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Money in the MHT Grant Fund shall be invested in the same manner as other State money.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The trustees shall review and make recommendations to the Secretary about grant applications and expenditure requests from the MHT Grant Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The trustees shall base their grant recommendations on a competitive selection process.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In any fiscal year, the Secretary may hold up to 20% of the money in the MHT Grant Fund in reserve for emergency use in accordance with subsection (e) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Grants to business entities may not exceed 10% of all grants awarded from the MHT Grant Fund under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To the extent required by regulations adopted by the Secretary and approved by the Board of Public Works, the Secretary shall submit to the Board of Public Works for approval grants or expenditures from the MHT Grant Fund to be financed through the sale of State general obligation bonds.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except for an expenditure under subsection (e)(2)(v) and (vi) of this section, grants and expenditures from the MHT Grant Fund are not subject to Titles 4 and 5 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">On or before December 31 of each year, the Trust shall report to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly on the financial status and the activities of the MHT Grant Program and the MHT Grant Fund for the preceding fiscal year.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not knowingly make or cause to be made a material false statement of fact, including an understatement or overstatement of financial condition, in a statement or report in or regarding an application for a grant or affecting an existing grant.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 2 years or a fine not exceeding $5,000 or both.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
