<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-14-407</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>407</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Locally grown food" means food grown in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Percentage price preference" means the percent by which a responsive bid from a responsible bidder whose product is a locally grown food may exceed the lowest responsive bid submitted by a responsible bidder whose product is not a locally grown food.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board shall adopt regulations that require State schools and facilities to establish a percentage price preference, not to exceed 5%, for the purchase of locally grown food.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A percentage price preference under this section may not be used in conjunction with any other percentage price preference established under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each State school and facility shall review the procurement specifications currently used and, to the extent practicable, require the use of a percentage price preference in their purchase of locally grown food.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, this section is broadly applicable to all procurements by State schools and facilities if the locally grown food is consistent with the requirements of the bid specification.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Only to the extent necessary to prevent the denial of federal moneys or eliminate the inconsistency with federal law, this section does not apply to a procurement by a State school or facility if it is determined that compliance with this section would:<section prefix="(i)">cause denial of federal moneys; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">be inconsistent with the requirements of federal law.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
