<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-11-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this Division II the following words have the meanings indicated unless:<section prefix="(1)">the context clearly requires a different meaning; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a different definition is provided for a particular title or provision.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Architectural services" means professional or creative work that:<section prefix="(i)">is performed in connection with the design and supervision of construction or landscaping; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">requires architectural education, training, and experience.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Architectural services" includes consultation, research, investigation, evaluation, planning, architectural design and preparation of related documents, and coordination of services that structural, civil, mechanical, and electrical engineers and other consultants provide.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Architectural services" does not include construction inspection services or services provided in connection with an energy performance contract.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Bid" means a response to an invitation for bids under &#xA7; 13-103 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Board" means the Board of Public Works.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Construction" means the process of building, altering, improving, or demolishing an improvement to real property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Construction" includes any major work necessary to repair, prevent damage to, or sustain existing components of an improvement to real property.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Construction" does not include the maintenance or routine operation of an existing improvement to real property, or activities related to an energy performance contract.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Construction related services" means feasibility studies, surveys, construction management, construction inspection, and similar efforts associated with construction or the acquisition of public improvements as defined in &#xA7; 4-401(d) of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Construction related services" does not include services provided in connection with an energy performance contract.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"County" means a county of the State and, unless expressly provided otherwise, Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Energy performance contract" means an agreement for the provision of energy services, including electricity, heating, ventilation, cooling, steam, or hot water, in which a person agrees to design, install, finance, maintain, or manage energy systems or equipment to improve the energy efficiency of a building or facility in exchange for a portion of the energy savings.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Engineering services" means professional or creative work that:<section prefix="(i)">is performed in connection with any utility, structure, building, machine, equipment, or process; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">requires engineering education, training, and experience in the application of special knowledge of the mathematical, physical, and engineering sciences.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Engineering services" includes consultation, investigation, evaluation, planning, design, and inspection of construction to interpret and ensure compliance with specifications and design within the scope of inspection services.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Engineering services" does not include services provided in connection with an energy performance contract.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Invitation for bids" means any document used for soliciting bids under &#xA7; 13-103 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Person" means an individual, receiver, trustee, guardian, personal representative, fiduciary, or representative of any kind and any partnership, firm, association, corporation, or other entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Primary procurement units" means:<section prefix="(1)">the State Treasurer;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Department of Budget and Management;</section><section prefix="(3)">the Department of General Services;</section><section prefix="(4)">the Department of Transportation;</section><section prefix="(5)">the Department of Information Technology;</section><section prefix="(6)">the University System of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(7)">the Maryland Port Commission;</section><section prefix="(8)">the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services;</section><section prefix="(9)">the Morgan State University; and</section><section prefix="(10)">the St. Mary's College of Maryland.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Procurement" means the process of:<section prefix="(i)">leasing real or personal property as lessee; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">buying or otherwise obtaining supplies, services, construction, construction related services, architectural services, engineering services, or services provided under an energy performance contract.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Procurement" includes the solicitation and award of procurement contracts and all phases of procurement contract administration.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Procurement contract" means an agreement in any form entered into by a unit for procurement.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Procurement contract" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">a collective bargaining agreement with an employee organization;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an agreement with a contractual employee, as defined in &#xA7; 1-101(d) of the State Personnel and Pensions Article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a Medicaid, Judicare, or similar reimbursement contract for which law sets:</section><section prefix="(iv)">a Medicaid contract with a managed care organization, as defined in &#xA7; 15-101(e) of the Health - General Article as to which regulations adopted by the Department establish:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Procurement officer" means an individual authorized by a unit to:<section prefix="(1)">enter into a procurement contract;</section><section prefix="(2)">administer a procurement contract; or</section><section prefix="(3)">make determinations and findings with respect to a procurement contract.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Proposal" means a response to any solicitation other than an invitation for bids.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Request for proposals" means any document used for soliciting proposals.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Responsible bidder or offeror" means a person who:<section prefix="(1)">has the capability in all respects to perform fully the requirements for a procurement contract; and</section><section prefix="(2)">possesses the integrity and reliability that will ensure good faith performance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Responsive bid" means a bid that:<section prefix="(1)">is submitted under &#xA7; 13-103 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">conforms in all material respects to the invitation for bids.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(t)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, "services" means:<section prefix="(i)">the labor, time, or effort of a contractor; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any product or report necessarily associated with the rendering of a service.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Services" includes services provided by attorneys, accountants, physicians, consultants, and other professionals who are independent contractors.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Services" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">construction related services;</section><section prefix="(ii)">architectural services;</section><section prefix="(iii)">engineering services; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">energy performance contract services.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(u)">"State" means:<section prefix="(1)">a state, possession, territory, or commonwealth of the United States; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the District of Columbia.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(v)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"State correctional facilities" means correctional institutions, and all places of correctional confinement, that are located within the State of Maryland and are primarily operated by the Maryland State government.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"State correctional facilities" includes Patuxent Institution.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(w)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Supplies" means:<section prefix="(i)">insurance;</section><section prefix="(ii)">tangible personal property;</section><section prefix="(iii)">printing; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">services necessarily associated with insurance or tangible personal property.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Supplies" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">an interest in real property; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">tangible personal property acquired or used in connection with an energy performance contract.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(x)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Unit" means an officer or other entity that is in the Executive Branch of the State government and is authorized by law to enter into a procurement contract.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Unit" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">a bistate, multistate, bicounty, or multicounty governmental agency; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a special tax district, sanitary district, drainage district, soil conservation district, water supply district, or other political subdivision of the State.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
