<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-14-410</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>410</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Committee" means the Maryland Green Purchasing Committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Environmentally preferable purchasing" means the procurement or acquisition of goods and services that have a lesser or reduced effect on human health and the environment when compared with competing goods or services that serve the same purpose, based on the raw materials, manufacturing, packaging, distribution, use, reuse, operation, maintenance, and disposal of the goods or services.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Maryland Green Purchasing Committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Committee consists of the following members:<section prefix="(i)">the Secretary of General Services, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Secretary of Budget and Management, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Secretary of Natural Resources, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Secretary of the Environment, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(v)">the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(vi)">the Secretary of Business and Economic Development, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(vii)">the Secretary of Transportation, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(viii)">the Secretary of Public Safety and Correctional Services, or the Secretary's designee; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">the Chancellor of the University System of Maryland, or the Chancellor's designee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary of General Services, or the Secretary's designee, shall serve as the Chair of the Committee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Committee shall provide the State with information and assistance regarding environmentally preferable purchasing, including:<section prefix="(1)">the promotion of environmentally preferable purchasing;</section><section prefix="(2)">the development and implementation of a strategy to increase environmentally preferable purchasing that may include the development of statewide policies, guidelines, programs, and regulations;</section><section prefix="(3)">coordination with other State or federal agencies, task forces, workgroups, regulatory efforts, research and data collection efforts, or other programs and services relating to environmentally preferable purchasing; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the development of an environmentally preferable purchasing best practices manual that may be adopted from other governmental or nongovernmental institutions.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In developing the best practices manual and strategy to increase environmentally preferable purchasing under subsection (c) of this section, the Committee shall consider:<section prefix="(1)">greater use and procurement of meters used to measure electricity consumption that are:<section prefix="(i)">capable of measuring the flow of electricity in two directions; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">compatible with advanced metering infrastructure;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">achievement of greater energy efficiency through implementation of policies that reduce operating times for heating, ventilation, and air-conditioning systems in State-owned or State-operated buildings;</section><section prefix="(3)">increasing the energy efficiency of new and existing computer servers and data storage center operations; and</section><section prefix="(4)">procurement of food and beverage containers and utensils that are made of biodegradable materials or plant-based plastics or recyclable products that may contain post consumer recycled contents.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Committee shall designate a single point of contact for State agencies, suppliers, and other interested parties to contact regarding environmentally preferable purchasing issues.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">On or before October 1 of each year, the Committee shall report to the General Assembly, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, on the Committee's activities and the progress made as a result of the implementation of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">This section may not be construed to:<section prefix="(1)">limit or supersede recycled content requirements under any other provision of law; or</section><section prefix="(2)">require the acquisition of goods or services that:<section prefix="(i)">do not perform adequately for the intended use;</section><section prefix="(ii)">exclude adequate competition; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">are not available at a reasonable price in a reasonable period of time.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A bidder or offeror for a procurement contract with the Department of General Services shall certify in writing that any claims of environmental attributes made relating to a product or service are consistent with the Federal Trade Commission's Guidelines for the Use of Environmental Marketing Terms.</section>
  </text>
</law>
