<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-7-110</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>110</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Capital expenditure" means an expenditure made by the Department of Transportation for:<section prefix="(i)">the construction, reconstruction, or rehabilitation of a transportation facility, as defined in &#xA7; 3-101(l) of the Transportation Article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">capital equipment as defined by the Secretary of Transportation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Modal administration" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Transportation Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Operating expenditure" means an expenditure that is made by the Department of Transportation, including the Office of the Secretary or a modal administration, and that is not a capital expenditure.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each budget bill shall set forth as part of the appropriation for the Office of the Secretary of Transportation and for each modal administration, separate items for:<section prefix="(i)">capital expenditures; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">operating expenditures.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The budget books shall set forth, for information, a summary of the capital expenditures and operating expenditures, as defined by the Secretary of Transportation, for the Maryland Transportation Authority.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The budget books for a fiscal year shall include the appropriation for the preceding fiscal year for each modal administration, as provided in the Consolidated Transportation Program.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
