<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-6-213</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided by law, in accordance with regulations and policies adopted by the Trea...</catch_line>
  <order_by>213</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided by law, in accordance with regulations and policies adopted by the Treasurer and the Comptroller, each unit of the State government shall:<section prefix="(1)">pay into depositaries designated by the Treasurer for the account of the State Treasury all collections, fees, income, and other revenues that are received by the unit; and</section><section prefix="(2)">account to the Comptroller for those revenues.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Comptroller shall credit the revenues that a unit pays into depositaries designated by the Treasurer for the account of the State Treasury:<section prefix="(1)">to the account that the law specifies; or</section><section prefix="(2)">if the law does not specify an account, to an account that the Comptroller designates for the use of the unit.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With the approval of the Governor, the Comptroller:<section prefix="(i)">shall exempt revenues from the requirements of subsection (a) of this section if the Comptroller determines that the exemption would be in the public interest; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">may rescind an exemption.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Comptroller shall keep a record that shows each exemption and the reasons for it.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The records shall be kept in the Office of the Comptroller and shall be open to public inspection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "State institution" includes a hospital or center that the State operates.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Treasurer may exclude from the State Treasury the personal funds that a State institution holds for its residents or clients.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A State institution shall use, as a depositary for these funds, a financial institution that the Treasurer approves.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Treasurer may require the submission of a proposed agreement between the State institution and the financial institution and may approve or disapprove the agreement.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The accounts established by a State institution shall be interest bearing accounts.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">All interest on money of a resident or client of a State institution shall be credited to the resident or client.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">A State institution shall:<section prefix="(i)">keep records of all transactions that involve money of a resident or client; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">provide the resident or client with a statement of those transactions at least each 6 months and on discharge.  </section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
