<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-12-501</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>501</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Direct involvement in the deportation of victims" means ownership or operation of the trains on which individuals were transported to extermination camps, death camps, or any facility used to transition individuals to extermination camps or death camps, during the period beginning on September 1, 1939, and ending on September 2, 1945.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Entity" means:<section prefix="(1)">a corporation, affiliate, or other similar organization or a successor in interest of the corporation, affiliate, or similar organization that controls, or is controlled or owned or partially owned by or under common control with, a corporation that had direct involvement in the deportation of victims; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a member of a partnership or a consortium that includes an entity that certifies that it had direct involvement in the deportation of victims.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"MARC" means the Maryland Area Regional Commuter.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Property" means any personal belongings owned or controlled by victims.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Property" includes:<section prefix="(i)">jewelry;</section><section prefix="(ii)">books;</section><section prefix="(iii)">artifacts;</section><section prefix="(iv)">precious metals; and</section><section prefix="(v)">currency.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Process of assembling the records" means to:<section prefix="(1)">organize, digitize, and make records available to the public in an Internet accessible, electronic format that is searchable and analyzable; and</section><section prefix="(2)">prepare to submit the information described in &#xA7; 12-507 of this subtitle to the State Archivist.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Records" means material relating to the deportation of victims.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Records" includes:<section prefix="(i)">documents;</section><section prefix="(ii)">correspondence;</section><section prefix="(iii)">memoranda;</section><section prefix="(iv)">receipts;</section><section prefix="(v)">invoices;</section><section prefix="(vi)">presentations;</section><section prefix="(vii)">audits; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">any other materials related to items (i) through (vii) of this paragraph.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Victim" means an individual who was on an entity's train for the purpose of being transported to an extermination camp, death camp, or a facility used to transition individuals to extermination camps or death camps during the period beginning on September 1, 1939 and ending on September 2, 1945.</section>
  </text>
</law>
