<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-13-107.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL SEPTEMBER 30, 2013 PER CHAPTER 662 OF 2008 //...</catch_line>
  <order_by>107.1</order_by>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL SEPTEMBER 30, 2013 PER CHAPTER 662 OF 2008 //<section prefix="(a)"><section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section><section prefix="(2)">"Business and economic development services" means services procured by the Department of Business and Economic Development.</section><section prefix="(3)">"Educational services" means services procured to provide or assist in providing training to third-party clients under a contract.</section><section prefix="(4)">"Health or social services" means services procured to provide or assist in providing support, care, or shelter to third-party clients under a contract.</section><section prefix="(5)">"Lottery services" means services procured by the Maryland State Lottery Agency.</section></section><section prefix="(b)">A procurement officer may enter into a contract based on an unsolicited proposal if the unsolicited proposal:<section prefix="(1)">is in writing;</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">contains a novel or innovative concept, application, approach, or method which, to the knowledge of the procurement officer, is not used by or available to another unit; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">demonstrates a novel capability of the offeror of the proposal;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">has not been previously submitted to the unit by another person;</section><section prefix="(4)">is for the delivery of:<section prefix="(i)">educational services;</section><section prefix="(ii)">health or social services;</section><section prefix="(iii)">business and economic development services; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">lottery services; and</section></section><section prefix="(5)">meets a need of or is otherwise advantageous to the unit.</section></section><section prefix="(c)"><section prefix="(1)">The procurement officer shall make a determination as to whether the unsolicited proposal meets the requirements of subsection (b) of this section.</section><section prefix="(2)">If the procurement officer determines that the unsolicited proposal does not meet the requirements of subsection (b) of this section, the procurement officer may not award a procurement contract based on the unsolicited proposal.</section><section prefix="(3)"><section prefix="(i)">The procurement officer shall make a determination under paragraph (1) of this subsection within 30 days after receiving the unsolicited proposal for review.</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the procurement officer fails to make a determination under paragraph (1) of this subsection within the 30-day period established under this subparagraph, the unsolicited proposal shall be deemed to have been disapproved.</section></section></section><section prefix="(d)">If an unsolicited proposal meets the requirements of subsection (b) of this section, the offeror of the proposal is not required to be the only available source for the contract awarded under this section.</section><section prefix="(e)">Before awarding a procurement contract under this section, a procurement officer shall obtain:<section prefix="(1)">the approval of the head of the unit;</section><section prefix="(2)">the approval of the Department of Budget and Management; and</section><section prefix="(3)">any other approval required by law.</section></section><section prefix="(f)">The term, including extensions, of a contract awarded under this section may not exceed 3 years.</section><section prefix="(g)">State expenditures under a contract awarded under this section may not exceed $2,000,000 annually and may not exceed $4,000,000 for the total contract.</section><section prefix="(h)"><section prefix="(1)">Except as provided under paragraph (2) of this subsection, a procurement officer shall treat the information contained in an unsolicited proposal as confidential information that is not subject to disclosure under any other State or local law.</section><section prefix="(2)">If a contract is awarded under this section, disclosure of the unsolicited proposal is governed by Title 10, Subtitle 6, Part III of the State Government Article.</section></section><section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="(1)">Not less than 30 days before the execution and award of a contract based on an unsolicited proposal under this section, the contracting unit shall publish a general notice of the intent to award the contract as follows:<section prefix="(i)">in eMaryland Marketplace; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">in at least one newspaper of general circulation in:<section prefix="1.">the county of the agency to be served under the contract; and</section><section prefix="2.">if applicable, the county of the client population to be served by the agency under the contract.</section></section></section><section prefix="(2)">For purposes of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">the Baltimore Sun and the Washington Post shall be considered newspapers of general circulation in the counties of the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">in Baltimore City, Baltimore County, and Anne Arundel County, the Baltimore Afro-American shall be considered a newspaper of general circulation.</section></section><section prefix="(3)">If, during the 30-day period established under paragraph (1) of this subsection, a person petitions the unit of State government conducting the procurement for reconsideration of a determination of approval under subsection (b) of this section, the procurement officer shall reconsider the determination of approval and make written findings affirming or reversing the determination of approval.</section></section><section prefix="(j)">In addition to publishing notice of the intent to award a contract based on an unsolicited proposal under subsection (i) of this section, not more than 30 days after the execution and approval of a procurement contract awarded under this section, a unit shall publish notice of the award in eMaryland Marketplace.</section><section prefix="(k)">Repealed.</section><section prefix="(l)">The following agencies shall implement an educational outreach campaign on the availability of the unsolicited proposal method of procurement:<section prefix="(1)">the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Department of Human Resources;</section><section prefix="(3)">the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation;</section><section prefix="(4)">the Department of Juvenile Services;</section><section prefix="(5)">the Department of Disabilities;</section><section prefix="(6)">the Department of Aging;</section><section prefix="(7)">the Department of Business and Economic Development; and</section><section prefix="(8)">the Maryland State Lottery Agency.</section></section><section prefix="(m)">On or before September 30 of each year, the agencies designated in subsection (l) of this section shall report to the Board of Public Works on the status of the educational outreach campaign, including activities conducted in the previous fiscal year and plans for future educational outreach activities.</section><section prefix="(n)">The Board of Public Works may adopt regulations to carry out the requirements of this section.</section></text>
</law>
