<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="19-109" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-19-109</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A request for a contested case hearing in accordance with the procedures specified in this section may be made by:<section prefix="(1)">a business entity, upon a Commission determination of probable cause for one or more of the allegations stated in the complaint against the business entity, and failure of timely conciliation; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a complainant on a Commission determination that the complainant has filed a knowingly false or frivolous complaint.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To submit a matter to an administrative hearing as a contested case under this title, the business entity or the complainant must request a contested case hearing by filing a written notice with the Commission within 15 calendar days of notice of the initial findings and recommendations.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice must contain the following information:<section prefix="(i)">a demand that the matter be referred to the Office of Administrative Hearings for a contested case hearing in accordance with &#xA7; 10-205(c)(2) of the State Government Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the names, addresses, and telephone numbers of the Commission, the business entity's representatives, and any other parties;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a reference to this title; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">a summary of the Commission's findings and recommendations that are being submitted for resolution to the administrative law judge for the contested case hearing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The requesting party shall immediately serve notice of the request for a contested case hearing upon all other parties.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the business entity fails to properly request a contested case hearing, the initial findings and recommendations of the Commission shall become the final administrative decision of the State, and the Commission shall then be authorized to enter any order and to take any action reasonably necessary or convenient to:<section prefix="(1)">implement remedies under &#xA7; 19-110 of this title;</section><section prefix="(2)">impose sanctions under &#xA7; 19-111 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(3)">govern the conduct of the parties in the manner described under &#xA7; 19-112 of this title so that the purposes of this title are achieved.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">For each contested case hearing properly requested by the business entity or by the complainant, the Commission shall file a statement of charges with the Office of Administrative Hearings and request a hearing before an administrative law judge in a manner consistent with the requirements of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Commission may designate the venue for the contested case hearing, taking into consideration the convenience of the parties and the location of the evidence.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">At the contested case hearing, the Commission shall have the burden of proof by a preponderance of the evidence.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Office of Administrative Hearings shall conduct any contested case hearing in accordance with its rules of procedure under COMAR 28.02.01.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">At the conclusion of the contested case hearing, the administrative law judge shall issue a written decision.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The administrative law judge's written decision may:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The administrative law judge's written decision shall be solely based on a preponderance of the evidence contained in the record of the contested case hearing and shall reflect the evidentiary basis for its findings.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">An administrative law judge may consider any evidence regarding the factors described in &#xA7; 19-108(a) of this title when determining whether to sustain an allegation presented in a statement of charges.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Notwithstanding any contrary provision in this title, unless the administrative law judge finds that one or more allegations giving rise to the Commission's findings or the business entity's challenge to the findings were frivolous or knowingly false when made, each party shall bear the cost of its own legal representation and expert witness fees.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If the administrative law judge finds that one or more allegations giving rise to the Commission's findings or the business entity's challenge to the findings was frivolous or knowingly false when made, the administrative law judge may require the party who made the frivolous or knowingly false allegations to bear all or a portion of the other party's legal fees and expert witness fees.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The business entity, the Commission, and the complainant shall cooperate in good faith to have the contested case hearing concluded within 180 days after the business entity issues its notice for a contested case hearing.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">If the Commission determines that one or more allegations are knowingly false or frivolous, the complainant making the allegations shall be entitled to a contested case hearing on the allegations that are determined to be knowingly false or frivolous in accordance with the procedures set forth in this section, except that all references to the business entity with respect to matters of contested case hearing rules and procedure shall apply to the complainant.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">If the complainant fails to properly request a contested case hearing regarding a determination of a knowingly false or frivolous allegation as provided in this title, the initial findings and recommendations shall become the final administrative decision of the State in accordance with &#xA7; 19-112 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a timely contested case hearing is not requested, the Commission may vacate the Commission staff's recommended remedy on written notice to all parties within 5 business days after the time for requesting a contested case hearing has expired.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the absence of notice, the Commission shall be deemed to have approved the Commission staff's recommended remedy.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">To the extent that procedures and standards stated in this title differ from those contained in Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article, this title shall govern but, in all other respects, the provisions of the State Government Article shall govern.</section>
  </text>
</law>
