<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5A-335" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-5A-335</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Archaeology Office shall:<section prefix="(1)">cooperate in excavating historically or archaeologically significant sites in the custody or control of any other State unit;</section><section prefix="(2)">encourage the preservation of prehistoric or historic sites on privately owned land in the State;</section><section prefix="(3)">coordinate the work of retrieving and preserving archaeologically significant objects and materials found during public construction in the State;</section><section prefix="(4)">cooperate with and help museums, institutions of higher education, and other scientific or historical institutions and organizations in preserving and protecting objects and materials of archaeological nature in their custody or control;</section><section prefix="(5)">cooperate with similar units of other states in preserving archaeologically significant sites, objects, and materials; and</section><section prefix="(6)">keep institutions or units of other states from exploiting archaeologically significant sites, objects, and materials in this State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Archaeology Office also shall:<section prefix="(1)">make available to museums, institutions of higher education, and other scientific or historical institutions and organizations objects and materials suitable for demonstrating the archaeological history of the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">make available to public and private schools in the State exhibits on, and help to teach students about, the life of the early settlers and Native Americans of the State;</section><section prefix="(3)">disseminate archaeological information by publishing reports of archaeological research and investigation; and</section><section prefix="(4)">establish an educational program to train interested members of the public to identify, investigate, and register terrestrial archaeological historic property.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Archaeology Office also shall:<section prefix="(1)">prepare a list of prioritized research goals and objectives to guide the Trust and the Department's Division of Historical and Cultural Programs in choosing archaeological research projects to perform;</section><section prefix="(2)">develop, in consultation with the Committee, a policy that specifies the circumstances under which the Trust may directly perform archaeological investigations to comply with State or federal law that the Trust or the State Historic Preservation Officer administers; and</section><section prefix="(3)">provide to the Committee each year a copy of the part of the Trust's annual report to the Governor, required by &#xA7; 5A-318(c)(16) of this subtitle, that relates to the Trust's archaeological activities.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, an archaeologist who is not working for the Trust need not adhere to the archaeological research goals and objectives developed by the Archaeology Office under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An archaeologist who performs a project governed by any State or federal law that the Trust or the State Historic Preservation Officer administers shall adhere to those goals and objectives to the extent required by law.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
