<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-5A-336</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>336</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is an Advisory Committee on Archaeology.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Committee consists of seven members appointed by the Governor on recommendation of the Secretary and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Committee shall include representatives of reputable museums, institutions of higher education, other recognized scientific or historical institutions or organizations, and qualified private firms that provide archaeological services.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each member of the Committee shall have skill and knowledge in archaeological matters.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 3 years and begins on July 1.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Committee on October 1, 2005.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Committee shall elect a chair from among its members.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Committee shall meet at least four times a year at the times and places that the chair sets.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At every meeting at least one of the following officers shall attend:<section prefix="(i)">the Chief Archaeologist;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the State Terrestrial Archaeologist; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the State Underwater Archaeologist.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A member of the Committee:<section prefix="(1)">may not receive compensation for duties performed as a member; but</section><section prefix="(2)">is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Committee shall:<section prefix="(1)">advise and assist the Archaeology Office on archaeological matters; and</section><section prefix="(2)">review policies, plans, and regulations relating to archaeological matters.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
