<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-201" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-11-201</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The purposes and policies of this Division II include:<section prefix="(1)">providing for increased confidence in State procurement;</section><section prefix="(2)">ensuring fair and equitable treatment of all persons who deal with the State procurement system;</section><section prefix="(3)">providing safeguards for maintaining a State procurement system of quality and integrity;</section><section prefix="(4)">fostering effective broad-based competition in the State through support of the free enterprise system;</section><section prefix="(5)">promoting increased long-term economic efficiency and responsibility in the State by encouraging the use of recycled materials;</section><section prefix="(6)">providing increased economy in the State procurement system;</section><section prefix="(7)">getting the maximum benefit from the purchasing power of the State;</section><section prefix="(8)">simplifying, clarifying, and modernizing the law that governs State procurement;</section><section prefix="(9)">allowing the continued development of procurement regulations, policies, and practices in the State; and</section><section prefix="(10)">promoting development of uniform State procurement procedures to the extent possible.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Unless otherwise indicated, this Division II shall be construed liberally and applied to promote the purposes and policies enumerated in subsection (a) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a provision of this Division II is inconsistent with a federal law, regulation, or grant agreement or other federal requirement that governs procurement or a procurement contract or with the terms of a gift, as defined in Article 1, &#xA7; 22 of the Code, the federal requirement or the terms of the gift control the procurement or procurement contract.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "bundle" means the consolidation of two or more procurement requirements for supplies or services previously provided or performed under separate contracts into a single solicitation seeking offers for a single contract that is unlikely to be accessible for award to a small business or minority business enterprise.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection does not apply if a unit bundles a procurement for the purpose of participating in the Small Business Reserve Program in accordance with Title 14, Subtitle 5 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For the purpose of precluding or limiting participation by a minority business enterprise as defined under Title 14, Subtitle 3 of this article or a small business as defined under Title 14, Subtitle 2 of this article, a unit subject to this Division II may not:<section prefix="(i)">bundle a procurement;</section><section prefix="(ii)">limit the number of competitive bidders or offerors; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">limit participation to a predetermined group of bidders or offerors.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
