<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-304" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-14-304</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL JULY 1, 2016 PER CHAPTER 154 OF 2012 //<section prefix="(a)"><section prefix="(1)">The certification agency shall develop and maintain a directory of all certified minority business enterprises.</section><section prefix="(2)">The directory shall be accessible to the public through the Internet.</section><section prefix="(3)">For each minority business enterprise included in the directory, the certification agency shall include the following information:<section prefix="(i)">all contract information available to the certification agency for the minority business enterprise;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the certification number and minority status of the minority business enterprise;</section><section prefix="(iii)">contact information for up to three professional references for the minority business enterprise; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">any other information the certification agency considers necessary or appropriate to encourage participation in the procurement process by minority business enterprises.</section></section><section prefix="(4)">The certification agency shall:<section prefix="(i)">update the directory at least monthly;</section><section prefix="(ii)">identify as recently certified in the directory each minority business enterprise that has obtained certification during the calendar year; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">include in the directory a list of all minority business enterprises that have become ineligible to participate in the Minority Business Enterprise Program because:</section></section></section><section prefix="(b)">In the same manner and with the same fees as provided by law in civil cases, in a matter regarding the decertification of a certified minority business enterprise, the certification agency may:<section prefix="(1)">subpoena witnesses;</section><section prefix="(2)">administer oaths; and</section><section prefix="(3)">compel the production of records, books, papers, and other documents.</section></section><section prefix="(c)">If a person fails to comply with a subpoena issued under subsection (b) of this section, or fails to produce documents or other evidence, on petition of the certification agency, a court of competent jurisdiction may pass an order directing compliance with the subpoena or compelling the production of documents or other evidence.</section></text>
</law>
