<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-13-224</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>224</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Children of current or former recipients" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 5-304 of the Human Services Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Department" means the Department of Human Resources.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Eligible contract" means a procurement contract designated by the Board as appropriate for the execution of a hiring agreement.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"FIP" means the Family Investment Program established under Title 5, Subtitle 3 of the Human Services Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Former recipient" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 5-304 of the Human Services Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Foster youth" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 5-304 of the Human Services Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Hiring agreement" means an agreement entered into by the Department or a local department and an entity doing business with the State under which the Department or the local department and the entity agree to work cooperatively in endeavoring to identify and hire current and former FIP recipients, children of current or former recipients, foster youth, and obligors to fill job openings of the entity.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">"Local department" means a local department of social services in a county or in Baltimore City created or continued under &#xA7; 3-201(a) of the Human Services Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(10)">"Obligor" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 10-101 of the Family Law Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On or before October 1, 1998, the Board, in consultation with the Department, shall designate the types of procurement contracts that are eligible contracts.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before December 1, 1998, the Department shall develop a model hiring agreement form that shall be completed by the Department or a local department and an entity in conjunction with the award of an eligible contract.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The model hiring agreement form shall include the following provisions:<section prefix="(i)">the entity will:<section prefix="1.">inform the Department or the local department, as appropriate, of all of the entity's job openings;</section><section prefix="2.">declare the Department or the local department, as appropriate, its "first source" in identifying and hiring candidates to fill those job openings;</section><section prefix="3.">work cooperatively with the Department or the local department, as appropriate, to develop any necessary training programs that will enable current and former FIP recipients, children of current or former recipients, foster youth, and obligors in qualifying for and securing the positions;</section><section prefix="4.">give first preference and first consideration to the extent permitted by law and any existing labor agreements to candidates referred to the entity by the Department or the local department, as appropriate;</section><section prefix="5.">agree to give candidates referred to the entity by the Department or the local department, as appropriate, priority in the filling of a job opening if the candidate meets the qualifications of the position;</section><section prefix="6.">provide the Department or the local department, as appropriate, with information on the disposition of all referrals made by the Department or the local department, as appropriate, including an explanation of why any such candidate was not hired or considered qualified;</section><section prefix="7.">provide the Department or the local department, as appropriate, with information regarding the progress and employment status of those candidates referred by the Department or the local department, as appropriate, that the entity hired; and</section><section prefix="8.">designate a specific individual that the Department or the local department, as appropriate, may contact in regard to the provisions of the hiring agreement; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">the Department or the local department, as appropriate, will assign an account representative to the entity who will:<section prefix="1.">receive and process all of the entity's job notifications;</section><section prefix="2.">refer only screened and qualified candidates to the entity;</section><section prefix="3.">assist in the development of any mutually agreed upon training programs, internship programs, or both that will better prepare current and former FIP recipients, children of current or former recipients, foster youth, and obligors for employment with the entity;</section><section prefix="4.">arrange follow-up and post-hire transitional/supportive services, such as child care and transportation, as necessary and appropriate; and</section><section prefix="5.">review and evaluate the effectiveness of the hiring agreement with the entity and make modifications in the agreement as necessary and appropriate.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each year, the Department and any local departments that have entered into hiring agreements shall submit a report to the Board, the Joint Committee on Welfare Reform, and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly on:<section prefix="(1)">the number of hiring agreements executed;</section><section prefix="(2)">the number of current and former FIP recipients, children of current or former recipients, foster youth, and obligors hired by an entity with which a hiring agreement was executed; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the effectiveness of each hiring agreement in obtaining employment for current and former FIP recipients, children of current or former recipients, foster youth, and obligors.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
