<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="17-201" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-17-201</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle, unless the context indicates otherwise, the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Apprentice" means an individual who:<section prefix="(1)">is at least 16 years old;</section><section prefix="(2)">has signed with an employer or employer's agent, an association of employers, an organization of employees, or a joint committee from both, an agreement including a statement of:<section prefix="(i)">the trade, craft, or occupation that the individual is learning; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the beginning and ending dates of the apprenticeship; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">is registered in a program of the Council or the Bureau of Apprenticeship and Training of the United States Department of Labor.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Commissioner" means:<section prefix="(1)">the Commissioner of Labor and Industry;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Deputy Commissioner of Labor and Industry; or</section><section prefix="(3)">an authorized representative of the Commissioner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Construction" includes all:<section prefix="(1)">building;</section><section prefix="(2)">reconstructing;</section><section prefix="(3)">improving;</section><section prefix="(4)">enlarging;</section><section prefix="(5)">painting and decorating;</section><section prefix="(6)">altering;</section><section prefix="(7)">maintaining; and</section><section prefix="(8)">repairing.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Council" means the Apprenticeship and Training Council.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Employee" means an apprentice or worker employed by a contractor or subcontractor under a public work contract.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Employee" does not include an individual employed by a public body.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Locality" means the county in which the work is to be performed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the public work is located within 2 or more counties, the locality includes all counties in which the public work is located.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Prevailing wage rate" means the hourly rate of wages paid in the locality as determined by the Commissioner under &#xA7; 17-208 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Public body" means:<section prefix="(i)">the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">except as provided in paragraph (2)(i) of this subsection, a unit of the State government or instrumentality of the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">any political subdivision, agency, person, or entity with respect to the construction of any public work for which 50% or more of the money used for construction is State money; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">notwithstanding paragraph (2)(ii) of this subsection, a political subdivision if its governing body:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Public body" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">a unit of the State government or instrumentality of the State funded wholly from a source other than the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">any political subdivision, agency, person, or entity with respect to the construction of any public work for which less than 50% of the money used for construction is State money.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, "public work" means a structure or work, including a bridge, building, ditch, road, alley, waterwork, or sewage disposal plant, that:<section prefix="(i)">is constructed for public use or benefit; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">is paid for wholly or partly by public money.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Public work" does not include, unless let to contract, a structure or work whose construction is performed by a public service company under order of the Public Service Commission or other public authority regardless of:<section prefix="(i)">public supervision or direction; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">payment wholly or partly from public money.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Public work contract" means a contract for construction of a public work.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Worker" means a laborer or mechanic.</section>
  </text>
</law>
