<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5A-333" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-5A-333</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this part the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Archaeology Office" means the Archaeology Office established under &#xA7; 5A-334 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Associated funerary objects" means objects that are reasonably believed to have been placed with individual human remains as a part of the death rite or ceremony of a culture.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Cave" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 5-1401 of the Natural Resources Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Cave" includes:<section prefix="(i)">any naturally occurring void, cavity, recess, cavern, sinkhole, grotto, rock shelter, or system of interconnecting passages beneath the surface of the earth or within a cliff or ledge; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">natural subsurface water and drainage systems.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Committee" means the Advisory Committee on Archaeology.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Human remains" means any part of the body of a deceased human being in any state of decomposition.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Native American" means an individual or a descendant of an individual who inhabited North America before European contact.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Submerged archaeological historic property" means any underwater structure, remains, or object that:<section prefix="(1)">yields or is likely to yield information significant to the study of human prehistory, history, or culture; and</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">is so embedded in underwater land that excavating tools are needed to move the bottom sediments to reach all or part of it and has remained unclaimed for at least 100 years; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">is included or is eligible to be included in the National Register of Historic Places.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
