<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-7-118</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the Secretary shall provide to the General Ass...</catch_line>
  <order_by>118</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the Secretary shall provide to the General Assembly on a biennial basis by no later than February 1 of the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year the report covers, a report that contains a statement of the estimated amount by which exemptions from taxation reduce, for the year:<section prefix="(1)">State revenues; and</section><section prefix="(2)">revenues that the State collects for local governments.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For each exemption, the statement shall:<section prefix="(1)">show the estimated amount by which the exemption reduces revenues;</section><section prefix="(2)">identify the person or the part of the population that benefits from the exemption; and</section><section prefix="(3)">say whether the exemption conflicts with any other State program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The statement shall include:<section prefix="(1)">each subtraction modification under &#xA7; 10-207, &#xA7; 10-208, or &#xA7; 10-209 of the Tax - General Article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">each exemption under:<section prefix="(i)">Title 8, Subtitle 7 of the Natural Resources Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">&#xA7; 5-104, &#xA7; 6-103, &#xA7; 7-203, &#xA7; 7-303, &#xA7; 9-203, &#xA7; 9-303, &#xA7; 9-304, &#xA7; 10-104, &#xA7; 10-211, &#xA7; 10-212, &#xA7; 12-104, or Title 11, Subtitle 2 of the Tax - General Article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Title 7 of the Tax - Property Article; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">&#xA7; 13-810 or &#xA7; 13-903 of the Transportation Article.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Comptroller, the Department of Assessments and Taxation, the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation, the Department of Natural Resources, the Department of Transportation, and other units of the State government shall help the Secretary of Budget and Management to prepare a draft of the statement under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
