<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-5-703</section_number>
  <catch_line>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL DECEMBER 31, 2020 PER CHAPTERS 488 AND 489 OF 2010 //...</catch_line>
  <order_by>703</order_by>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL DECEMBER 31, 2020 PER CHAPTERS 488 AND 489 OF 2010 //<section prefix="(a)"><section prefix="(1)">The Commission consists of the following members:<section prefix="(i)">two members of the House Environmental Matters Committee, appointed by the Speaker of the House;</section><section prefix="(ii)">two members of the Senate Education, Health, and Environmental Affairs Committee, appointed by the President of the Senate;</section><section prefix="(iii)">as ex officio members:<section prefix="1.">the Secretary of Planning, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="2.">the Secretary of the Environment, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="3.">the Secretary of Transportation, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="4.">the Secretary of Housing and Community Development, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="5.">the Secretary of Natural Resources, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="6.">the Secretary of Business and Economic Development, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="7.">the Secretary of Agriculture, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="8.">the Superintendent of the Maryland State Department of Education, or the Superintendent's designee;</section><section prefix="9.">the Chair of the Base Realignment and Closure Subcabinet, or the Chair's designee;</section><section prefix="10.">the Executive Director of the Rural Maryland Council, or the Executive Director's designee; and</section><section prefix="11.">the Director of the University of Maryland's National Center for Smart Growth, or the Director's designee;</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">four representatives of local government:<section prefix="1.">two designated by the Maryland Municipal League; and</section><section prefix="2.">two designated by the Maryland Association of Counties;</section></section><section prefix="(v)">appointed by the Governor:<section prefix="1.">one representative of the smart growth community;</section><section prefix="2.">one representative of the environmental community;</section><section prefix="3.">one representative of the residential building and development community;</section><section prefix="4.">one representative of the commercial building and development community;</section><section prefix="5.">one representative of the agricultural community;</section><section prefix="6.">one representative of a rural community;</section><section prefix="7.">one representative of a citizen organization that addresses housing;</section><section prefix="8.">one representative of a citizen organization that addresses transportation;</section><section prefix="9.">one representative from Western Maryland;</section><section prefix="10.">one representative from Southern Maryland;</section><section prefix="11.">three representatives from the Washington metropolitan area;</section><section prefix="12.">three representatives from the Baltimore metropolitan area; and</section><section prefix="13.">one representative from the Eastern Shore.</section></section></section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">The members representing a region of the State shall have knowledge of smart growth and planning issues.</section><section prefix="(ii)">Of the three members representing the Washington metropolitan area, one shall represent local or regional government.</section><section prefix="(iii)">Of the three members representing the Baltimore metropolitan area, one shall represent local or regional government.</section><section prefix="(iv)">Of the members appointed by the Governor, one shall be an architect that:<section prefix="1.">is licensed to practice in the State; and</section><section prefix="2.">is a resident of the State.</section></section></section></section><section prefix="(b)"><section prefix="(1)">Except for ex officio members or their designees, the term of a member is 5 years.</section><section prefix="(2)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section><section prefix="(3)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section></section><section prefix="(c)">If the Governor appoints a regulated lobbyist to serve as a member of the Commission, the lobbyist:<section prefix="(1)">is not subject to &#xA7; 15-504(d) of the State Government Article with respect to that service; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is not subject to &#xA7; 15-703(f)(3) of the State Government Article as a result of that service.</section></section><section prefix="(d)">A member of the Commission:<section prefix="(1)">may not receive compensation as a member of the Commission; but</section><section prefix="(2)">is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section></text>
</law>
