<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-806" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-4-806</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">So that it can audit and evaluate competing design proposals, the Department, in cooperation with the Maryland Energy Administration, shall set standards for energy performance indices.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">As experience develops on the energy performance achieved in State buildings, the energy performance indices will serve as a measure of building performance with respect to energy consumption.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department, in cooperation with the Maryland Energy Administration, shall set energy performance standards that require the average energy consumption in State buildings be reduced from the level in 2005 as follows:<section prefix="(1)">5% by 2009; and</section><section prefix="(2)">10% by 2010.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subsection (f) of this section, by December 31, 2007, each State agency shall conduct an analysis on each of the buildings under its jurisdiction of its gas and electric consumption and the cost of this consumption under the direction of the Maryland Energy Administration and in coordination with the Department of General Services.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The analysis required in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph shall include an examination of methods to achieve energy and costs savings, including:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">By July 1, 2008, each State agency shall upgrade its energy conservation plan developed in consultation with the Maryland Energy Administration and the Department of General Services to achieve the energy performance standards set under subsection (c) of this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The plan required under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph shall include provisions for the training of State personnel, including management and maintenance personnel, in conservation practices that reduce the consumption of energy and assist the agency in achieving the standards set under subsection (c) of this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">In the development and implementation of the provisions of subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, each agency shall consider alternative financing opportunities in shared savings and performance contracting as administered by the Maryland Energy Administration and include an analysis of the payback and cost advantage to the State of shared savings and performance contracting.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">All plans developed in accordance with subsection (d) of this section shall be filed with the Maryland Energy Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Maryland Energy Administration, in coordination with the Department of General Services, shall review and analyze these plans and submit to the Governor the plans and proposals to implement the plans.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, this section does not apply to a building under the jurisdiction of the Department of Transportation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department of Transportation shall comply with the requirements of this section for any office building under its jurisdiction, if the building contains:<section prefix="(i)">the Department's headquarters; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the administrative offices of a Modal Administration in the Department of Transportation.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
