<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-15-219.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>A unit may assert a contract claim against a contractor by sending written notice to the contractor ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>219.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A unit may assert a contract claim against a contractor by sending written notice to the contractor and the procurement officer that states:<section prefix="(i)">the basis for the contract claim;</section><section prefix="(ii)">to the extent known, the amount, or the performance or other action, requested by the unit in the contract claim; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the date by which the contractor is required to provide a written response to the contract claim.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On receipt of a contract claim from a unit, a procurement officer:<section prefix="(i)">shall review the substance of the contract claim;</section><section prefix="(ii)">may request additional information or substantiation through an appropriate procedure; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">may discuss or, if appropriate, negotiate the contract claim with the unit or contractor.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The procurement officer shall proceed under subsection (b) of this section if the contractor fails to respond, provides an inadequate response, or denies the contract claim or the relief sought by the unit in whole or in part.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the contractor and the unit do not resolve the contract claim, the procurement officer shall prepare a proposed decision on the contract claim, including:<section prefix="(i)">a description of the contract claim;</section><section prefix="(ii)">references to pertinent contract provisions;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a statement of factual areas of agreement or disagreement; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">a statement in the proposed decision wholly or partly granting or denying the relief sought, with supporting rationale.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless otherwise provided by regulation, the procurement officer shall submit the contract claim and proposed decision to:<section prefix="(i)">the head of the unit; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the head of the principal department or other equivalent unit of which the unit is a part.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The reviewing authority shall approve, modify, or disapprove the proposed decision.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In disapproving a proposed decision, the reviewing authority may remand the contract claim with instructions to the procurement officer.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">On remand, the procurement officer shall proceed as required under this subsection and in accordance with the instructions of the reviewing authority.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The decision of the reviewing authority is the final action of the unit.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
