<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-5-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Secretary is responsible for the budget of the Department....</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary is responsible for the budget of the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary may adopt regulations for the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary shall review and shall have the power to approve or disapprove or revise the regulations of all boards, commissions, divisions, and other agencies within the jurisdiction of the Department.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In addition to the meetings of any board or commission within the Department that are provided for by law or are called by the chair of the board or commission, the Secretary, whenever appropriate, may call a meeting of a board or commission to consider any subject that the Secretary considers necessary and proper.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">All boards, commissions, divisions, and other agencies of the Department shall report to the Secretary or the Secretary's designee as provided in regulations or written directives of the Secretary.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Secretary may create any citizens' advisory body that the Secretary considers necessary for the operation of the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Secretary shall have a seal.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary is responsible for the comprehensive planning of programs and services of the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary shall review and approve or disapprove the plans of the units in the Department.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Secretary or a staff member of the Department designated by the Secretary shall have access to information that relates to State planning in the possession of any unit of the State government, of a regional government, or of a local government.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">If the entry is made in a manner so as to cause no unnecessary injury, the Secretary or a staff member of the Department designated by the Secretary may enter, at any reasonable hour, on any land in order to make examinations and surveys that relate to State planning.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">After providing adequate public notice, the Secretary shall hold hearings on matters of State planning whenever it is in the public interest to do so.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">In the interest of intergovernmental cooperation, the Secretary shall attend:<section prefix="(1)">meetings of regional planning commissions;</section><section prefix="(2)">interstate planning conferences; and</section><section prefix="(3)">other planning conferences.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">The Secretary may contract for professional or consultant services for work related to State planning as provided in the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">The Secretary may exercise any power necessary and proper to discharge the Secretary's duties.</section>
  </text>
</law>
