<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-2-602</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>602</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Treasurer shall deposit in a box or vault as provided in subsection (b) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">all of the physical securities that the State owns; and</section><section prefix="(2)">all of the physical securities that, by State law, the Treasurer holds, in trust or otherwise, for a corporation or individual.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With the approval of the Board of Public Works, the Treasurer shall procure a box or vault.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The box or vault shall be located in the offices of the Treasurer.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each box or vault in which securities are kept shall be built so that 2 different keys are needed to gain access to the securities.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Comptroller and the Treasurer each shall have 1 of these keys.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Access to a box or vault in which physical securities are kept under this section shall be permitted only:<section prefix="(i)">when the Governor, the Comptroller, the Chief Deputy Comptroller, or a Deputy Comptroller accompanies the Treasurer; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if access is needed and the Treasurer cannot be present:<section prefix="1.">when the Governor, the Comptroller, the Chief Deputy Comptroller, or a Deputy Comptroller accompanies the Chief Deputy Treasurer; or</section><section prefix="2.">when the Governor, the Comptroller, or the Chief Deputy Comptroller accompanies a Deputy Treasurer.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Treasurer shall determine which physical securities are deposited or held in each box or vault.</section>
  </text>
</law>
