<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-19-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>As a condition of participating in an economic development project, the State shall require the gove...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">As a condition of participating in an economic development project, the State shall require the governmental entity, quasi-governmental entity, corporation, developer, or contractor that receives assistance from the State to comply with this title:<section prefix="(1)">in administering the economic development project; and</section><section prefix="(2)">in awarding contracts to manage or perform the work entailed in the economic development project.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each contract and subcontract awarded in connection with an economic development project shall contain the nondiscrimination clause set forth in &#xA7; 19-115 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any claim of discrimination relating to the economic development project shall be subject to investigation and adjudication by the State in accordance with this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This title does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">other than a lease of real estate for the State's use, any real property acquisition by the State, including property subject to condemnation;</section><section prefix="(2)">settlement of litigation;</section><section prefix="(3)">except for proceedings to enforce this title, settlement of judicial or administrative enforcement proceedings by or on behalf of the State; and</section><section prefix="(4)">agreements concerning standards for locating facilities in a State right-of-way when a business entity has a statutory right to be in the right-of-way.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
