<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="17-221" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-17-221</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each public body that awards a public work contract shall:<section prefix="(1)">take cognizance of a complaint of a violation of this subtitle committed in the course of performance of the public work contract; and</section><section prefix="(2)">when making payments to the contractor, withhold any amount that the contractor owes to its employees or the public body as a result of the violation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner shall institute an investigation as necessary to determine compliance with this subtitle and regulations adopted under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner promptly shall investigate a complaint of a violation of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any written or oral complaint or statement made by an employee is confidential and may not be disclosed to the employer without the consent of the employee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A contractor or subcontractor subject to an investigation under this section shall allow the Commissioner to observe work being performed at the site of a public work project, to interview employees, and to review books and records, to determine:<section prefix="(1)">the correctness of each classification;</section><section prefix="(2)">the ratio of apprentices to mechanics; and</section><section prefix="(3)">payment of straight and overtime prevailing wage rates as required under the public work contract.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If, after investigation, the Commissioner determines that a provision of this subtitle may have been violated, the Commissioner immediately shall notify the public body.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On notification, the public body shall withhold from payment due the contractor or subcontractor an amount sufficient to:<section prefix="(i)">pay each employee of the contractor or subcontractor the full amount of wages due under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">satisfy a liability of a contractor for liquidated damages as provided in &#xA7; 17-222(a) of this subtitle, pending a final determination.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a subcontractor is responsible for a violation of this subtitle, the contractor:<section prefix="(i)">may withhold from payment to the subcontractor an amount equal to the amount withheld from the contractor under paragraph (1) of this subsection; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if payment has been made to the subcontractor, may sue to recover that amount.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commissioner shall:<section prefix="(1)">issue an order for a hearing within 30 days after completing an investigation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">expeditiously conduct the hearing.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 10 days before the hearing, the Commissioner shall serve, personally or by mail, written notice of the hearing on all interested persons, including the public body.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice shall include:<section prefix="(i)">a statement of the facts disclosed in the investigation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the time and place of the hearing.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In conducting an investigation or hearing under this section, the Commissioner is deemed to be acting in a quasi-judicial capacity and may:<section prefix="(i)">issue subpoenas;</section><section prefix="(ii)">administer oaths; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">examine witnesses.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner shall grant each interested person an opportunity to speak at the hearing on matters relevant to the complaint.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After the conclusion of the hearing, the Commissioner shall:<section prefix="(i)">file in the Commissioner's office an order that states the Commissioner's determination; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">serve, personally or by mail, the public body and parties to the hearing with a copy of the order and notice of its filing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Commissioner finds a violation, the Commissioner shall determine the amount of liquidated damages and restitution to be assessed for the violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On the entry and service of a Commissioner's order, the public body, from the money due the contractor or subcontractor, shall:<section prefix="(i)">pay the affected employees the full amount of wages due them; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">satisfy the obligation of the contractor or subcontractor to pay liquidated damages as required under &#xA7; 17-222 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
