<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-5-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Department:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department:<section prefix="(1)">shall provide planning assistance, including surveys, land use studies, urban renewal plans, technical services, and other planning work, to local governments; and</section><section prefix="(2)">may provide financial and other planning assistance to local governments as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department may provide financial or other planning assistance to regional planning agencies as provided in the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before providing the assistance, the Secretary shall consider the adequacy and competency of any regional or local planning agency that requests financial assistance from the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary may require any local government or regional planning agency that receives financial or other planning assistance from the State to submit to the Secretary a copy of its planning budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary may require any local government or regional planning agency that receives financial or other planning assistance from the State to submit to an annual audit of its financial operations related to planning.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The audit shall be performed by the Legislative Auditor or by an auditor or accountant legally qualified to perform municipal audits.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary may accept an audit by the federal unit for a local government that receives financial or other planning assistance from a unit of the federal government.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Whenever the Department requests and receives financial or other assistance from any unit of the federal government for planning assistance to a local government or a regional planning agency, the Department shall satisfy any requirement imposed by federal law.</section>
  </text>
</law>
