<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-7-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Financial records" means the generally accepted budgets, journals, ledgers, reports of expenses and revenue, or other forms of financial documentation that may be required as a condition for receiving State funds.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Health or social welfare organization" means an organization that is operated for the promotion of the public health or social welfare, whether or not the organization is tax exempt under &#xA7; 501(c) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Uniform accounting standards" means:<section prefix="(i)">accounting standards and procedures that the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants has adopted for voluntary health or social welfare organizations; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">uniform standards of an equivalent nature that:<section prefix="1.">are applied consistently; and</section><section prefix="2.">conform to generally accepted accounting principles.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">a dentist;</section><section prefix="(2)">a hospital that the State Health Services Cost Review Commission regulates;</section><section prefix="(3)">a pharmacist; or</section><section prefix="(4)">a physician.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only to a contract for the provision of health or social welfare services between:<section prefix="(i)">a unit of the State government; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a health or social welfare organization or an individual.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A contract with an individual who is a Maryland resident or with a health or social welfare organization incorporated under the laws of this State shall require the individual or the health or social welfare organization to keep financial records in accordance with uniform accounting standards.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A contract with any other individual or private health or social welfare organization may require the individual or private health or social welfare organization to keep financial records in accordance with uniform accounting standards.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A unit of the State government that makes a grant to a private health or social welfare organization shall require the private health or social welfare organization to keep financial records in accordance with uniform accounting standards.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A unit of the State government may not require an individual or a private health or social welfare organization to keep financial records in a manner that is inconsistent with uniform accounting standards.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The chief accountant of a unit of the State government or of the principal department to which the unit is assigned may examine the financial records of an individual or a health or social welfare organization that receives a grant from the unit.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The accountant shall give 30 days' prior notice of an examination under this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraphs (ii) and (iii) of this paragraph, the chief accountant of a unit or of the principal department to which the unit is assigned shall examine any financial records required to be kept under subsection (c) of this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For the financial records required to be kept under subsection (c)(2) of this section, the accountant shall give 30 days' prior notice of the examination under this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">For any financial records required to be kept under subsection (c)(3) of this section, the accountant shall examine the financial records when an examination is authorized by:<section prefix="1.">the secretary of the principal department to which the unit is assigned; or</section><section prefix="2.">if the unit is not assigned to a principal department, the head of the unit.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A unit of the State government may not:<section prefix="(1)">make a grant to an organization that fails to keep financial records in accordance with uniform accounting standards; or</section><section prefix="(2)">make a contract with an organization or individual who fails to keep financial records as required under this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
