<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-305" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-7-305</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "capital expenditure" includes an expenditure for:<section prefix="(1)">acquisition of land, buildings, or equipment; or</section><section prefix="(2)">new construction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">At the end of a fiscal year, the unspent part of an appropriation for a capital expenditure made through the State budget or a supplementary appropriation act other than an enabling act for a general obligation loan:<section prefix="(1)">does not revert to the General Fund; and</section><section prefix="(2)">with the approval of the Board of Public Works, may be carried in a capital account until it is spent in accordance with subsection (c) of this section or until the authority to spend the appropriation for a project terminates.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Money carried in a capital account under subsection (b) of this section may be spent only for a capital purpose.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Unless otherwise provided by law, the authority to spend the appropriation for a project terminates:<section prefix="(1)">2 years after the effective date of the appropriation act that authorizes the project, if:<section prefix="(i)">evidence that a required matching fund will be provided has not been presented to the Board; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">no part of the project is under contract and the Board has not encumbered money for any part of the project;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">1 year after the latest of abandonment, completion, or acceptance of the project; or</section><section prefix="(3)">except to the extent the Board has encumbered money for a State project or program authorized by an appropriation act, 7 years after the effective date of the appropriation act that authorized the project unless:<section prefix="(i)">the appropriation act provides otherwise; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">in an emergency, the Board unanimously grants a temporary exception for 1 year.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
