<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-7-327</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Mortgage Loan Servicing Practices Settlement Fund....</catch_line>
  <order_by>327</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Mortgage Loan Servicing Practices Settlement Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund is a continuing, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except for restitution and funds designated as fines, civil penalties, and money that are otherwise required under Maryland law, a judgment, or a settlement agreement to be paid into the General Fund of the State, there shall be credited to the Fund all revenues consisting of funds received by the State from any source resulting, directly or indirectly, from any judgment against or settlement with bank mortgage servicers or any other person in the mortgage servicing industry relating to litigation, administrative proceedings, or any other claims made or prosecuted by the State to recover damages for violations of State law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Treasurer shall:<section prefix="(1)">invest and reinvest the Fund in the same manner as other State funds; and</section><section prefix="(2)">credit any investment earnings to the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Expenditures from the Fund shall be made by an appropriation in the annual State budget or may be transferred by budget amendment.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund shall be expended subject to any restrictions on its use or other limitations on its allocation that are:<section prefix="(i)">expressly provided by statute; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">required as a condition of the acceptance of funds.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">It is the intent of the General Assembly that disbursements from the Fund to programs funded by the State or with federal funds administered by the State shall be used as provided in this section solely to supplement, and not to supplant, funds otherwise available for the programs under federal or State law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Mortgage Loan Servicing Practices Settlement Fund shall be used for housing and foreclosure-relief purposes and for related investigation and enforcement activities, including:<section prefix="(i)">the provision of housing counseling;</section><section prefix="(ii)">legal assistance related to foreclosure and housing activities;</section><section prefix="(iii)">criminal or civil investigations of fraud related to housing and the securitization of mortgage loans;</section><section prefix="(iv)">relevant enforcement activities;</section><section prefix="(v)">foreclosure prevention, remediation, and restitution;</section><section prefix="(vi)">programs to address community blight;</section><section prefix="(vii)">programs reasonably targeted to benefit persons harmed by mortgage fraud; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">any other public purpose reasonably related to housing and foreclosure relief.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The provisions of this subsection may not be construed to affect the Governor's powers with respect to a request for an appropriation in the annual budget bill.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">For each program, project, or activity under subsection (f)(1) of this section for which funds are appropriated, the Governor shall:<section prefix="(1)">develop appropriate statements of vision, mission, key goals, objectives, and performance indicators and report these statements in a discrete part of the State budget submission, which shall also provide data for key performance indicators; and</section><section prefix="(2)">on or before October 1 of each year until 2016, report, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly on:<section prefix="(i)">total funds expended, by program and subdivision, in the prior fiscal year from the Fund established under this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the specific outcomes or public benefits resulting from that expenditure.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
