<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-11-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, this Division II does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">procurement by:<section prefix="(i)">the Blind Industries and Services of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Maryland State Arts Council, for the support of the arts;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Maryland Health and Higher Educational Facilities Authority, if no State money is to be spent on a procurement contract;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Maryland Industrial Training Program or the Partnership for Workforce Quality Program in the Department of Business and Economic Development, for training services or programs for new or expanding businesses or industries or businesses or industries in transition;</section><section prefix="(v)">the Maryland Food Center Authority, to the extent the Authority is exempt under Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the Economic Development Article;</section><section prefix="(vi)">the Maryland Public Broadcasting Commission:<section prefix="1.">for services of artists for educational and cultural television productions; or</section><section prefix="2.">when planning for or fulfilling the obligations of grants or cooperative agreements that support the educational and cultural activities of the Commission;</section></section><section prefix="(vii)">public institutions of higher education, for cultural, entertainment, and intercollegiate athletic procurement contracts;</section><section prefix="(viii)">the Maryland State Planning Council on Developmental Disabilities, for services to support demonstration, pilot, and training programs;</section><section prefix="(ix)">the Maryland Automobile Insurance Fund;</section><section prefix="(x)">the Maryland Historical Trust for:<section prefix="1.">surveying and evaluating architecturally, archeologically, historically, or culturally significant properties; and</section><section prefix="2.">other than as to architectural services, preparing historic preservation planning documents and educational material;</section></section><section prefix="(xi)">the University of Maryland, for University College Overseas Programs, if the University adopts regulations that:<section prefix="1.">establish policies and procedures governing procurement for University College Overseas Programs; and</section><section prefix="2.">promote the purposes stated in &#xA7; 11-201(a) of this subtitle;</section></section><section prefix="(xii)">the Department of Business and Economic Development, for negotiating and entering into private sector cooperative marketing projects that directly enhance promotion of Maryland and the tourism industry where there will be a private sector contribution to the project of not less than 50% of the total cost of the project, if the project is reviewed by the Attorney General and approved by the Secretary of Business and Economic Development or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(xiii)">the Rural Maryland Council;</section><section prefix="(xiv)">the Maryland State Lottery Agency, for negotiating and entering into private sector cooperative marketing projects that directly enhance promotion of the Maryland State Lottery and its products, if the cooperative marketing project:<section prefix="1.">provides a substantive promotional or marketing value that the lottery determines acceptable in exchange for advertising or other promotional activities provided by the lottery;</section><section prefix="2.">does not involve the advertising or other promotion of alcohol or tobacco products; and</section><section prefix="3.">is reviewed by the Attorney General and approved by the Maryland Lottery Director or the Director's designee;</section></section><section prefix="(xv)">the Maryland Health Insurance Plan established under Title 14, Subtitle 5 of the Insurance Article;</section><section prefix="(xvi)">the Maryland Energy Administration, when negotiating or entering into grants or cooperative agreements with private entities to meet federal specifications or solicitation requirements related to energy conservation, energy efficiency, or renewable energy projects that benefit the State;</section><section prefix="(xvii)">the Maryland Developmental Disabilities Administration of the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene for family and individual support services, and individual family care services, as those terms are defined by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene in regulation;</section><section prefix="(xviii)">the Department of General Services for the renovation of a structure that:<section prefix="1.">was built during the 18th or 19th century; and</section><section prefix="2.">is listed in or eligible for listing in the National Register of Historic Places; and</section></section><section prefix="(xix)">the Department of Natural Resources, for negotiating or entering into grants, agreements, or partnerships with nonprofit entities related to conservation service opportunities;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">procurement by a unit from:<section prefix="(i)">another unit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a political subdivision of the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an agency of a political subdivision of the State;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a government, including the government of another state, of the United States, or of another country;</section><section prefix="(v)">an agency or political subdivision of a government; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">a bistate, multistate, bicounty, or multicounty governmental agency; or</section></section><section prefix="(3)">procurement in support of enterprise activities for the purpose of:<section prefix="(i)">direct resale; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">remanufacture and subsequent resale.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The following provisions of this Division II apply to each procurement enumerated in subsection (a) of this section:<section prefix="(i)">&#xA7; 11-205 of this subtitle ("Collusion");</section><section prefix="(ii)">&#xA7; 10-204 of this article ("Approval for designated contracts");</section><section prefix="(iii)">Title 12, Subtitle 2 of this article ("Supervision of Capital Expenditures and Real Property Leases");</section><section prefix="(iv)">&#xA7; 13-219 of this article ("Required clauses - Nondiscrimination clause");</section><section prefix="(v)">&#xA7; 13-221 of this article ("Disclosures to Secretary of State");</section><section prefix="(vi)">Title 12, Subtitle 4 of this article ("Policies and Procedures for Exempt Units");</section><section prefix="(vii)">Title 16 of this article ("Suspension and Debarment of Contractors"); and</section><section prefix="(viii)">Title 17 of this article ("Special Provisions - State and Local Subdivisions").</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A procurement by an entity listed in subsection (a)(1)(i) through (xiii) and (xvii) of this section shall be made under procedures that promote the purposes stated in &#xA7; 11-201(a) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A unit that procures human, social, or educational services from an entity enumerated in subsection (a)(2) of this section shall publish in eMaryland Marketplace notice of a procurement contract or an extension or renewal of a procurement contract if:<section prefix="1.">the procurement contract, extension, or renewal costs more than $25,000; and</section><section prefix="2.">the procurement is made for 3rd party clients described in &#xA7; 13-106 of this article.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The notice required under this paragraph shall be published not more than 30 days after the execution and approval of the procurement contract or the extension or renewal of the procurement contract.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The purchase of advisory services from the General Selection Board or the Transportation Selection Board under &#xA7; 13-305 of this article shall be governed by the Maryland Architectural and Engineering Services Act.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as provided in Title 12, Subtitle 4 and Title 14, Subtitle 3 of this article, this Division II does not apply to the Maryland Stadium Authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as provided in Title 12, Subtitle 4 and Title 14, Subtitle 3 of this article, this Division II does not apply to the Board of Trustees of the State Retirement and Pension System for:<section prefix="(1)">services of managers to invest the assets of the State Retirement and Pension System, including real and personal property;</section><section prefix="(2)">expenditures to manage, maintain, and enhance the value of the assets of the State Retirement and Pension System in accordance with investment guidelines adopted by the Board of Trustees;</section><section prefix="(3)">services related to the administration of the optional retirement program under Title 30 of the State Personnel and Pensions Article; and</section><section prefix="(4)">services related to the administration of the Postretirement Health Benefits Trust Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "University" means the University System of Maryland, Morgan State University, or St. Mary's College of Maryland.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, this Division II does not apply to the University System of Maryland, Morgan State University, or St. Mary's College of Maryland.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A procurement by a University shall comply with the policies and procedures developed by the University and approved by the Board of Public Works and the Administrative, Executive, and Legislative Review Committee of the General Assembly in accordance with &#xA7; 12-112 of the Education Article for the University System of Maryland, &#xA7; 14-109 of the Education Article for Morgan State University, or &#xA7; 14-405(f) of the Education Article for St. Mary's College of Maryland.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">The review and approval of the Board of Public Works shall be required for the following types of contracts with a value that exceeds $1,000,000:</section>
          <section prefix="2.">In its review of a contract for services or capital improvements with a value that exceeds $1,000,000, the Board of Public Works may request the comments of the appropriate agencies, including the Department of Budget and Management and the Department of General Services.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A University's policies shall:<section prefix="(i)">to the maximum extent practicable, require the purchasing of supplies and services in accordance with Title 14, Subtitle 1 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">promote the purposes of the regulations adopted by the Department of General Services governing the procurement of architectural and engineering services.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in paragraph (7) of this subsection, the following provisions of Division II of this article apply to a University:<section prefix="1.">&#xA7; 11-205 of this subtitle ("Collusion");</section><section prefix="2.">&#xA7; 11-205.1 of this subtitle ("Falsification, concealment, etc., of material facts");</section><section prefix="3.">&#xA7; 13-219 of this article ("Required clauses - Nondiscrimination clause");</section><section prefix="4.">&#xA7; 13-225 of this article ("Retainage");</section><section prefix="5.">Title 14, Subtitle 3 of this article ("Minority Business Participation");</section><section prefix="6.">Title 15, Subtitle 1 of this article ("Procurement Contract Administration");</section><section prefix="7.">&#xA7; 15-226 of this article ("Policy established; timing of payments; notice upon nonpayment; disputes; appeals"); and</section><section prefix="8.">Title 16 of this article ("Suspension and Debarment of Contractors").</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a procurement violates the provisions of this subsection or policies adopted in accordance with this subsection, the procurement contract is void or voidable in accordance with the provisions of &#xA7; 11-204 of this subtitle.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The State Board of Contract Appeals shall have authority over contract claims related to procurement contracts awarded by:<section prefix="1.">the University System of Maryland before July 1, 1999; and</section><section prefix="2.">Morgan State University before July 1, 2004.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">At the election of the Board of Regents of the University System of Maryland and subject to the approval of the Board of Public Works, the State Board of Contract Appeals shall have authority over contract claims related to procurement contracts awarded by the University after June 30, 1999.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">At the election of the Board of Regents of Morgan State University and subject to the approval of the Board of Public Works, the State Board of Contract Appeals shall have authority over contract claims related to procurement contracts awarded by the University after June 30, 2004.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">At the election of the Board of Trustees of St. Mary's College of Maryland and subject to the approval of the Board of Public Works, the State Board of Contract Appeals shall have authority over contract claims related to procurement contracts awarded by St. Mary's College of Maryland after June 30, 2006.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Paragraphs (3), (4), and (5) of this subsection do not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">procurement by a University from:<section prefix="1.">another unit;</section><section prefix="2.">a political subdivision of the State;</section><section prefix="3.">an agency of a political subdivision of the State;</section><section prefix="4.">a government, including the government of another state, of the United States, or of another country;</section><section prefix="5.">an agency or political subdivision of a government; or</section><section prefix="6.">a bistate, multistate, bicounty, or multicounty governmental agency;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">procurement by a University in support of enterprise activities for the purpose of:<section prefix="1.">direct resale;</section><section prefix="2.">remanufacture and subsequent resale; or</section><section prefix="3.">procurement by the University for overseas programs; or</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">procurement by the University System of Maryland for:<section prefix="1.">services of managers to invest, in accordance with the management and investment policies adopted by the Board of Regents of the University System of Maryland, gift and endowment assets received by the University System of Maryland in accordance with &#xA7; 12-104(e) of the Education Article; or</section><section prefix="2.">expenditures to manage, maintain, and enhance, in accordance with the management and investment policies adopted by the Board of Regents of the University System of Maryland, the value of gift and endowment assets received by the University System of Maryland in accordance with &#xA7; 12-104(e) of the Education Article.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Except as provided in Title 12, Subtitle 4 and Title 14, Subtitle 3 of this article, this Division II does not apply to the College Savings Plans of Maryland for:<section prefix="(1)">services of managers to invest the assets of the Maryland Prepaid College Trust in accordance with the comprehensive investment plan adopted by the College Savings Plans of Maryland Board under &#xA7; 18-1906 of the Education Article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">expenditures to manage, maintain, and enhance the value of the assets of the Maryland Prepaid College Trust in accordance with the comprehensive investment plan adopted by the College Savings Plans of Maryland Board under &#xA7; 18-1906 of the Education Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">This Division II does not apply to a contract or grant awarded by a unit of State government to the Chesapeake Bay Trust for a project involving the restoration or protection of the Chesapeake Bay and other aquatic and land resources of the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
