<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-15-110</section_number>
  <catch_line>The following persons are subject to an audit of books, accounts, or records:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>110</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The following persons are subject to an audit of books, accounts, or records:<section prefix="(1)">before the expiration of the period of retention under subsection (c) of this section, a person who submits cost and price information under &#xA7; 13-220 of this article, if the books, accounts, or records being audited are reasonably connected with the cost and price information;</section><section prefix="(2)">a contractor or subcontractor under a procurement contract if, from an audit of a cost-type contract, the unit has reason to believe that costs have been inappropriately assigned to the cost-type contract from a fixed-price contract; and</section><section prefix="(3)">a contractor or subcontractor under a procurement contract that:<section prefix="(i)">was awarded by a method other than competitive sealed bids; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is not a firm fixed-price procurement contract.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An audit under this section may be conducted by:<section prefix="(1)">the Department of Legislative Services;</section><section prefix="(2)">a unit engaged in procurement; or</section><section prefix="(3)">as authorized by law, any other unit.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person subject to an audit under subsection (a) of this section shall keep books, accounts, and records for:<section prefix="(1)">at least 3 years after the day on which the person receives final payment under a procurement contract or a subcontract; or</section><section prefix="(2)">if longer, the period required under the procurement contract.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
