<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-7-121</section_number>
  <catch_line>The budget books shall contain a section that, by unit of the State government, sets forth, for each...</catch_line>
  <order_by>121</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The budget books shall contain a section that, by unit of the State government, sets forth, for each program or purpose of that unit:<section prefix="(1)">the total number of officers and employees and the number in each job classification:<section prefix="(i)">authorized in the State budget for the last full fiscal year and the current fiscal year; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">requested for the next fiscal year;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the total amount for salaries of officers and employees and the amount for salaries of each job classification:<section prefix="(i)">spent during the last full fiscal year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">authorized in the State budget for the current fiscal year; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">requested for the next fiscal year;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">an itemized statement of the expenditures for contractual services, supplies and materials, equipment, land and structures, fixed charges, and other operating expenses:<section prefix="(i)">made in the last full fiscal year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">authorized in the State budget for the current fiscal year; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">requested for the next fiscal year; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">the StateStat or managing for results agency strategic plan required under this article that shall be limited to a description of the agency's mission, goals, objectives, and performance measures.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In its annual submission of the proposed budget, the Department of Budget and Management shall provide, for informational purposes, a budget presentation that includes a description of the proposed expenditures under the Maryland Emergency Medical System Operations Fund for the:<section prefix="(1)">Maryland Institute for Emergency Medical Services Systems;</section><section prefix="(2)">R Adams Cowley Shock Trauma Center;</section><section prefix="(3)">Maryland Fire and Rescue Institute;</section><section prefix="(4)">Aviation Division of the Special Operations Bureau, Department of State Police; and</section><section prefix="(5)">grants under the Senator William H. Amoss Fire, Rescue, and Ambulance Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Cancer Program" means the Cancer Prevention, Education, Screening, and Treatment Program established under Title 13, Subtitle 11 of the Health - General Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Tobacco Program" means the Tobacco Use Prevention and Cessation Program established under Title 13, Subtitle 10 of the Health - General Article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The budget books shall contain a budget presentation that provides an overview of the proposed expenditures for:<section prefix="(i)">the Tobacco Program, including the proposed expenditures for:<section prefix="1.">each Component of the Tobacco Program;</section><section prefix="2.">each program funded under each Component of the Tobacco Program; and</section><section prefix="3.">each Local Public Health Tobacco Grant;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">the Cancer Program, including the proposed expenditures for:<section prefix="1.">each Component of the Cancer Program;</section><section prefix="2.">each program funded under each Component of the Cancer Program;</section><section prefix="3.">each Local Public Health Cancer Grant;</section><section prefix="4.">each statewide Academic Health Center Public Health Grant;</section><section prefix="5.">each statewide Academic Health Center Cancer Research Grant;</section><section prefix="6.">each statewide Academic Health Center Tobacco-Related Diseases Research Grant; and</section><section prefix="7.">each statewide Academic Health Center Network Grant; and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">any other program that is funded with the Cigarette Restitution Fund established under &#xA7; 7-317 of this title.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
