<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-5A-346</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person who violates &#xA7; 5A-339, &#xA7; 5A-341, &#xA7; 5A-342, or &#xA7; 5A-343 of this subtitle, or a regulatio...</catch_line>
  <order_by>346</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who violates &#xA7; 5A-339, &#xA7; 5A-341, &#xA7; 5A-342, or &#xA7; 5A-343 of this subtitle, or a regulation adopted under any of those sections is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 30 days or a fine not exceeding $1,000 or both.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a person is found guilty of a violation under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the court:<section prefix="(i)">may impose costs against the person; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">on request by the Trust, may revoke any permit issued to the person under &#xA7; 5A-340, &#xA7; 5A-341, &#xA7; 5A-342, or &#xA7; 5A-343 of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each day on which a violation occurs is a separate violation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who violates any term of a permit issued under &#xA7; 5A-341 of this subtitle for use of a submerged archaeological historic property for commercial salvage or other income-producing purpose is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 1 year or a fine not exceeding $10,000 or both.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a person is found guilty of a violation under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the court:<section prefix="(i)">may impose costs against the person; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">on request by the Trust, may revoke the person's permit.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each day on which a violation occurs is a separate violation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Materials and recorded information obtained in violation of &#xA7; 5A-339, &#xA7; 5A-341, &#xA7; 5A-342, or &#xA7; 5A-343 of this subtitle are subject to appropriation by the State and will be managed, cared for, and administered by the Trust.</section>
  </text>
</law>
