<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-3A-501</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>501</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the Governor's Advisory Board for Telecommunications Relay.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Communications company" means a public service company, as defined in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Public Utilities Article, or any other company, that provides a communications service.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Communications service" means:<section prefix="(1)">landline telephone service;</section><section prefix="(2)">wireless or cellular telephone service; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Voice over Internet Protocol (VoIP) service, as defined in &#xA7; 8-601 of the Public Utilities Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Dual party telephone relay program" means a service that provides full and simultaneous communication between a person or persons with a disability that prevents them from using a standard telephone and a person or persons without that disability using conventional telephone equipment or other technology or equipment, whereby the disabled person or persons have their message relayed through an intermediary party using specialized telecommunications equipment.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Program" means the dual party telephone relay program.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Program participant" means a resident of the State who uses the dual party telephone relay program.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Specialized customer telephone equipment" means any communications device that enables or assists a person with a disability to communicate with others by means of the public switched telephone network or Internet protocol-enabled voice communications service.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Specialized customer telephone equipment" includes:<section prefix="(i)">TDD/TT/TTY;</section><section prefix="(ii)">amplifiers;</section><section prefix="(iii)">captioned telephones;</section><section prefix="(iv)">VRS equipment;</section><section prefix="(v)">cell phones;</section><section prefix="(vi)">pagers;</section><section prefix="(vii)">puff blow devices;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Braille-TTY devices; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">equipment for the mobility disabled.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Telecommunications device for the deaf" or "TDD/TT/TTY" means all types of mechanical devices that enable disabled individuals to communicate through messages sent and received through a telephone or wireless network.</section>
  </text>
</law>
