<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-13-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>Whenever procurement is based on competitive sealed bids, a procurement officer shall seek bids by i...</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whenever procurement is based on competitive sealed bids, a procurement officer shall seek bids by issuing an invitation for bids.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to subsection (b) of this section, an invitation for bids shall include:<section prefix="(i)">the specifications of the procurement contract, including the expected degree of minority business enterprise participation, as provided in &#xA7; 14-303(b) of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">whether the procurement contract will be awarded based on the lowest bid price, the lowest evaluated bid price or, if the procurement is subject to &#xA7; 11-202(3) of this article, the bid most favorable to the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">if the procurement contract will be based on evaluated bid price, the objective measurable criteria by which the lowest evaluated bid price will be determined; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">if the Secretary of General Services, the Secretary of Transportation, or the Chancellor of the University System of Maryland has so designated, the small business preference.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whenever a procurement officer determines that an initial preparation of specifications for price bids is impracticable, the invitation for bids may:<section prefix="(i)">include a request for unpriced technical offers or samples; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">direct bidders to submit price bids:<section prefix="1.">with the unpriced technical offers or samples; or</section><section prefix="2.">after the unit evaluates the technical offers or samples and finds that they are acceptable under the criteria set forth in the invitation for bids.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A unit shall consider the prices submitted by bidders whose technical offers or samples have been found acceptable.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Price bids may not be opened until after the unit has completed evaluation of the technical offers or samples.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A price bid may not be opened at any time if the bid is submitted by a bidder whose technical offer or sample has been evaluated as unacceptable to the unit.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A procurement officer shall return an unopened price bid submitted by a bidder whose technical offer or sample has been evaluated as unacceptable.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A unit shall give public notice of an invitation for bids before bid opening in accordance with this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A unit shall give reasonable notice that shall be at least 10 days before bid opening.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Until July 1, 2006, the unit shall publish notice in the Contract Weekly, Contract Weekly Online, and eMaryland Marketplace at least 20 days before bid opening if:<section prefix="(i)">the procurement officer reasonably expects bid prices to exceed $25,000 or a lower amount set by the Board by regulation in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 1 of the State Government Article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">at least part of the procurement contract is to be performed in this State or the District of Columbia.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On and after July 1, 2006, the unit shall publish the notice required under paragraph (3) of this subsection in eMaryland Marketplace.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In addition to any notice required under this subsection, a unit may publish notice of an invitation for bids:<section prefix="(i)">on a bid board or eMaryland Marketplace; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">in a newspaper, periodical, or trade journal.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A procurement officer shall:<section prefix="(i)">open bids in public at the time and place designated in the invitation for bids; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">announce, record, and post:<section prefix="1.">the name of each bidder; and</section><section prefix="2.">the amount of each bid.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, a bid is irrevocable, after bid opening, for the period specified in the invitation for bids.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A procurement officer may allow a bidder to correct or withdraw a bid if correction or withdrawal is:<section prefix="(i)">allowed under regulations adopted under this Division II; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">approved in writing by the Office of the Attorney General.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After obtaining any approval required by law, the procurement officer shall award the procurement contract to the responsible bidder who submits the responsive bid that:<section prefix="(i)">is the lowest bid price;</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the invitation for bids so provides, is the lowest evaluated bid price; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">for procurement subject to &#xA7; 11-202(3) of this article, is the bid most favorable to the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If, after competitive sealed bids have been opened, a procurement officer determines that only 1 responsible bidder has submitted a responsive bid, the unit may negotiate the procurement contract with that 1 bidder under the procedure for sole source procurement.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">After competitive sealed bids have been opened, a procurement officer may award a procurement contract on the basis of revised bids if:<section prefix="1.">all bids are rejected under &#xA7; 13-206(b) of this title;</section><section prefix="2.">all bid prices exceed the funds available for the procurement; or</section><section prefix="3.">with the approval of the head of the unit or a designee, the procurement officer determines that all bids are unreasonable as to at least 1 requirement and the delay that would result from issuing a new invitation for bids with revised specifications or quantities would be fiscally disadvantageous or otherwise not in the best interests of the State.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If there is more than 1 bidder, discussions about revised specifications or quantities shall be conducted with all responsible bidders who submitted responsive bids. The bidders shall be treated fairly and equally with respect to any discussions.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">As promptly as possible, the procurement officer shall:<section prefix="1.">issue an invitation for revised bids, which shall state whether the award will be made without competitive negotiations; and</section><section prefix="2.">require a prompt response to that invitation.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">An invitation for revised bids is not subject to the notice requirements in subsection (c) of this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">After revised bids have been submitted, negotiations with bidders may not be conducted unless the procurement officer determines that there is a compelling reason to negotiate.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">After revised bids have been opened and any approval required by law has been obtained, the procurement officer shall award the procurement contract to the responsible bidder who submits a responsive bid that:<section prefix="1.">is the lowest bid price;</section><section prefix="2.">if the invitation for revised bids so provides, is the lowest evaluated bid price; or</section><section prefix="3.">for procurement subject to &#xA7; 11-202(3) of this article, is the bid most favorable to the State.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A responsible bid or proposal shall include the criteria specified in subsection (a) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Not more than 30 days after the execution and approval of a procurement contract in excess of $25,000 awarded under this section, or a lower amount set by the Board by regulation in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 1 of the State Government Article, a unit shall publish notice of the award:<section prefix="(1)">until July 1, 2006, in the Contract Weekly and eMaryland Marketplace; and</section><section prefix="(2)">on and after July 1, 2006, in eMaryland Marketplace.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
