<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-2-603</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to the limitations in this section and notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Treas...</catch_line>
  <order_by>603</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the limitations in this section and notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Treasurer may lend to a bank or securities broker any security that is owned by the State and is in the custody of the Treasurer.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Treasurer and the bank or broker to whom a loan is to be made under this section shall make a written contract that governs the loan.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The contract shall set forth:<section prefix="(i)">the term of the loan;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the consideration for the loan;</section><section prefix="(iii)">any provisions that the Treasurer determines are needed to protect the interests of the State; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">any other conditions of the loan.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Consideration for a loan under this section may not be less than the current market lending rate for the securities on loan.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The bank or broker to whom a loan is to be made under this section shall deposit with the Treasurer collateral with a value that equals or exceeds the value of the securities on loan.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Collateral that may be used under this section shall be:<section prefix="(i)">money; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a security in which the Treasurer may invest under &#xA7; 6-222 or &#xA7; 6-223 of this article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Treasurer may enter into a contractual agreement with a financial institution to lend, as agent, securities owned by the State and in the custody of the Treasurer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The financial institution shall provide security or indemnification acceptable to the Treasurer.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
