<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-3A-601</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>601</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the Governor's Advisory Board for Telecommunications Relay established in Subtitle 5 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Program" means the program developed and administered by the Department in consultation with the Board and the Department of Disabilities to provide financial assistance for the purchase of specialized customer telephone equipment by eligible program participants.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Program participant" means a person who:<section prefix="(1)">is a resident of the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">is certified by a licensed professional as having a disability which seriously limits or prohibits the use of the telephone or wireless network without specialized customer telephone equipment;</section><section prefix="(3)">is certified by a licensed professional as being able to use specialized customer telephone equipment for which application is made;</section><section prefix="(4)">meets the financial eligibility requirements established by the Department in consultation with the Department of Disabilities as a recipient of:<section prefix="(i)">Transitional Emergency Medical and Housing Assistance (TEMHA);</section><section prefix="(ii)">Supplemental Security Income (SSI);</section><section prefix="(iii)">Social Security Disability Income (SSDI); or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (TANF); and</section></section><section prefix="(5)">at the time of application is not receiving similar services which are available and can be provided in a timely manner through another program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Qualified entity" means a nonprofit organization that:<section prefix="(1)">produces audio editions of daily newspapers, available for interstate distribution using high-speed computer and telecommunications technology; and</section><section prefix="(2)">provides a means of program administration and reader registration on the Internet.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Specialized customer telephone equipment" or "equipment" means any communications device designed to assist program participants in using a telephone or wireless service provider's network.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"System" means the method which the Department shall use to provide equipment to eligible program participants.</section>
  </text>
</law>
