<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-10-402</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Board may not convey any title to land covered by this subtitle to any person other than the rip...</catch_line>
  <order_by>402</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board may not convey any title to land covered by this subtitle to any person other than the riparian owner or proprietor of the land abutting the land conveyed.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board may convey title to land covered by this subtitle only after seeking the advice of:<section prefix="(1)">the Department of Natural Resources;</section><section prefix="(2)">appropriate agricultural agencies, including:<section prefix="(i)">the Maryland Agricultural Commission;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the agricultural stabilization and conservation committee of the county in which the land lies; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the soil conservation district committee of the county in which the land lies; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">other interested federal and State agencies.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before the Board may convey title to land covered by this subtitle, the Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">hold a public hearing, after proper notice, in the county in which the land lies; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">issue a written decision that justifies the action of the Board, taking into account the best interests of the State with respect to the varying ecological, economic, developmental, agricultural, recreational, and aesthetic values of the area under consideration.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The written decision issued under this subsection shall be kept among the permanent records of the Board and be open to public inspection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
