<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsf" order_by="gsf" level="1">State Financial and Procurement</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsf-3-609</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Construction Contingency Fund....</catch_line>
  <order_by>609</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Construction Contingency Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Fund is a continuing, nonlapsing, revolving fund that consists of:<section prefix="(1)">money appropriated to the Fund:<section prefix="(i)">in the annual budget; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">in an annual General Construction Loan Act or in a Maryland Consolidated Capital Bond Loan Act; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">unspent proceeds of an enabling act allocated to the Fund by the Governor under &#xA7; 8-129 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(3)">the amount of an appropriation in an annual General Construction Loan Act or in a Maryland Consolidated Capital Bond Loan Act that is in excess of the amount needed for a project included in the Act and that is allocated to the Fund by the Governor.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An appropriation or allocation to the Fund may not be made if it would cause the total balance in the Fund to exceed 1.25% of the capital debt affordability limit, determined under Title 8 of this article, for that year.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">With the advice and assistance of the Departments of Budget and Management and General Services, the Fund shall be administered by the Board of Public Works.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">With the approval of the Governor, the Secretaries of Budget and Management and General Services may request the Board of Public Works to authorize an expenditure from the Fund to supplement any capital appropriation or to conduct value engineering on a project:<section prefix="(1)">that is for a capital project to be owned by the State or a unit of the State government;</section><section prefix="(2)">that was contained in a capital appropriation of an annual budget, in an annual general construction loan, or in an annual Maryland consolidated capital bond loan; and</section><section prefix="(3)"><section prefix="(i)">that is insufficient in amount to permit the initial award of a contract for the project to the bidder or offeror selected in accordance with applicable State law, or to cover change orders during construction of the project which do not increase the scope of the project; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if, in the belief of the Department of General Services or at the request of the budget committees, the project cost could be reduced or quality improved through the use of value engineering.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Secretaries of Budget and Management and General Services shall evaluate any project for additional funding and certify in writing that the project meets the criteria in subsection (e) of this section and that:<section prefix="(1)">all reasonable attempts to reduce the cost of the project have been made;</section><section prefix="(2)">no practicable alternative exists for securing funding to complete the project; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the requested additional funding does not increase the scope of the project.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Prior to seeking approval from the Board of Public Works, the Department of General Services and the Department of Budget and Management shall:<section prefix="(i)">provide written notice to the budget committees on the planned use of the funds; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">allow 45 days for review and comment by the budget committees.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each time an expenditure from the Fund is authorized by the Board of Public Works, the amount specified by the Board of Public Works may be transferred from the account to the appropriate annuity bond account to supplement the specified authorization.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">By January 1 of each year, the Secretaries of Budget and Management and General Services shall submit a report, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly on the moneys:<section prefix="(1)">appropriated to the Fund;</section><section prefix="(2)">authorized for expenditure from the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(3)">expended from the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Money in the Fund shall be deposited with the State Treasurer.</section>
  </text>
</law>
