<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-2-1609</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1609</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An investigating committee may hold any hearing that the investigating committee considers appropriate, at the times and places that it determines.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The rules of an investigating committee shall provide for written notice of a hearing to be given to the members:<section prefix="(i)">at least 3 days before the hearing, if it is held when the General Assembly is in session; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">at least 7 days before the hearing, if it is held when the General Assembly is not in session.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notice of a hearing shall include a statement of the subject matter.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A hearing and action that is taken at a hearing are not invalid only because notice is not given as provided in this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A hearing shall be public unless, by a majority vote of all of the members of the investigating committee, the investigating committee determines otherwise.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With the consent of a majority of the members of an investigating committee who are present at a hearing, a witness or counsel for the witness may submit to the investigating committee a sworn statement that is relevant to the purpose, subject, and scope of the investigation or inquiry.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an investigating committee believes that a person may be affected adversely because the person is named or otherwise identified at a hearing, the person may:<section prefix="(i)">on request of the person or a member of the investigating committee, testify in the person's behalf; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">with the consent of the investigating committee, submit a sworn statement or other documentary evidence.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">With the consent of a majority of the members of the investigating committee, any other person may testify or submit a sworn statement or other documentary evidence.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At a hearing, a person shall testify under oath unless, by a majority vote of the members who are present at the hearing, the investigating committee waives the requirement for the person.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any member of the investigating committee may administer an oath.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Counsel may accompany a witness at a hearing and advise the witness of the rights of the witness.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An investigating committee may set limits to prevent obstruction of or interference with the orderly conduct of the hearing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A witness at a hearing or counsel for the witness may submit to the investigating committee a proposed question, for the witness or any other witness.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The investigating committee shall ask the question if the investigating committee considers the question appropriate to the subject matter of the hearing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An investigating committee shall have a record made of each hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The record shall include:<section prefix="(i)">each ruling of the presiding officer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">each question of the investigating committee and its staff;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the testimony and responses of each witness;</section><section prefix="(iv)">each sworn statement or other documentary evidence that the investigating committee permits a person to submit; and</section><section prefix="(v)">any other matter that the investigating committee or its chairman directs.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The investigating committee shall provide to a witness a certified transcript of the witness' testimony, if the witness asks in advance and pays for the transcript.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not:<section prefix="(i)">prevent the disclosure of evidence by the person who gives evidence, if only that person could claim a privilege against disclosure; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">limit any power of the General Assembly, the Senate, or the House to discipline a member or employee or to impose a penalty if a State's Attorney or court does not act under this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a hearing of an investigating committee is closed to the public, testimony and other evidence that is given at the hearing may not be made public unless, by a majority vote of all of the members of the investigating committee, the investigating committee permits disclosure and specifies the form and manner of disclosure.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On application of a person who claims to have been injured or prejudiced by an unauthorized disclosure or on motion of a State's Attorney, the State's Attorney may begin proceedings for imposition of penalties under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A person who violates any provision of this subsection is subject to a fine not exceeding $1,000 or imprisonment not exceeding 30 days or both.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
