<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-1901</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is an Assisted Living Programs Board established to:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1901</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is an Assisted Living Programs Board established to:<section prefix="(1)">develop statewide policy on assisted living programs;</section><section prefix="(2)">coordinate agency responsibility for implementation of policies and programs related to assisted living;</section><section prefix="(3)">review and approve policies and regulations governing assisted living programs; and</section><section prefix="(4)">establish appropriate interagency agreements relative to assisted living programs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board consists of 15 voting members as follows:<section prefix="(1)">the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Secretary of Human Resources;</section><section prefix="(3)">the Secretary of Aging; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the following voting members appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate:<section prefix="(i)">one representative of the Disability Law Center;</section><section prefix="(ii)">one representative of a small program that was certified as a sheltered housing project by the Department of Aging as of December 31, 1995, or could have been certified as a sheltered housing project by the Department of Aging if it had been in existence on December 31, 1995;</section><section prefix="(iii)">one representative of a small program that was certified as a care program by the Department of Human Resources as of December 31, 1995, or could have been certified as a care program by the Department of Human Resources if it had been in existence on December 31, 1995;</section><section prefix="(iv)">one representative of a small program that was licensed or registered as a domiciliary care program by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene as of December 31, 1995, or could have been licensed or registered as a domiciliary care program by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene if it had been in existence on December 31, 1995;</section><section prefix="(v)">four consumer members;</section><section prefix="(vi)">one representative of the Assisted Living Facilities Association of America;</section><section prefix="(vii)">one representative of the Maryland Association of Nonprofit Homes for the Aging;</section><section prefix="(viii)">one representative of the Health Facilities Association of Maryland; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">one representative of the Long-Term Care Association.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor shall appoint a chairperson of the Board from among the three State agency representatives to the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Governor shall appoint the provider and consumer members from the recommendations of organizations representing assisted living program providers and consumers.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Governor is not restricted to these recommendations in appointing members.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The provider and consumer members shall represent a broad geographic cross section of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The term of a member who is not a cabinet member or who does not represent the Maryland Disability Law Center or the Department of Aging is 4 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each member of the Board shall serve without compensation but shall be entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Board may establish its own procedures and voting requirements.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Departments of Health and Mental Hygiene, Human Resources, and Aging shall provide the Board with the necessary staff and support services.</section>
  </text>
</law>
