<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-2402</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>2402</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In the Office of the Governor, there is an Office of the Deaf and Hard of Hearing.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The head of the Office is the Director.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Director is appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Director serves at the pleasure of the Governor and is responsible directly to the Governor.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Director shall be:<section prefix="(i)">a deaf or hard of hearing person; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">knowledgeable and experienced with issues affecting deaf and hard of hearing individuals.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Director is entitled to the salary provided in the State budget.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Office shall:<section prefix="(i)">advise the Governor on all matters assigned to the Office; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">carry out the Governor's policies on the matters assigned to the Office.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Director shall:<section prefix="(i)">manage the operation of the Office and establish guidelines and procedures to promote the orderly and efficient operation of the Office; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">adopt regulations necessary to carry out the provisions of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to the provisions of this subtitle, the Director may establish, reorganize, or consolidate areas of responsibility in the Office as necessary to fulfill the responsibilities assigned by the Director.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Office shall be given adequate staff and funding to carry out its duties.</section>
  </text>
</law>
