<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-206.2" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-7-206.2</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Division may arrange for data bases derived from publications issued by the Division to be made available to the public for direct online searching by contracting with third-party or value-added resellers.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Division shall make available to the public, at no cost, direct online searching of:<section prefix="(1)">the Code of Maryland Regulations (COMAR);</section><section prefix="(2)">the Maryland Register; and</section><section prefix="(3)">any other material the Division determines to be in the public interest.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The receipt of any material made available to the public under the terms of subsection (b) of this section shall be preceded by a legend stating that:</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The legend referenced in subsection (c) of this section shall be presented to the recipient in a manner that affords the recipient an opportunity to refuse to access the material.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "prohibited commercial purpose" includes any use that involves the resale or other compensated transfer of information made available under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Prohibited commercial purpose" does not include the incorporation of portions of information made available under subsection (b) of this section into documents commenting upon or advising persons of the legal effect of that information, even though the person incorporating the information may be compensated for the comments or advice.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Data or material obtained under subsection (b) of this section may not be used for any prohibited commercial purpose.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person who violates subsection (e) of this section is subject to a fine not exceeding $1,000 for each violation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
