<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-1A-15" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-1A-15</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless a manufacturer holds a valid manufacturer's license issued by the Commission before conducting business with a licensee or the State, the manufacturer may not offer any video lottery terminal, central monitor and control system, associated equipment or software, or goods or services that directly relate to the operation of video lottery terminals under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless a manufacturer holds a valid manufacturer's license issued by the Commission before conducting business with a licensee, the manufacturer may not offer any table games or table game equipment under this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each manufacturer, and each person that owns or controls the manufacturer or management and supervisory personnel and other principal employees of the manufacturer, shall qualify under the standards and provisions set forth in &#xA7;&#xA7; 9-1A-07 and 9-1A-08 of this subtitle for video lottery operation licensees.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 9-1A-16(a) of this subtitle, the Commission may not grant an exemption or waiver of any licensing requirement to an applicant for or holder of a manufacturer's license.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A manufacturer of the video lottery terminals, central monitor and control system, and associated equipment and software shall manufacture or distribute the video lottery terminals, central monitor and control system, and associated equipment and software that meet specifications and procedures established by the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A manufacturer of table games and table game equipment shall manufacture or distribute the table games and table game equipment that meet specifications and procedures established by the Commission.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
