<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-607" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-15-607</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A statement that is required by &#xA7; 15-601(a) of this subtitle shall contain schedules disclosing the information and interests specified in this section, if known, for the individual making the statement for the applicable period under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The statement shall include a schedule of each interest in real property, wherever located, including each interest held in the name of a partnership, limited liability partnership, or limited liability company in which the individual held an interest.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For each interest reported the schedule shall include:<section prefix="(i)">the nature of the property;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the street address, mailing address, or legal description of the property;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the nature and extent of the interest in the property, including any conditions to and encumbrances on the interest;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the date and manner in which the interest was acquired;</section><section prefix="(v)">the identity of the entity from which the interest was acquired;</section><section prefix="(vi)">if the interest was acquired by purchase, the nature and amount of the consideration given for the interest;</section><section prefix="(vii)">if the interest was acquired in any other manner, the fair market value of the interest when acquired;</section><section prefix="(viii)">if any interest was transferred, in whole or in part, during the applicable period:</section><section prefix="(ix)">the identity of any other entity with an interest in the property.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The statement shall include a schedule of each interest held by the individual in a corporation, partnership, limited liability partnership, or limited liability company, whether or not the corporation, partnership, limited liability partnership, or limited liability company does business with the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For each interest reported, the schedule shall include:<section prefix="(i)">the name and address of the principal office of the corporation, partnership, limited liability partnership, or limited liability company;</section><section prefix="(ii)">subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, the nature and amount of the interest held, including any conditions to and encumbrances on the interest;</section><section prefix="(iii)">except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, if any interest was acquired during the applicable period:</section><section prefix="(iv)">if any interest was transferred, in whole or in part, during the applicable period:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">As to an equity interest in a corporation, the individual may satisfy paragraph (2)(ii) of this subsection by reporting, instead of a dollar amount:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">As to an equity interest in a partnership, limited liability partnership, or limited liability company, the individual may satisfy paragraph (2)(ii) of this subsection by reporting, instead of a dollar amount, the percentage of equity interest held.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If an interest acquired during the applicable reporting period consists of additions to existing publicly traded corporate interests acquired by dividend or dividend reinvestment, and the total value of the acquisition is less than $500, only the manner of acquisition is required to be disclosed under paragraph (2)(iii) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The statement shall include a schedule of each interest in a business entity doing business with the State, other than interests reported under subsection (c) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For each interest reported, the schedule shall include:<section prefix="(i)">the name and address of the principal office of the business entity;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the nature and amount of the interest held, including any conditions to and encumbrances on the interest;</section><section prefix="(iii)">if any interest was acquired during the applicable period:</section><section prefix="(iv)">if any interest was transferred, in whole or in part, during the applicable period:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to a gift received from a member of the immediate family, another child, or a parent of the individual.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The statement shall include a schedule of each gift, specified in paragraph (3) of this subsection, received during the applicable period:<section prefix="(i)">by the individual or by another entity at the direction of the individual; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">directly or indirectly, from or on behalf of an entity that is:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the schedule shall include each gift with a value of more than $20 and each of two or more gifts with a cumulative value of $100 or more received from one entity during the applicable period.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The statement need not include as a gift:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Notwithstanding the provisions of subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the statement shall include the acceptance of each of two or more tickets or free admissions, extended to a member of the General Assembly by the person sponsoring or conducting the event, with a cumulative value of $100 or more received from one entity during the applicable period.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">For each gift subject to this subsection, the schedule shall include:<section prefix="(i)">the nature and value of the gift; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the identity of the entity from which, directly or indirectly, the gift was received.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">This subsection does not authorize any gift not otherwise allowed by law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The statement shall include, as specified in this subsection, a schedule of all offices, directorships, and salaried employment, or any similar interest not otherwise disclosed, in business entities doing business with the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection applies to positions and interests held at any time during the applicable period by:<section prefix="(i)">the individual; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">any member of the individual's immediate family.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For each position or interest reported, this schedule shall include:<section prefix="(i)">the name and address of the principal office of the business entity;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the nature of the position or interest and the date it commenced;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the name of each governmental unit with which the entity is doing business; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the nature of the business with the State, which, at a minimum, shall be specified by reference to the applicable criteria of doing business described in &#xA7; 15-102(j) of this title.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The statement shall include a schedule, to the extent the individual may reasonably be expected to know, of each debt, excluding retail credit accounts, owed at any time during the applicable period to entities doing business with the State:<section prefix="(i)">by the individual; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the individual was involved in the transaction giving rise to the debt, by any member of the immediate family of the individual.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For each debt, the schedule shall include:<section prefix="(i)">the identity of the entity to which the debt was owed;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the date it was incurred;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the amount owed at the end of the applicable period;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the terms of payment;</section><section prefix="(v)">the extent to which the principal was increased or decreased during the applicable period; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">any security given.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The statement shall include a schedule listing the members of the immediate family of the individual who were employed by the State in any capacity at any time during the applicable period.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the statement shall include a schedule listing the name and address of each:<section prefix="(i)">place of salaried employment, including secondary employment, of the individual or a member of the individual's immediate family at any time during the applicable period; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">business entity of which the individual or a member of the individual's immediate family was a sole or partial owner, and from which the individual or family member received earned income, at any time during the applicable period.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The statement may not include a listing of a minor child's employment or business entities of which the child is sole or partial owner, unless the place of employment or the business entity:<section prefix="(i)">is subject to the regulation or authority of the agency that employs the individual; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">has contracts in excess of $10,000 with the agency that employs the individual.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The statement may include a schedule listing additional interests or information that the individual chooses to disclose.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">To the extent not reported under subsections (a) through (j) of this section, a statement filed by a member of the General Assembly shall include:<section prefix="(1)">the information required under &#xA7; 15-513(b) of this title; and</section><section prefix="(2)">an acknowledgment, signed by the member, that any information, required under &#xA7; 15-513(b) of this title, that becomes reportable after the statement is filed shall be reported immediately to the Joint Ethics Committee as required by &#xA7; 15-513(b) of this title.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
