<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="20-601" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-20-601</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Disability" means:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">a record of having a physical or mental impairment as otherwise defined under this subsection; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">being regarded as having a physical or mental impairment as otherwise defined under this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Disability" includes:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">retardation and any other mental impairment or deficiency that may have necessitated remedial or special education and related services.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Employee" means an individual employed by an employer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless the individual is subject to the State or local civil service laws, "employee" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">an individual elected to public office;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an individual chosen by an elected officer to be on the officer's personal staff;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an appointee on the policy making level; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">an immediate adviser with respect to the exercise of the constitutional or legal powers of an elected office.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Employer" means:<section prefix="(i)">a person that:</section><section prefix="(ii)">an agent of a person described in item (i) of this paragraph.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Employer" includes the State to the extent provided in this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except for a labor organization, "employer" does not include a bona fide private membership club that is exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 501(c) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Employment agency" means:<section prefix="(i)">a person that regularly undertakes with or without compensation to procure:</section><section prefix="(ii)">an agent of a person described in item (i) of this paragraph.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except for the United States Employment Service and the system of State and local employment services receiving federal assistance, "employment agency" does not include a unit of the United States, the State, or a political subdivision of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Genetic information" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 27-909(a)(3) of the Insurance Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Genetic test" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 27-909(a)(5) of the Insurance Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Labor organization" means:<section prefix="(i)">a labor organization engaged in an industry; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">an agent of an organization described in item (i) of this paragraph.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Labor organization" includes:<section prefix="(i)">an organization of any kind, an agency, or an employee representation committee, group, association, or plan:</section><section prefix="(ii)">a conference, general committee, joint or system board, or joint council that is subordinate to a national or international labor organization.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Religion" includes all aspects of religious observances, practice, and belief.</section>
  </text>
</law>
