<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-821" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-15-821</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An applicant for appointment as commissioner shall file the financial disclosure statement required by this Part III as prescribed in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The statement shall be filed with the county council and the chief administrative officer of the county from which the applicant seeks appointment.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In Montgomery County, an applicant for appointment or reappointment to the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission shall file the statement not later than 5 days before the interview conducted under &#xA7; 15-104 of the Land Use Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The statement shall cover the 12-month period ending 60 days before the day the statement is filed.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In Prince George's County, an applicant for appointment to the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission shall file the statement not later than 5 days before the confirmation hearing conducted under &#xA7; 15-103 of the Land Use Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The statement shall cover the 12-month period ending 60 days before the initial date set for the confirmation hearing.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An applicant for appointment to the Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission shall file the statement not later than 5 days before the interview conducted under &#xA7; 17-103 of the Public Utilities Article. The statement shall cover the 12-month period ending 60 days before the day the statement is filed.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An applicant for appointment to the Washington Suburban Transit Commission shall file the statement at least 10 days before the appointment becomes effective. The statement shall cover the 12-month period ending not more than 60 days before the day the statement is filed.</section>
  </text>
</law>
