<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-1A-05" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-1A-05</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Video Lottery Facility Location Commission established under &#xA7; 9-1A-36 of this subtitle may not:<section prefix="(1)">award more than six video lottery operation licenses;</section><section prefix="(2)">award more than 16,500 video lottery terminals for operation at video lottery facilities in the State;</section><section prefix="(3)">subject to the requirements of &#xA7; 9-1A-36(h) and (i) of this subtitle, award more than 4,750 terminals for operation at any video lottery facility; and</section><section prefix="(4)">for a location in Allegany County:<section prefix="(i)">award a video lottery operation license to an applicant that does not agree to purchase the Rocky Gap Lodge and Resort; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">notwithstanding &#xA7; 9-1A-36(i)(2) of this subtitle, award more than 1,500 video lottery terminals for operation at a video lottery facility in Allegany County.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An owner or operator of a video lottery destination location described under &#xA7; 9-1A-01 of this subtitle may submit an application for a video lottery operation license.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A video lottery operation license issued under this subtitle is not valid at a geographic location other than the geographic location authorized in the license awarded by the Video Lottery Facility Location Commission and issued by the State Lottery and Gaming Control Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "owner" includes any type of owner or beneficiary of a business entity, including an officer, director, principal employee, partner, investor, stockholder, or beneficial owner of the business entity and, notwithstanding any other provisions of this subtitle, including a person having any ownership interest regardless of the percentage of ownership interest.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual or business entity may not own an interest in more than one video lottery facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member of the Senate of Maryland or the House of Delegates may not be an owner or an employee of any business entity that holds a video lottery operation license.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Notwithstanding paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">an individual or business entity may enter into a management agreement to operate a facility located in Allegany County that it does not own, subject to the approval of the Video Lottery Facility Location Commission and the State Lottery and Gaming Control Commission; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a holder of a video lottery operation license may apply to the Video Lottery Facility Location Commission for an additional license provided that the application required under &#xA7; 9-1A-36 of this subtitle includes a plan for divesting from the video lottery operation license held on the date of the application.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
