<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-20A-05</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>05</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To receive a loan under the Program, a borrower must file an application with the Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the borrower is an eligible business, the application must be signed by the chief operating officer or an authorized officer of the business.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the borrower is a local jurisdiction, the application must be signed by the chief elected officer of the county or municipality, or if none, by the governing body of the county or municipality in which the project is located.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the borrower is a public school, the application must be signed by the board of education of the county in which the project is located.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The application shall contain any information the Administration determines is necessary, including:<section prefix="(1)">the projected cost to accomplish a proposed project;</section><section prefix="(2)">if applicable, the amount of energy or fuel a proposed project is expected to save over a defined period of time after completion of the project;</section><section prefix="(3)">the anticipated environmental benefits in the form of reduced emissions or pollution attributable to the proposed project;</section><section prefix="(4)">the amount of cost savings expected to be generated over a defined period of time after completion of the proposed project;</section><section prefix="(5)">a description of the borrower's contribution to a proposed project as required by &#xA7; 9-20A-06 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(6)">any additional information relating to the borrower or the proposed project that may be required by the Administration in order to administer the Program.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
