<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-1505.2" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-2-1505.2</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Committee" means the Joint Committee on Administrative, Executive, and Legislative Review.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Economic impact analysis" means an estimate of the cost or the economic benefit to small businesses that may be affected by a regulation proposed by an agency pursuant to Title 10, Subtitle 1 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Economic impact analysis rating" means an estimate that a proposed regulation will have:<section prefix="(i)">minimal or no economic impact on small businesses; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">meaningful economic impact on small businesses.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Small business" means a corporation, partnership, sole proprietorship, or other business entity, including its affiliates, that:<section prefix="(i)">is independently owned and operated;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is not dominant in its field; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">employs 50 or fewer full-time employees.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An economic impact analysis rating and an economic impact analysis, as appropriate, shall be prepared by the appropriate Executive Branch agency for each regulation that the agency proposes for adoption pursuant to Title 10, Subtitle 1 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A copy of the economic impact analysis rating and the economic impact analysis required under this subsection shall be submitted by the appropriate agency:<section prefix="(i)">to the Department of Legislative Services no later than the time the agency submits the regulation to the Committee to allow the Department to comment on the economic impact analysis rating and the economic impact analysis; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">to the Committee at the time the agency submits the regulation to the Committee.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the appropriate Executive Branch agency or the Department of Legislative Services determines that a regulation will have minimal or no economic impact on small businesses, the agency or Department shall indicate that determination by a brief written statement.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the appropriate Executive Branch agency or the Department of Legislative Services determines that a regulation will have a meaningful economic impact on small businesses, the agency or Department shall develop a complete written economic impact analysis.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the appropriate Executive Branch agency or the Department determines that a regulation will have a meaningful economic impact on small businesses and is unable to provide a complete written economic impact analysis, the agency or Department shall provide a written explanation of why the agency determined that the regulation will have a meaningful economic impact.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The explanation may identify the impact in general terms and need not quantify the specific economic impact.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The economic impact analysis rating and the economic impact analysis required under this section shall include estimates directly relating to the following factors, as appropriate:<section prefix="(1)">cost of providing goods and services;</section><section prefix="(2)">effect on the workforce;</section><section prefix="(3)">effect on the cost of housing;</section><section prefix="(4)">efficiency in production and marketing;</section><section prefix="(5)">capital investment, taxation, competition, and economic development; and</section><section prefix="(6)">consumer choice.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Executive Branch agency or the Department of Legislative Services preparing the economic impact analysis rating and the economic impact analysis required under this section shall consult with, as appropriate:<section prefix="(i)">other units of State government;</section><section prefix="(ii)">units of local government; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">business, trade, consumer, labor, and other groups impacted by or having an interest in the regulation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On request of the Executive Director of the Department of Legislative Services, a unit of the State or a local government shall provide the Department with assistance or information in the preparation of an economic impact analysis rating and economic impact analysis.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department of Legislative Services shall:<section prefix="(1)">comment on the economic impact analysis rating and economic impact analysis prepared by the appropriate Executive Branch agency; and</section><section prefix="(2)">transmit its comment to the Committee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Department of Legislative Services shall revise the economic impact analysis rating and economic impact analysis consistent with an amended version of a regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department of Legislative Services shall keep a copy of each economic impact analysis rating and economic impact analysis for 3 years after preparation of the rating or the analysis.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The copies shall be reasonably available for public inspection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Economic impact analysis ratings and economic impact analyses shall be published in the Maryland Register at the same time as:<section prefix="(1)">a notice of proposed adoption of a regulation is published in the Maryland Register; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a notice of emergency adoption for a regulation is published in the Maryland Register.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The validity of an enactment of a regulation is not affected by the presence, absence, or content of an economic impact analysis rating or an economic impact analysis.</section>
  </text>
</law>
