<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-906</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>906</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"State veterans' cemetery" means a cemetery that the Department establishes under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In this section and in &#xA7; 9-907 of this subtitle, "veteran" means an individual who:<section prefix="(i)">served other than dishonorably on active duty in the armed forces of the United States; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">served other than dishonorably as a member of the State militia ordered into active service of the United States by order of the President and was killed in the line of duty.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Washington Cemetery" means the Civil War cemetery grounds authorized by Chapter 213 of the Acts of the General Assembly of 1870.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department may establish one or more cemeteries in the State for the burial of veterans and their eligible spouse or dependents as authorized by the Secretary.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department may accept land, on behalf of the State or a political subdivision of the State, or otherwise acquire land for a State veterans' cemetery, if the Department has the approval of:<section prefix="(1)">the governing body of the county where the State veterans' cemetery is to be located;</section><section prefix="(2)">the delegation in the General Assembly for the county where the State veterans' cemetery is to be located; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the Board of Public Works.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall maintain and supervise each State veterans' cemetery.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Washington Cemetery shall be under the supervision of the Department.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Department shall provide a plot in a State veterans' cemetery, without charge, to a veteran who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">To qualify for a plot in a State veterans' cemetery:<section prefix="(1)">the applicant must be a veteran who meets the requirements for burial at a national veterans' cemetery or an eligible spouse or dependent of a veteran who meets the requirements of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(2)">if a veteran, the veteran must also have been a resident of the State:<section prefix="(i)">when the veteran entered the armed forces;</section><section prefix="(ii)">when the veteran died; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">for 2 years, unless, for a reason that the Department finds compelling, the Department waives the time period.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">To obtain a plot in a State veterans' cemetery, an applicant shall submit to the Department an application on the form that the Department provides.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In a plot that is allotted to a veteran, the Department shall bury:<section prefix="(i)">the veteran; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any member of the immediate family who is an eligible spouse or dependent of the veteran if the family member can be buried in a space above or below the veteran or in the next available plot.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">With each plot, the Department shall provide one grave liner.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For an eligible veteran, the Department shall pay for the grave liner.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">For an eligible spouse or dependent, the grave liner shall be paid for by the family or estate.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall bury the veteran without charge.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For burial of a member of the immediate family who is an eligible spouse or dependent, the Department may set a fee that does not exceed the cost of burial.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
