<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-15-502</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>502</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to members of the General Assembly.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsections (c) and (d) of this section, an official or employee may not:<section prefix="(1)">be employed by or have a financial interest in:<section prefix="(i)">an entity subject to the authority of that official or employee or of the governmental unit with which the official or employee is affiliated; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an entity that is negotiating or has entered a contract with that governmental unit or an entity that is a subcontractor on a contract with that governmental unit; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">hold any other employment relationship if that employment relationship would impair the impartiality and independent judgment of the official or employee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The prohibitions of subsection (b) of this section do not apply:<section prefix="(1)">to employment or a financial interest allowed by regulation of the Ethics Commission if:<section prefix="(i)">the employment does not create a conflict of interest or the appearance of a conflict of interest; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the financial interest is disclosed;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">to a public official who is appointed to a regulatory or licensing unit pursuant to a statutory requirement that entities subject to the jurisdiction of the unit be represented in appointments to it;</section><section prefix="(3)">as allowed by regulations adopted by the Commission, to an employee whose government duties are ministerial, if the private employment or financial interest does not create a conflict of interest or the appearance of a conflict of interest; or</section><section prefix="(4)">to a member of a board who holds the employment or financial interest when appointed if the employment or financial interest is publicly disclosed to the appointing authority, the Ethics Commission, and, if applicable, the Senate of Maryland before Senate confirmation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Ethics Commission may exempt a public official of an executive unit or an employee of an executive unit from the prohibitions of subsection (b) of this section if the Ethics Commission determines that:<section prefix="(i)">failure to grant the exemption would limit the ability of the State to:<section prefix="1.">recruit and hire highly qualified or uniquely qualified professionals for public service; or</section><section prefix="2.">assure the availability of competent services to the public; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">the number of exemptions granted under this subsection has not tended to erode the purposes of subsection (b) of this section or other provisions of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Ethics Commission may grant an exemption under paragraph (1) of this subsection only:<section prefix="1.">in extraordinary situations; and</section><section prefix="2.">upon the recommendation of the Governor, at the request of the executive unit involved.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Ethics Commission shall apply this subsection as consistently as possible under similar facts and circumstances.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
