<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-103" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-15-103</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The determination of whether an individual is a "public official" for the purposes of this title shall be made in accordance with the provisions of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (f) of this section, the following individuals in executive units are public officials:<section prefix="(1)">an individual who receives compensation at a rate equivalent to at least State grade level 16, or who is appointed to a board, if the Ethics Commission determines under &#xA7; 15-208 of this title that:<section prefix="(i)">the individual, acting alone or as a member of an executive unit, has decision making authority or acts as a principal advisor to one with that authority:</section><section prefix="(ii)">the individual's duties are not essentially administrative and ministerial;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">any other individual in an executive unit, if the Ethics Commission determines that the individual, acting alone or as a member of the executive unit, has decision making authority or acts as a principal advisor to one with that authority in drafting specifications for, negotiating, or executing contracts that commit the State or an executive unit to spend more than $10,000 in a year;</section><section prefix="(3)">a member, appointee, or employee of the Maryland Stadium Authority;</section><section prefix="(4)">a member, appointee, or employee of the Canal Place Preservation and Development Authority; and</section><section prefix="(5)">a member of the Emergency Medical Services Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as provided in subsection (f) of this section, an individual in the Legislative Branch is a public official if the individual:<section prefix="(1)">receives compensation at a rate equivalent to at least State grade level 16; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is designated a public official by order of the presiding officers of the General Assembly.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection or in subsection (f) of this section, an individual in the Judicial Branch is a public official if the individual receives compensation at a rate equivalent to at least State grade level 16.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For the purposes of paragraph (1) of this subsection, "individual in the Judicial Branch" includes an individual who is:<section prefix="(i)">employed in the office of a clerk of court;</section><section prefix="(ii)">paid by a county to perform services in an orphans' court or circuit court;</section><section prefix="(iii)">employed by the Attorney Grievance Commission;</section><section prefix="(iv)">employed by the State Board of Law Examiners; or</section><section prefix="(v)">employed by the Court of Appeals Standing Committee on Rules of Practice and Procedure.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Ethics Commission may exclude the individuals in a position in the Judicial Branch from inclusion as public officials under paragraph (1) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">upon the recommendation of the State Court Administrator; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the Ethics Commission determines that the position does not have policy, policy advice, quasi-judicial, or procurement functions.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A member of a bicounty commission is a public official.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The following are not public officials:<section prefix="(1)">a State official;</section><section prefix="(2)">an individual employed on a contractual basis unless the individual is:<section prefix="(i)">employed on a full-time basis for more than 6 months; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">designated pursuant to subsection (b)(1) or (c) of this section; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">a part-time or full-time faculty member at a State institution of higher education:<section prefix="(i)">as to subsection (b)(2) of this section, only when the individual is acting in the capacity of a faculty member; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">as to any other provision of this section, unless the individual also:</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
