<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-6-406</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>406</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Unit shall report in a timely manner to the Executive Director, the Secretary, and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of this article, the Speaker of the House of Delegates and the President of the Senate:<section prefix="(1)">knowledge of any problem regarding the care, supervision, and treatment of children in facilities;</section><section prefix="(2)">findings, actions, and recommendations, related to the investigations of disciplinary actions, grievances, incident reports, and alleged cases of child abuse and neglect; and</section><section prefix="(3)">all other findings and actions related to the monitoring required under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Unit shall report quarterly to the Executive Director and the Secretary.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A copy of the report shall be provided to the State Advisory Board for Juvenile Services and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of this article, the General Assembly.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The report shall include:<section prefix="(i)">all activities of the Unit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">actions taken by the Department resulting from the findings and recommendations of the Unit, including the Department's response; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">a summary of any violations of the standards and regulations of the Department that remained unabated for 30 days or more during the reporting period.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Beginning in 2006, on or before November 30 of each year, the Unit shall report to the Executive Director, the Secretary, the advisory boards established under &#xA7; 9-230 of the Human Services Article, the Governor, and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of this article, the General Assembly, on all the activities of the Office and the actions taken by the Department in response to findings and recommendations of the Unit.</section>
  </text>
</law>
