<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-1A-10" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-1A-10</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For the construction and procurement, including the procurement of equipment and ongoing services, related to the operation of video lottery terminals, the applicant or licensee shall at a minimum meet the same requirements of a designated unit for minority business participation as described under Title 14, Subtitle 3 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the county in which a video lottery facility will be located has higher minority business participation requirements than the State as described in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the applicant shall meet the county's minority business participation requirements to the extent possible.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A county in which a video lottery facility will be located may impose local business, local minority business participation, and local hiring requirements to the extent authorized by local law and permitted by the United States Constitution.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Any collective bargaining agreement or agreements, including a project labor agreement or a neutrality agreement, entered into by an applicant or licensee may not negate the requirements of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If an applicant for employment at a video lottery facility believes that the applicant has been discriminated against in the employment process, the applicant may appeal the employment decision to the local human relations board in the county where the facility is located.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Notwithstanding any collective bargaining agreement or agreements, a licensee shall:<section prefix="(i)">provide health insurance coverage for its employees; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">give a preference to hiring qualified employees from the communities within 10 miles of the video lottery facility.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">A licensee shall:<section prefix="(i)">provide retirement benefits for its employees; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the licensee is a racetrack licensee, provide retirement benefits to its video lottery operation employees that are equivalent to the level of benefits provided to the racetrack employees who are eligible under the Maryland Racetrack Employees Pension Fund.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(8)">Notwithstanding any collective bargaining agreement or agreements, if the licensee is a racetrack location, the licensee shall provide health insurance coverage to all employees of the racetrack, including the employees of the racetrack on the backstretch of the racetrack.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall ensure that a video lottery operation licensee complies with the requirements of subsection (a)(1) and (2) of this section as a condition of holding the video lottery operation license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Governor's Office of Minority Affairs shall monitor a licensee's compliance with subsection (a)(1) and (2) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Governor's Office of Minority Affairs shall report to the Commission at least every 6 months on the compliance of licensees with subsection (a)(1) and (2) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the Governor's Office of Minority Affairs reports that a licensee is not in compliance with subsection (a)(1) and (2) of this section, the Commission may take immediate action to ensure the compliance of the licensee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">On or after July 1, 2018, the provisions of subsections (a)(1) and (2) and (b) of this section and any regulations adopted under subsections (a)(1) and (2) and (b) of this section shall be of no effect and may not be enforced.</section>
  </text>
</law>
