<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-519" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-15-519</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Joint Ethics Committee shall adopt written procedures for conducting a hearing to consider a complaint, allegation summary, and written answer, if any, as provided in &#xA7; 15-518(b) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The written procedures adopted by the Joint Ethics Committee under subsection (a) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">shall be available for public inspection;</section><section prefix="(2)">shall be provided to each legislator who is the subject of a hearing;</section><section prefix="(3)">shall authorize a legislator to:<section prefix="(i)">be represented by counsel;</section><section prefix="(ii)">cross-examine witnesses; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">subject to limitations established by the Joint Ethics Committee in its written procedures, be provided an opportunity to reasonably inspect any records that the Joint Ethics Committee intends to use during the hearing; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">subject to paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection, may be amended by the Joint Ethics Committee at any time.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the Joint Ethics Committee determines that a hearing is required under &#xA7; 15-518(b) of this subtitle, the Joint Ethics Committee, by a two-thirds vote of the members of the Joint Ethics Committee, may issue one or more subpoenas that require the appearance of a person, the production of relevant records, and the giving of relevant testimony.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the Joint Ethics Committee exercises subpoena powers under this paragraph, the legislator who is the subject of the investigation may require the Joint Ethics Committee to issue one or more subpoenas on that legislator's behalf.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A request to appear, appearance, or submission of evidence does not limit the subpoena power of the Joint Ethics Committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A subpoena issued under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be served:<section prefix="(i)">in the manner provided by law for service of a subpoena in a civil action;</section><section prefix="(ii)">before the time that the subpoena sets for appearance or production of records; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">with the following documents:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A person who is subpoenaed to appear at a hearing is entitled to receive the fees and allowances that are provided for a person who is subpoenaed by a circuit court.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A person may be held in contempt if the person unjustifiably:<section prefix="(i)">fails or refuses to comply with a subpoena for appearance;</section><section prefix="(ii)">appears but fails or refuses to testify under oath; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">unless the directive is overruled by a majority vote of the members of the Joint Ethics Committee who are present at the hearing, disobeys a directive of the presiding chairman at the hearing to answer a relevant question or to produce a record, including electronic record that has been subpoenaed.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">By a two-thirds vote of all of the members of the Joint Ethics Committee, the Joint Ethics Committee may apply for a contempt citation to a circuit court.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
