<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-703" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-15-703</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At the times specified in subsection (d) of this section, each regulated lobbyist shall register with the Ethics Commission on a form provided by the Ethics Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A regulated lobbyist shall register separately for each entity that has engaged the regulated lobbyist for lobbying purposes.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each registration form shall include, if applicable, the following information:<section prefix="(1)">the regulated lobbyist's name and permanent address;</section><section prefix="(2)">the name and permanent address of each other regulated lobbyist that will be lobbying on the regulated lobbyist's behalf;</section><section prefix="(3)">the name, address, and nature of business of the entity, if any, that has engaged the regulated lobbyist for lobbying purposes, accompanied by a statement indicating whether, because of the filing and reporting of the regulated lobbyist, the compensating entity is exempt under &#xA7; 15-701(c) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the identification, by formal designation if known, of the matters on which the regulated lobbyist expects to perform acts, or to engage another regulated lobbyist to perform acts, that require registration under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If applicable, each registration shall include the authorization required by &#xA7; 15-702 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A regulated lobbyist who is not currently registered shall register within 5 days after first performing an act that requires registration under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A regulated lobbyist shall file a new registration form on or before November 1 of each year if, on that date, the regulated lobbyist is engaged in lobbying.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each registration form shall be accompanied by a fee of $100.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The fee shall be credited to the Lobbyist Registration Fund established under &#xA7; 15-210 of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, each registration shall terminate on the earlier of:<section prefix="(i)">the October 31 following the filing of the registration; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an earlier termination date specified in an authorization filed with respect to that registration under &#xA7; 15-702 of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A regulated lobbyist may terminate the registration before the date specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection by:<section prefix="(i)">ceasing all activity that requires registration; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">after ceasing activity in accordance with item (i) of this paragraph:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraphs (ii) and (iii) of this paragraph, if a regulated lobbyist is or becomes subject to regulation under this title as an official or employee, the regulated lobbyist shall immediately terminate the registration in accordance with paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">After holding a public hearing, the Ethics Commission shall adopt regulations establishing criteria under which a regulated lobbyist may serve on a State board or commission.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The regulations adopted under subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph shall:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
