<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-8-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The secretary of each principal department serves at the pleasure of the Governor unless otherwise provided by law.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A secretary shall:<section prefix="(1)">receive the salary and have the assistants, employees, and professional consultants provided in the budget, unless otherwise provided by law;</section><section prefix="(2)">be responsible for establishing policy to be followed by the units of State government within the secretary's department;</section><section prefix="(3)">be responsible for the efficient and orderly administration of the department;</section><section prefix="(4)">be responsible for the comprehensive planning of programs and services within the secretary's jurisdiction and for reviewing and approving the plans of all units of State government within the secretary's jurisdiction;</section><section prefix="(5)">be responsible for the budget of the secretary's office and for the budgets of other units of State government within the secretary's jurisdiction;</section><section prefix="(6)">be responsible for the organization of the secretary's office and for recommending to the Governor changes in the organization and placement of units of State government within the secretary's jurisdiction; and</section><section prefix="(7)">recommend to the Governor any modification, abolition, and transfer of advisory bodies within the secretary's jurisdiction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A secretary may:<section prefix="(1)">appoint officers and employees in the secretary's office as provided in the budget and review the personnel action taken by any unit of State government within the secretary's jurisdiction; and</section><section prefix="(2)">create the citizen advisory bodies that may be necessary for the operation of the secretary's department.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
