<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-10-617</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>617</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Unless otherwise provided by law, a custodian shall deny inspection of a part of a public record, as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "disability" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 20-701 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, a custodian shall deny inspection of the part of a public record that contains:<section prefix="(i)">medical or psychological information about an individual, other than an autopsy report of a medical examiner;</section><section prefix="(ii)">personal information about an individual with a disability or an individual perceived to have a disability; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">any report on human immunodeficiency virus or acquired immunodeficiency syndrome submitted in accordance with Title 18 of the Health - General Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A custodian shall permit the person in interest to inspect the public record to the extent permitted under &#xA7; 4-304(a) of the Health - General Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Except for paragraph (2)(iii) of this subsection, this subsection does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">a nursing home as defined in &#xA7; 19-1401 of the Health - General Article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an assisted living facility as defined in &#xA7; 19-1801 of the Health - General Article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the official custodian has adopted rules or regulations that define sociological information for purposes of this subsection, a custodian shall deny inspection of the part of a public record that contains sociological information, in accordance with the rules or regulations.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A custodian shall deny inspection of the part of a public record that contains any of the following information provided by or obtained from any person or governmental unit:<section prefix="(1)">a trade secret;</section><section prefix="(2)">confidential commercial information;</section><section prefix="(3)">confidential financial information; or</section><section prefix="(4)">confidential geological or geophysical information.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Subject to &#xA7; 21-504 of the State Personnel and Pensions Article, a custodian shall deny inspection of the part of a public record that contains the home address or telephone number of an employee of a unit or instrumentality of the State or of a political subdivision unless:<section prefix="(1)">the employee gives permission for the inspection; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the unit or instrumentality that employs the individual determines that inspection is needed to protect the public interest.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to the salary of a public employee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, a custodian shall deny inspection of the part of a public record that contains information about the finances of an individual, including assets, income, liabilities, net worth, bank balances, financial history or activities, or creditworthiness.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A custodian shall permit inspection by the person in interest.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A custodian shall deny inspection of the part of a public record that contains information about the security of an information system.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraphs (2) through (4) of this subsection, a custodian shall deny inspection of the part of a public record that contains information about the licensing of an individual in an occupation or profession.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A custodian shall permit inspection of the part of a public record that gives:<section prefix="(i)">the name of the licensee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the business address of the licensee or, if the business address is not available, the home address of the licensee after the custodian redacts all information, if any, that identifies the location as the home address of an individual with a disability as defined in subsection (b) of this section;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the business telephone number of the licensee;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the educational and occupational background of the licensee;</section><section prefix="(v)">the professional qualifications of the licensee;</section><section prefix="(vi)">any orders and findings that result from formal disciplinary actions; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">any evidence that has been provided to the custodian to meet the requirements of a statute as to financial responsibility.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A custodian may permit inspection of other information about a licensee if:<section prefix="(i)">the custodian finds a compelling public purpose; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the rules or regulations of the official custodian permit the inspection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Except as otherwise provided by this subsection or other law, a custodian shall permit inspection by the person in interest.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A custodian who sells lists of licensees shall omit from the lists the name of any licensee, on written request of the licensee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A custodian shall deny inspection of the part of a public record that contains information, generated by the bid analysis management system, concerning an investigation based on a transportation contractor's suspected collusive or anticompetitive activity submitted to the Department by:<section prefix="(1)">the United States Department of Transportation; or</section><section prefix="(2)">another state.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraphs (2) through (5) of this subsection, a custodian shall deny inspection of the part of a public record that contains information about the application and commission of a person as a notary public.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A custodian shall permit inspection of the part of a public record that gives:<section prefix="(i)">the name of the notary public;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the home address of the notary public;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the home and business telephone numbers of the notary public;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the issue and expiration dates of the notary public's commission;</section><section prefix="(v)">the date the person took the oath of office as a notary public; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">the signature of the notary public.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A custodian may permit inspection of other information about a notary public if the custodian finds a compelling public purpose.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A custodian may deny inspection of a record by a notary public or any other person in interest only to the extent that the inspection could:<section prefix="(i)">interfere with a valid and proper law enforcement proceeding;</section><section prefix="(ii)">deprive another person of a right to a fair trial or an impartial adjudication;</section><section prefix="(iii)">constitute an unwarranted invasion of personal privacy;</section><section prefix="(iv)">disclose the identity of a confidential source;</section><section prefix="(v)">disclose an investigative technique or procedure;</section><section prefix="(vi)">prejudice an investigation; or</section><section prefix="(vii)">endanger the life or physical safety of an individual.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A custodian who sells lists of notaries public shall omit from the lists the name of any notary public, on written request of the notary public.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a custodian shall deny inspection of the part of an application for a marriage license under &#xA7; 2-402 of the Family Law Article or a recreational license under Title 4 of the Natural Resources Article that contains a Social Security number.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A custodian shall permit inspection of the part of an application described in paragraph (1) of this subsection that contains a Social Security number to:<section prefix="(i)">a person in interest; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">on request, the State Child Support Enforcement Administration.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a custodian shall deny inspection of the part of a public record that identifies or contains personal information about a person, including a commercial entity, that maintains an alarm or security system.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A custodian shall permit inspection by:<section prefix="(i)">the person in interest;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an alarm or security system company if the company can document that it currently provides alarm or security services to the person in interest;</section><section prefix="(iii)">law enforcement personnel; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">emergency services personnel, including:<section prefix="1.">a career firefighter;</section><section prefix="2.">an emergency medical services provider, as defined in &#xA7; 13-516 of the Education Article;</section><section prefix="3.">a rescue squad employee; and</section><section prefix="4.">a volunteer firefighter, rescue squad member, or advanced life support unit member.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Senior citizen activities center" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 10-513 of the Human Services Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, a custodian shall deny inspection of the part of a public record that contains the name, address, telephone number, or electronic mail address of any individual enrolled in or any member of a senior citizen activities center.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A custodian shall permit inspection by:<section prefix="(i)">a person in interest;</section><section prefix="(ii)">law enforcement personnel; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">emergency services personnel, including:<section prefix="1.">a career firefighter;</section><section prefix="2.">an emergency medical services provider, as defined in &#xA7; 13-516 of the Education Article;</section><section prefix="3.">a rescue squad employee; and</section><section prefix="4.">a volunteer firefighter, rescue squad member, or advanced life support unit member.</section></section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
