<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-831" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-15-831</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An applicant or agent of the applicant may not make a payment to a member of the County Council, the County Executive, or a slate that includes the County Executive or a member of the County Council, during the pendency of the application.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After an application has been filed, a member of the County Council may not vote or participate in any way in the proceeding on the application if the member's treasurer or continuing political committee, or a slate to which the member belongs or belonged during the 36-month period preceding the filing of the application, received a payment during the 36-month period before the filing of the application or during the pendency of the application from any of the applicants or the agents of the applicants.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member is not subject to the requirements of paragraph (1) of this subsection if:<section prefix="(i)">a transfer to the member's treasurer, a continuing political committee, or a slate to which the member belongs or belonged during the 36-month period preceding the filing of the application was made by a political action committee to which an applicant or agent had made a payment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the applicant or agent made the payment to the political action committee without any intent to subvert the purposes of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the applicant's or agent's payment to the political action committee, and the political action committee's transfer, are disclosed in an affidavit; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the transfer is returned to the political action committee by the member, or the payment is returned to the applicant or agent by the political action committee.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After an application is filed, the applicant shall file an affidavit, under oath, stating to the best of the applicant's information, knowledge, and belief that:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)"/><section prefix="(iii)"/></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The affidavit may be filed any time prior to consideration of the application by the District Council, at the discretion of the applicant. However, in no event may the affidavit be filed less than 30 calendar days prior to consideration by the District Council of the application.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A supplemental affidavit shall be filed whenever a payment is made after the original affidavit was filed.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An applicant has no obligation to make any representations pertaining to the actions of anyone other than that applicant under the affidavit. In the case of business entities, anyone with authority to act on behalf of, and bind, the business entity may execute an affidavit on behalf of the business entity itself.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The only disclosures required under the affidavit are those involving individuals or business entities that would be subject to the provisions of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An agent shall file an affidavit in an application only if:<section prefix="(i)">the agent has acted on behalf of the applicant with regard to the specific application; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">during the 36-month period before the filing of the application and during the pendency of the application, and after becoming an agent of the applicant:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection, an agent shall disclose in the affidavit a payment made before becoming an agent if the agent:<section prefix="(i)">made the payment by prearrangement or in coordination with one or more applicants; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">acted as an agent as to any other application filed during the 36-month period.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a contributor, a member of the County Council, or a political action committee is subject to this Part IV if a payment is made by the contributor or a transfer is made by the political action committee to:<section prefix="(i)">the candidate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the candidate's continuing political committee; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a slate to which the member or candidate belongs or belonged during the 36-month period preceding the filing of the application.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The provisions of this Part IV do not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">any transfer to the continuing political committee of a candidate or member of the County Council by the continuing political committee of another individual running for elective office; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a payment or transfer to the Prince George's County Central Committee, or State Central Committee, of a political party, even if the Central Committee supports a candidate.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A person may not make a payment in violation of this Part IV.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An applicant or agent may not take any action, directly or indirectly, with the intent to circumvent the intent of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
