<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-10A-11" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-2-10A-11</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Joint Committee on Unemployment Insurance Oversight.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Committee consists of the following 15 members:<section prefix="(1)">three members of the Senate, appointed by the President of the Senate;</section><section prefix="(2)">three members of the House of Delegates, appointed by the Speaker of the House of Delegates;</section><section prefix="(3)">the Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(4)">the Secretary of Business and Economic Development, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(5)">a representative of the Maryland Retailers Association, designated by the Maryland Retailers Association;</section><section prefix="(6)">a representative of the Maryland Chamber of Commerce, designated by the Maryland Chamber of Commerce;</section><section prefix="(7)">a representative of the National Federation of Independent Business, designated by the National Federation of Independent Business;</section><section prefix="(8)">a representative of the Job Opportunities Task Force, designated by the Job Opportunities Task Force;</section><section prefix="(9)">two representatives of union labor, designated by the Maryland State and District of Columbia AFL-CIO; and</section><section prefix="(10)">a representative of the academic profession who is knowledgeable in unemployment insurance law, designated jointly by the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Delegates.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The members of the Committee serve at the pleasure of the presiding officer who appointed them.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The President and the Speaker shall appoint a Senator and a Delegate, respectively, each to serve as cochair.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Committee shall examine the condition of the unemployment insurance system in the State as a result of the implementation of Chapter 169 of the Acts of the General Assembly of 2005.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Committee may examine the need for additional alterations to the unemployment insurance system, including the charging and taxation provisions and the eligibility and benefit provisions, in consideration of the fairness of the system and in order to maintain the Unemployment Insurance Trust Fund at a level sufficient to ensure that benefits will be paid from the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department of Legislative Services shall provide staffing for the Committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation shall report to the Committee on the condition of unemployment insurance in the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A member of the Committee may not receive compensation for serving on the Committee, but is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Committee shall report its findings and recommendations to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of this title, the General Assembly on December 31 of each year.</section>
  </text>
</law>
