<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-15-102</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this title the following words have the meanings indicated unless:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>102</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated unless:<section prefix="(1)">the context clearly requires a different meaning; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a different definition is adopted for a particular provision.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Advisory body" means:<section prefix="(1)">a governmental unit designated by the Court of Appeals, for the purpose of issuing advisory opinions as to questions arising under Subtitles 5 and 6 of this title regarding a State official of the Judicial Branch;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Joint Ethics Committee, for questions arising under Subtitle 5 of this title regarding a State official of the Legislative Branch; or</section><section prefix="(3)">the Ethics Commission, for all other questions.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Bicounty commission" means:<section prefix="(1)">the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission; or</section><section prefix="(3)">the Washington Suburban Transit Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Board" means an executive unit comprised of at least two members, all of whom:<section prefix="(1)">are appointed; and</section><section prefix="(2)">serve on a part-time basis.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Business entity" means a person engaged in business, whether profit or nonprofit, regardless of form.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Compensation" means money or any other valuable thing, regardless of form, received or to be received by a person from an employer for services rendered.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of Subtitle 7 of this title, if lobbying is only a portion of a person's employment, "compensation" means a prorated amount that is based on the time devoted by the person to lobbying compared to the time devoted to other employment duties.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Employee" means an individual who is employed:<section prefix="(i)">by an executive unit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">by the Legislative Branch; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">in the Judicial Branch.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Employee" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">a public official; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a State official.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Employer" means an entity that pays or agrees to pay compensation to another entity for services rendered.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Entity" means:<section prefix="(1)">a person; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a government or instrumentality of government.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Entity doing business with the State" means:<section prefix="(1)">a regulated lobbyist;</section><section prefix="(2)">an entity regulated by the executive unit of the applicable official or employee; or</section><section prefix="(3)">an entity that is a party to one or a combination of sales, purchases, leases, or contracts to, from, or with the State, or any unit of the State, involving consideration:<section prefix="(i)">of at least $5,000 on a cumulative basis during the calendar year for which a statement required by Subtitle 6 of this title is filed, regardless of when the consideration is to be paid; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">which shall include, as of the award or execution of a contract or lease, the total consideration committed to be paid under the contract or lease, to the extent ascertainable when awarded or executed, regardless of the period over which payments are to be made.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Ethics Commission" means the State Ethics Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Executive action" means an act for which the Executive Branch of State government is responsible and that is taken by an official or employee of that branch.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Executive unit" means a department, agency, commission, board, council, or other body of State government that:<section prefix="(i)">is established by law; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is not in the Legislative Branch or the Judicial Branch of State government.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Executive unit" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a county health department unless the officials and employees of the department are expressly designated as "local officials" in &#xA7; 15-807 of this title;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the office of the sheriff in each county;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the office of the State's Attorney in each county; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Liquor Control Board for Somerset County.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Financial interest" means:<section prefix="(1)">ownership of an interest as the result of which the owner has received within the past 3 years, is currently receiving, or in the future is entitled to receive, more than $1,000 per year; or</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">ownership of more than 3% of a business entity by:<section prefix="1.">an official;</section><section prefix="2.">an employee; or</section><section prefix="3.">the spouse of an official or employee; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">ownership of securities of any kind that represent, or are convertible into, ownership of more than 3% of a business entity by:<section prefix="1.">an official;</section><section prefix="2.">an employee; or</section><section prefix="3.">the spouse of an official or employee.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"General Assembly" includes a member, committee, or subcommittee of the General Assembly.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Gift" means the transfer of anything of economic value, regardless of form, without adequate and lawful consideration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Gift" does not include the solicitation, acceptance, receipt, or regulation of a political contribution that is regulated in accordance with:<section prefix="(i)">the Election Law Article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">any other State law regulating:<section prefix="1.">the conduct of elections; or</section><section prefix="2.">the receipt of political contributions.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Governmental unit" means a department, agency, commission, board, council, or other body of State government that is established by law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Governmental unit" includes an executive unit.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(r)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Honorarium" means the payment of money or anything of value for:<section prefix="(i)">speaking to, participating in, or attending a meeting or other function; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">writing an article that has been or is intended to be published.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Honorarium" does not include payment for writing a book that has been or is intended to be published.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Immediate family" means an individual's spouse and dependent children.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Interest" means a legal or equitable economic interest that is owned or held wholly or partly, jointly or severally, or directly or indirectly, whether or not the economic interest is subject to an encumbrance or condition.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Interest" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">an interest held in the capacity of agent, custodian, fiduciary, personal representative, or trustee, unless the holder has an equitable interest in the subject matter;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an interest in a time or demand deposit in a financial institution;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an interest in an insurance policy, endowment policy, or annuity contract by which an insurer promises to pay a fixed amount of money in a lump sum or periodically for life or a specified period; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">a common trust fund or a trust that forms part of a pension or a profit-sharing plan that:<section prefix="1.">has more than 25 participants; and</section><section prefix="2.">is determined by the Internal Revenue Service to be a qualified trust or college savings plan under the Internal Revenue Code.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(u)">"Joint Ethics Committee" means the Joint Committee on Legislative Ethics.</section>
    <section prefix="(v)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Legislative action" means an official action or nonaction relating to:<section prefix="(i)">a bill, resolution, amendment, nomination, appointment, report, or other matter within the jurisdiction of the General Assembly; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a bill presented to the Governor for signature or veto.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Legislative action" includes the following actions:<section prefix="(i)">introduction;</section><section prefix="(ii)">sponsorship;</section><section prefix="(iii)">consideration;</section><section prefix="(iv)">debate;</section><section prefix="(v)">amendment;</section><section prefix="(vi)">passage;</section><section prefix="(vii)">defeat;</section><section prefix="(viii)">approval; or</section><section prefix="(ix)">veto.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(w)">"Legislative unit" means:<section prefix="(1)">the General Assembly;</section><section prefix="(2)">either house of the General Assembly;</section><section prefix="(3)">a standing committee of the General Assembly, provided that the presiding officer of the House of Delegates or Senate shall be deemed an ex officio member of any standing committee of the presiding officer's chamber; or</section><section prefix="(4)">a county or regional delegation of members of the General Assembly that is recognized by a presiding officer of the General Assembly.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(x)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Lobbying" means performing any act that requires registration under &#xA7; 15-701 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">With respect to Subtitle 8 of this title, "lobbying" means performing acts, of a nature comparable to acts requiring registration under Subtitle 7 of this title, before the local government involved.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(y)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Local official", subject to &#xA7; 15-807 of this title, means an official, officer, or employee of a county or municipal corporation that the governing body of the county or municipal corporation determines is subject to Subtitle 8, Part I of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Local official", subject to &#xA7; 15-807 of this title, includes each member and employee of a board of license commissioners that the applicable governing body determines is subject to Subtitle 8, Part I of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(z)">"Member of household" means:<section prefix="(1)">if sharing an individual's legal residence, the individual's:<section prefix="(i)">spouse;</section><section prefix="(ii)">child;</section><section prefix="(iii)">ward;</section><section prefix="(iv)">financially dependent parent; or</section><section prefix="(v)">other financially dependent relative; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">an individual's spouse, child, ward, parent, or other relative, over whose financial affairs the individual has legal or actual control.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(aa)">"Municipal corporation" means a municipality governed by Article XI-E of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
    <section prefix="(bb)">"Official" means either a State official or a public official.</section>
    <section prefix="(cc)">"Political contribution" means contributions as defined in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Election Law Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(dd)">"Principal political party" means the State Democratic Party or the State Republican Party.</section>
    <section prefix="(ee)">"Procurement contract" has the meaning provided in &#xA7; 11-101 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(ff)">"Public official" means an individual determined to be a public official in or pursuant to &#xA7; 15-103 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(gg)">"Qualifying relative" means a spouse, parent, child, brother, or sister.</section>
    <section prefix="(hh)">"Regulated lobbyist" means an entity that is required to register with the Ethics Commission pursuant to &#xA7; 15-701(a) of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(ii)">"Respondent" means any of the following that is the subject of a complaint before the Ethics Commission:<section prefix="(1)">an official;</section><section prefix="(2)">an employee;</section><section prefix="(3)">a candidate for office as a State official;</section><section prefix="(4)">an entity subject to Subtitle 7 of this title; or</section><section prefix="(5)">an entity subject to &#xA7; 15-508 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(jj)">"School board" means a county board of education or, in Baltimore City, the Board of School Commissioners.</section>
    <section prefix="(kk)">"School system" means the educational system under the authority of a school board.</section>
    <section prefix="(ll)">"State official" means:<section prefix="(1)">a constitutional officer or officer-elect in an executive unit;</section><section prefix="(2)">a member or member-elect of the General Assembly;</section><section prefix="(3)">a judge or judge-elect of a court under Article IV, &#xA7; 1 of the Constitution;</section><section prefix="(4)">a judicial appointee as defined in Maryland Rule 16-814;</section><section prefix="(5)">a State's Attorney;</section><section prefix="(6)">a clerk of the circuit court;</section><section prefix="(7)">a register of wills; or</section><section prefix="(8)">a sheriff.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(mm)">"Superintendent" means a county superintendent as defined in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Education Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
