<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-10-132.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>132.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to subsection (b) of this section, the adopting authority for each unit shall every 8 years, beginning on or after October 1, 2001, submit to the Governor and to the Committee a schedule of regulations to be reviewed under this part during the following 8 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">To the extent possible and reasonable, an adopting authority shall schedule related regulations to be reviewed concurrently.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Unless good cause exists for publishing a larger group of regulations concurrently, the largest group of regulations that an adopting authority may schedule for review concurrently shall be a subtitle.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At the time that a unit's regulations are scheduled for review under this part, an adopting authority may certify to the Committee and the Governor that the review of a regulation or group of related regulations would not be effective or cost-effective and is exempt from the review process under this subtitle because the regulation or group of related regulations was:<section prefix="(i)">adopted to implement a federally mandated or federally approved program; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">initially adopted or comprehensively amended during the preceding 8 years.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An adopting authority issuing a certificate of exemption shall provide the Governor and Committee with written justification for the certificate of exemption.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If there is more than one adopting authority for a regulation or group of related regulations for which an exemption is to be certified, each adopting authority shall sign the certificate of exemption and written justification required under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">At any time during a review cycle, the Governor or Committee may ask that an adopting authority review a regulation or group of regulations for which a certificate of exemption has been issued, notwithstanding the claim of exemption.</section>
  </text>
</law>
