<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-13-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Flag to honor and remember members of the armed forces who died in the line of duty" means:<section prefix="(i)">a flag created by Honor and Remember, Inc.; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the flag designated by the United States Congress as the official symbol to honor and remember members of the armed forces who died in the line of duty.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"POW/MIA flag" means the POW/MIA flag of the National League of Families of American Prisoners and Missing in Southeast Asia.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, each year, the POW/MIA flag and a flag to honor and remember members of the armed forces who died in the line of duty shall be flown on the State House grounds on:<section prefix="(i)">the third Saturday in May, for Armed Forces Day;</section><section prefix="(ii)">May 30, for Memorial Day;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the day that the United States Congress designates for the observance of Memorial Day if other than May 30;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Saturday and Sunday that are closest to May 30, unless the United States Congress designates another day for the observance of Memorial Day, in which case, the Saturday and Sunday that are closest to the day designated by the United States Congress;</section><section prefix="(v)">July 4, for Independence Day;</section><section prefix="(vi)">the third Friday in September, for POW/MIA Recognition Day;</section><section prefix="(vii)">November 11, for Veterans' Day;</section><section prefix="(viii)">the day that the United States Congress designates for the observance of Veterans' Day if other than November 11; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">the Saturday and Sunday that are closest to November 11, unless the United States Congress designates another day for the observance of Veterans' Day, in which case, the Saturday and Sunday that are closest to the day designated by the United States Congress.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the United States Congress designates a flag as the official symbol to honor and remember members of the armed forces who died in the line of duty, the flag designated by Congress shall be flown in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
