<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-601" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-15-601</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c) of this section, and subject to subsections (d) and (e) of this section, each official and candidate for office as a State official shall file a statement as specified in &#xA7;&#xA7; 15-602 through 15-608 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Financial disclosure by a judge of a court under Article IV, &#xA7; 1 of the Maryland Constitution, a candidate for elective office as a judge, or a judicial appointee as defined in Maryland Rule 16-814 is governed by &#xA7; 15-610 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The requirement to file a financial disclosure statement under subsection (a) of this section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">a deputy sheriff and all other employees in the office of the sheriff in a county; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a deputy or assistant State's Attorney and all other employees in the office of the State's Attorney in a county.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual who is a public official only as a member of a board and who receives annual compensation that is less than 25% of the lowest annual compensation at State grade level 16 shall file the statement required by subsection (a) of this section in accordance with &#xA7; 15-609 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member of the Harford County Liquor Control Board shall file the statement required by subsection (a) of this section in accordance with &#xA7; 15-609 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A commissioner or an applicant for appointment as commissioner of a bicounty commission shall file the statement required by subsection (a) of this section in accordance with Subtitle 8, Part III of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
