<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-917</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>917</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission consists of the following members appointed by the Governor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the members:<section prefix="(i)">1 shall be appointed from each of the 8 congressional districts in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">1 shall be a veteran appointed from the State at large;</section><section prefix="(iii)">1 shall be a woman veteran appointed from the State at large;</section><section prefix="(iv)">1 shall be a representative of a retired enlisted organization;</section><section prefix="(v)">1 shall be a veteran of the Iraq or Afghanistan conflict, as defined in &#xA7; 1-202(a-1) of the Public Safety Article;</section><section prefix="(vi)">1 shall be appointed from a list of individuals submitted to the Governor by each of the following organizations:<section prefix="1.">the American Ex-Prisoners of War, Inc.;</section><section prefix="2.">the American Legion;</section><section prefix="3.">the Amvets;</section><section prefix="4.">the Catholic War Veterans;</section><section prefix="5.">the Disabled American Veterans;</section><section prefix="6.">the Fleet Reserve Association;</section><section prefix="7.">the Jewish War Veterans;</section><section prefix="8.">the Marine Corps League;</section><section prefix="9.">the Maryland Military Officers Association of America;</section><section prefix="10.">the Military Order of the Purple Heart;</section><section prefix="11.">the Polish Legion of American Veterans;</section><section prefix="12.">the Veterans of Foreign Wars;</section><section prefix="13.">the Vietnam Veterans of America;</section><section prefix="14.">the Korean War Veterans Association, Inc.;</section><section prefix="15.">the National Association for Black Veterans; and</section><section prefix="16.">the Colonial Chapter of the Paralyzed Veterans of America; and</section></section><section prefix="(vii)">1 shall be an honorary nonvoting member appointed from a list of individuals submitted to the Governor by the Pearl Harbor Survivors Association.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each member must be a resident of the State and a veteran.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of an appointed member is 5 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of the appointed members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Commission on October 1, 1984.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">When an organization is no longer a part of the Commission, the appointment shall terminate at the end of the current member's term.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A new organization may not be eligible for representation on the Commission, by appointment of the Governor, unless it is congressionally chartered.</section>
  </text>
</law>
