<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-20-1029</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1029</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In accordance with the Commission's regulations, the Commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">review any findings, conclusions, or orders issued under &#xA7; 20-1028 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">issue a final order.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a timely appeal of the findings, conclusions, or orders issued under &#xA7; 20-1028 of this subtitle is not filed with the Commission in accordance with the Commission's regulations, the findings, conclusions, or orders issued by the administrative law judge under &#xA7; 20-1028 of this subtitle shall become a final order of the Commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission shall cause the findings of fact and conclusions of law made with respect to any final order for relief under this section, together with a copy of the order, to be served on each aggrieved person and respondent in the proceeding.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If an order is issued concerning a discriminatory housing practice that occurred in the course of a business subject to licensing or regulation by a State or local unit, the Commission shall, within 30 days after the date of the issuance of the final order of the Commission or, if the order is judicially reviewed, 30 days after the final order is affirmed in substance after review:<section prefix="(1)">send copies of the findings of fact and conclusions of law and the final order to the State or local unit; and</section><section prefix="(2)">recommend to the State or local unit appropriate disciplinary action, including, if appropriate:<section prefix="(i)">the suspension or revocation of the license of the respondent; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the suspension or debarment of the respondent from participation in State and local loan, grant, or other regulated programs.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
