<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-2901</section_number>
  <catch_line>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL DECEMBER 31, 2014 PER CHAPTERS 250 AND 251 OF 2011 //...</catch_line>
  <order_by>2901</order_by>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL DECEMBER 31, 2014 PER CHAPTERS 250 AND 251 OF 2011 //<section prefix="(a)">There is a Commission on Maryland Cybersecurity Innovation and Excellence.</section><section prefix="(b)"><section prefix="(1)">The Commission consists of the following members:<section prefix="(i)">one member of the Senate of Maryland, appointed by the President of the Senate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">one member of the House of Delegates, appointed by the Speaker of the House;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Secretary of Information Technology, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Secretary of Business and Economic Development, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(v)">the Secretary of the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(vi)">the Executive Director of the Maryland Technology Development Corporation, or the Executive Director's designee;</section><section prefix="(vii)">the Chair of the Tech Council of Maryland, or the Chair's designee;</section><section prefix="(viii)">the President of the Fort Meade Alliance, or the President's designee; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">the following members appointed by the Governor:<section prefix="1.">five representatives of cybersecurity companies located in the State, with at least three representing cybersecurity companies with 50 employees or less;</section><section prefix="2.">three representatives from statewide or regional business associations;</section><section prefix="3.">four representatives from institutions of higher education located in the State;</section><section prefix="4.">one representative of a crime victims organization;</section><section prefix="5.">three representatives from industries that may be susceptible to attacks on cybersecurity; and</section><section prefix="6.">one representative of an organization that has expertise in electronic health care records.</section></section></section><section prefix="(2)">The Governor also shall invite the following representatives of federal agencies to serve on the Commission:<section prefix="(i)">the Director of the National Institute for Standards and Technology, or the Director's designee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Secretary of Defense, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Director of the National Security Agency, or the Director's designee;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Secretary of Homeland Security, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(v)">the Director of the Defense Information Systems Agency, or the Director's designee; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">the Director of the Intelligence Advanced Research Projects Activity, or the Director's designee.</section></section></section><section prefix="(c)">The members appointed by the Presiding Officers of the General Assembly shall cochair the Commission.</section><section prefix="(d)">The University of Maryland University College shall provide staff for the Commission.</section><section prefix="(e)">A member of the Commission:<section prefix="(1)">may not receive compensation as a member of the Commission; but</section><section prefix="(2)">is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section><section prefix="(f)">The purpose of the Commission is to provide a road map for making the State the epicenter of cybersecurity innovation and excellence.</section><section prefix="(g)">The Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">conduct a comprehensive review of and identify any inconsistencies in:<section prefix="(i)">State and federal cybersecurity laws; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">policies, standards, and best practices for ensuring the security of computer systems and networks used by educational institutions and State government and other organizations that work with health care records, personal identification information, public safety, and public service and utilities;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">conduct a comprehensive review of the State's role in promoting cyber innovation;</section><section prefix="(3)">identify any federal preemption issues relating to cybersecurity;</section><section prefix="(4)">provide recommendations for:<section prefix="(i)">a comprehensive State framework and strategic plan for cybersecurity innovation and excellence;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a comprehensive State strategic plan to ensure a coordinated and adaptable response to and recovery from attacks on cybersecurity;</section><section prefix="(iii)">coordinated and unified policies to clarify the roles and responsibilities of State units regarding cybersecurity;</section><section prefix="(iv)">growth opportunities and economic development strategies and action plans; and</section><section prefix="(v)">strategies that can be used to coordinate State and federal resources to attract private sector investment and job creation in cybersecurity;</section></section><section prefix="(5)">make recommendations regarding:<section prefix="(i)">methods the State can use to increase cybersecurity innovation by:<section prefix="1.">promoting public and private partnerships, research and development, and workforce training, education, and development;</section><section prefix="2.">promoting science, technology, engineering, and mathematics courses in all levels of education;</section><section prefix="3.">helping companies transfer research to product;</section><section prefix="4.">protecting intellectual properties; and</section><section prefix="5.">leveraging federal funds for research, development, and commercialization;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">methods that the State can use to promote collaboration and coordination among cybersecurity companies and among institutions of higher education located in the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a unit of State government that is suitable to run a pilot program regarding cybersecurity; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the designation of a cybersecurity policy official that would be responsible for coordinating the State's cybersecurity policies, strategies, and activities.</section></section></section><section prefix="(h)">On or before January 1, 2012, the Commission shall submit an interim report of its findings and recommendations, including recommended legislation, to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of this article, the General Assembly.</section><section prefix="(i)">On or before September 1, 2014, the Commission shall submit a final report of its findings and recommendations, including recommended legislation, to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of this article, the General Assembly.</section></text>
</law>
