<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-1A-38</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Joint Committee on Gaming Oversight....</catch_line>
  <order_by>38</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Joint Committee on Gaming Oversight.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Committee consists of the following eight members:<section prefix="(i)">four members of the Senate, appointed by the President of the Senate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">four members of the House of Delegates, appointed by the Speaker of the House.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At least one Senator and one Delegate appointed under this subsection shall be a member of the minority party.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The members of the Committee serve at the pleasure of the presiding officer who appointed them.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The President and the Speaker of the House shall appoint a Senator and a Delegate, respectively, to serve as cochairs.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Committee shall examine:<section prefix="(i)">the status of the State's gaming program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the implementation of new laws relating to gaming.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Committee shall make recommendations for potential improvements to the State's gaming program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department of Legislative Services shall provide staffing for the Committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A member of the Committee may not receive compensation for serving on the Committee, but is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">On or before December 31 of each year, the Committee shall report its findings and recommendations to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of this article, the General Assembly.</section>
  </text>
</law>
