<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-1A-35</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Small, Minority, and Women-Owned Businesses Account under the authority of the Board of P...</catch_line>
  <order_by>35</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Small, Minority, and Women-Owned Businesses Account under the authority of the Board of Public Works.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Account shall receive money as required under &#xA7; 9-1A-27 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Money in the Account shall be invested and reinvested by the Treasurer and interest and earnings shall accrue to the Account.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Comptroller shall:<section prefix="(i)">account for the Account; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">on a properly approved transmittal prepared by the Board of Public Works, issue a warrant to pay out money from the Account in the manner provided under this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Account is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Expenditures from the Account shall only be made on a properly approved transmittal prepared by the Board of Public Works as provided under subsection (c) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "eligible fund manager" means an entity that has significant financial or investment experience, under criteria developed by the Board of Public Works.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (3) of this subsection, the Board of Public Works shall make grants to eligible fund managers to provide investment capital and loans to small, minority, and women-owned businesses in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board of Public Works shall ensure that eligible fund managers allocate at least 50% of the funds from this Account to small, minority, and women-owned businesses in the jurisdictions and communities surrounding a video lottery facility.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Fund managers receiving grants under this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">keep proper records of funds and accounts;</section><section prefix="(2)">provide an annual report to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of this article, the General Assembly on investment capital and loans made pursuant to subsection (c) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(3)">be subject to audit by the Office of Legislative Audits of the Department of Legislative Services.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, an eligible fund manager may use money from grants received under this section to pay expenses for administrative, actuarial, legal, and technical services.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board of Public Works shall set the maximum amount of grant money that each eligible fund manager may use under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Each fiscal year the Legislative Auditor shall audit and evaluate the utilization of the funds that are allocated to small, minority, and women-owned businesses by eligible fund managers under subsection (c)(3) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
