<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-1011" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-1011</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Archives is the central depository for and custodian of each deed, title insurance policy, and other record that relates to real property acquired by the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Archives may allow a unit of the State government to have custody of an original record that relates to real property acquired by the State, if the unit:<section prefix="(1)">needs the record for the daily operation of the unit;</section><section prefix="(2)">demonstrates to the Archives that the unit will preserve the record adequately; and</section><section prefix="(3)">deposits with the Archives a security microform copy of the record.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Archives shall receive, index, and file durable-backed, microfilm aperture card copies or electronic images of plats showing property or rights-of-way acquired or conveyed by the State Roads Commission and the State Highway Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Archives electronically shall post an image of each plat on the Archives website (http://www.plats.net) for the county where the property or right-of-way is located.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The posted image shall conform to a generally accepted archival standard in quality and permanence.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The image shall include or be linked to a certification by the State Archivist that the image is an authentic representation of the plat received by the Archives.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Such certification by the State Archivist shall constitute a recordation of the plat.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The Archives may charge a reasonable fee to the State Roads Commission, the State Highway Administration, and the courts to recover the cost of electronically posting and maintaining the images of plats.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The Archives may charge a reasonable fee, not to exceed $3, to the public for the cost of reproducing a copy of a plat under this subsection.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
