<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-2701</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>2701</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Council" means the Maryland Youth Advisory Council.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"High school student" means a youth who is enrolled in high school, who is a home school student, or who is enrolled in a program that leads to a high school diploma or certificate of attendance or a general equivalency diploma.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Institution of postsecondary education" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 10-101 of the Education Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Public senior higher education institution" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 10-101 of the Education Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Youth" means an individual who is 14 to 22 years old.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Maryland Youth Advisory Council.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Council consists of:<section prefix="(1)">the following members appointed by the President of the Senate:<section prefix="(i)">six high school students, including at least three who are students in the State and who are enrolled in public high schools;</section><section prefix="(ii)">two youths who are students at institutions of postsecondary education located in the State; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">one member of the Senate;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the following members appointed by the Speaker of the House of Delegates:<section prefix="(i)">six high school students, including at least three who are students in the State and who are enrolled in public high schools;</section><section prefix="(ii)">two youths who are students at institutions of postsecondary education located in the State; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">one member of the House of Delegates;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">the following members appointed by the Governor:<section prefix="(i)">twelve youths, including at least ten high school students, at least five of whom shall be students in the State who are enrolled in public high schools; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">four youths who are students at institutions of postsecondary education located in the State;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">the following members selected by other youths, including:<section prefix="(i)">fifteen high school students chosen by the Maryland Association of Student Councils; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">eight youths who are students at institutions of postsecondary education located in the State, including:<section prefix="1.">three members selected by the University System of Maryland Student Council; and</section><section prefix="2.">five members selected by the Student Advisory Council to the Maryland Higher Education Commission, including:</section></section></section><section prefix="(5)">an executive board that consists of:<section prefix="(i)">four members selected by the youth members appointed by the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House, including:<section prefix="1.">three high school students; and</section><section prefix="2.">one student at an institution of postsecondary education;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">four members selected by the youth members appointed by the Governor, including:<section prefix="1.">three high school students; and</section><section prefix="2.">one student at an institution of postsecondary education; and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">four members selected by the youth members chosen by other youth, including:<section prefix="1.">three high school students; and</section><section prefix="2.">one student at an institution of postsecondary education.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In deciding which members to appoint or select:<section prefix="(1)">the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House shall, to the extent practicable, consider:<section prefix="(i)">the geographic and demographic diversity of the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">diversity in education, including nontraditional settings such as vocational and tech-oriented education; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">youths with disabilities;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the Governor shall, to the extent practicable, consider:<section prefix="(i)">the geographic and demographic diversity of the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">diversity in education, including nontraditional settings such as vocational and tech-oriented education;</section><section prefix="(iii)">youths with disabilities; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">transitional youths who are not in high school or an institution of postsecondary education and not likely to attend an institution of postsecondary education; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">the Maryland Association of Student Councils shall consider youths who are enrolled in schools represented by the Association as well as applicants who are enrolled in schools that are not represented by the Association.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a youth member of the Council is 1 year, from September 1 through August 30 of the following year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A youth member who is appointed or selected after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed or selected and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A youth member may not serve more than two consecutive terms.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The member from the Senate and the member from the House serve, respectively, at the pleasure of the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At the first meeting of each youth member term period, the youth members shall elect one of the youth members to serve as cochair for a term of 1 year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A representative of the Governor's Office for Children appointed by the Governor, the member from the Senate, and the member from the House shall serve as cochairs with the elected youth member cochair.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Council may appoint any officers that it considers necessary.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The cochair appointed by the Governor shall, on behalf of the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House, develop an initial application and application process, both of which the Council may change at its discretion.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Governor's Office for Children, in addition to the member from the Senate, or the member from the House, or both, shall provide staff support for the Council.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Council shall:<section prefix="(1)">inform the Governor and the General Assembly of issues concerning youth, including offering testimony on these issues before legislative bodies;</section><section prefix="(2)">examine issues of importance to youth, including:<section prefix="(i)">education;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a safe learning environment;</section><section prefix="(iii)">employment opportunities;</section><section prefix="(iv)">strategies to increase youth participation in local and State government;</section><section prefix="(v)">health care access and quality of care;</section><section prefix="(vi)">substance abuse and underage drinking;</section><section prefix="(vii)">emotional and physical well-being;</section><section prefix="(viii)">the environment;</section><section prefix="(ix)">poverty;</section><section prefix="(x)">homelessness;</section><section prefix="(xi)">youth access to State and local services;</section><section prefix="(xii)">suicide prevention; and</section><section prefix="(xiii)">educational accessibility issues for students with disabilities, including access to:<section prefix="1.">schools;</section><section prefix="2.">school-related activities; and</section><section prefix="3.">classes;</section></section></section><section prefix="(3)">recommend one legislative proposal each legislative session concerning an issue included in item (2) of this subsection for possible introduction; and</section><section prefix="(4)">conduct a public awareness campaign to raise awareness about the Council among Maryland youth.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Council shall work with the State Department of Education regarding the granting of school credit for Council service.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Department of Education and the Maryland Higher Education Commission shall notify the head administrators of all State high schools and of all institutions of postsecondary education, respectively, of the creation of the Council so that the administrators may inform their students.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The State Department of Education shall allow up to four absences of a youth member from school per school year to be categorized as lawful absences if the absences were due to the business of the Council.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Council shall set priorities and determine:<section prefix="(i)">the function of subcommittees;</section><section prefix="(ii)">standards of conduct;</section><section prefix="(iii)">procedures; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the use of technology to convene or conduct meetings or facilitate communications among members.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Council shall review and consider whether the procedures and rules used by the General Assembly would be appropriate for use as models for the Council.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The Council shall:<section prefix="(1)">meet at least four times each year and conduct one or two public hearings each year on issues of importance to youth;</section><section prefix="(2)">conduct one educational meeting concerning the legislative process, to which the President of the Senate, the Speaker of the House, and the Executive Director of the Department of Legislative Services, or their designees, shall be invited to speak; and</section><section prefix="(3)">open all meetings to the public.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">A member of the Council:<section prefix="(1)">may not receive compensation as a member of the Council; but</section><section prefix="(2)">is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">On or before the last day of the youth members' terms, the Council shall report its activities to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of this article, to the General Assembly.</section>
  </text>
</law>
