<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-20-704</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>704</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This subtitle does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">the sale or rental of a single-family dwelling, if the dwelling is sold or rented without:<section prefix="(i)">the use of the sales or rental facilities or services of any:<section prefix="1.">real estate broker, agent, or salesperson;</section><section prefix="2.">agent of any real estate broker, agent, or salesperson;</section><section prefix="3.">person in the business of selling or renting dwellings; or</section><section prefix="4.">agent of a person in the business of selling or renting dwellings; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">the publication, posting, or mailing, after notice, of any advertisement or written notice in violation of this subtitle; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">with respect to discrimination on the basis of sex, sexual orientation, or marital status:<section prefix="(i)">the rental of rooms in any dwelling, if the owner maintains the dwelling as the owner's principal residence; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the rental of any apartment in a dwelling that contains not more than five rental units, if the owner maintains the dwelling as the owner's principal residence.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The use of attorneys, escrow agents, abstractors, title companies, and other similar professional assistance as necessary to perfect or transfer the title to a single-family dwelling does not subject a person to this subtitle if the person otherwise would be exempted under subsection (a) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection, "housing for older persons" means housing:<section prefix="1.">provided under any State or federal program that is specifically designed and operated to assist elderly persons, as defined in the State or federal program;</section><section prefix="2.">intended for, and solely occupied by, persons who are at least 62 years old;</section><section prefix="3.">intended and operated for occupancy by at least one person who is at least 55 years old in each unit; or</section><section prefix="4.">that meets the requirements set forth in regulations adopted by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development under 42 U.S.C. &#xA7; 3607(b)(2)(C).</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Housing for older persons" includes:<section prefix="1.">unoccupied units, if the units are reserved for occupancy by persons who meet the age requirements of subparagraph (i) of this paragraph; or</section><section prefix="2.">units occupied as of September 13, 1988 by persons who do not meet the age requirements of subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, if the new occupant of the unit meets the age requirement.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The provisions in this subtitle concerning familial status do not apply to housing for older persons.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
