<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-108" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-6-108</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Attorney General or any Deputy Attorney General or assistant Attorney General whom the Attorney General designates may:<section prefix="(1)">become a member of an organization of attorneys general of other states or their deputies or assistants and, as provided in the State budget, contribute to the expenses of the organization; and</section><section prefix="(2)">use the services of the Council of State Governments and, as provided in the State budget, contribute to the cost of the services.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On January 1 of each year, the Attorney General shall submit an annual report to the Governor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual report shall:<section prefix="(i)">describe the business and proceedings of the Office during the preceding calendar year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">include an itemized statement of the receipts and disbursements of the Attorney General during the preceding fiscal year; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">include any recommendations that the Attorney General considers appropriate.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Attorney General shall keep the following records until they are disposed of in accordance with &#xA7; 10-639 of this article:<section prefix="(1)">a copy of the pleadings in each suit, action, or other proceeding of which the Office has charge;</section><section prefix="(2)">a complete and current docket of those proceedings;</section><section prefix="(3)">a copy of each written opinion that the Office issues; and</section><section prefix="(4)">an abstract of each title that the Office examines or has examined.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Attorney General annually shall have published, in bound volume:<section prefix="(1)">the opinions that the Office issued during the preceding calendar year; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the annual report for that preceding calendar year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The papers of the Office shall be filed in its offices until disposed of in accordance with &#xA7; 10-639 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The papers and books of the Office shall be indexed so that they are readily accessible.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
