<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-15-514</section_number>
  <catch_line>A legislator may request a written opinion from the Joint Ethics Committee with respect to the propr...</catch_line>
  <order_by>514</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A legislator may request a written opinion from the Joint Ethics Committee with respect to the propriety of any current or proposed conduct of the legislator and involving the applicable standards of ethical conduct for legislators established by law, rule, or other standard of ethical conduct.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A request for an opinion shall:<section prefix="(i)">be in writing and signed by the legislator;</section><section prefix="(ii)">be addressed to the Joint Ethics Committee or either cochairman;</section><section prefix="(iii)">be submitted in a timely manner; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">include a complete and accurate statement of the relevant facts.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a request is unclear or incomplete, the Joint Ethics Committee may seek additional information from the legislator.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Counsel to the Joint Ethics Committee shall prepare for the Committee a response to each written request for an opinion under this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Each response shall discuss all applicable laws, rules, or other standards.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Except as provided in paragraph (6)(i) of this subsection, an opinion must be approved by a majority of the members of the Joint Ethics Committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The cochairmen of the Joint Ethics Committee may approve an opinion on behalf of the Committee if they determine that the opinion is consistent with prior precedent and therefore does not require consideration by the full Committee.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An opinion for which approval by the co-chairmen under this paragraph is anticipated shall be distributed to each member of the Joint Ethics Committee not later than the next meeting of the Joint Ethics Committee.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Notwithstanding subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, if a cochairman of the Joint Ethics Committee is the legislator requesting the opinion, the opinion must be approved by a majority of the Committee.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Joint Ethics Committee is not required to issue an opinion if the request is not made in a timely manner.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Joint Ethics Committee on its own motion may render opinions as it considers appropriate.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The cochairmen shall determine whether an opinion shall be made public, with deletions and changes necessary to protect the legislator's identity.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Counsel to the Joint Ethics Committee shall compile and index each opinion that will be made public.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The compilation of opinions shall be distributed to each member of the General Assembly and shall be available to the public.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Joint Ethics Committee may take no adverse action with regard to conduct that has been undertaken in reliance on a written opinion if the conduct conforms to the specific facts addressed in the opinion.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Information provided to the Joint Ethics Committee by a legislator seeking advice regarding prospective conduct may not be used as the basis for initiating an investigation under &#xA7; 15-515 of this subtitle if the legislator acts in good faith in accordance with the advice of the Committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An opinion issued under this section is binding on any legislator to whom it is addressed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A published opinion is binding on all members of the General Assembly.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
