<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-15-849</section_number>
  <catch_line>When an application is filed, the applicant shall file an affidavit, under oath, stating whether the...</catch_line>
  <order_by>849</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When an application is filed, the applicant shall file an affidavit, under oath, stating whether the applicant:<section prefix="(i)">has made any contribution or contributions having a cumulative value of $500 or more to the treasurer of a candidate or the treasurer of a political committee during the 48-month period before the application is filed, to the best of the applicant's information, knowledge, and belief; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">is currently engaging in business with an elected official.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the applicant or a party of record or a family member has made a contribution or contributions having a cumulative value of $500 or more during the 48-month period before the application was filed or during the pendency of the application, the applicant or the party of record shall file a disclosure providing the name of the candidate or elected official to whose treasurer or political committee the contribution was made, the amount, and the date of the contribution. However, if the party of record is a community association, this paragraph may not be construed to require the association to poll its members to disclose individual contributions.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A contribution made between the filing of the application and the disposition of the application shall be disclosed within 5 business days of the contribution.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An applicant who begins engaging in business with an elected official between the filing of the application and the disposition of the application shall file the affidavit at the time of engaging in business with the elected official.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (a)(3) of this section, the affidavit or disclosure shall be filed at least 30 calendar days prior to any consideration of the application by an elected official.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Within 2 weeks after entering a proceeding, a party of record that has made a contribution shall submit a disclosure as described in subsection (a)(2) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a contributor and an elected official are subject to the provisions of this Part VII if the contributor makes a contribution to:<section prefix="(i)">the candidate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a slate; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the candidate's political committee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The provisions of this Part VII do not apply to a transfer by a political action committee to a candidate or the candidate's continuing political committee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An affidavit or a disclosure required under this Part VII shall be in a form established by the Howard County Solicitor and approved by the County Council. The completed form shall be filed in the appropriate case file of an application. The disclosure form shall repeat the penalty provision in &#xA7; 15-850(a) of this Part VII.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A contribution made after the filing of the initial disclosure and before final disposition of the application by the County Council shall be disclosed within 5 business days of the contribution.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In the enforcement of this Part VII, the administrative clerk to the zoning board or the administrator of the County Council, as appropriate, considering an application shall be subject to the authority of the Howard County Ethics Commission and, unless otherwise directed by the Ethics Commission, shall:<section prefix="(1)">receive filings of affidavits and disclosures;</section><section prefix="(2)">maintain filed affidavits and disclosures as public records available for review by the general public during normal business hours;</section><section prefix="(3)">report violations to the Howard County Ethics Commission; and</section><section prefix="(4)">perform ministerial duties necessary to administer this Part VII.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Promptly on receipt, the administrative assistant to the zoning board and the administrator of the County Council shall prepare a summary report compiling all affidavits and disclosures filed under this Part VII.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The summary report shall be a matter of public record and available for immediate inspection upon written request.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
