<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-20B-07</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Strategic Energy Investment Advisory Board....</catch_line>
  <order_by>07</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Strategic Energy Investment Advisory Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall review the Program and the Administration's proposed uses of and expenditures from the Fund and make recommendations to the Administration concerning any proposed use or expenditure.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration shall consider the Board's recommendations when making decisions about uses and expenditures from the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board consists of the following members:<section prefix="(1)">one member of the Senate, appointed by the President of the Senate;</section><section prefix="(2)">one member of the House of Delegates, appointed by the Speaker of the House of Delegates;</section><section prefix="(3)">the following members appointed by the Governor:<section prefix="(i)">two representatives of Maryland residential customers;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a representative of Maryland commercial customers;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a representative of large electricity users in the State;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a representative of an electric company;</section><section prefix="(v)">a representative of an electric cooperative;</section><section prefix="(vi)">a representative of electricity suppliers;</section><section prefix="(vii)">a representative of a Maryland environmental group; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">a representative of a renewable electricity industry; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">the following nonvoting ex officio members:<section prefix="(i)">the Chairman of the Public Service Commission or the Chairman's designee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the People's Counsel or the designee of the People's Counsel; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Secretary of the Environment or the Secretary's designee.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a regulated lobbyist is appointed to serve as a member of the Board, the lobbyist:<section prefix="(1)">is not subject to &#xA7; 15-504(d) of this article with respect to that service; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is not subject to &#xA7; 15-703(f)(3) of this article as a result of that service.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member appointed by the Governor is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of the members appointed by the Governor are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Board on June 1, 2008.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board shall meet at least 2 times each year.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Board may act only by the affirmative vote of at least six voting members.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A member of the Board:<section prefix="(i)">may not receive compensation as a member of the Board; but</section><section prefix="(ii)">is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Administration shall provide staff support for the Board.</section>
  </text>
</law>
