<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9.5-309" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9.5-309</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the approval of the Governor, the Commission may by regulation establish a process for an Indian community that is indigenous to the State to apply to the Commission for recognition of Maryland Indian status.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Commission finds that a petitioning group meets the requirements for recognition, the Commission may recommend to the Governor that it be granted recognition of Maryland Indian status.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member of the Commission may not vote or participate in deliberations on an application for recognition of Maryland Indian status made by the petitioning group to which the member belongs.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor may issue an executive order providing recognition of Maryland Indian status to the petitioning group.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The executive order:<section prefix="(i)">shall be submitted to the Joint Committee on Administrative, Executive, and Legislative Review; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall take effect 30 days after it is submitted.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section does not:<section prefix="(i)">create a right of ownership or any other right to land;</section><section prefix="(ii)">create a benefit or entitlement of any kind;</section><section prefix="(iii)">impair existing rights, benefits, or entitlements belonging to Indians living in the State;</section><section prefix="(iv)">impair existing judicial rulings of the State regarding Indians of the State; or</section><section prefix="(v)">give the Commission the power to establish standards for membership in an Indian community.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The power to establish standards for membership in an Indian community is reserved to the community.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An act or failure to act by the Commission under this section does not create a private cause of action under State law.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
