<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-1A-31</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>31</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (7) of this subsection, the local impact grants provided under &#xA7; 9-1A-27 of this subtitle shall be distributed as provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The following amounts shall be distributed to the following jurisdictions:<section prefix="(i)">Allegany County - $200,000;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Cecil County - $130,000;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Town of Perryville - $70,000; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Worcester County - $200,000.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The remaining funds for local impact grants shall be distributed in the following manner:<section prefix="(i)">82% to the local jurisdictions with video lottery facilities, based on each jurisdiction's percentage of overall gross revenues from video lottery terminals; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, for operations at a video lottery facility starting in fiscal year 2012 and ending in fiscal year 2032, 18% to Baltimore City with the Pimlico Community Development Authority acting as the local development council in accordance with subsection (d) of this section, to be distributed primarily for capital projects benefiting economic and community development in the following manner:<section prefix="1.">at least 75% in a manner that is consistent with the Park Heights Master Plan; and</section><section prefix="2.">the remainder dedicated to the needs of:</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Of the amount specified under paragraph (3)(ii) of this subsection, $1,000,000 shall be provided annually to Prince George's County to be used for public safety projects in the community within 5 miles surrounding Rosecroft Raceway.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Legislative Policy Committee shall report its findings and recommendations concerning the advisability of the continuation of the distribution of funds after fiscal year 2032 to the Comptroller and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of this article, the General Assembly, on or before November 1, 2030.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Baltimore City and Prince George's County shall report to the Legislative Policy Committee by December 31 of each year as to the distribution of the funds provided under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The distribution under paragraph (3)(i) of this subsection to Anne Arundel County, Baltimore City, and Prince George's County equals the sum of the amounts to be distributed to Anne Arundel County, Baltimore City, and Prince George's County divided by three.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Notwithstanding subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the amount distributed to Anne Arundel County and Baltimore City under paragraph (3)(i) of this subsection may not be less than the amount received in the fiscal year before the video lottery operation license for a video lottery facility in Prince George's County was issued.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Beginning after a video lottery operation license is issued to a video lottery facility in Baltimore City, 100% of the local impact grants provided under &#xA7; 9-1A-27 of this subtitle from the proceeds of the video lottery facilities located in Allegany, Cecil, and Worcester counties shall be distributed to the local jurisdictions in which those video lottery facilities are located.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection and subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection, local impact grants provided under subsection (a)(3)(i) of this section shall be used for improvements primarily in the communities in immediate proximity to the video lottery facilities and may be used for the following purposes:<section prefix="(i)">infrastructure improvements;</section><section prefix="(ii)">facilities;</section><section prefix="(iii)">public safety;</section><section prefix="(iv)">sanitation;</section><section prefix="(v)">economic and community development, including housing; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">other public services and improvements.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Allegany County, local impact grants provided under subsection (a)(3)(i) of this section may be used:<section prefix="(i)">for purposes listed in paragraph (1) of this subsection throughout the county; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">to pay down the debt incurred by the county in the construction and related costs for the golf course, lodge, and other improvements in Rocky Gap State Park.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In Baltimore City, local impact grants provided under subsection (a)(3)(i) of this section shall be used for improvements in the communities in immediate proximity to the video lottery facility and may be used for the following purposes:<section prefix="(i)">infrastructure improvements;</section><section prefix="(ii)">facilities;</section><section prefix="(iii)">public safety;</section><section prefix="(iv)">sanitation;</section><section prefix="(v)">economic and community development, including housing; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">other public services and improvements.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, in Prince George's County, 40% of local impact grants provided under this section shall be used to address infrastructure needs related to Maryland Route 210 in Prince George's County.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The amount of local impact grants used as provided in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph may not exceed $15,000,000 in a fiscal year.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Prince George's County may be reimbursed by the State for any money used as provided in this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A local development council shall be established in each geographic area where a video lottery facility is located.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, a local development council shall consist of the following 15 members appointed by the chief executive of the county in which the local development council is located, in consultation with the Senators and Delegates who represent the communities surrounding the facility and the respective county councils, city councils, or county commissioners:<section prefix="(i)">one Senator who represents the district where the facility is located;</section><section prefix="(ii)">two Delegates who represent the districts where the communities surrounding the facility are located;</section><section prefix="(iii)">one representative of the video lottery operation licensee;</section><section prefix="(iv)">seven residents of the communities in immediate proximity to the facility; and</section><section prefix="(v)">four representatives of businesses or institutions located in immediate proximity to the facility.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the video lottery facility is at a racetrack location at Laurel Park, the County Executive of Anne Arundel County, the County Executive of Prince George's County, and the County Executive of Howard County shall jointly appoint the local development council.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the video lottery facility is at a racetrack location at the Ocean Downs Race Course:<section prefix="1.">the County Commissioners of Worcester County shall appoint the local development council;</section><section prefix="2.">the Senator or the Senator's designee shall serve as a member of the local development council; and</section><section prefix="3.">the Delegates or the Delegates' designees shall serve as members of the local development council.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Prior to any expenditure of local impact grant funds provided under &#xA7; 9-1A-27 of this subtitle, a county or municipality shall develop, in consultation with the local development council, a multiyear plan for the expenditure of the local impact grant funds for services and improvements consistent with subsection (b) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A county or municipality shall submit the plan to the local development council for review and comment before adopting the plan or expending any grant funds.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The local development council shall advise the county or municipality on the impact of the facility on the communities and the needs and priorities of the communities in immediate proximity to the facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A local development council shall have 45 days to review, comment, and make recommendations on the plan required under this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">On the request of a local development council, the county or municipality shall hold a public hearing on the plan.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A county or municipality shall make best efforts to accommodate the recommendations of the local development council and any testimony presented at the hearing before adopting the plan required under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A video lottery operation licensee shall provide to the local development council a master plan for the development of the site on which the video lottery facility will be located.</section>
  </text>
</law>
