<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-10-502.5</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>502.5</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Any person may file a written complaint with the Board seeking a written opinion from the Board on the application of the provisions of this subtitle to the action of a public body covered by this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The complaint shall:<section prefix="(1)">be signed by the person making the complaint; and</section><section prefix="(2)">identify the public body, specify the action of the public body, the date of the action, and the circumstances of the action.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On receipt of the written complaint, and except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, the Board shall promptly send the complaint to the public body identified in the complaint and request that a response to the complaint be sent to the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The public body shall file a written response to the complaint within 30 days of its receipt of the complaint.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">On request of the Board, the public body shall include with its written response to the complaint a copy of:<section prefix="1.">a notice provided under &#xA7; 10-506 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="2.">a written statement made under &#xA7; 10-508(d)(2)(ii) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="3.">minutes and any tape recording made by the public body under &#xA7; 10-509 of this subtitle.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Board shall maintain the confidentiality of minutes and any tape recording submitted by a public body that are sealed in accordance with &#xA7; 10-509(c)(3)(ii) of this subtitle.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the public body identified in the complaint no longer exists, the Board shall promptly send the complaint to the official or entity that appointed the public body.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The official or entity that appointed the public body shall, to the extent feasible, comply with the requirements of paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If after 45 days, a written response is not received, the Board shall decide the case on the facts before it.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">review the complaint and any response; and</section><section prefix="(2)">if the information in the complaint and response is sufficient to permit a determination, issue a written opinion as to whether a violation of the provisions of this subtitle has occurred or will occur not later than 30 days after receiving the response.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Board is unable to reach a determination based on the written submissions before it, the Board may schedule an informal conference to hear from the complainant, the public body, or any other person with relevant information about the subject of the complaint.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An informal conference scheduled by the Board is not a "contested case" within the meaning of &#xA7; 10-202(d) of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board shall issue a written opinion not later than 30 days following the informal conference.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Board is unable to render an opinion on a complaint within the time periods specified in subsection (d) or (e) of this section, the Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">state in writing the reason for its inability; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">issue an opinion as soon as possible but not later than 90 days after the filing of the complaint.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An opinion of the Board may state that the Board is unable to resolve the complaint.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Board shall send a copy of the written opinion to the complainant and to the affected public body.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On a periodic basis, the Board may send to any public body in the State any written opinion that will provide the public body with guidance on compliance with the provisions of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On request, a copy of a written opinion shall be provided to any person.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The opinions of the Board are advisory only.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may not require or compel any specific actions by a public body.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">A written opinion issued by the Board may not be introduced as evidence in a proceeding conducted in accordance with &#xA7; 10-510 of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
