<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-10-224</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>224</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Business" means a trade, professional activity, or other business that is conducted for profit.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Nonprofit organization" means an organization that is exempt or eligible for exemption from taxation under &#xA7; 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only to:<section prefix="(1)">an agency operating statewide;</section><section prefix="(2)">a business that, on the date when the contested case or civil action is initiated:<section prefix="(i)">is independently owned and operated; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">has less than 50 employees, including, if a corporation owns 50% or more of the stock of the business, each employee of the corporation; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">a nonprofit organization.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subject to the limitations in this section, an agency or court may award to a business or nonprofit organization reimbursement for expenses that the business or nonprofit organization reasonably incurs in connection with a contested case or civil action that:<section prefix="(1)">is initiated against the business or nonprofit organization by an agency as part of an administrative or regulatory function;</section><section prefix="(2)">is initiated without substantial justification or in bad faith; and</section><section prefix="(3)">does not result in:<section prefix="(i)">an adjudication, stipulation, or acceptance of liability of the business or nonprofit organization;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a determination of noncompliance, violation, infringement, deficiency, or breach on the part of the business or nonprofit organization; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a settlement agreement under which the business or nonprofit organization agrees to take corrective action or to pay a monetary sum.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To qualify for an award under this section when the agency has initiated a contested case, the business or nonprofit organization must make a claim to the agency before taking any appeal.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The agency shall act on the claim.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An award under this section may include:<section prefix="(i)">the expenses incurred in the contested case;</section><section prefix="(ii)">court costs;</section><section prefix="(iii)">counsel fees; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the fees of necessary witnesses.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An award under this section may not exceed $10,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The court may reduce or deny an award to the extent that the conduct of the business or nonprofit organization during the proceedings unreasonably delayed the resolution of the matter in controversy.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An award under this section shall be paid as provided in the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the agency denies an award under this section, the business or nonprofit organization may appeal, as provided in this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An agency may appeal an award that a court makes under this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
