<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-2-10A-12</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>12</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Joint Committee on Base Realignment and Closure.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Committee consists of 16 members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 16 members:<section prefix="(i)">eight shall be members of the Senate of Maryland, appointed by the President of the Senate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">eight shall be members of the House of Delegates, appointed by the Speaker of the House.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">From among the membership of the Committee, the President of the Senate shall appoint a Senator to serve as the Senate Chair of the Committee, and the Speaker of the House shall appoint a Delegate to serve as the House Chair of the Committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department of Legislative Services shall provide staff assistance to the Committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Committee shall provide continuing legislative oversight of the State's response to changes and opportunities occurring as a result of the Base Realignment and Closure process.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Committee shall oversee and participate, in cooperation with State and local units, in the development of systems and processes that, with the intent of accelerating planning and development so that the State is prepared to receive the influx of jobs and personnel associated with the Base Realignment and Closure process, fast track the approval of:<section prefix="(1)">transportation infrastructure;</section><section prefix="(2)">water and sewer infrastructure;</section><section prefix="(3)">State and local planning processes;</section><section prefix="(4)">affordable housing options;</section><section prefix="(5)">education facilities, including public school and community college construction; and</section><section prefix="(6)">health care facilities and infrastructure.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
