<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-11-520</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>520</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A local government shall act on each application for a development permit to be issued by the local government in accordance with the law and procedures applicable to the granting of the development permit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the local government has participated in a joint hearing, it shall give prompt notice of its action to the Coordinator, who shall send the notice to each State unit that participated in the joint hearing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each State unit that has participated in a joint hearing shall act promptly on each application for a development permit to be issued by the State unit within 60 days after the day on which the State unit receives notice that the local government has acted on the application for the local development permit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the local government has denied the local development permit, the State unit may deny its development permit for that reason. However, the State unit may reconsider the application for a development permit if the local development permit is later granted.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A State unit that has participated in a joint hearing shall give the Coordinator and the local government notice of the action by the State unit on each application for a development permit.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each State unit that has participated in a consolidated hearing shall act on each application for a development permit to be issued by the State unit within 60 days after the day on which the consolidated hearing concludes.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each State unit that does not hold a hearing shall act on an application for a development permit within 60 days after receiving the completed application for the development permit.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Unless a State unit obtains an extension under &#xA7; 11-521 of this subtitle, failure of the State unit to act within the time set by this section and by &#xA7; 11-515 of this subtitle constitutes automatic approval of the application for a development permit as submitted to the State unit, and the State unit immediately shall issue the development permit.</section>
  </text>
</law>
