<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-1A-16</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>16</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">For all licenses required under this subtitle other than a video lottery operation license, if an applicant or licensee holds a valid license in another state and the Commission determines that the licensing standards of the other state are comprehensive, thorough, and provide similar adequate safeguards to those provided in this subtitle, the Commission may:<section prefix="(1)">waive some or all of the requirements of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">issue a license to a person having a similar license in another state.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, on the request of an applicant, the Commission may grant an exemption or waiver of a licensing requirement or grounds for denial of a license if the Commission determines that the requirement or grounds for denial of a license as applied to the applicant are not necessary in order to protect the public interest or accomplish the policies established by this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On granting to an applicant an exemption or waiver of a licensing requirement or grounds for denial of a license, or at any time after a waiver or exemption has been granted, the Commission may:<section prefix="(i)">limit or place restrictions on the exemption or waiver as the Commission considers necessary in the public interest; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">require the person that is granted the exemption or waiver to cooperate with the Commission and to provide the Commission with any additional information required by the Commission as a condition of the waiver or exemption.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission may not waive any of the requirements of this subtitle related to a video lottery operation license.</section>
  </text>
</law>
