<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-20-1024</section_number>
  <catch_line>During the period between the filing of a complaint and the filing of a charge or a dismissal by the...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1024</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">During the period between the filing of a complaint and the filing of a charge or a dismissal by the Commission, the Commission, to the extent feasible, shall engage in conciliation with respect to the complaint.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A conciliation agreement is subject to approval by the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A conciliation agreement may provide for binding arbitration of the dispute arising from the complaint.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Any arbitration that results from a conciliation agreement may award appropriate relief, including monetary relief.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each conciliation agreement shall be made public unless the complainant and respondent otherwise agree and the Commission determines that the disclosure is not required to further the purposes of this part and Subtitle 7 of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the Commission has probable cause to believe that a respondent has breached a conciliation agreement, the Commission may bring a civil action to enforce the conciliation agreement in the same manner as provided in &#xA7; 20-1011 of this subtitle for the enforcement of an order of the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except in a proceeding to enforce a conciliation agreement, statements and acts in the course of conciliation under this section may not be made public or used as evidence in a subsequent proceeding under this part without the written consent of the persons concerned.</section>
  </text>
</law>
