<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-10-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a board, commission, or agency head authorized to conduct a contested case hearing shall:<section prefix="(i)">conduct the hearing; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">delegate the authority to conduct the contested case hearing to:<section prefix="1.">the Office; or</section><section prefix="2.">with the prior written approval of the Chief Administrative Law Judge, a person not employed by the Office.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A hearing held in accordance with &#xA7; 4-608(f) or &#xA7; 5-610(f) of the Business Occupations and Professions Article may not be delegated to the Office.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">With the written approval of the Chief Administrative Law Judge, a class of contested case hearings may be delegated as provided in paragraph (1)(ii)2 of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">This subsection is not intended to restrict the right of an individual, expressly authorized by a statute in effect on October 1, 1993, to conduct a contested case hearing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An agency may delegate to the Office the authority to issue:<section prefix="(1)">proposed or final findings of fact;</section><section prefix="(2)">proposed or final conclusions of law;</section><section prefix="(3)">proposed or final findings of fact and conclusions of law;</section><section prefix="(4)">proposed or final orders or orders under Title 20 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(5)">the final administrative decision of an agency in a contested case.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Promptly after receipt of a request for a contested case hearing, an agency shall:<section prefix="(1)">notify the parties that the authorized agency head, board, or commission shall conduct the hearing;</section><section prefix="(2)">transmit the request to the Office so that the Office shall conduct the hearing in accordance with the agency's delegation; or</section><section prefix="(3)">request written approval from the Chief Administrative Law Judge to appoint a person not employed by the Office to conduct the hearing.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, an agency's delegation and transmittal of all or part of a contested case to the Office is final.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an agency has adopted regulations specifying the criteria and procedures for the revocation of a delegation of a contested case, delegation of authority to hear all or part of a contested case may be revoked, by the agency head, board, or commission, in accordance with the agency's regulations, at any time prior to the earlier of:<section prefix="(i)">the issuance of a ruling on a substantive issue; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the taking of oral testimony from the first witness.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Office shall:<section prefix="(i)">conduct the hearing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection or as otherwise required by law, within 90 days after the completion of the hearing, complete the procedure authorized in the agency's delegation to the Office.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The time limit specified in paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection may be extended with the written approval of the Chief Administrative Law Judge.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
