<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-11-518</section_number>
  <catch_line>On receiving notice of the time, date, and place of a joint hearing or consolidated hearing, the app...</catch_line>
  <order_by>518</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On receiving notice of the time, date, and place of a joint hearing or consolidated hearing, the applicant shall give public notice of the application and hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice shall be published once in each of 2 successive weeks before the hearing in a newspaper of general circulation in each county in which the development project is to be located.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Coordinator shall publish notice of the application and hearing in the Maryland Register.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each notice under this section shall contain:<section prefix="(1)">a description of the development project, including its location, the land area involved, and the nature of the development project;</section><section prefix="(2)">a list of the local and State units that will participate in the hearing and their post office addresses and telephone numbers;</section><section prefix="(3)">a description of each development permit requested;</section><section prefix="(4)">the time, date, and place of the hearing; and</section><section prefix="(5)">if the hearing is a joint hearing with a local government or involves a unit of the federal government, any other information that the local government or federal unit requires.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition to the notices required by this section, if the law governing the issuance of a development permit requires that a person or governmental unit provide notice of an application or a hearing to a particular person or unit, that person or governmental unit shall do so in the manner required by that law.</section>
  </text>
</law>
