<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-15-605</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>605</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, a candidate who is required by &#xA7; 15-601(a) of this subtitle to file a statement shall file the statement each year beginning with the year in which the candidate files a certificate of candidacy through the year of the election.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not require the filing of a statement for any full year covered by a statement filed by the individual under &#xA7; 15-602 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A statement under this section shall be filed with the election board with which the certificate of candidacy is required to be filed.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The first statement required under this section shall be filed no later than the filing of the certificate of candidacy.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the year of the election the statement shall be filed on or before the earlier of:<section prefix="(i)">April 30; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the last day for the withdrawal of a candidacy under &#xA7; 5-502 of the Election Law Article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a statement required by this section is overdue and is not filed within 20 days after the candidate receives from the election board written notice of the failure to file, the candidate is deemed to have withdrawn the candidacy.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An election board may not accept a certificate of candidacy or certificate of nomination of a candidate covered by this section unless the candidate has filed a statement required by this section or &#xA7; 15-602 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An election board, within 30 days after receiving a statement, shall forward the statement to the Ethics Commission.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
