<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-701</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>701</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Commission to Coordinate the Study, Commemoration, and Impact of Slavery's History and Legacy in Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The purpose of the Commission is to:<section prefix="(1)">network museums, cultural organizations, cultural parks and centers, and private collections in order to support the cataloging, preservation, and presentation of cultural resources relative to the history and legacy of slavery in Maryland;</section><section prefix="(2)">work with grass roots organizations, foundations, and government agencies in publicizing and seeking support for initiatives relating to the history and legacy of slavery, with special attention to the development of initiatives aimed at and benefitting Maryland youth;</section><section prefix="(3)">target funding for the identification and maintenance of library and archival resources relevant to the history and legacy of slavery, in order to produce guides and maintain online databases of relevant holdings, especially holdings not appropriately cataloged and documented;</section><section prefix="(4)">identify historical sites throughout the State that relate to the history and legacy of slavery and monitor the preservation and development of those sites;</section><section prefix="(5)">keep the State informed of how best to support programs and initiatives to commemorate the middle passage, slavery, indentured servitude, and the underground railroad;</section><section prefix="(6)">keep the State informed of the latest research on the lingering psychological, sociological, and economic impacts of slavery and its legacy, including the impact on crime and crime control; and</section><section prefix="(7)">work cooperatively with private and public tourist agencies and organizations to oversee and monitor the allocation of public resources to sites and undertakings relating to the history and legacy of slavery in Maryland, and ensure that there is a fair allocation of resources for African American businesses and institutions.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission consists of 11 members.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The membership of the Commission includes:<section prefix="(1)">one member of the Senate of Maryland, appointed by the President;</section><section prefix="(2)">one member of the House of Delegates, appointed by the Speaker;</section><section prefix="(3)">the State Archivist or a designee of the State Archivist;</section><section prefix="(4)">the Director of the Maryland Historical Trust; and</section><section prefix="(5)">the following individuals, appointed by the Governor:<section prefix="(i)">two historians who are knowledgeable about Maryland history, and particularly about the middle passage, slavery, Reconstruction, and the Jim Crow era;</section><section prefix="(ii)">two anthropologists or sociologists who are knowledgeable about African American culture and society;</section><section prefix="(iii)">two representatives of African American organizations; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">a member of the public, who shall serve as the chair of the Commission.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of an appointed member of the Commission is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of the appointed members of the Commission are staggered as provided on October 1, 2000.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the remainder of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A member of the Commission:<section prefix="(1)">may not receive compensation as a member of the Commission; but</section><section prefix="(2)">is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Maryland Historical Trust and the State Archives shall provide for the staffing of the Commission.</section>
  </text>
</law>
