<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-10-606</section_number>
  <catch_line>The plan shall:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>606</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The plan shall:<section prefix="(1)">ensure that the forms management officer approves the use of a form by the department or independent unit only if the form:<section prefix="(i)">is needed for the effective or efficient operation of the department or independent unit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">requests information that is needed for or relevant to a lawful purpose of the department or independent unit;</section><section prefix="(iii)">does not impose an undue burden on the individual who is to complete the form;</section><section prefix="(iv)">is as brief, as plainly written, as well designed, and as easily completed as possible; and</section><section prefix="(v)">does not duplicate unnecessarily:<section prefix="1.">another form of the department or independent unit; or</section><section prefix="2.">a form of another department or independent unit;</section></section></section><section prefix="(2)">require a register of the forms that the forms management officer approves;</section><section prefix="(3)">require identification of each form in accordance with a standard identification system of the Division;</section><section prefix="(4)">provide for the most economical system by which to prepare, reproduce, and use a form; and</section><section prefix="(5)">require the forms management officer:<section prefix="(i)">to review periodically each form that has been approved to determine whether the officer still approves the form; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">if not, to remove the form from the register.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to any duties set forth elsewhere, the Division shall:<section prefix="(1)">develop a standard identification system to identify forms;</section><section prefix="(2)">help each department and independent unit to:<section prefix="(i)">develop a proposed plan; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">coordinate the proposed plan with other plans;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">review each proposed plan;</section><section prefix="(4)">approve each proposed plan that meets the requirements of this section; and</section><section prefix="(5)">monitor and help in the administration of each plan to ensure compliance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In the preparation of a form that requires identification of individuals by race, a department or independent unit shall include the following racial categories:<section prefix="(i)">American Indian or Alaska Native;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Asian;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Black or African American;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Native Hawaiian or other Pacific Islander; and</section><section prefix="(v)">White.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A form that requires identification of individuals by race shall include instructions that multiracial respondents may select all applicable racial categories.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Respondents shall select their own answers, except when it is not possible for the respondent to do so.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In the event that a respondent is not able to select an answer, an observer, such as a family member or friend, may select the answer on behalf of the respondent.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A form that requires identification of individuals by race shall include a separate question about whether a respondent is of Hispanic or Latino origin, with the question preceding the racial category question.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
