<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-611" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-15-611</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Additional individuals, other than officials, shall disclose information annually if designated pursuant to subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For disclosure under this section:<section prefix="(1)">the Governor, by executive order, may designate:<section prefix="(i)">an employee of an executive unit; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a noncompensated appointee of the Governor;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the Chief Judge of the Court of Appeals, by order, may designate:<section prefix="(i)">an employee of the Judicial Branch; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a noncompensated appointee of the Court of Appeals or the Chief Judge; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">the presiding officers of the General Assembly, by order, may designate:<section prefix="(i)">an employee of the Legislative Branch; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a noncompensated appointee of either or both of the presiding officers.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A statement filed under this section is a public record and shall contain the relevant information concerning the financial affairs of the individual submitting the statement that is considered necessary by the applicable designating authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In complying with subsection (b)(1) of this section, the Governor, by executive order, shall designate any employee of an executive unit who is:<section prefix="(i)">a home inspector or licensed home inspector, under &#xA7; 16-101 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a building code enforcement official employed by the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an accredited inspector of lead for the Department of the Environment under &#xA7; 6-818 of the Environment Article; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">an environmental sanitarian under Title 11 of the Environment Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An employee under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall file a statement in accordance with &#xA7; 15-601 of this subtitle, that:<section prefix="(i)">discloses any interest the employee may have in any real property in the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">discloses any other information the Ethics Commission considers a conflict of interest related to the employment of the employee.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
