<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-406" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-406</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall study possible ways to preserve and improve Annapolis as the capital of the State, with particular emphasis on the location of State offices and buildings and county and city buildings.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">As part of these studies, the Commission may:<section prefix="(i)">inventory current residential, commercial, and governmental uses of land in Annapolis and adjacent areas;</section><section prefix="(ii)">study the landmark resources of Annapolis and adjacent areas;</section><section prefix="(iii)">study the relationship between the needs of governmental activities and the resources of the community; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">study the fiscal implications of:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission may cooperate with public agencies to:<section prefix="(1)">develop plans for the physical development of Annapolis and adjacent areas; and</section><section prefix="(2)">ensure adequate access to and transportation facilities for Annapolis and adjacent areas.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission may make specific recommendations on the following community needs or projects in Annapolis and adjacent areas:<section prefix="(1)">arterial highways;</section><section prefix="(2)">building codes;</section><section prefix="(3)">economic development;</section><section prefix="(4)">federal and State assistance programs;</section><section prefix="(5)">housing;</section><section prefix="(6)">industrial and commercial growth;</section><section prefix="(7)">parking facilities;</section><section prefix="(8)">space for public buildings;</section><section prefix="(9)">traffic control;</section><section prefix="(10)">urban renewal; and</section><section prefix="(11)">any other community need or project that the Commission believes may improve:<section prefix="(i)">the facilities and development of Annapolis and adjacent areas; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the facilities and development of any unit of the State government.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A study or recommendation of the Commission is advisory only.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission may not require or compel the adoption or implementation of any recommendation.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
