<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-20-207</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>207</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may:<section prefix="(i)">conduct studies and surveys concerning human relations, conditions, and problems; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">promote in every way possible the improvement of human relations.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In conducting studies and surveys, the Commission may expend any funds provided in the State budget or otherwise made available.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On the basis of studies or surveys, the Commission may recommend legislation to the Governor.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission may apply for and accept grants from State, federal, and private nonprofit organizations in furtherance of its mission.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">On or before January 1 of each year, the Commission shall submit a report on the work of the Commission to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of this article, to the General Assembly.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whenever any problem of racial discrimination arises, the Commission immediately may hold an investigatory hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The purpose of the hearing shall be to resolve the problem promptly by gathering all of the facts from each interested party and making recommendations as necessary.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The hearing shall be held in the geographic area where the problem exists.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall meet at least once each month.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In addition to its regular monthly meetings, the Chair or a majority of the members of the Commission may, at any time, call a special meeting of the Commission.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">At least 5 days' notice of a special meeting shall be given to the members.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission shall establish procedures for the conduct of its meetings.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to their other duties, the commissioners shall serve on appeal boards to review decisions of the administrative law judges.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">As determined by the Commission's rules of procedure, an appeal board may allow any party affected by an administrative law judge's decision to introduce additional relevant testimony or evidence.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
