<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-1A-28</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Purse Dedication Account under the authority of the State Racing Commission....</catch_line>
  <order_by>28</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Purse Dedication Account under the authority of the State Racing Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Account shall receive money as required under &#xA7; 9-1A-27 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Money in the Account shall be invested and reinvested by the Treasurer and interest and earnings shall accrue to the Account.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Comptroller shall:<section prefix="(i)">account for the Account; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">on a properly approved transmittal prepared by the State Racing Commission, issue a warrant to pay out money from the Account in the manner provided under this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Account is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Expenditures from the Account shall only be made on a properly approved transmittal prepared by the State Racing Commission as provided under subsection (c) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subject to subsections (d) and (e) of this section, the State Racing Commission shall allocate funds in the Account as follows:<section prefix="(1)">80% to the thoroughbred industry; and</section><section prefix="(2)">20% to the standardbred industry.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The amount of funds allocated to thoroughbred purses and the Maryland-bred Race Fund shall be allocated as follows:<section prefix="(1)">89% to thoroughbred purses at the Pimlico Race Course, Laurel Park, the racecourse in Allegany County, and the racecourse at Timonium; and</section><section prefix="(2)">11% to the Maryland-bred Race Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The amount of funds allocated to standardbred purses and the Standardbred Race Fund shall be allocated as follows:<section prefix="(1)">89% to standardbred purses at Rosecroft Raceway, Ocean Downs Race Course, and the racecourse in Allegany County, allocated based on the number of live racing days at each track location; and</section><section prefix="(2)">11% to the Standardbred Race Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">From the amount provided to thoroughbred purses, the State Racing Commission shall pay an annual grant of $100,000 to Fair Hill, as defined under &#xA7; 11-811 of the Business Regulation Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Of the amount provided from the Purse Dedication Account under subsection (e)(1) of this section:<section prefix="(i)">for Ocean Downs Race Course, up to $1,200,000 each year for calendar years 2012, 2013, 2014, and 2015 may be used to provide operating assistance to support a minimum of 40 annual live racing days for calendar years 2012, 2013, 2014, and 2015 unless the racing licensee is prevented by weather, acts of God, or other circumstances beyond the racing licensee's control; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">for Rosecroft Raceway, up to $1,200,000 each year for calendar years 2012, 2013, 2014, and 2015 may be used to provide operating assistance to support a minimum of 40 annual live racing days for calendar years 2012, 2013, 2014, and 2015 unless the racing licensee is prevented by weather, acts of God, or other circumstances beyond the racing licensee's control.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Funds received by Ocean Downs Race Course or Rosecroft Raceway under paragraph (1) of this subsection may not be used to contribute to a campaign finance entity under Title 13 of the Election Law Article or make an independent expenditure as defined in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Election Law Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To obtain operating assistance under this section:<section prefix="(i)">a holder of a racing license to race at Ocean Downs Race Course or Rosecroft Raceway may apply to the Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation for the reimbursement of expenditures made by the racing licensee to conduct the annual live racing schedule; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a holder of a racing license to race at Rosecroft Raceway shall:<section prefix="1.">agree to rehire workers employed at the facility prior to the end of live racing on June 27, 2008; and</section><section prefix="2.">recognize collective bargaining agreements that were in place as of June 1, 2008.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">On the completion of the review of the application by a certified public accountant, the Secretary may authorize the reimbursement of expenditures by the racing licensee that are necessary to conduct the annual live racing schedule.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Expenditures eligible for reimbursement under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph shall include the ordinary and reasonable costs of conducting the race meetings, pari-mutuel wagering, and stabling activities of the racing licensee, net of ordinary income and receipts.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The reimbursement calculation under subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph may not include:<section prefix="1.">extraordinary income and expense-related items, including extraordinary litigation expenses;</section><section prefix="2.">lobbying fees;</section><section prefix="3.">capital investments, including predevelopment costs; or</section><section prefix="4.">prior year adjustments and claims.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">All costs associated with the racing licensee's application shall be paid by the racing licensee.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In support of the racing licensee's application and request for reimbursement submitted under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the racing licensee shall provide to the Secretary:<section prefix="(i)">monthly financial information requested by the Secretary, in a form satisfactory to the Secretary; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">an annual audited financial statement.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A racing licensee may not receive assistance under this section while the racing licensee is a party to a proceeding challenging the issuance or denial of a video lottery operation license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The provisions of this section may not be construed to apply to the racecourse in Allegany County until horse racing begins at that racecourse.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">On or before December 1, 2014, the State Racing Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">conduct a study to determine the impact of the Purse Dedication Account on the racing industry in the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">make recommendations to the General Assembly regarding the continuation of the Purse Dedication Account and the amount of money distributed to the Purse Dedication Account.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
