<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-207" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-3-207</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the limitation in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Secretary of General Services may provide any necessary facility or service that a Governor-elect requests for use in preparing to assume the duties of office, including the facilities and services set forth in this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary of General Services may not pay any obligation for the provision of facilities or services that a Governor-elect incurs on or before the date of the general election for the office of Governor.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">After consultation with a Governor-elect, the Secretary of General Services may provide office space that is suitable and has appropriate supplies and furnishings.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary of General Services may authorize:<section prefix="(1)">payment of any expenses for services of consultants for the Governor-elect;</section><section prefix="(2)">reimbursement of a unit of the State government whose employee is assigned to the office staff of the Governor-elect;</section><section prefix="(3)">payment of the compensation that the Governor-elect sets for other staff; and</section><section prefix="(4)">payment of appropriate subsistence allowances and other travel expenses, including the rental of motor vehicles, that the Governor-elect finds necessary for individuals who are employed intermittently or serve without compensation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary of General Services may:<section prefix="(1)">provide the communication services that the Governor-elect finds necessary;</section><section prefix="(2)">authorize payment for necessary printing and binding; and</section><section prefix="(3)">provide for the conveyance of mail that the Governor-elect sends in connection with preparing to assume the duties of office.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
