<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-20A-01</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>01</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Administration" means the Maryland Energy Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Borrower" means an eligible local jurisdiction, nonprofit organization, or eligible business that applies and qualifies for a loan under this Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Eligible business" means a commercial enterprise or business:<section prefix="(1)">that is incorporated in the State; or</section><section prefix="(2)">whose principal owners are State residents and the business of which is principally carried out in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Energy cost savings" means the actual reduction in operating expenses resulting from the improved energy efficiency generated by an energy conservation project financed under the Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Fund" means the Jane E. Lawton Conservation Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Local jurisdiction" means any county or municipality of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Local jurisdiction" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a board of education of a county or municipality;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a special district that is established by State law and that operates within a single county;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a special district that is established by a county under public general law; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">an office, board, or department that is established in a county under State law and that is funded, under State law, at least in part by the county governing body.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Municipality" means any municipal corporation in the State that is subject to the provisions of Article XI-E of the Maryland Constitution or any duly authorized agency or instrumentality of the municipality.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Nonprofit organization" means a corporation, foundation, school, hospital, or other legal entity, no part of the net earnings of which inure to the benefit of any private shareholder or individual holding an interest in the entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Program" means the Jane E. Lawton Conservation Loan Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Project" means:<section prefix="(i)">one or more improvements or modifications that enhance the energy efficiency and reduce the operating expenses of a structure; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">installation of infrastructure for renewable energy generation by local jurisdictions and nonprofit organizations.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Project" includes:<section prefix="(i)">start-up opportunities for new businesses if the loan would enhance the energy efficiency of the borrower's business;</section><section prefix="(ii)">installation of equipment to make buildings self-sustaining and of emergency generating units that use renewable energy resources; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">implementation of methane removal at landfills.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Project" does not include improvements or modifications for energy conservation or renewable energy generation in structures used primarily for religious or fraternal activities.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Renewable energy resource" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Public Utilities Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
