<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-10-134</section_number>
  <catch_line>At least 1 year before the commencement of the review and evaluation of its regulations, each unit s...</catch_line>
  <order_by>134</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">At least 1 year before the commencement of the review and evaluation of its regulations, each unit shall prepare a work plan and submit the work plan to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of this article, the Committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The work plan shall:<section prefix="(1)">include a description of the procedures and methods to be used by the unit, which may include:<section prefix="(i)">procedures for inviting public comment, including:<section prefix="1.">the publication of notices in the Maryland Register;</section><section prefix="2.">the publication of notices in newspapers of general circulation in the State;</section><section prefix="3.">the posting of a notice on the unit's website or on a statewide website created for units to post notices of regulations review;</section><section prefix="4.">the mailing of notices; and</section><section prefix="5.">the holding of public hearings at various locations around the State;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">procedures for ensuring the participation of stakeholders in the review process;</section><section prefix="(iii)">procedures for ensuring the participation in the review process of other units affected by the regulations; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">procedures for gathering and reviewing:<section prefix="1.">recent scientific information related to the regulations being reviewed;</section><section prefix="2.">similar regulations adopted or repealed by other states or the federal government; and</section><section prefix="3.">other appropriate information;</section></section></section><section prefix="(2)">identify the individual or individuals in the unit who will coordinate the evaluation and communicate with the Committee; and</section><section prefix="(3)">establish the schedule the unit will follow to complete its evaluation report in a timely manner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 30 days after receipt of the work plan by the Committee, it shall:<section prefix="(i)">advise the unit in writing of any part of the work plan with which it disagrees;</section><section prefix="(ii)">submit to the unit in writing any changes it recommends to the work plan; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">in the event of a disagreement, attempt to meet with the head of the unit.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The head of the unit and the Committee shall attempt to resolve any disagreements within 30 days after the Committee acts under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
