<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-15-805</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>805</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Elected local official" includes:<section prefix="(i)">any individual who holds an elective office of a county or municipal corporation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a candidate for elective office as a local official of a county or municipal corporation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Local official" includes an individual, designated as a local official, whose position is funded wholly or partly by the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection and subsection (c) of this section, the financial disclosure provisions enacted by a county or municipal corporation under &#xA7; 15-803 of this subtitle shall be similar to the provisions of Subtitle 6 of this title, but shall be modified to the extent necessary to make the provisions relevant to the prevention of conflicts of interest in that jurisdiction.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The financial disclosure provisions for elected local officials enacted by a county or municipal corporation under &#xA7; 15-803 of this subtitle shall be equivalent to or exceed the requirements of Subtitle 6 of this title, but shall be modified to the extent necessary to make the provisions relevant to the prevention of conflicts of interest in that jurisdiction.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subtitle does not compel the governing body of a county or municipal corporation to require a local official to file a financial disclosure statement except:<section prefix="(i)">when the personal interest of the local official will present a potential conflict with the public interest in connection with an anticipated public action of the local official; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">at least annually to report on gifts received by the local official.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The provisions shall require:<section prefix="(i)">that a statement filed under paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection be filed sufficiently in advance of the action to provide adequate disclosure to the public; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a statement filed by an elected local official under subsection (b)(2) of this section to be filed on or before April 30 of each year.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Financial disclosure provisions applicable to a candidate shall be consistent with the provisions applicable to an incumbent holding the office involved.</section>
  </text>
</law>
