<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-1A-06</section_number>
  <catch_line>The following persons shall be licensed under this subtitle:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>06</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The following persons shall be licensed under this subtitle:<section prefix="(1)">a video lottery operator;</section><section prefix="(2)">a manufacturer;</section><section prefix="(3)">a person not licensed under item (1) or (2) of this subsection who manages, operates, supplies, provides security for, or provides service, maintenance, or repairs for video lottery terminals or table games; and</section><section prefix="(4)">a video lottery employee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission may by regulation require a person that contracts with a licensee and the person's employees to obtain a license under this subtitle if the Commission determines that the licensing requirements are necessary in order to protect the public interest and accomplish the policies established by this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, unless an individual holds a valid license issued under this subtitle, the individual may not be employed by a licensee as a video lottery employee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission by regulation may exempt categories of video lottery employees who are not directly involved in the video lottery operations from the requirement under paragraph (1) of this subsection if the Commission determines that the requirement is not necessary in order to protect the public interest or accomplish the policies established under this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For a period of 1 year after the individual's service on the State Lottery Commission or the Video Lottery Facility Location Commission ends, a licensee may not employ, or enter into a financial relationship with, an individual who has been a member of the State Lottery Commission or the Video Lottery Facility Location Commission.</section>
  </text>
</law>
