<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-15-405</section_number>
  <catch_line>After the Ethics Commission considers all of the evidence presented at the hearing, it shall make fi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>405</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">After the Ethics Commission considers all of the evidence presented at the hearing, it shall make findings of fact and conclusions of law with respect to each alleged violation.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the Ethics Commission determines that the respondent has not violated this title, the Ethics Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">dismiss the complaint in a signed order; and</section><section prefix="(2)">promptly send a copy of the order to the complainant and the respondent.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the Ethics Commission determines that the respondent has violated any provision of this title, the Ethics Commission may:<section prefix="(1)">issue an order of compliance directing the respondent to cease and desist from the violation;</section><section prefix="(2)">issue a reprimand; or</section><section prefix="(3)">recommend to the appropriate authority other appropriate discipline of the respondent, including censure or removal, if that discipline is authorized by law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the Ethics Commission determines that a respondent has violated Subtitle 7 of this title, the Ethics Commission may:<section prefix="(1)">require a respondent who is a regulated lobbyist to file any additional reports or information that reasonably relates to information required under &#xA7;&#xA7; 15-703 and 15-704 of this title;</section><section prefix="(2)">impose a fine not exceeding $5,000 for each violation; or</section><section prefix="(3)">subject to subsection (e) of this section, suspend the registration of a regulated lobbyist.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Ethics Commission determines it necessary to protect the public interest and the integrity of the governmental process, the Ethics Commission may issue an order to:<section prefix="(i)">suspend the registration of an individual regulated lobbyist if the Ethics Commission determines that the individual regulated lobbyist:<section prefix="1.">has knowingly and willfully violated Subtitle 7 of this title; or</section><section prefix="2.">has been convicted of a criminal offense arising from lobbying activities; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">revoke the registration of an individual regulated lobbyist if the Ethics Commission determines that, based on acts arising from lobbying activities, the individual regulated lobbyist has been convicted of bribery, theft, or other crime involving moral turpitude.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Commission suspends the registration of an individual regulated lobbyist under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the individual regulated lobbyist may not engage in lobbying for compensation for a period, not to exceed 3 years, that the Commission determines as to that individual regulated lobbyist is necessary to satisfy the purposes of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the Commission revokes the registration of an individual regulated lobbyist under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the individual regulated lobbyist may not engage in lobbying for compensation.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the Ethics Commission initiates a complaint based on a violation or conviction described in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Ethics Commission shall initiate the complaint within 2 years of:<section prefix="(i)">the Ethics Commission's knowledge of the violation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the date the conviction becomes final.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The termination or expiration of the registration of an individual regulated lobbyist does not limit the authority of the Ethics Commission to issue an order under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, an individual whose registration as an individual regulated lobbyist is revoked or suspended under subsection (e) of this section may apply to the Ethics Commission for reinstatement.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Ethics Commission may reinstate the registration of an individual whose registration as a regulated lobbyist has been revoked or suspended under subsection (e) of this section if the Commission determines that reinstatement of the individual would not be detrimental to the public interest and the integrity of the governmental process, based on:<section prefix="(i)">the nature and circumstances of the original misconduct or violation leading to revocation or suspension;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the individual's subsequent conduct and reformation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the present ability of the individual to comply with the provisions of the ethics law.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the respondent is a regulated lobbyist, for each report required under Subtitle 7 of this title that is filed late the respondent shall pay a fee of $10 for each late day, not to exceed a total of $250.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the respondent is an official, for each financial disclosure statement found to have been filed late, the respondent shall pay a fee of $2 for each late day, not to exceed a total of $250.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
