<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-10-624</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "personal record" means a public record that names or, with reasonable certainty, o...</catch_line>
  <order_by>624</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "personal record" means a public record that names or, with reasonable certainty, otherwise identifies an individual by an identifying factor such as:<section prefix="(1)">an address;</section><section prefix="(2)">a description;</section><section prefix="(3)">a finger or voice print;</section><section prefix="(4)">a number; or</section><section prefix="(5)">a picture.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Personal records may not be created unless the need for the information has been clearly established by the unit collecting the records.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Personal information collected for personal records:<section prefix="(i)">shall be appropriate and relevant to the purposes for which it is collected;</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall be accurate and current to the greatest extent practicable; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">may not be obtained by fraudulent means.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection only applies to units of State government.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided by law, an official custodian who keeps personal records shall, to the greatest extent practicable, collect personal information from the person in interest.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An official custodian who requests personal information for personal records shall provide the following information to each person in interest from whom personal information is collected:<section prefix="(i)">the purpose for which the personal information is collected;</section><section prefix="(ii)">any specific consequences to the person for refusal to provide the personal information;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the person's right to inspect, amend, or correct personal records, if any;</section><section prefix="(iv)">whether the personal information is generally available for public inspection; and</section><section prefix="(v)">whether the personal information is made available or transferred to or shared with any entity other than the official custodian.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Each unit of State government shall post its privacy policies with regard to the collection of personal information, including the policies specified in this subsection, on its Internet website.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The following personal records shall be exempt from the requirements of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">information pertaining to the enforcement of criminal laws or the administration of the penal system;</section><section prefix="(ii)">information contained in investigative materials kept for the purpose of investigating a specific violation of State law and maintained by a State agency whose principal function may be other than law enforcement;</section><section prefix="(iii)">information contained in public records which are accepted by the State Archivist for deposit in the Maryland Hall of Records;</section><section prefix="(iv)">information gathered as part of formal research projects previously reviewed and approved by federally mandated institutional review boards; and</section><section prefix="(v)">any other personal records exempted by regulations adopted by the Secretary of Budget and Management, based on the recommendation of the Secretary of Information Technology.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">If the Secretary of Budget and Management adopts regulations under paragraph (5)(v) of this subsection, the Secretary shall, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of this article, report to the General Assembly on the personal records exempted from the requirements of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">a unit in the Legislative Branch of the State government;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a unit in the Judicial Branch of the State government; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a board of license commissioners.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a unit or instrumentality of the State government keeps personal records, the unit or instrumentality shall submit an annual report to the Secretary of General Services, as provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An annual report shall state:<section prefix="(i)">the name of the unit or instrumentality;</section><section prefix="(ii)">for each set of the personal records:<section prefix="1.">the name;</section><section prefix="2.">the location; and</section><section prefix="3.">if a subunit keeps the set, the name of the subunit;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">for each set of personal records that has not been previously reported:<section prefix="1.">the category of individuals to whom the set applies;</section><section prefix="2.">a brief description of the types of information that the set contains;</section><section prefix="3.">the major uses and purposes of the information;</section><section prefix="4.">by category, the source of information for the set; and</section><section prefix="5.">the policies and procedures of the unit or instrumentality as to access and challenges to the personal record by the person in interest and storage, retrieval, retention, disposal, and security, including controls on access; and</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">for each set of personal records that has been disposed of or changed significantly since the unit or instrumentality last submitted a report, the information required under item (iii) of this paragraph.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A unit or instrumentality that has 2 or more sets of personal records may combine the personal records in the report only if the character of the personal records is highly similar.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Secretary of General Services shall adopt regulations that govern the form and method of reporting under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The annual report shall be available for public inspection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The official custodian may permit inspection of personal records for which inspection otherwise is not authorized by a person who is engaged in a research project if:<section prefix="(1)">the researcher submits to the official custodian a written request that:<section prefix="(i)">describes the purpose of the research project;</section><section prefix="(ii)">describes the intent, if any, to publish the findings;</section><section prefix="(iii)">describes the nature of the requested personal records;</section><section prefix="(iv)">describes the safeguards that the researcher would take to protect the identity of the persons in interest; and</section><section prefix="(v)">states that persons in interest will not be contacted unless the official custodian approves and monitors the contact;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the official custodian is satisfied that the proposed safeguards will prevent the disclosure of the identity of persons in interest; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the researcher makes an agreement with the unit or instrumentality that:<section prefix="(i)">defines the scope of the research project;</section><section prefix="(ii)">sets out the safeguards for protecting the identity of the persons in interest; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">states that a breach of any condition of the agreement is a breach of contract.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
