<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-6.5-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>As soon as practicable, but no later than 90 days after receiving a complete application, including ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">As soon as practicable, but no later than 90 days after receiving a complete application, including all necessary expert reports, the appropriate regulating entity shall hold a public hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the nonprofit health entity is a hospital, the regulating entity shall hold the public hearing in the jurisdiction in which the hospital is located.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A public hearing under this section shall be a quasi-legislative hearing and not a contested case hearing.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any person may file written comments and exhibits or make a statement at the public hearing.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The regulating entity may:<section prefix="(1)">subpoena information and witnesses;</section><section prefix="(2)">require sworn statements;</section><section prefix="(3)">take depositions; and</section><section prefix="(4)">use related discovery procedures.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The regulating entity may contract with experts as reasonably necessary to:<section prefix="(i)">determine whether to approve an acquisition generally;</section><section prefix="(ii)">perform an independent valuation of the public or charitable assets of the transferor;</section><section prefix="(iii)">evaluate the impact of the acquisition on the affected community;</section><section prefix="(iv)">determine whether there has been due diligence by the transferor; and</section><section prefix="(v)">determine the existence of any conflicts of interest.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The selection of an expert by a regulating entity under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be subject to the State procurement laws.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a regulating entity contracts for expert assistance under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the transferee shall pay the reasonable cost of the expert assistance, as determined by the regulating entity.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Within 60 days after the record, including the public hearing process, has been closed, the appropriate regulating entity shall:<section prefix="(1)">approve the acquisition, with or without modifications; or</section><section prefix="(2)">disapprove the acquisition.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, at its discretion, the regulating entity may extend for good cause for a 60-day period the time for making a determination under subsection (f) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The regulating entity is limited to a maximum of two 60-day extensions for making a determination on the same application.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A determination made by the appropriate regulating entity under subsection (f) of this section may not take effect until 90 calendar days after the date the determination is made or when ratified or rejected by the General Assembly, whichever is earlier.</section>
  </text>
</law>
