<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-705" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-15-705</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to any other report required under this subtitle, a regulated lobbyist shall file a separate report disclosing the name of any State official of the Executive Branch or member of the immediate family of a State official of the Executive Branch who has benefited during the reporting period from gifts of meals or beverages from the regulated lobbyist, whether or not in connection with lobbying activities, allowed under &#xA7; 15-505(c)(2)(i)1 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Gifts reported by name of recipient under &#xA7; 15-704(b)(2)(ix) of this subtitle need not be allocated for the purposes of disclosure under subsection (a) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The disclosure required by this section shall be under oath or affirmation, on a form issued by the Ethics Commission, and shall include:<section prefix="(1)">the name and business address of the regulated lobbyist;</section><section prefix="(2)">the name of each recipient of a gift of a meal or beverages;</section><section prefix="(3)">the date and value of each gift of a meal or beverages, and the identity of the entity or entities to which the gift is attributable; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the total cumulative value of gifts of meals or beverages, calculated as to each recipient.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The regulated lobbyist may explain the circumstances under which the gift of a meal or beverages was given.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Gifts of meals or beverages reported by a regulated lobbyist under this section need not be counted or reported by the regulated lobbyist for purposes of disclosure under &#xA7; 15-704(c) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The report shall be filed at the time and in the manner prescribed for reports filed under &#xA7; 15-704 of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
