<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-10-616</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>616</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Unless otherwise provided by law, a custodian shall deny inspection of a public record, as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A custodian shall deny inspection of public records that relate to the adoption of an individual.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A custodian shall deny inspection of public records that relate to welfare for an individual.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A custodian shall deny inspection of a letter of reference.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, a custodian shall prohibit inspection, use, or disclosure of a circulation record of a public library or other item, collection, or grouping of information about an individual that:<section prefix="(i)">is maintained by a library;</section><section prefix="(ii)">contains an individual's name or the identifying number, symbol, or other identifying particular assigned to the individual; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">identifies the use a patron makes of that library's materials, services, or facilities.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A custodian shall permit inspection, use, or disclosure of a circulation record of a public library only in connection with the library's ordinary business and only for the purposes for which the record was created.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A custodian shall deny inspection of library, archival, or museum material given by a person to the extent that the person who made the gift limits disclosure as a condition of the gift.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraphs (2) through (7) of this subsection, a custodian shall deny inspection of a retirement record for an individual.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A custodian shall permit inspection:<section prefix="(i)">by the person in interest;</section><section prefix="(ii)">by the appointing authority of the individual;</section><section prefix="(iii)">after the death of the individual, by a beneficiary, personal representative, or other person who satisfies the administrators of the retirement and pension systems that the person has a valid claim to the benefits of the individual; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">by any law enforcement agency in order to obtain the home address of a retired employee of the agency when contact with a retired employee is documented to be necessary for official agency business.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A custodian shall permit inspection by the employees of a county unit that, by county law, is required to audit the retirement records for current or former employees of the county. However, the information obtained during the inspection is confidential, and the county unit and its employees may not disclose any information that would identify a person in interest.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On request, a custodian shall state whether the individual receives a retirement or pension allowance.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A custodian shall permit release of information as provided in &#xA7; 21-504 or &#xA7; 21-505 of the State Personnel and Pensions Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">On written request, a custodian shall:<section prefix="(i)">disclose the amount of that part of a retirement allowance that is derived from employer contributions and that is granted to:<section prefix="1.">a retired elected or appointed official of the State;</section><section prefix="2.">a retired elected official of a political subdivision; or</section><section prefix="3.">a retired appointed official of a political subdivision who is a member of a separate system for elected or appointed officials; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">disclose the benefit formula and the variables for calculating the retirement allowance of:<section prefix="1.">a current elected or appointed official of the State;</section><section prefix="2.">a current elected official of a political subdivision; or</section><section prefix="3.">a current appointed official of a political subdivision who is a member of a separate system for elected or appointed officials.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies to Anne Arundel County.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">On written request, a custodian of retirement records shall disclose:<section prefix="1.">the total amount of that part of a pension or retirement allowance that is derived from employer contributions and that is granted to a retired elected or appointed official of the county;</section><section prefix="2.">the total amount of that part of a pension or retirement allowance that is derived from employee contributions and that is granted to a retired elected or appointed official of the county, if the retired elected or appointed official consents to the disclosure;</section><section prefix="3.">the benefit formula and the variables for calculating the retirement allowance of a current elected or appointed official of the county; or</section><section prefix="4.">the amount of the employee contributions plus interest attributable to a current elected or appointed official of the county, if the current elected or appointed official consents to the disclosure.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A custodian of retirement records shall maintain a list of those elected or appointed officials of the county who have consented to the disclosure of information under subparagraph (ii)2 or 4 of this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only to public records that relate to:<section prefix="(i)">police reports of traffic accidents;</section><section prefix="(ii)">criminal charging documents prior to service on the defendant named in the document; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">traffic citations filed in the Maryland Automated Traffic System.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A custodian shall deny inspection of a record described in paragraph (1) of this subsection to any of the following persons who request inspection of records for the purpose of soliciting or marketing legal services:<section prefix="(i)">an attorney who is not an attorney of record of a person named in the record; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a person who is employed by, retained by, associated with, or acting on behalf of an attorney described in this paragraph.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, a custodian shall deny inspection of a personnel record of an individual, including an application, performance rating, or scholastic achievement information.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A custodian shall permit inspection by:<section prefix="(i)">the person in interest; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an elected or appointed official who supervises the work of the individual.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">A custodian shall deny inspection of a hospital record that:<section prefix="(1)">relates to:<section prefix="(i)">medical administration;</section><section prefix="(ii)">staff;</section><section prefix="(iii)">medical care; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">other medical information; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">contains general or specific information about 1 or more individuals.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, a custodian shall deny inspection of a school district record about the home address, home phone number, biography, family, physiology, religion, academic achievement, or physical or mental ability of a student.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A custodian shall permit inspection by:<section prefix="(i)">the person in interest; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an elected or appointed official who supervises the student.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A custodian may permit inspection of the home address or home phone number of a student of a public school by:<section prefix="1.">an organization of parents, teachers, students, or former students, or any combination of those groups, of the school;</section><section prefix="2.">an organization or force of the military;</section><section prefix="3.">a person engaged by a school or board of education to confirm a home address or home phone number;</section><section prefix="4.">a representative of a community college in the State; or</section><section prefix="5.">the Maryland Higher Education Commission.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Commission or a person, organization, or community college that obtains information under this paragraph may not:<section prefix="1.">use this information for a commercial purpose; or</section><section prefix="2.">disclose this information to another person, organization, or community college.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">When a custodian permits inspection under this paragraph, the custodian shall notify the Commission, person, organization, or community college of the prohibitions under subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph regarding use and disclosure of this information.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">Subject to the provisions of &#xA7; 4-310 of the Insurance Article, a custodian shall deny inspection of all RBC reports and RBC plans and any other records that relate to those reports or plans.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, a custodian shall deny inspection of all photographs, videotapes or electronically recorded images of vehicles, vehicle movement records, personal financial information, credit reports, or other personal or financial data created, recorded, obtained by or submitted to the Maryland Transportation Authority or its agents or employees in connection with any electronic toll collection system or associated transaction system.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A custodian shall permit inspection of the records enumerated in paragraph (1) of this subsection by:<section prefix="(i)">an individual named in the record;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the attorney of record of an individual named in the record;</section><section prefix="(iii)">employees or agents of the Maryland Transportation Authority in any investigation or proceeding relating to a violation of speed limitations or to the imposition of or indemnification from liability for failure to pay a toll in connection with any electronic toll collection system;</section><section prefix="(iv)">employees or agents of a third party that has entered into an agreement with the Maryland Transportation Authority to use an electronic toll collection system for nontoll applications in the collection of revenues due to the third party; or</section><section prefix="(v)">employees or agents of an entity in another state operating or having jurisdiction over a toll facility.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, a custodian shall deny inspection of any record disclosing:<section prefix="(i)">the name of an account holder or qualified beneficiary of a prepaid contract under Title 18, Subtitle 19 of the Education Article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the name of an account holder or qualified designated beneficiary of an investment account under Title 18, Subtitle 19A of the Education Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A custodian:<section prefix="(i)">shall permit inspection by a person in interest; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">may release information to an eligible institution of higher education designated:<section prefix="1.">by an account holder of a prepaid contract or qualified beneficiary under Title 18, Subtitle 19A of the Education Article; or</section><section prefix="2.">by an account holder or qualified designated beneficiary under Title 18, Subtitle 19A of the Education Article.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "recorded images" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 21-202.1, &#xA7; 21-809, &#xA7; 21-810, or &#xA7; 24-111.3 of the Transportation Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, a custodian of recorded images produced by a traffic control signal monitoring system operated under &#xA7; 21-202.1 of the Transportation Article, a speed monitoring system operated under &#xA7; 21-809 of the Transportation Article, a work zone speed control system operated under &#xA7; 21-810 of the Transportation Article, or a vehicle height monitoring system operated under &#xA7; 24-111.3 of the Transportation Article shall deny inspection of the recorded images.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A custodian shall allow inspection of recorded images:<section prefix="(i)">as required in &#xA7; 21-202.1, &#xA7; 21-809, &#xA7; 21-810, or &#xA7; 24-111.3 of the Transportation Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">by any person issued a citation under &#xA7; 21-202.1, &#xA7; 21-809, &#xA7; 21-810, or &#xA7; 24-111.3 of the Transportation Article, or an attorney of record for the person; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">by an employee or agent of an agency in an investigation or proceeding relating to the imposition of or indemnification from civil liability pursuant to &#xA7; 21-202.1, &#xA7; 21-809, &#xA7; 21-810, or &#xA7; 24-111.3 of the Transportation Article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) through (5) of this subsection, a custodian may not knowingly disclose a public record of the Motor Vehicle Administration containing personal information.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A custodian shall disclose personal information when required by federal law.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies only to the disclosure of personal information for any use in response to a request for an individual motor vehicle record.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The custodian may not disclose personal information without written consent from the person in interest.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">
          <section prefix="1.">At any time the person in interest may withdraw consent to disclose personal information by notifying the custodian.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The withdrawal by the person in interest of consent to disclose personal information shall take effect as soon as practicable after it is received by the custodian.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies only to the disclosure of personal information for inclusion in lists of information to be used for surveys, marketing, and solicitations.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The custodian may not disclose personal information for surveys, marketing, and solicitations without written consent from the person in interest.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">
          <section prefix="1.">At any time the person in interest may withdraw consent to disclose personal information by notifying the custodian.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The withdrawal by the person in interest of consent to disclose personal information shall take effect as soon as practicable after it is received by the custodian.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The custodian may not disclose personal information under this paragraph for use in telephone solicitations.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">Personal information disclosed under this paragraph may be used only for surveys, marketing, or solicitations and only for a purpose approved by the Motor Vehicle Administration.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraphs (3) and (4) of this subsection, a custodian shall disclose personal information:<section prefix="(i)">for use by a federal, state, or local government, including a law enforcement agency, or a court in carrying out its functions;</section><section prefix="(ii)">for use in connection with matters of:<section prefix="1.">motor vehicle or driver safety;</section><section prefix="2.">motor vehicle theft;</section><section prefix="3.">motor vehicle emissions;</section><section prefix="4.">motor vehicle product alterations, recalls, or advisories;</section><section prefix="5.">performance monitoring of motor vehicle parts and dealers; and</section><section prefix="6.">removal of nonowner records from the original records of motor vehicle manufacturers;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">for use by a private detective agency licensed by the Secretary of State Police under Title 13 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article or a security guard service licensed by the Secretary of State Police under Title 19 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article for a purpose permitted under this paragraph;</section><section prefix="(iv)">for use in connection with a civil, administrative, arbitral, or criminal proceeding in a federal, state, or local court or regulatory agency for service of process, investigation in anticipation of litigation, and execution or enforcement of judgments or orders;</section><section prefix="(v)">for purposes of research or statistical reporting as approved by the Motor Vehicle Administration provided that the personal information is not published, redisclosed, or used to contact the individual;</section><section prefix="(vi)">for use by an insurer, insurance support organization, or self-insured entity, or its employees, agents, or contractors, in connection with rating, underwriting, claims investigating, and antifraud activities;</section><section prefix="(vii)">for use in the normal course of business activity by a legitimate business entity, its agents, employees, or contractors, but only:<section prefix="1.">to verify the accuracy of personal information submitted by the individual to that entity; and</section><section prefix="2.">if the information submitted is not accurate, to obtain correct information only for the purpose of:</section></section><section prefix="(viii)">for use by an employer or insurer to obtain or verify information relating to a holder of a commercial driver's license that is required under the Commercial Motor Vehicle Safety Act of 1986 (49 U.S.C. &#xA7; 31101 et seq.);</section><section prefix="(ix)">for use in connection with the operation of a private toll transportation facility;</section><section prefix="(x)">for use in providing notice to the owner of a towed or impounded motor vehicle;</section><section prefix="(xi)">for use by an applicant who provides written consent from the individual to whom the information pertains if the consent is obtained within the 6-month period before the date of the request for personal information;</section><section prefix="(xii)">for use in any matter relating to:<section prefix="1.">the operation of a Class B (for hire), Class C (funeral and ambulance), or Class Q (limousine) vehicle; and</section><section prefix="2.">public safety or the treatment by the operator of a member of the public;</section></section><section prefix="(xiii)">for a use specifically authorized by the law of this State, if the use is related to the operation of a motor vehicle or public safety;</section><section prefix="(xiv)">for use by a hospital to obtain, for hospital security purposes, information relating to ownership of vehicles parked on hospital property;</section><section prefix="(xv)">for use by a procurement organization requesting information under &#xA7; 4-516 of the Estates and Trusts Article for the purposes of organ, tissue, and eye donation;</section><section prefix="(xvi)">for use by an electric company, as defined in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Public Utilities Article, but only:<section prefix="1.">information describing a plug-in vehicle, as defined in &#xA7; 25-108 of the Transportation Article, and identifying the address of the registered owner of the plug-in vehicle;</section><section prefix="2.">for use in planning for the availability and reliability of the electric power supply; and</section><section prefix="3.">if the information is not:</section></section><section prefix="(xvii)">for use by an attorney, a title insurance producer, or any other individual authorized to conduct a title search of a manufactured home under Title 8B of the Real Property Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A person receiving personal information under paragraph (4) or (5) of this subsection may not use or redisclose the personal information for a purpose other than the purpose for which the custodian disclosed the personal information.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A person receiving personal information under paragraph (4) or (5) of this subsection who rediscloses the personal information shall:<section prefix="1.">keep a record for 5 years of the person to whom the information is redisclosed and the purpose for which the information is to be used; and</section><section prefix="2.">make the record available to the custodian on request.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The custodian shall adopt regulations to implement and enforce the provisions of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">The custodian shall adopt regulations and procedures for securing a person in interest's waiver of privacy rights under this subsection when an applicant requests personal information about the person in interest that the custodian is not authorized to disclose under paragraphs (2) through (5) of this subsection.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The regulations and procedures adopted under this subparagraph shall:</section>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The custodian may develop and implement methods for monitoring compliance with this section and ensuring that personal information is used only for purposes for which it is disclosed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection and subject to the provisions of paragraph (5) of this subsection, unless otherwise ordered by the court, files and records of the court pertaining to an arrest warrant issued pursuant to Maryland Rule 4-212(d)(1) or (2) and the charging document upon which the arrest warrant was issued may not be open to inspection until either:<section prefix="(i)">the arrest warrant has been served and a return of service has been filed in compliance with Maryland Rule 4-212(g); or</section><section prefix="(ii)">90 days have elapsed since the arrest warrant was issued.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection and subject to the provisions of paragraph (5) of this subsection, unless otherwise ordered by the court, files and records of the court pertaining to an arrest warrant issued pursuant to a grand jury indictment or conspiracy investigation and the charging document upon which the arrest warrant was issued may not be open to inspection until all arrest warrants for any co-conspirators have been served and all returns of service have been filed in compliance with Maryland Rule 4-212(g).</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to the provisions of paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection, unless sealed pursuant to Maryland Rule 4-201(d), the files and records shall be open to inspection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the name, address, birth date, driver's license number, sex, height, and weight of an individual contained in an arrest warrant issued pursuant to Maryland Rule 4-212(d)(1) or (2) or issued pursuant to a grand jury indictment or conspiracy investigation may be released to the Motor Vehicle Administration for use by the Administration for purposes of &#xA7; 13-406.1 or &#xA7; 16-204 of the Transportation Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Except as provided in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, information contained in a charging document that identifies an individual may not be released to the Motor Vehicle Administration.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The provisions of paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection may not be construed to prohibit:<section prefix="(i)">the release of statistical information concerning unserved arrest warrants;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the release of information by a State's Attorney or peace officer concerning an unserved arrest warrant and the charging document upon which the arrest warrant was issued;</section><section prefix="(iii)">inspection of files and records, of a court pertaining to an unserved arrest warrant and the charging document upon which the arrest warrant was issued, by:<section prefix="1.">a judicial officer;</section><section prefix="2.">any authorized court personnel;</section><section prefix="3.">a State's Attorney;</section><section prefix="4.">a peace officer;</section><section prefix="5.">a correctional officer who is authorized by law to serve an arrest warrant;</section><section prefix="6.">a bail bondsman, surety insurer, or surety who executes bail bonds who executed a bail bond for the individual who is subject to arrest under the arrest warrant;</section><section prefix="7.">an attorney authorized by the individual who is subject to arrest under the arrest warrant;</section><section prefix="8.">the Department of Juvenile Services; or</section><section prefix="9.">a federal, State, or local criminal justice agency described under Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the Criminal Procedure Article; or</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">the release of information by the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services or the Department of Juvenile Services for the purpose of notification of a victim under &#xA7; 11-507 of the Criminal Procedure Article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(r)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a custodian shall deny inspection of all records of persons created, generated, obtained by, or submitted to the Maryland Transit Administration, its agents, or employees in connection with the use or purchase of electronic fare media provided by the Maryland Transit Administration, its agents, employees, or contractors.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A custodian shall permit inspection of the records enumerated in paragraph (1) of this subsection by:<section prefix="(i)">an individual named in the record; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the attorney of record of an individual named in the record.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(s)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to &#xA7; 8-704.1 of the Natural Resources Article and paragraph (2) of this subsection, a custodian may not knowingly disclose a public record of the Department of Natural Resources containing personal information about the owner of a registered vessel.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, a custodian shall disclose personal information about the owner of a registered vessel for use in the normal course of business activity by a financial institution, as defined in &#xA7; 1-101(i) of the Financial Institutions Article, its agents, employees, or contractors, but only:<section prefix="(i)">to verify the accuracy of personal information submitted by the individual to that financial institution; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the information submitted is not accurate, to obtain correct information only for the purpose of:<section prefix="1.">preventing fraud by the individual;</section><section prefix="2.">pursuing legal remedies against the individual; or</section><section prefix="3.">recovering on a debt or security interest against the individual.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(t)">A custodian shall deny inspection of an application for renewable energy credit certification or a claim for renewable energy credits under Title 10, Subtitle 15 of the Agriculture Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "surveillance image" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 10-112 of the Criminal Law Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, a custodian of a surveillance image shall deny inspection of the surveillance image.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A custodian shall allow inspection of a surveillance image:<section prefix="(i)">as required in &#xA7; 10-112 of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">by any person issued a citation under &#xA7; 10-112 of the Criminal Law Article, or an attorney of record for the person; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">by an employee or agent of the Baltimore City Department of Public Works in an investigation or proceeding relating to the imposition of or indemnification from civil liability under &#xA7; 10-112 of the Criminal Law Article.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
