<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-2203" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-2203</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a CEO Board of Advisors for E-Commerce.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may not exceed 12 members and shall be appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate and serve at the pleasure of the Governor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each member of the Board serves for a period of 3 years and may be reappointed.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Governor shall designate two representatives of State government to serve as ex officio members of the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The members appointed by the Governor shall be industry leaders who have substantial experience and expertise in electronic commerce.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Governor shall designate a chairman or cochairmen from among the members.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Board shall meet at least twice annually.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">advise the Governor on economic development policies and initiatives to advance the promotion, deployment, and use of e-commerce in the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">recommend ways to improve the State's position as an international leader of e-commerce; and</section><section prefix="(3)">provide policy guidance to the "eMaryland" ASP Consortium and related ASP initiatives.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A member of the Board may not receive compensation as a member but is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations as provided in the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Department of Budget and Management and University of Maryland, College Park shall provide staff support to the Board.</section>
  </text>
</law>
