<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-102" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-14-102</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">With respect to land that the United States or any of its units leases or otherwise holds in the State, the State reserves jurisdiction and authority over the land and over persons, property, and transactions on the land to the fullest extent that is permitted by the United States Constitution and that is not inconsistent with the governmental purpose for which the land is held.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not affect the jurisdiction and authority of the State over land or persons, property, and transactions on land that the United States or its unit has acquired on or before May 31, 1943 to the extent that the State ceded jurisdiction under:<section prefix="(1)">Chapter 193, &#xA7;&#xA7; 3 and 4, of the Acts of the General Assembly of 1874;</section><section prefix="(2)">Chapter 395, &#xA7;&#xA7; 13 and 14, of the Acts of the General Assembly of 1874;</section><section prefix="(3)">Chapter 67, &#xA7; 21, of the Acts of the General Assembly of 1900;</section><section prefix="(4)">Chapter 743, &#xA7;&#xA7; 2 and 3, of the Acts of the General Assembly of 1906;</section><section prefix="(5)">Chapter 194 of the Acts of the General Assembly of 1908; or</section><section prefix="(6)">any other act that gave consent for the acquisition of property and ceded jurisdiction with respect to that property.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, for the purpose of enforcing the civil or criminal laws of the State, the Governor may enter into agreements with the United States to establish full or partial concurrent jurisdiction by the State and the United States over any lands in the State held by the United States.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, and for as long as the United States shall own such land, the State cedes exclusive jurisdiction to the United States over all that certain tract or parcel of land situate in the State of Maryland, Anne Arundel County, being a portion of the Fort George G. Meade Military Reservation, lands owned by the United States of America as designated by Tract Numbers 170-1, 171, 172 and 174, comprising approximately 265 acres and hereinafter referred to by the tract number and more particularly bounded and described as follows:</section>
      <section prefix="(1)">south 05 degrees 48 minutes 40 seconds west 665.51 feet,</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">south 21 degrees 08 minutes 19 seconds west 1,586.36 feet,</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">south 61 degrees 34 minutes 06 seconds west 784.82 feet,</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">south 61 degrees 45 minutes 24 seconds west 243.08 feet,</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">south 17 degrees 49 minutes 32 seconds east 377.50 feet,</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">south 72 degrees 10 minutes 13 seconds west, passing concrete monument number 65 at 300.00 feet, in all 849.95 feet to concrete monument 64,</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">south 18 degrees 03 minutes 44 seconds east 100.16 feet, to concrete monument number 63,</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">south 73 degrees 03 minutes 24 seconds west 246.48 feet,</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">south 53 degrees 53 minutes 26 seconds east 108.71 feet, to concrete monument number 61,</section>
      <section prefix="(10)">south 29 degrees 19 minutes 41 seconds west 198.24 feet, to concrete monument number 60,</section>
      <section prefix="(11)">south 44 degrees 57 minutes 02 seconds west 1,201.77 feet, to concrete monument number 58,</section>
      <section prefix="(12)">north 61 degrees 38 minutes 35 seconds west 148.49 feet, to concrete monument number 57,</section>
      <section prefix="(13)">south 42 degrees 41 minutes 45 seconds west 1,087.75 feet,</section>
      <section prefix="(14)">south 59 degrees 02 minutes 46 seconds west 619.72 feet,</section>
      <section prefix="(15)">south 36 degrees 20 minutes 02 seconds west 453.33 feet, to concrete monument number 54,</section>
      <section prefix="(16)">south 46 degrees 48 minutes 10 seconds west 136.61 feet, to an iron pipe located in the northern right-of-way line of State Route 32; thence leaving said original Military Reservation line of Fort George G. Meade and running and binding along the Fort George G. Meade Military Reservation boundary line being the southerly line of said Tract Number 170-1, and said northerly road right-of-way,</section>
      <section prefix="(1)">north 05 degrees 08 minutes 30 seconds east 93.49 feet,</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">north 37 degrees 00 minutes 50 seconds east 408.54 feet; thence leaving said Colony Seven Road easterly right-of-way line and continuing running and binding along said Military Reservation boundary line and said westerly line of Tract Number 170-1 the following two (2) courses and distances:</section>
      <section prefix="(1)">north 15 degrees 08 minutes 34 seconds east 505.57 feet,</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">north 49 degrees 50 minutes 53 seconds east 478.74 feet to a point in the easterly right-of-way line of State Route 295, commonly known as the Baltimore-Washington Parkway, said point being a corner common to Tract Number 170-1 and Tract Number 174 of said Military Reservation; thence continuing running and binding along said Military Reservation boundary line being common to the westerly lines of said Tract Numbers 174 and 170-1, and said Parkway easterly right-of-way line, the following nine (9) courses and distances:</section>
      <section prefix="(1)">north 49 degrees 42 minutes 59 seconds east 311.11 feet,</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">north 47 degrees 19 minutes 55 seconds east 1,441.09 feet,</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">north 47 degrees 23 minutes 45 seconds east 290.05 feet,</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">north 45 degrees 09 minutes 58 seconds east, crossing the center line of the old Severn-Annapolis Junction Road at 27.00 feet, in all 220.64 feet,</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">north 36 degrees 46 minutes 58 seconds east 319.80 feet,</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">south 63 degrees 38 minutes 32 seconds east 200.28 feet,</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">north 25 degrees 51 minutes 09 seconds east 997.62 feet,</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">north 30 degrees 20 minutes 54 seconds east 1,542.06 feet,</section>
      <section prefix="(1)">south 50 degrees 05 minutes 05 seconds east 87.89 feet,</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">north 86 degrees 29 minutes 26 seconds east 123.40 feet,</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">south 04 degrees 51 minutes 50 seconds east 635.41 feet,</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">south 75 degrees 17 minutes 41 seconds east 86.63 feet,</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">south 02 degrees 22 minutes 05 seconds east 866.38 feet,</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">north 88 degrees 17 minutes 30 seconds east 278.48 feet to the point of beginning, containing 265.45 acres, more or less.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">It is the intent of the description in paragraph (1) of this subsection, to include all the same lands acquired by the United States of America and as filed and recorded in the land records of Anne Arundel County, Maryland for the following four tracts:<section prefix="(i)">Tracts 170-1 and 170-2 - by declaration of taking, civil number WN 87-2810, filed October 19, 1987.</section><section prefix="(ii)">Tract 171 - from John Cronmiller, et al., by deed dated August 22, 1988, Deed Book 4676, page 779.</section><section prefix="(iii)">Tract 172 from Nancy V. Allan and Alexander V. Allan, by deed dated February 23, 1988, Deed Book 4555, page 846.</section><section prefix="(iv)">Tract 174 - From Colony 7 Motor Inn Limited Partnership, Party of the First Part, and Arthur C. Grant, Frieda C. Grant, William A. Grant, Harold Pollin, Elaine Korn and Richard Pollin, Trustees and Nominees of Colony 7 Motor Inn Limited Partnership I, by deed dated July 11, 1980, Deed Book 5129, page 168.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding the grant of exclusive jurisdiction ceded by the State in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the State shall retain the right to:<section prefix="(i)">serve all civil and criminal process of the courts of this State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">enforce and ensure compliance with all applicable environmental and Public Service Commission laws and regulations.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
