<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-2-10A-03</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Joint Committee on Workers' Compensation Benefit and Insurance Oversight....</catch_line>
  <order_by>03</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Joint Committee on Workers' Compensation Benefit and Insurance Oversight.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Committee consists of 16 members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 16 members:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">2 shall be members of the Senate appointed by the President of the Senate; and</section><section prefix="2.">2 shall be Delegates appointed by the Speaker of the House of Delegates; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">12 shall be appointed jointly by the President and the Speaker as follows:<section prefix="1.">1 representative of the business community;</section><section prefix="2.">1 representative of the Maryland labor organizations;</section><section prefix="3.">1 representative of the Maryland building and construction labor organizations;</section><section prefix="4.">1 representative of a self-insured local government entity;</section><section prefix="5.">2 members of the public;</section><section prefix="6.">1 member of the insurance industry;</section><section prefix="7.">1 member of the Medical and Chirurgical Faculty of Maryland;</section><section prefix="8.">1 member of a workers' compensation rating organization;</section><section prefix="9.">2 members of the Bar of the Court of Appeals of Maryland, 1 of whom represents plaintiffs in workers' compensation cases and 1 of whom represents defendants in workers' compensation cases; and</section><section prefix="10.">1 member who is certified by the Workers' Compensation Commission as a Maryland rehabilitation service provider.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The members of the Committee serve at the pleasure of the presiding officer who appointed them.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The President and the Speaker shall jointly appoint a Senator and a Delegate each to serve as cochair.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Committee shall examine and evaluate:<section prefix="(i)">the condition of the workers' compensation benefit and insurance structure in the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the effect of Chapters 590 and 591 of the Laws of Maryland of 1987 on that structure.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This examination shall include the regulations adopted by the Workers' Compensation Commission that are to be used by physicians to measure impairment when preparing medical evaluations of claimants.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Insurance Commissioner and the Workers' Compensation Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">cooperate fully with the Committee;</section><section prefix="(2)">keep the Committee fully informed as to the condition of workers' compensation benefits and workers' compensation insurance in the State and the effect of Chapters 590 and 591 of the Laws of Maryland of 1987 on those benefits and that insurance; and</section><section prefix="(3)">submit an annual report, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of this title, to the Committee on or before October 1 of each year that incorporates the information described in item (2) of this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Committee shall report to the Governor and the Legislative Policy Committee on December 31 of each year.</section>
  </text>
</law>
