<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-2-1224</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "unit" includes the Board of Liquor License Commissioners for Baltimore City....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1224</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "unit" includes the Board of Liquor License Commissioners for Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except with the written approval of the Legislative Auditor, an employee or authorized representative of the Office of Legislative Audits shall submit any report of findings only to the Legislative Auditor.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On the completion of each examination, the Legislative Auditor shall submit a full and detailed report to the Joint Audit Committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A report shall include:<section prefix="(i)">the findings;</section><section prefix="(ii)">any appropriate recommendations for changes in record keeping or in other conduct of the unit or body that is the subject of the report; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">any response of that unit or body, subject to procedures approved by the Joint Audit Committee.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Legislative Auditor shall send a copy of the report to:<section prefix="(1)">the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Delegates;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Chairmen of the Senate Budget and Taxation and House Appropriations Committees;</section><section prefix="(3)">members of the General Assembly, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(4)">the Governor, unless the report is of the Board of Liquor License Commissioners for Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="(5)">the Comptroller;</section><section prefix="(6)">the State Treasurer, unless the report is of the Board of Liquor License Commissioners for Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="(7)">the Attorney General, unless the report is of the Board of Liquor License Commissioners for Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="(8)">the unit or body that is the subject of the report;</section><section prefix="(9)">the Secretary of Budget and Management, unless the report is of the Board of Liquor License Commissioners for Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="(10)">the Executive Director; and</section><section prefix="(11)">any other person whom the Joint Audit Committee specifies.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In addition to the requirements of subsection (d) of this section, each report of:<section prefix="(1)">a local school system shall be distributed to the chair of the House Ways and Means Committee and the cochairs of the Joint Committee on the Management of Public Funds; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the Board of Liquor License Commissioners for Baltimore City shall be distributed to the chair of the Baltimore City delegation and the chair of the Baltimore City senators.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">After the expiration of any period that the Joint Audit Committee specifies, a report of the Legislative Auditor is available to the public under &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-602 and 10-611 through 10-628 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Legislative Auditor shall review each unit's response and advise the unit of the results of the review. The Legislative Auditor shall advise the Joint Audit Committee when:<section prefix="(i)">a unit does not make a response to a recommendation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a unit does not indicate action to be taken in response to a recommendation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a unit has not taken the action the unit indicated in its response to a recommendation;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a unit requests a waiver from a recommendation; or</section><section prefix="(v)">the response by the unit is not considered appropriate to carry out the recommendation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Executive Director or the Joint Audit Committee may direct the Legislative Auditor to undertake a review to determine the extent to which action has been taken by a unit to implement a report recommendation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">With respect to findings and recommendations of a fiscal/compliance nature, the Committee may recommend to the Governor and the Comptroller that the unit take the corrective action the unit indicates would be taken or take action to correct the findings in the report or the Committee may grant a waiver from the recommended action.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Within 45 days after receipt of the recommendation the Governor shall advise the Committee as to the action taken with respect to the recommendation.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Without concurrence of the Comptroller, the Committee may not waive a recommendation of the Legislative Auditor with respect to fiscal and financial record keeping, a uniform system of accounting, or the submission of fiscal and financial reports by the units.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">With respect to findings and recommendations of a performance nature, the Committee may make recommendations to the Governor or propose legislation after reviewing a unit's response to a recommended action.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The Legislative Auditor shall review each local school system's response to an audit conducted under &#xA7; 2-1220(e) of this subtitle and advise the local school system of the results of the review. The Legislative Auditor shall advise the Joint Audit Committee when a local school system:<section prefix="(i)">does not make a response to a recommendation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">does not indicate action to be taken in response to a recommendation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">has not taken the action the local school system indicated in its response to a recommendation; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">responds in a manner that is not considered appropriate to carry out the recommendation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The Executive Director or the Joint Audit Committee may direct the Legislative Auditor to undertake a review to determine the extent to which action has been taken by a local school system to implement a report recommendation.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">With respect to findings and recommendations made to a local school system, the Joint Audit Committee may make recommendations to the Governor, State Superintendent of Schools, the local school governing board, or local school officials after reviewing a local school system's response to a recommended action.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor and the Chief Judge of the Court of Appeals shall implement systems and processes to monitor the efforts of the Executive Departmental Units and the Judiciary, respectively, to correct audit findings reported by the Office of Legislative Audits.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 9 months of the most recent audit report, any unit that has five or more repeat audit findings shall report to the Office of Legislative Audits for each finding in that audit report:<section prefix="(i)">the corrective actions taken; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a schedule for when specific corrective actions will be implemented.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each unit required to report to the Office of Legislative Audits under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall continue to report to the Office of Legislative Audits on a quarterly basis after the initial report until the actions reported by the agency indicate that satisfactory progress has been made to address all findings.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
