<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-109</section_number>
  <catch_line>In addition to the specific powers granted and duties imposed by this subtitle, the Commission has t...</catch_line>
  <order_by>109</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to the specific powers granted and duties imposed by this subtitle, the Commission has the powers and duties set forth in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall conduct studies of the State lottery and gaming program to:<section prefix="(i)">identify any defect in this subtitle, Subtitle 1A of this title, or the regulations of the Agency that may allow abuses in the operation and administration of the State lottery and gaming program or any evasion of this subtitle, Subtitle 1A of this title, or the regulations;</section><section prefix="(ii)">guard against the use of this subtitle, Subtitle 1A of this title, and the regulations of the Agency as a means of conducting organized crime;</section><section prefix="(iii)">ensure that the regulations of the Agency are proper and that this subtitle, Subtitle 1A of this title, and the regulations are administered to serve the purpose of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">analyze the gaming industry within and outside the State to determine whether Maryland's gaming program is competitive and maximizing revenues for the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall conduct studies of:<section prefix="(i)">the operation and administration of similar laws in other states or countries;</section><section prefix="(ii)">federal laws that may affect the operation of the State lottery or gaming activities;</section><section prefix="(iii)">literature on lotteries and gaming activities, including problem gambling programs; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the reaction of citizens of the State to existing and potential features of the State lottery and gaming program.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall submit to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of this article, to the General Assembly the reports required under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall submit monthly a report that states the total State lottery and gaming revenues and the total prize disbursements and other expenses for the preceding month.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission shall submit annually a report that states the total State lottery and gaming revenues and the total prize disbursements and other expenses for the preceding year.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Commission shall submit a report whenever a matter requires an immediate change in a State law to:<section prefix="(i)">prevent an abuse or evasion of this subtitle, Subtitle 1A of this title, or a regulation of the Agency; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">rectify an undesirable condition in the operation or administration of the State lottery and gaming program.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
