<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-906" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-2-906</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Committee shall:<section prefix="(1)">as to the relations between the State and the federal government:<section prefix="(i)">monitor and evaluate the relations;</section><section prefix="(ii)">monitor proposals to change the relations;</section><section prefix="(iii)">evaluate the impact of the proposals on the State and its citizens and on local governments; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">keep officials of the Executive and Legislative branches of the State government and others informed about the relations and the potential impact of proposals to change the relations;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">serve as a forum for consideration of certain State-local issues;</section><section prefix="(3)">try to advance the cooperation between the State and other units of government by proposing or facilitating any actions that the Committee considers advisable, including:<section prefix="(i)">the adoption of compacts;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the enactment of uniform statutes;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the enactment of reciprocal statutes;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the adoption of uniform administrative rules or regulations;</section><section prefix="(v)">the adoption of reciprocal administrative rules or regulations;</section><section prefix="(vi)">the informal cooperation between government offices;</section><section prefix="(vii)">the personal cooperation between officials and employees of governments; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">the exchange of information; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">do any other thing that the Legislative Policy Committee assigns.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of this title, the Committee shall submit to the General Assembly:<section prefix="(1)">an annual report, within 15 days after the General Assembly convenes for a regular session; and</section><section prefix="(2)">any other report that the Committee considers appropriate.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
