<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-11-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>This title applies only to a development project and only through the completion of a final action u...</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This title applies only to a development project and only through the completion of a final action under &#xA7; 11-520 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This title does not apply to an application for a renewal, amendment, or extension of a development permit.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This title applies to the procedures of the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission for a subdivision or site review to the same extent that this title applies to the procedures of any local government.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, this title does not affect any exclusive jurisdiction granted by law to a local government or State unit to act on an application for a particular type of development permit, and a local government or State unit that has power to grant development permits may exercise the power free from interference by another unit.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The coordinator may inquire as to any application for a development permit and may set a time limit for action to issue or deny a development permit, if the application has not been acted on within the prescribed time.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The procedures set forth in this title are exclusive and shall prevail over any inconsistent law or order.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This title does not affect the authority of a local government or State unit to set and to collect an application, permit, or other fee, and the fee shall be paid in accordance with the law and procedures relating to that fee.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This title does not affect the authority of the Department of Planning under Title 5 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This title does not apply to the construction of:<section prefix="(1)">an electric generating station; or</section><section prefix="(2)">an overhead transmission line designed to carry more than 69,000 volts.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
