<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-2006</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>2006</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Ballast" means a device used with an electric discharge lamp to obtain necessary circuit conditions, including voltage, current, and waveform, for starting and operating the lamp.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Bottle-type water dispenser" means a water dispenser that uses a bottle or reservoir as the source of potable water.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Ceiling fan" means a nonportable device that is suspended from a ceiling for the purpose of circulating air via the rotation of fan blades.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Ceiling fan light kit" means equipment designed to provide light from a ceiling fan, which can be:<section prefix="(i)">integral, such that the equipment is hardwired to the ceiling fan; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">attachable, such that at the time of sale the equipment is not physically attached to the ceiling fan but may be included inside the ceiling fan package at the time of sale or sold separately for subsequent attachment to the fan.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Commercial clothes washer" means a soft mount front-loading or soft mount top-loading clothes washer that is designed for use in:<section prefix="(i)">applications where the occupants of more than one household will be using it, including multifamily housing common areas and coin laundries; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">other commercial applications, if the clothes container compartment is not greater than:<section prefix="1.">3.5 cubic feet for horizontal-axis clothes washers; or</section><section prefix="2.">4.0 cubic feet for vertical-axis clothes washers.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Commercial hot food holding cabinet" means a heated, fully enclosed compartment with one or more solid or glass doors that is designed to maintain the temperature of hot food that has been cooked in a separate appliance.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Commercial hot food holding cabinet" does not include a heated glass merchandizing cabinet, drawer warmer, or cook-and-hold appliance.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(8)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Commercial refrigeration cabinet" means a refrigerator, freezer, or refrigerator-freezer designed for use by commercial or institutional facilities for the purpose of storing food products, ice, or other perishable items at specified temperatures and that may be configured with either solid or transparent doors as a:<section prefix="1.">reach-in cabinet;</section><section prefix="2.">pass-through cabinet;</section><section prefix="3.">roll-in cabinet; or</section><section prefix="4.">roll-through cabinet.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Commercial refrigeration cabinet" does not include:<section prefix="1.">a product with 85 cubic feet or more of internal volume;</section><section prefix="2.">a walk-in refrigerator or walk-in freezer;</section><section prefix="3.">a consumer product regulated under the National Appliance Energy Conservation Act of 1987 (Public Law 100-12); or</section><section prefix="4.">any refrigerator, freezer, or refrigerator-freezer designed and marketed exclusively for medical, scientific, or research purposes.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(9)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Electricity ratio" is the ratio of furnace electricity use to total furnace energy use.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Electricity ratio" is equal to a fraction:<section prefix="1.">the numerator of which is 3.412 times the average annual auxiliary electrical consumption as defined in Appendix N to subpart B of part 430 of title 10 of the Code of Federal Regulations; and</section><section prefix="2.">the denominator of which is the sum of:</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(10)">"High-intensity discharge lamp" means a lamp in which:<section prefix="(i)">light is produced by the passage of an electric current through a vapor or gas;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the light-producing arc is stabilized by bulb wall temperature; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the arc tube has a bulb wall loading in excess of 3 watts per square centimeter.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(11)">"Illuminated exit sign" means an internally illuminated sign that is designed to be permanently fixed in place to identify an exit and the background of which is not transparent.</section>
      <section prefix="(12)">"Large packaged air-conditioning equipment" means packaged air-conditioning equipment with at least 20 tons but not more than 80 tons of cooling capacity.</section>
      <section prefix="(13)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Low-voltage dry-type distribution transformer" means a distribution transformer that:<section prefix="1.">has an input voltage of 600 volts or less;</section><section prefix="2.">is air-cooled; and</section><section prefix="3.">does not use oil as a coolant.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Low-voltage dry-type distribution transformer" does not include any of the following transformers:<section prefix="1.">an autotransformer in which the primary and secondary windings are not electronically isolated and at least a portion of the secondary voltage is derived from the primary winding;</section><section prefix="2.">a drive transformer designed only to provide power to operate an electronic variable speed motor drive;</section><section prefix="3.">a grounding transformer designed only to provide a system ground reference point;</section><section prefix="4.">a harmonic transformer designed to supply a load with a higher than normal harmonic current level and that has a k-rating of k-4 or greater;</section><section prefix="5.">an impedance transformer that has a specified impedance of less than 4% or greater than 8%;</section><section prefix="6.">a machine tool transformer designed only to provide power to machine tool equipment;</section><section prefix="7.">a rectifier transformer designed to provide power only to a rectifier circuit and that has a nameplate rating for both the fundamental frequency power rating and the RMS power rating;</section><section prefix="8.">a regulating transformer with automatic tap changers;</section><section prefix="9.">a sealed and nonventilating transformer designed to prevent airflow through the transformer;</section><section prefix="10.">a testing transformer designed only as part of, or to supply power to, electrical test equipment;</section><section prefix="11.">a UPS transformer designed only as an integral part of an uninterruptible power system; or</section><section prefix="12.">a welding transformer designed only to provide power to welding equipment.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(14)">"Metal halide lamp" means a high intensity discharge lamp in which the major portion of the light is produced by radiation of metal halides and their products of dissociation, and possibly in combination with metallic vapors.</section>
      <section prefix="(15)">"Metal halide lamp fixture" means a light fixture designed to be operated with a metal halide lamp and a ballast for a metal halide lamp.</section>
      <section prefix="(16)">"Packaged air-conditioning equipment" means air-conditioning equipment that is built as a package and shipped as a whole to end-user sites.</section>
      <section prefix="(17)">"Pass-through cabinet" means a commercial refrigerator or commercial freezer with hinged or sliding doors on both the front and rear of the refrigerator or freezer.</section>
      <section prefix="(18)">"Probe-start metal halide ballast" means a ballast used to operate metal halide lamps, that:<section prefix="(i)">does not contain an igniter; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">starts lamps by using a third starting electrode probe in the arc tube.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(19)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Reach-in cabinet" means a commercial refrigerator, commercial freezer, or commercial refrigerator-freezer with hinged or sliding doors or lids.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Reach-in cabinet" does not include a roll-in or roll-through cabinet or a pass-through cabinet.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(20)">"Residential furnace" means a self-contained space heater that:<section prefix="(i)">is designed to supply heated air through ducts of more than 10 inches in length;</section><section prefix="(ii)">uses single-phase electric current or DC current in conjunction with natural gas or propane; and</section><section prefix="(iii)"><section prefix="1.">is designed to be the principal heating source for the living space of one or more residences;</section><section prefix="2.">is not contained within the same cabinet with a central air conditioner whose rated cooling capacity is above 65,000 B.T.U. per hour; and</section><section prefix="3.">has a heat input rate of less than 225,000 B.T.U. per hour.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(21)">"Retailer" means a person engaged in the business of making retail sales within the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(22)">"Roll-in cabinet" means a commercial refrigerator or commercial freezer with hinged or sliding doors that allow wheeled racks of product to be rolled into the refrigerator or freezer.</section>
      <section prefix="(23)">"Roll-through cabinet" means a commercial refrigerator or commercial freezer with hinged or sliding doors that allow wheeled racks of product to be rolled through the refrigerator or freezer.</section>
      <section prefix="(24)">"Single-voltage external AC to DC power supply" means a device that:<section prefix="(i)">is designed to convert line voltage AC input into lower voltage DC output;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is able to convert to only one DC output voltage at a time;</section><section prefix="(iii)">is sold with, or intended to be used with, a separate end-use product that constitutes the primary power load;</section><section prefix="(iv)">is contained within a separate physical enclosure from the end-use product;</section><section prefix="(v)">is connected to the end-use product through a removable or hard-wired male/female electrical connection, cable, cord, or other wiring;</section><section prefix="(vi)">does not have a battery or battery pack, removable or otherwise, that physically attaches directly to the power supply unit;</section><section prefix="(vii)">does not have a battery chemistry or type selector switch and indicator light or does not have a battery chemistry or type selector switch and a state-of-charge meter; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">has a nameplate output power not exceeding 250 watts.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(25)">"State-regulated incandescent reflector lamp" means a lamp, not colored or designed for rough or vibration service applications:<section prefix="(i)">with an inner reflective coating on the outer bulb to direct the light;</section><section prefix="(ii)">with an E26 medium screw base;</section><section prefix="(iii)">with a rated voltage or voltage range that lies at least partially within 115 to 130 volts; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">that is:<section prefix="1.">a blown PAR (BPAR);</section><section prefix="2.">a bulged reflector (BR);</section><section prefix="3.">an elliptical reflector (ER) or similar bulb shape with a diameter equal to or greater than 2.25 inches; or</section><section prefix="4.">a reflector (R), parabolic aluminized reflector (PAR), or similar bulb shape with a diameter of 2.25 to 2.75 inches, inclusive.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(26)">"Torchiere lighting fixture" means a portable electric lighting fixture with a reflector bowl giving light directed upward so as to give indirect illumination.</section>
      <section prefix="(27)">"Traffic signal" means a device consisting of a set of signal lights operating in sequence and placed at intersections to regulate traffic.</section>
      <section prefix="(28)">"Traffic signal module" means a standard 8-inch (200mm) or 12-inch (300mm) round traffic signal indication that:<section prefix="(i)">consists of a light source, lens, full-color ball, and all parts necessary for operation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">communicates movement messages to drivers through red, amber, and green colors.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(29)">"Transformer" means a device consisting essentially of two or more coils of insulated wire that transfers alternating current by electromagnetic induction from one coil to another in order to change the original voltage or current value.</section>
      <section prefix="(30)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Unit heater" means a self-contained fan-type heater that:<section prefix="1.">is designed to be installed within the heated space; and</section><section prefix="2.">includes an apparatus or appliance to supply heat and a fan for circulating air over a heat exchange surface, all enclosed in a common casing.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Unit heater" does not include a "warm air furnace" as defined under the federal Energy Policy Act of 1992.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(31)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Walk-in refrigerator and freezer" means a refrigerated space that:<section prefix="1.">can be walked into;</section><section prefix="2.">has a total chilled and frozen storage area of less than 3,000 square feet;</section><section prefix="3.">operates at chilled (above 32 degrees Fahrenheit) or frozen (at or below 32 degrees Fahrenheit) temperature; and</section><section prefix="4.">is connected to a self-contained or remote condensing unit.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Walk-in refrigerator and freezer" does not include:<section prefix="1.">a product designed and marketed exclusively for medical, scientific, or research purposes; and</section><section prefix="2.">a refrigerated warehouse.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(32)">"Water dispenser" means a factory-made assembly that:<section prefix="(i)">mechanically cools and heats potable water; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">dispenses the cooled or heated water by integral or remote means.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(33)">"Widely available in Maryland" means a conforming product available in the State from three or more manufacturers.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section applies to the testing, certification, and enforcement of efficiency standards for the following types of new products sold, offered for sale, or installed in the State:<section prefix="(i)">torchiere lighting fixtures;</section><section prefix="(ii)">unit heaters;</section><section prefix="(iii)">low-voltage dry-type distribution transformers;</section><section prefix="(iv)">ceiling fan light kits;</section><section prefix="(v)">red and green traffic signal modules;</section><section prefix="(vi)">illuminated exit signs;</section><section prefix="(vii)">commercial refrigeration cabinets;</section><section prefix="(viii)">large packaged air-conditioning equipment;</section><section prefix="(ix)">commercial clothes washers;</section><section prefix="(x)">bottle-type water dispensers;</section><section prefix="(xi)">commercial hot food holding cabinets;</section><section prefix="(xii)">metal halide lamp fixtures;</section><section prefix="(xiii)">residential furnaces;</section><section prefix="(xiv)">single-voltage external AC to DC power supplies;</section><section prefix="(xv)">state-regulated incandescent reflector lamps; and</section><section prefix="(xvi)">walk-in refrigerators and freezers.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">new products manufactured in the State and sold outside the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">new products manufactured outside the State and sold at wholesale inside the State for final retail sale and installation outside the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">products installed in mobile manufactured homes at the time of construction;</section><section prefix="(iv)">products designed expressly for installation and use in recreational vehicles; or</section><section prefix="(v)">residential furnaces that use natural gas or propane and that are installed as a replacement for a previously installed furnace.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before January 1, 2004, the Administration shall adopt regulations establishing minimum efficiency standards for the types of new products set forth in subsection (b)(1)(i) through (ix) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The regulations shall provide for the following minimum efficiency standards:<section prefix="(i)">torchiere fixtures may not consume more than 190 watts and may not be capable of operating with lamps that total more than 190 watts;</section><section prefix="(ii)">unit heaters shall be equipped with an intermittent ignition device and shall have either power venting or an automatic flue damper;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the efficiency of all low-voltage dry-type distribution transformers may not be less than the values shown in Table 4-2 of National Electrical Manufacturers Association Standard TP-1-2002;</section><section prefix="(iv)">ceiling fan light kits:<section prefix="1.">shall meet the Tier 1 lighting criteria of version 1.1 of the product specification contained in the "Energy Star Program Requirements for Residential Ceiling Fans", developed by the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency that took effect on January 1, 2002; and</section><section prefix="2.">may contain light sources that are not compact fluorescent lamps but that have lumen-per-watt performance at least equivalent to comparably configured compact fluorescent lamps meeting "Energy Star Program Requirements for CFLS: Energy Efficiency Criteria - Version 3.0";</section></section><section prefix="(v)">red and green traffic signal modules shall:<section prefix="1.">meet the requirements of the "Energy Star Program Requirements for Traffic Signals" developed by the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency that took effect in February 2001; and</section><section prefix="2.">be installed with compatible, electrically connected signal control interface devices and conflict monitoring systems;</section></section><section prefix="(vi)">illuminated exit signs shall meet the requirements of the "Energy Star Program Requirements for Exit Signs - Version 2.0" developed by the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency that took effect on January 1, 1999;</section><section prefix="(vii)">commercial refrigeration cabinets shall meet the requirements shown in the following Table in which "V" means total volume in cubic feet and "AV" means adjusted volume which is the sum of the volume of refrigerated space and 1.63 times the volume of freezer space:</section><section prefix="(viii)">large packaged air-conditioning equipment shall meet the Tier II requirements of the "Minimum Equipment Efficiencies for Unitary Commercial Air Conditioners" or "Minimum Equipment Efficiencies for Heat Pumps", as  appropriate, developed by the Consortium for Energy Efficiency, Boston, Massachusetts, as in effect on January 1, 2002; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">commercial clothes washers shall have a minimum modified energy factor of 1.26 and a maximum water consumption factor of 9.5, as measured in accordance with the federal test method for clothes washers as defined in 10 C.F.R. Section 430.23(j) (Appendix J1 to Subpart B of Part 430) (2001).</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before January 1, 2008, the Administration shall adopt regulations establishing minimum efficiency standards for the types of new products set forth in subsection (b)(1)(x) through (xvi) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The regulations shall provide for the following minimum efficiency standards:<section prefix="(i)">except as provided in subsubparagraph 2 of this subparagraph:<section prefix="1.">bottle-type water dispensers designed for dispensing both hot and cold water may not have standby energy consumption greater than 1.2 kilowatt-hours per day, as measured in accordance with the test criteria contained in version 1.1 of the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency's "Energy Star Program Requirements for Bottled Water Coolers"; and</section><section prefix="2.">bottle-type water dispenser units with an integral, automatic timer may not be tested using Section D, "Timer Usage" of the test criteria;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">commercial hot food holding cabinets shall have a maximum idle energy rate not exceeding 40 watts per cubic foot of interior volume, as determined by the "idle energy rate-dry test" in ASTM F2140-01, "Standard Test Method for Performance of Hot Food Holding Cabinets" published by ASTM International, and interior volume shall be measured in accordance with the method shown in the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency's "Energy Star Program Requirements for Commercial Hot Food Holding Cabinets" effective August 15, 2003;</section><section prefix="(iii)">metal halide lamp fixtures designed to be operated with lamps rated at least 150 watts but not exceeding 500 watts may not contain a probe-start metal halide ballast;</section><section prefix="(iv)">residential furnaces that use natural gas or propane and that are installed as the original furnace in newly constructed residential buildings shall:<section prefix="1.">have a minimum Annual Fuel Utilization Efficiency (AFUE) of 90% and a maximum electricity ratio of 2%; and</section><section prefix="2.">be measured in accordance with the federal test method for measuring the energy consumption of furnaces and boilers contained in 10 C.F.R. Part 430 (Appendix N to subpart B);</section></section><section prefix="(v)">the standard for single-voltage external AC to DC power supplies:<section prefix="1.">shall apply to single voltage AC to DC power supplies that are sold individually and to those that are sold as a component of or in conjunction with another product;</section><section prefix="2.">does not apply to single voltage external AC to DC power supplies that require U.S. Food and Drug Administration listing and approval as a medical device;</section><section prefix="3.">shall meet the energy efficiency requirements in the following table:</section><section prefix="4.">shall be measured in accordance with the test methodology specified by the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency's Energy Star Program, "Test Method for Calculating the Energy Efficiency of Single-Voltage External AC-DC and AC-AC Power Supplies (August 11, 2004)", except that tests shall be conducted at 115 volts only;</section></section><section prefix="(vi)">the standard for State-regulated incandescent reflector lamps:<section prefix="1.">shall meet the minimum average lamp efficacy requirements for federally regulated incandescent reflector lamps contained in 42 U.S.C. &#xA7; 6295 (i)(1)(A); and</section><section prefix="2.">does not apply to the following types of incandescent reflector lamps:</section></section><section prefix="(vii)">walk-in refrigerators and freezers:<section prefix="1.">shall have automatic door closers that firmly close all reach-in doors and that firmly close walk-in doors no wider than 3 feet 9 inches and no higher than 6 feet 11 inches that have been closed to within 1 inch of full closure;</section><section prefix="2.">shall have wall, ceiling, and door insulation of at least R-28 for refrigerators (door insulation requirements do not apply to glazed portions of doors, nor to structural members);</section><section prefix="3.">shall have wall, ceiling, and door insulation of at least R-32 for freezers (door insulation requirements do not apply to glazed portions of doors, or to structural members);</section><section prefix="4.">shall have floor insulation of at least R-28 for freezers;</section><section prefix="5.">shall have, for single-phase evaporator fan motors of under one horsepower and less than 460 volts, electronically commutated motors;</section><section prefix="6.">shall have, for condenser fan motors of under one horsepower either electronically commutated motors, permanent split capacitor-type motors, or polyphase motors of at least one-half horsepower;</section><section prefix="7.">shall have light sources with an efficacy of at least 40 lumens per watt, including any ballast losses, except that light sources with an efficacy of 40 lumens per watt or less, including any ballast losses, may be used in conjunction with a timer or device that turns off the lights within 15 minutes after the walk-in ceases to be occupied; and</section><section prefix="8.">with transparent reach-in doors and walk-in door windows shall meet the following additional requirements:</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraphs (ii) and (iii) of this paragraph, on or after March 1, 2005, a new product of any type set forth in subsection (b)(1)(i) through (ix) of this section may not be sold or offered for sale in the State unless the efficiency of the new product meets or exceeds the efficiency standards set forth in the regulations adopted under subsection (c) of this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">With respect to ceiling fan light kits, energy efficiency standards may not take effect until March 1, 2007.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">With respect to commercial clothes washers, efficiency standards may not take effect until March 1, 2007.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph does not apply to a product that is sold before the applicable date under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Except as provided in subparagraphs (iii) and (iv) of this paragraph, on or after January 1, 2006, a new product of a type set forth in subsection (b)(1)(i) through (ix) of this section may not be installed in the State unless the efficiency of the new product meets or exceeds the efficiency standards set forth in the regulations adopted under subsection (c) of this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Ceiling fan light kits that do not meet the energy efficiency standards may be installed in the State until January 1, 2008.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Commercial clothes washers that do not meet the efficiency standards under subsection (c)(2)(ix) of this section may be installed in the State until January 1, 2008.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or after January 1, 2009, no new bottle-type water dispenser, commercial hot food holding cabinet, metal halide lamp fixture, State-regulated incandescent reflector lamp, or walk-in refrigerator or walk-in freezer may be sold or offered for sale in the State unless the efficiency of the new product meets or exceeds the efficiency standards set forth in the regulations adopted under subsection (d) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On or after March 1, 2012, no new single-voltage external AC to DC power supply may be sold or offered for sale in the State unless the efficiency of the new product meets or exceeds the efficiency standards set forth in the regulations adopted under subsection (d) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Administration may adopt regulations to exempt compliance with the residential furnace AFUE standards under subsection (d)(2)(iv) of this section at any building, site, or location where complying with the standards would conflict with any local zoning ordinance, building or plumbing code, or other rule regarding installation and venting of residential furnaces or residential boilers.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">On or before January 1, 2008, the Administration, in consultation with the Attorney General, shall determine if federal law preempts State implementation of the residential furnace standards.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Administration shall make separate determinations with respect to minimum AFUE and maximum electricity ratio standards.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">If the Administration determines that a waiver from federal preemption is not needed, then on the later of January 1, 2009, or 1 year after the date of that determination, a new residential furnace may not be sold or offered for sale in the State unless the efficiency of the new product meets or exceeds the applicable nonpreempted efficiency standards set forth in the regulations adopted under subsection (d) of this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">If the Administration determines that a waiver from federal preemption is required, then the Administration shall apply for the waiver within 1 year after that determination. On approval of the waiver application, the applicable State standards shall take effect at the earliest date allowed by federal law.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Single-voltage external AC to DC power supplies made available by a manufacturer directly to a consumer or to a service or repair facility after and separate from the original sale of the product requiring the power supply as a service part or spare part may not be required to meet the standards of this section before January 1, 2013.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Administration may delay implementation of subsection (d)(2)(vii)5 of this section on a determination that the motors are only available from one manufacturer or in insufficient quantities to serve the needs of the walk-in industry for evaporator-fan applications.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">One year after the sale or offering for sale of a product becomes subject to the requirements of paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of this subsection, the product may not be installed for compensation in the State unless the efficiency of the new product meets or exceeds the efficiency standards set forth in the regulations adopted under subsection (d) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By regulation, the Administration may clarify but not expand the scope of the devices defined under subsections (a) and (b) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On request of a Maryland business or consumer and after public notice and comment, the Administration may delay the effective date of any standard under this section by not more than 1 year if the Administration determines that products conforming to the standard will not be widely available in Maryland by the applicable date stated in subsections (e)(1) and (f)(1), (2), and (3) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Administration may limit a delay under paragraph (2) of this subsection to identifiable subcategories of any category of covered products.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration may adopt regulations to increase the efficiency standards for the products listed in subsection (b)(1)(x) through (xvi) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Every 2 years, the Administration shall consider and propose to the General Assembly:<section prefix="(i)">new standards for products not specifically listed in subsection (b)(1) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">revised, more stringent standards for products listed in subsection (b)(1) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In considering new or amended standards, the Administration shall propose new or amended efficiency standards if it determines that any new or increased efficiency standards would:<section prefix="(i)">serve to promote energy conservation in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">be life-cycle cost effective for consumers who purchase and use the new products; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">be technologically feasible and economically justified.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A new or increased efficiency standard may not become effective less than 1 year after the adoption of that standard.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Subject to paragraphs (6) and (7) of this subsection, the Administration may apply for a waiver of federal preemption in accordance with federal procedures (42 U.S.C. &#xA7; 6297(d)) for State efficiency standards for any product regulated by the federal government.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Administration may apply for a waiver under paragraph (5) of this subsection, if:<section prefix="(i)">at least 90 days before the day on which the application for the waiver is submitted to the federal government, the Administration announces its intention to submit the application by publication in the Maryland Register and writing to the presiding officers of the General Assembly; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">at least 60 days before the day on which the application for the waiver is submitted to the federal government, the Administration, after reasonable notice other than publication in the Maryland Register, shall hold a public hearing on the proposed application to receive public comment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Delegates may direct that the appropriate standing committees of the General Assembly hold hearings on the proposed application for the waiver and provide comments to the Administration.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After public notice and comment, the Administration shall adopt procedures by rule for testing the energy efficiency of the new products listed in subsection (b)(1) of this section if testing procedures are not provided for in the Maryland Building Performance Standards.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration may adopt updated test methods by regulation when new versions of test methods become available or when an alternative test method has been adopted by another state or the federal government.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Administration shall use appropriate nationally recognized test methods such as those approved by the United States Department of Energy.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The manufacturers of new products listed in subsection (b)(1) of this section shall cause samples of their products to be tested in accordance with the test procedures adopted under this subsection or those specified in the Maryland Building Performance Standards.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for those products listed in subsection (b)(1)(xiv) and (xvi) of this section, manufacturers of new products listed in subsection (b)(1) of this section shall certify to the Administration that the products are in compliance with the provisions of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Administration shall adopt regulations governing the certification of new products and may coordinate with the certification programs of other states with similar standards.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Any manufacturer that has certified a product to another state or to the federal Energy Star Program may provide the Administration with a copy of the certification that the manufacturer made to the other state or agency in place of a separate certification to the State of Maryland, provided that:<section prefix="1.">the other state's standards or the Energy Star specifications are equivalent to or more stringent than the standards of the State of Maryland; and</section><section prefix="2.">all information required by the regulations adopted under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph is included in the certification.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Manufacturers of new products listed in subsection (b)(1) of this section shall identify each product offered through retailers for sale or installation in the State as in compliance with the minimum efficiency standards established under subsection (c) of this section by means of a mark, label, or tag on the product or packaging at the time of sale or installation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Administration shall adopt regulations governing the identification of such products or packaging which shall be coordinated to the greatest practical extent with the labeling programs and requirements of other states and federal agencies with equivalent efficiency standards.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a national efficiency standard is established by federal law or regulation for a product listed in subsection (b) of this section, the labeling requirements set forth in COMAR 14.26.03.10 do not apply to that product.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">In accordance with COMAR 14.26.03.10, all display models of products shall be displayed with a mark, label, or tag on the product.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration may test products listed in subsection (b)(1) of this section using an accredited testing facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If products tested are found not to be in compliance with the minimum efficiency standards established under subsections (c) and (d) of this section, the Administration shall:<section prefix="(i)">charge the manufacturer of the product for the cost of product purchase and testing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">make information available to the public on products found not to be in compliance with the standards.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With prior notice and at reasonable and convenient hours, the Administration may make periodic inspections of distributors or retailers of new products listed in subsection (b)(1) of this section in order to determine compliance with the provisions of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration shall coordinate with the Department of Housing and Community Development regarding inspections, prior to occupancy, of newly constructed buildings containing new products that are also covered by the Maryland Building Performance Standards.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration may investigate complaints received concerning violations of this section and shall report the results of an investigation to the Attorney General.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Attorney General may institute proceedings to enforce the provisions of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A manufacturer, distributor, or retailer of new products listed in subsection (b)(1) of this section that violates any provision of this section shall be issued a warning by the Administration for a first violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Repeat violators shall be subject to a civil penalty of not more than $250.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Each violation of this section shall constitute a separate offense and each day that a violation continues shall constitute a separate offense.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Penalties assessed under this subsection are in addition to costs assessed under subsection (l)(2)(i) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Penalties assessed under this subsection shall be paid into the General Fund of the State.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
