<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-2-1505</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1505</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, a committee may not vote on a bill unless:<section prefix="(1)">a fiscal note accompanies the bill; and</section><section prefix="(2)">if the bill affects the funding of a State pension system, an actuarial analysis of the bill is attached to or summarized in the note or the analysis is waived.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a bill affects the funding of a State pension system and the standing committee to which the bill is referred determines that the fiscal impact on the State warrants an actuarial analysis of the bill, the standing committee shall ask the Department of Legislative Services to obtain the actuarial analysis.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The standing committee may waive the actuarial analysis if the standing committee certifies that prompt action on the bill is needed to conduct legislative business.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Executive Director of the Department of Legislative Services shall have that Department prepare a fiscal note for each bill.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the chairman of the committee to which a bill is referred certifies that prompt committee action on the bill is needed to conduct legislative business and, before the Department prepares the fiscal note for the bill, holds a hearing on the bill, the Department shall prepare the note as soon after the hearing as possible.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">When a standing committee asks for an actuarial analysis of a bill that affects a State pension system, the Department of Legislative Services shall:<section prefix="(i)">obtain the analysis; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">summarize the analysis in the fiscal note or attach the analysis to the note.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Department of Legislative Services shall send a copy of a fiscal note for a bill to the committee to which the bill is referred and to the primary sponsor of the bill.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Upon request of the Department of Legislative Services, a unit of State or local government promptly shall provide any information requested by the Department for preparing a fiscal note.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A fiscal note for a bill shall contain an estimate of the fiscal impact of the bill on the revenues and expenditures of the State government and of local governments:<section prefix="(i)">during the year in which the bill is to become effective and the next 4 years after that year; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the full fiscal impact of a bill is not expected to occur during those years, during each year until and the first year during which that impact is expected to occur.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a bill, as introduced or amended, imposes a mandate on a local government unit, the fiscal note for the bill shall contain:<section prefix="(i)">a statement that clearly identifies the imposition of the mandate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">an estimate of the fiscal impact of the mandate and, if applicable and if data is available, the effect on local property tax rates.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a bill, as introduced or amended, requires a mandated appropriation, the fiscal note for the bill shall contain:<section prefix="(i)">a statement that clearly identifies the imposition of the mandated appropriation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">an estimate of the fiscal impact of the mandated appropriation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A fiscal note shall identify the sources of the information that the Department used in preparing the estimates of fiscal impact.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">As soon as possible after the adoption of an amendment that changes the fiscal impact of a bill, the Department of Legislative Services shall:<section prefix="(1)">prepare a revised fiscal note for the bill; and</section><section prefix="(2)">send the revised note:<section prefix="(i)">to the chairman of the committee to which the bill is referred in the house of origin;</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the bill has reached the opposite house, to the chairman of the committee to which the bill is referred in that house;</section><section prefix="(iii)">if the bill is in the custody of either the Secretary of the Senate or the Chief Clerk of the House, to that officer; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">to the primary sponsor of the bill.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department of Legislative Services shall keep a copy of each fiscal note for 3 years after preparation of the note.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The copies shall be reasonably available for public inspection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Fiscal notes need not be published in the Senate journal or House journal.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A bill may be introduced without a fiscal note accompanying the bill.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The validity of an enactment is not affected by the presence, absence, or content of the fiscal note.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In its summary report of legislation enacted by the General Assembly that has a fiscal impact, the Department of Legislative Services shall include a list of legislation that:<section prefix="1.">affects local government units; or</section><section prefix="2.">requires a mandated appropriation in the annual budget bill.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In the list of legislation described in subparagraph (i)1 of this paragraph, the Department of Legislative Services shall indicate which legislation imposes mandates on local government units.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Where applicable and if data is available, the report shall indicate:<section prefix="(i)">the fiscal impact of the bill on local government units;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the impact of the bill on local property tax rates;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the cumulative fiscal impact of all legislation imposing mandates on more than one local government unit; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the cumulative fiscal impact of all legislation requiring mandated appropriations.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
