<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-15-838</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this Part V the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>838</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this Part V the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Applicant" means an individual or business entity that is:<section prefix="1.">a title owner or contract purchaser of land that is the subject of an application;</section><section prefix="2.">a trustee who has an interest in land that is the subject of an application, excluding trustees described in a mortgage or deed of trust; or</section><section prefix="3.">a holder of 5 percent or greater interest in a business entity who has an interest in land that is the subject of an application.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Applicant" includes, if the applicant is a corporation, the directors and officers of the corporation which actually holds title to the land, or is a contract purchaser of the land which is the subject of an application.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Applicant" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">a financial institution that has loaned money or extended financing for the acquisition, development, or construction or improvements on the land that is the subject of an application;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a municipal or public corporation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a public authority;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a public service company acting within the scope of Division I of the Public Utilities Article; or</section><section prefix="(v)">a person who is hired or retained as an accountant, attorney, architect, engineer, land use consultant, economic consultant, real estate agent, real estate broker, traffic consultant, or traffic engineer.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Application" means an application for a local map amendment, including a reclassification.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Business entity" means:<section prefix="(1)">a sole proprietorship;</section><section prefix="(2)">a corporation;</section><section prefix="(3)">a general partnership;</section><section prefix="(4)">a limited partnership;</section><section prefix="(5)">a limited liability company; or</section><section prefix="(6)">a joint venture.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Candidate" means an individual who wins an election to the Office of County Executive or County Council of Montgomery County.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Contribution" means any payment or transfer of money or property of $500 or more, calculated cumulatively during a 4-year election cycle, or the incurring of any liability or promise of anything of value of $500 or more, calculated cumulatively during a 4-year election cycle, to the treasurer of either a candidate or a political committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Contribution" includes a payment or transfer to a slate with which a candidate is associated.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, the $500 cumulative threshold contribution is calculated separately as to each candidate or elected official.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">For purposes of this subtitle, a cumulative contribution of $500 or more to a slate is fully attributed to each candidate on the slate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Contributor" means an individual or business entity that makes a contribution.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Elected official" means an individual who holds the Office of County Executive or member of the County Council of Montgomery County.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Party of record" means an individual or business entity that is granted standing to participate in a local map amendment proceeding by the County Council, sitting as the District Council, or its hearing examiner.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Party of record" does not include an attorney, consultant, employee, or other agent of a party of record, including an authorized representative of a community association who is participating in a proceeding solely on behalf of the association.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Political action committee" means a political committee that is not:<section prefix="(1)">a political party;</section><section prefix="(2)">a central committee;</section><section prefix="(3)">a slate; or</section><section prefix="(4)">a political committee organized and operated by, and solely on behalf of, an individual running for any elective office or a slate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Political committee" means any combination of two or more persons appointed by a candidate or any other person or formed in any other manner which assists or attempts to assist in any manner the promotion of the success or defeat of any candidate, candidates, political party, principle, or proposition submitted to a vote in any election.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Slate" means a political committee of two or more candidates who join together to conduct and pay for joint activities.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Slate" does not include a political party or a central committee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Treasurer" has the meaning provided in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Election Law Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Treasurer" includes a subtreasurer.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
