<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-15-602</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, a statement filed under &#xA7; 15-601, &#xA7; 15-603, &#xA7; 15-6...</catch_line>
  <order_by>602</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, a statement filed under &#xA7; 15-601, &#xA7; 15-603, &#xA7; 15-604, or &#xA7; 15-605 of this subtitle shall:<section prefix="(1)">be filed with the Ethics Commission;</section><section prefix="(2)">be filed under oath;</section><section prefix="(3)">be filed on or before April 30 of each year;</section><section prefix="(4)">cover the calendar year immediately preceding the year of filing; and</section><section prefix="(5)">contain the information required in &#xA7; 15-607 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notwithstanding subsection (a)(1) of this section, a statement filed by a member of the General Assembly shall be filed in duplicate with the Joint Ethics Committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to the statement filed under &#xA7; 15-601 of this subtitle, a member of the General Assembly shall file a preliminary disclosure on or before the seventh day of the regular legislative session if there will be a substantial change in the statement covering the calendar year immediately preceding the year of filing, as compared to the next preceding calendar year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member of the General Assembly whose statement under &#xA7; 15-601 of this subtitle will not contain a substantial change is not required to file a preliminary disclosure under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Joint Ethics Committee shall:<section prefix="(i)">prescribe the form of a preliminary disclosure under this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">determine which aspects of financial disclosure are subject to this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A preliminary disclosure shall be filed and maintained, and may be disclosed, in the same manner prescribed for a statement filed under &#xA7; 15-601 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Ethics Commission shall develop procedures under which a statement under this subtitle may be filed electronically and without additional cost to the individual who files the statement.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">To comply with the requirement of paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Ethics Commission may adopt regulations to modify the format for disclosure of information required under &#xA7; 15-607 of this subtitle.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The regulations adopted under this paragraph shall be consistent with the intent of this title.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the financial disclosure statement filed electronically under subsection (d) of this section is required to be made under oath or affirmation, the oath or affirmation shall be made by an electronic signature that:<section prefix="(i)">is in the financial disclosure statement or attached to and made part of the financial disclosure statement; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is made expressly under the penalties for perjury.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An electronic signature made under paragraph (1) of this subsection subjects the individual making it to the penalties for perjury to the same extent as an oath or affirmation made before an individual authorized to administer oaths.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
