<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-214" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-7-214</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This subtitle does not affect any other requirement as to notice, including a time that is specifically set for the publication of the notice.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A unit shall submit a notice that sets a date for a hearing or meeting or for the termination of the opportunity to be heard in time for publication in an issue of the Register that will be published:<section prefix="(i)">on or before the date set by law for publication of the notice; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the date for publication is not set by law, at least 15 days before the date for the hearing or meeting or for the termination of the opportunity to be heard.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">As to a notice that paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection governs, publication of the notice less than 15 days before the date for a hearing or meeting or the termination of the opportunity to be heard does not prejudice the effectiveness of the notice, if notice of less than 15 days is reasonable.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Unless notice by publication is insufficient in law, a notice that sets a date for a hearing or meeting or for the termination of the opportunity to be heard and that is submitted as required by this subsection constitutes, on publication, notice to:<section prefix="(i)">each person who resides in the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">each person who holds an interest in property in the State.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Publication of a notice as required by this subtitle and as required by any other provision of the Code are both necessary to constitute full compliance with law.</section>
  </text>
</law>
