<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-10-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Administrator" means the Administrator of the Division of State Documents.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Committee" means the Joint Committee on Administrative, Executive, and Legislative Review.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Local government unit" means:<section prefix="(1)">a county;</section><section prefix="(2)">a municipal corporation;</section><section prefix="(3)">a special district that is established by State law and that operates within a single county;</section><section prefix="(4)">a special district that is established by a county pursuant to public general law; or</section><section prefix="(5)">an office, board, or department that is established in each county under State law and that is funded, pursuant to State law, at least in part by the county governing body.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Mandate" means a directive in a regulation that requires a local government unit to perform a task or assume a responsibility that has a discernible fiscal impact on the local government unit.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Register" means the Maryland Register.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Regulation" means a statement or an amendment or repeal of a statement that:<section prefix="(i)">has general application;</section><section prefix="(ii)">has future effect;</section><section prefix="(iii)">is adopted by a unit to:</section><section prefix="(iv)">is in any form, including:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Regulation" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">a statement that:</section><section prefix="(ii)">a response of the unit to a petition for adoption of a regulation, under &#xA7; 10-123 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a declaratory ruling of the unit as to a regulation, order, or statute, under Subtitle 3 of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Regulation", as used in &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-110 and 10-111.1 of this subtitle, means all or any portion of a regulation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Substantively" means in a manner substantially affecting the rights, duties, or obligations of:<section prefix="(1)">a member of a regulated group or profession; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a member of the public.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Unit" means an officer or unit authorized by law to adopt regulations.</section>
  </text>
</law>
