<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-908</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>908</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "veterans' memorials and monuments" means:<section prefix="(1)">the Maryland Vietnam Veterans Memorial and Associated Land as established pursuant to Joint Resolution No. 22 of 1983;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Maryland Korean War Memorial and Associated Land as established pursuant to Joint Resolution No. 3 of 1985; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the Maryland World War II Memorial and Associated Land.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Veterans' Memorials and Monuments Program administered by the Department of Veterans Affairs.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The purpose of the Program is to provide for the operation, maintenance, security, and preservation of veterans' memorials and monuments.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In furtherance of these purposes, the Department may, as provided for in the budget:<section prefix="(1)">lease land on behalf of the State or a political subdivision of the State; or</section><section prefix="(2)">acquire land that has been improved by construction of a memorial or monument.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Secretary may adopt regulations to carry out the provisions of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall, as provided for in the budget, provide for the management of the veterans' memorials and monuments as provided in this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department may delegate any of its powers and duties under this section to a special commission or board created by the Department and approved by the Governor.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Department may acquire, hold, use, and improve property for the purposes specified in subsection (c) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Subject to Title 7 of the State Finance and Procurement Article, the Department may:<section prefix="(1)">accept gifts or grants;</section><section prefix="(2)">unless otherwise provided, spend the principal and income of a gift or grant; and</section><section prefix="(3)">invest all or part of the principal income in general obligations of the State or any other security.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
