<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-20A-06</section_number>
  <catch_line>Loans from the Fund may be used for:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>06</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Loans from the Fund may be used for:<section prefix="(1)">the costs of implementing projects, including the costs of all necessary:<section prefix="(i)">technical assessments;</section><section prefix="(ii)">studies;</section><section prefix="(iii)">surveys;</section><section prefix="(iv)">plans and specifications; and</section><section prefix="(v)">start-up, architectural, engineering, or other special services;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the costs of procuring necessary technology, equipment, licenses, or materials; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the costs of construction, rehabilitation, or modification, including the purchase and installation of any necessary machinery, equipment, or furnishings.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each borrower shall make a contribution to a project that is of a type and amount acceptable to the Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the sole or primary purpose of the project is to reduce energy consumption, the borrower must document that the anticipated energy cost savings over a defined period after the completion of the project are greater than the cost of the project.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Loans made under the Program shall:<section prefix="(1)">be repayable by the borrower from specified revenues that may include the energy cost savings generated by a project;</section><section prefix="(2)">bear interest at a rate that the Administration determines to be necessary and reasonable for the project; and</section><section prefix="(3)">be repayable in accordance with a schedule that the Administration sets, which may be on a deferred payment basis.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A borrower shall provide assurances for the repayment of a loan.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The assurances:<section prefix="(i)">shall include a promissory note; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">may include superior or subordinate mortgage liens, guarantees of repayment, or other forms of collateral.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Loans may be made in conjunction with, or in addition to, financial assistance provided through other State or federal programs.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A loan under the Fund may be deposited into a revolving loan fund of a county's economic development commission if the county approves the transaction and project for the local jurisdiction.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a county accepts a loan under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the funds deposited from the Fund may be used only for purposes of providing capital for renewable energy infrastructure projects under this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
