<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-301" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-8-301</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Governor is responsible for a continuing review of the organization of the Executive Branch of the State government.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to any reorganization under Article II, &#xA7; 24 of the Maryland Constitution, the Governor may order any other reorganization of the Executive Branch that is considered by the Governor to be necessary and desirable and that is not inconsistent with law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A reorganization under this subsection may include:<section prefix="(i)">the reorganization of the principal departments;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the placement of a unit in a principal department; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the transfer of a unit or function from 1 principal department to another.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A reorganization under this subsection may be effected through the issuance of an executive order or the approval of a recommendation that the secretary of a principal department submits. An approval shall be treated as an executive order. However, notwithstanding any other provision of law, the recommendation is not effective unless approved or issued as an executive order.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other law that relates to organization of the Executive Branch of the State government, if a program involves more than 1 principal department and cannot be carried out efficiently through cooperation of the departments, the Governor may establish a task force to integrate the services of the departments so as to carry out the program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A task force established under this subsection may exist for not more than 1 year unless the Governor expressly extends the existence of the task force.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Governor shall recommend to the General Assembly the placement of any new program or new unit within an appropriate principal department.</section>
  </text>
</law>
