<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-1243" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-2-1243</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After each regular session, the Department shall compile and index:<section prefix="(i)">the laws that are enacted during that session;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the executive orders that have been adopted pursuant to Article II, &#xA7; 24 of the Maryland Constitution since the last compilation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the certificates of the State Board of Elections as to the referendum vote on a law, if the vote has not been published previously; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the titles of laws and statements of referendum on laws of each municipal corporation, code county, and charter county that have been delivered to the Department as required by law.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After each special session, the Department shall compile and index the laws that are enacted during that session.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After completion of the compilation and index, the Department shall deliver copies of the laws, executive orders adopted pursuant to Article II, &#xA7; 24 of the Maryland Constitution, certificates, and titles to the printer who is designated to print the session laws.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The printer shall print promptly:<section prefix="(i)">the documents delivered under this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">with the compilation for a regular session, the statement of receipts and expenditures of public money delivered under &#xA7; 2-103 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The printer shall deliver the volumes to the Executive Director.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Department shall publish other executive orders delivered to it in accordance with &#xA7; 3-406(b) of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">create and maintain, in the form of a statutory database, a code comprising the public general laws of the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">maintain the structural integrity and textual accuracy of that code.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
