<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-1A-07</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in &#xA7; 9-1A-36 of this subtitle, an applicant for a license shall submit to the Co...</catch_line>
  <order_by>07</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 9-1A-36 of this subtitle, an applicant for a license shall submit to the Commission an application:<section prefix="(1)">in the form that the Commission requires; and</section><section prefix="(2)">on or before the date set by the Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to license fees for a video lottery operation license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall by regulation establish a fee for a license under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An applicant shall submit the fee with the application.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Applicants and licensees shall have the affirmative responsibility to establish by clear and convincing evidence the person's qualifications.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Applicants and licensees shall provide information required by this subtitle and satisfy requests for information relating to qualifications in the form specified by the Commission or the Video Lottery Facility Location Commission, if applicable.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Applicants and licensees shall consent to inspections, searches, and seizures authorized by this subtitle or regulations issued under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Applicants and licensees shall have the continuing duty to:<section prefix="1.">provide assistance or information required by the Commission; and</section><section prefix="2.">cooperate in an inquiry, investigation, or hearing conducted by the Commission.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">On issuance of a formal request to answer or produce information, evidence, or testimony, if an applicant or licensee refuses to comply, the application or license of the person may be denied, suspended, or revoked by the Commission.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the applicant is an individual, the applicant shall be photographed and fingerprinted for identification and investigation purposes.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the applicant is not an individual, the Commission by regulation may establish the categories of individuals who shall be photographed and fingerprinted for identification and investigation purposes.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Applicants and licensees shall have a duty to inform the Commission of an act or omission that the person knows or should know constitutes a violation of this subtitle or the regulations issued under this subtitle.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Applicants and licensees may not discriminate against a person who in good faith informs the Commission of an act or omission that the person believes constitutes a violation of this subtitle or the regulations issued under this subtitle.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Applicants and licensees shall produce information, documentation, and assurances to establish the following qualification criteria by clear and convincing evidence:<section prefix="(i)">the financial stability, integrity, and responsibility of the applicant or licensee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the integrity of any financial backers, investors, mortgagees, bondholders, and holders of other evidences of indebtedness that bear a relation to the application;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the applicant's or licensee's good character, honesty, and integrity;</section><section prefix="(iv)">sufficient business ability and experience of the applicant or licensee; and</section><section prefix="(v)">that:<section prefix="1.">the applicant or licensee has entered into a labor peace agreement with each labor organization that is actively engaged in representing or attempting to represent video lottery and hospitality industry workers in the State;</section><section prefix="2.">the labor peace agreement is valid and enforceable under 29 U.S.C. &#xA7; 158;</section><section prefix="3.">the labor peace agreement protects the State's revenues by prohibiting the labor organization and its members from engaging in picketing, work stoppages, boycotts, and any other economic interference with the operation of the video lottery facility within the first 5 years of the effective date of the video lottery operation license; and</section><section prefix="4.">the labor peace agreement applies to all operations at the video lottery facility that are conducted by a lessee or tenant or under a management agreement.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">On the filing of an application for any license required under this subtitle and any supplemental information required by the Commission, the Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">refer the application to the Department of State Police or an approved vendor under &#xA7; 9-1A-20 of this subtitle to conduct a background investigation on the qualifications of the applicant and any person who is required to be qualified under this subtitle as a condition of a license; and</section><section prefix="(2)">if the applicant is applying for a video lottery operation license, conduct a hearing on the qualifications of the applicant and any person who is required to be qualified under this subtitle as a condition of a license.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for a video lottery operation license, after receiving the results of the background investigation, the Commission may either grant a license to an applicant whom the Commission determines to be qualified or deny the license to an applicant whom the Commission determines to be not qualified or disqualified.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an application for a license is denied, the Commission shall prepare and file an order denying the license with a statement of the reasons for the denial, including the specific findings of fact.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for a video lottery operation license as provided in &#xA7; 9-1A-13 of this subtitle, if satisfied that an applicant is qualified to receive a license, and on tender of all required application, license, and other fees and taxes, and any bond required under &#xA7; 9-1A-04(e) of this subtitle, the Commission shall issue a license for a term of 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission may stagger the terms of licenses.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual may not knowingly give false information or make a material misstatement in an application required for any license under this subtitle or in any supplemental information required by the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 3 years or a fine not exceeding $5,000 or both.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
