<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-10-509</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section does not:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>509</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not:<section prefix="(1)">require any change in the form or content of the Journal of the Senate of Maryland or Journal of the House of Delegates of Maryland; or</section><section prefix="(2)">limit the matters that a public body may include in its minutes.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, as soon as practicable after a public body meets, it shall have written minutes of its session prepared.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A public body need not prepare written minutes of an open session:<section prefix="(i)">if live and archived video or audio streaming of the open session is available; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the public body votes on legislation and the individual votes taken by each member of the public body who participates in the voting are posted promptly on the Internet.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The information specified under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be deemed the minutes of the open session.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The written minutes shall reflect:<section prefix="(i)">each item that the public body considered;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the action that the public body took on each item; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">each vote that was recorded.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a public body meets in closed session, the written minutes for its next open session shall include:<section prefix="(i)">a statement of the time, place, and purpose of the closed session;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a record of the vote of each member as to closing the session;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a citation of the authority under this subtitle for closing the session; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">a listing of the topics of discussion, persons present, and each action taken during the session.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A session may be tape recorded by a public body.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Except as otherwise provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, the written minutes and any tape recording of a closed session shall be sealed and may not be open to public inspection.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The written minutes and any tape recording shall be unsealed and open to inspection as follows:<section prefix="(i)">for a meeting closed under &#xA7; 10-508(a)(5) of this subtitle, when the public body invests the funds;</section><section prefix="(ii)">for a meeting closed under &#xA7; 10-508(a)(6) of this subtitle, when the public securities being discussed have been marketed; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">on request of a person or on the public body's own initiative, if a majority of the members of the public body present and voting vote in favor of unsealing the written minutes and any tape recording.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, written minutes of a public body are public records and shall be open to public inspection during ordinary business hours.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A public body shall keep a copy of the written minutes of each session and any tape recording made under subsections (b)(2) or (c)(3)(i) of this section for at least 1 year after the date of the session.</section>
  </text>
</law>
