<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-943</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>943</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For the purposes of reaching any veteran, veteran's dependent, or veteran's survivor in need of assistance in obtaining services or benefits granted by the law, the director shall develop and implement an outreach plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In order to carry out the director's responsibilities under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the director may:<section prefix="(i)">enter into contracts; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">work with governmental units and community-based organizations, including the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene, the Department of Aging, faith-based groups, veterans groups, senior centers, adult day care centers, institutions of higher education, and other entities the director considers appropriate.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The director shall develop mechanisms for outreach to be disseminated by direct mail and through community-based veterans organizations, the Department of Veterans Affairs, the Department of Human Resources, the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene, and any other State agency or unit the director considers appropriate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The mechanisms for outreach shall include:<section prefix="(i)">the development of a pamphlet describing the services provided by the Outreach and Advocacy Program;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a regular newsletter;</section><section prefix="(iii)">brochures describing various benefits or any other issue or benefit of interest to veterans or their dependents; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">other measures the director considers appropriate.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department shall develop and maintain a database of veterans in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department, in conjunction with the types of community-based organizations listed in subsection (a)(2) of this section, shall develop a survey to assist in identifying veterans and dependents who may be eligible for pension programs.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Program shall:<section prefix="(1)">in conjunction with other governmental units and community-based groups, seek out veterans and their dependents who may be eligible for pension program benefits; and</section><section prefix="(2)">provide wounded or disabled veterans with information on available services and benefits and support in obtaining these services and benefits.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
