<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-10A-05" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-2-10A-05</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Committee" means the Joint Committee on Access to Mental Health Services.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Joint Committee on Access to Mental Health Services.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Committee consists of ten members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the ten members:<section prefix="(i)">five shall be Senators, appointed by the President; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">five shall be Delegates, appointed by the Speaker.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Of the five Senators:<section prefix="(i)">two shall be members of the Finance Committee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">one shall be a member of the Budget and Taxation Committee;</section><section prefix="(iii)">one shall be a member of the Education, Health, and Environmental Affairs Committee; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">one shall be a member of the Judicial Proceedings Committee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Of the five Delegates:<section prefix="(i)">two shall be members of the Health and Government Operations Committee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">one shall be a member of the Appropriations Committee;</section><section prefix="(iii)">one shall be a member of the Economic Matters Committee; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">one shall be a member of the Judiciary Committee.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The members of the Committee serve at the pleasure of the presiding officer who appointed them.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">From among the membership of the Committee, the President shall appoint a Senator to serve as the Senate Chair of the Committee, and the Speaker shall appoint a Delegate to serve as the House Chair of the Committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Senate Chair and the House Chair shall alternate annually as presiding chairs and cochairs of the Committee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department of Legislative Services shall provide staff assistance to the Committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Committee shall monitor access to:<section prefix="(1)">public mental health services for eligible individuals; and</section><section prefix="(2)">medically necessary mental health services for individuals covered by private insurance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Committee shall submit an annual report to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of this title, to the General Assembly, regarding:<section prefix="(1)">systemic barriers to access to mental health services; and</section><section prefix="(2)">recommendations to mitigate these barriers.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
