<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-1A-11</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>11</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Any video lottery operation licenses not issued or awarded for a location authorized under this subtitle shall automatically revert to the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, a licensee shall commence operation of video lottery terminals in a permanent facility at the location for which the video lottery operation license has been awarded within 18 months after the license is awarded.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">On a determination by the Commission that extenuating circumstances exist that are beyond the control of an awardee and have prevented the awardee from complying with the requirements of paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Commission may allow the awardee an extension of 6 months to comply with the requirements.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Commission may not grant more than two extensions to an awardee under this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection, the Commission may allow an awardee of a video lottery operation license in Prince George's County to commence operation in a permanent facility more than 18 months, but not more than 30 months, after the license is awarded.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If a video lottery operation awardee fails to comply with the requirements of this subsection, the license awarded to the awardee shall be revoked and shall automatically revert to the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Nothing in this subtitle may be construed to prohibit a video lottery operation licensee that is issued a license from beginning video lottery terminal or table game operations in a temporary facility that meets the minimum requirements established in regulations adopted by the State Lottery and Gaming Control Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (1) of this subsection, a video lottery operation licensee shall be operational in a permanent facility no later than 30 months after the award of the video lottery operation license.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, a video lottery facility in Prince George's County may not begin video lottery terminal or table game operations in a temporary facility or in a structure, including a hotel or conference center, that exists on August 15, 2012.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For a location in Allegany County, if video lottery terminals are permanently located in the Rocky Gap Lodge and Resort, the licensee shall restrict public access to the video lottery facility from the Rocky Gap Lodge and Resort.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraphs (ii) and (iii) of this paragraph, for a location in Allegany County, if video lottery terminals are permanently located in the Rocky Gap Lodge and Resort and existing meeting space is eliminated as a result of the video lottery terminals, the licensee shall provide for meeting space that is accessible from the Rocky Gap Lodge and Resort within 36 months after issuance of the video lottery operation license, subject to the approval of the Video Lottery Facility Location Commission and the State Lottery and Gaming Control Commission.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The licensee shall restrict public access to the video lottery facility from any meeting space provided under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The licensee may not begin table game operations until the licensee submits evidence satisfactory to the State Lottery and Gaming Control Commission that replacement work has begun to provide meeting space equal to or greater than the eliminated meeting space.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
