<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-124" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-124</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not prohibit:<section prefix="(1)">giving a State lottery ticket or share as a gift;</section><section prefix="(2)">buying a State lottery ticket or share as a gift for a minor; or</section><section prefix="(3)">the Agency from directly selling any State lottery ticket to the public as provided in &#xA7; 9-111(d) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, a person or governmental unit may not:<section prefix="(1)">unless a licensed agent or employee of a licensed agent, sell a State lottery ticket or share;</section><section prefix="(2)">sell or purchase:<section prefix="(i)">a State lottery ticket or share at any price other than the price that the regulations of the Agency set; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the prize validated for payment by the Agency;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">sell a State lottery ticket or share to a minor;</section><section prefix="(4)">knowingly present a counterfeit or altered State lottery ticket or share for payment;</section><section prefix="(5)">knowingly transfer a counterfeit or altered State lottery ticket or share to another person to present for payment; or</section><section prefix="(6)">knowingly purchase a State lottery ticket or share from another person with the intent to deceive or circumvent the payment of prize winnings to the State, in accordance with:<section prefix="(i)">&#xA7; 11-616(b) of the Criminal Procedure Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">&#xA7; 10-113.1(a) of the Family Law Article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">&#xA7; 3-307 of the State Finance and Procurement Article; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">&#xA7; 10-905(c)(3) of the Tax - General Article.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensed agent may not fail to report, as required by the Internal Revenue Service or the Agency, income tax information relating to holders of winning lottery tickets.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For prizes of over $600, a licensed agent may not fail to determine, through the Agency and prior to paying the prize whether a holder of a winning lottery ticket has been certified under:<section prefix="(i)">&#xA7; 11-616(b) of the Criminal Procedure Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">&#xA7; 10-113.1(a) of the Family Law Article; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">&#xA7; 3-307 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A licensed agent may not pay a prize to a holder of a winning lottery ticket if the Agency has notified the licensed agent that the holder has been certified under:<section prefix="(i)">&#xA7; 11-616(b) of the Criminal Procedure Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">&#xA7; 10-113.1 of the Family Law Article; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">&#xA7; 3-307 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A licensed agent may not:<section prefix="(i)">pay a prize winner less than the lawfully due prize amount;</section><section prefix="(ii)">deceive or conspire with another person to pay less than the lawfully due prize amount to any prize winner;</section><section prefix="(iii)">seek payment or claim reimbursement of a cashing fee for cashing a winning ticket for less than the lawfully due prize amount; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">receive a cashing fee for cashing a winning ticket filed in error.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person who violates any provision of subsection (b) or (c) of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $2,500 or imprisonment not exceeding 3 years or both.</section>
  </text>
</law>
