<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-111.2" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-10-111.2</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The website of the General Assembly shall include a list of all emergency regulations the Committee has received but has not approved.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For each regulation, the list shall include:<section prefix="(i)">the date the Committee received the regulation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">whether a member of the Committee has requested a public hearing;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the date of any public hearing scheduled;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the date and a summary of any action the Committee has taken; and</section><section prefix="(v)">the name and telephone number of a member of the Committee's staff who can provide further information.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A regulation shall be added to the list within 3 business days after receipt of the regulation by the Committee and the Department of Legislative Services.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department of Legislative Services shall maintain a list of members of the public who have requested to receive notice when the Department of Legislative Services receives proposed regulations for which the promulgating unit has requested emergency adoption.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member of the public who requests notice under this subsection shall specify:<section prefix="(i)">whether the individual wants to receive notice by United States mail or electronic mail; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">which agencies' regulations the individual wants to receive notice of receipt.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Within 2 business days of receipt of a proposed regulation, the Department of Legislative Services shall provide notice to members of the public who have requested notice, as specified in paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Department of Legislative Services:<section prefix="(i)">may impose a reasonable fee for sending notice under this subsection by United States mail; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">may not impose a fee for sending notice under this subsection by electronic mail.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Upon request, a promulgating unit shall provide copies of emergency regulations to members of the public.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
