<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-111" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-111</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Director shall:<section prefix="(1)">supervise and administer the State lottery in accordance with the regulations of the Agency and this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">confer, at least once a month, with the Commission on the operation and administration of the State lottery;</section><section prefix="(3)">make available to the Commission any record or other information of the Agency that the Commission requests;</section><section prefix="(4)">advise the Commission about any change needed to improve the operation or administration of the State lottery;</section><section prefix="(5)">with the approval of the Commission and subject to Division II of the State Finance and Procurement Article, contract for:<section prefix="(i)">the operation of all or any part of the State lottery; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the use of space, for advertising or promotional purposes, on tickets or publications distributed by the Agency, if, in the Director's discretion, the action is fiscally prudent and in the best interest of the State lottery;</section></section><section prefix="(6)">submit monthly to the Comptroller and to the Commission a certified statement of the total State lottery revenues and the total prize disbursements and other expenses for the preceding month; and</section><section prefix="(7)">with the approval of the Commission, contract for the promotion of the State lottery and enter into private sector cooperative marketing project agreements as provided for in &#xA7; 11-203(a)(1)(xiv) of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">With the approval of the Commission and the Legislative Policy Committee, the Director may enter into agreements to operate multijurisdictional lotteries with:<section prefix="(1)">any other political entity outside the State or outside the United States that operates a lottery; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a private licensee of a state or a foreign nation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission may advise the Director on the operation and administration of the State lottery.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In accordance with the regulations of the Agency and this subtitle, the Director may:<section prefix="(1)">arrange for a person to perform any activity, function, or service in connection with the operation of the State lottery which shall constitute a lawful activity, function, or service of the person; and</section><section prefix="(2)">authorize the Agency to sell lottery tickets for a temporary period at any promotional or special event being held in the State if:<section prefix="(i)">in the Director's determination, no licensed agent is available to conduct the sale; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the person holding the promotional or special event has authorized the Agency to sell lottery tickets at the event.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
