<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-10-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Agency" means:<section prefix="(1)">an officer or unit of the State government authorized by law to adjudicate contested cases; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a unit that:<section prefix="(i)">is created by general law;</section><section prefix="(ii)">operates in at least 2 counties; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">is authorized by law to adjudicate contested cases.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Agency head" means:<section prefix="(1)">an individual or group of individuals in whom the ultimate legal authority of an agency is vested by any provision of law; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the secretary of the State department that is responsible for State programs that are administered by the Montgomery County Department of Health and Human Services.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Contested case" means a proceeding before an agency to determine:<section prefix="(i)">a right, duty, statutory entitlement, or privilege of a person that is required by statute or constitution to be determined only after an opportunity for an agency hearing; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the grant, denial, renewal, revocation, suspension, or amendment of a license that is required by statute or constitution to be determined only after an opportunity for an agency hearing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Contested case" does not include a proceeding before an agency involving an agency hearing required only by regulation unless the regulation expressly, or by clear implication, requires the hearing to be held in accordance with this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"License" means all or any part of permission that:<section prefix="(1)">is required by law to be obtained from an agency;</section><section prefix="(2)">is not required only for revenue purposes; and</section><section prefix="(3)">is in any form, including:<section prefix="(i)">an approval;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a certificate;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a charter;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a permit; or</section><section prefix="(v)">a registration.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Office" means the Office of Administrative Hearings.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Presiding officer" means the board, commission, agency head, administrative law judge, or other authorized person conducting an administrative proceeding under this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
