<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="20-1021" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-20-1021</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An aggrieved person may file a complaint with the Commission alleging a discriminatory housing practice.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The complaint shall be filed within 1 year after the alleged discriminatory housing practice occurred or terminated.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission may:<section prefix="(1)">file a complaint on the Commission's own initiative; and</section><section prefix="(2)">investigate housing practices to determine whether a complaint should be filed under this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A complaint shall:<section prefix="(1)">be in writing;</section><section prefix="(2)">be in the form that the Commission requires; and</section><section prefix="(3)">contain the information that the Commission requires.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">After a complaint is filed, the Commission shall serve notice on the aggrieved person acknowledging the filing and advising the aggrieved person of the time limits and choice of forums provided under this part.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Within 10 days after a complaint is filed or an additional respondent is identified under &#xA7; 20-1022(b) of this subtitle, the Commission shall serve on the respondent:<section prefix="(1)">a copy of the original complaint; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a notice identifying the alleged discriminatory housing practice and advising the respondent of the procedural rights and obligations of respondents under this part.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each respondent may file an answer to the complaint.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The answer shall be filed within 10 days after receipt of the copy of the complaint and notice from the Commission under subsection (e) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Complaints and answers:<section prefix="(1)">shall be under oath; and</section><section prefix="(2)">may be reasonably amended at any time.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
