<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-912" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-912</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To carry out the responsibilities and goals of the Department, the Department may acquire, hold, use, improve, and convey property.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to any other power under this section and subject to Title 7 of the State Finance and Procurement Article, to carry out the purposes or goals of the Department, the Department may:<section prefix="(1)">accept a gift or grant; and</section><section prefix="(2)">unless the terms of a gift or grant require otherwise, and subject to the approval of the Secretary:<section prefix="(i)">spend the principal and income of the gift or grant through grants or loans to:</section><section prefix="(ii)">invest all or part of the principal and income in:</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Gifts and grants that the Department accepts under subsection (b) of this section shall be deposited in the Maryland Veterans Trust Fund under &#xA7; 9-913 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary shall adopt regulations to implement a program for gifts and grants made under subsection (b)(2) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to any other power under this section, the Department may lease any part of the home property for use as a concession or other commercial purpose that is consistent with the purposes of the Department. However, the Department may not lease its property merely for investment purposes.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding any other law, unless the lease expressly provides for redemption by the tenant, the lease is not subject to redemption.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
