<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-19-109</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>109</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">No authentication is necessary if the acknowledgment is:<section prefix="(1)">taken within the State; or</section><section prefix="(2)">made outside the United States by an officer of the United States.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">No authentication is necessary if the acknowledgment is taken outside of the State, but within another state.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The certificate may, however, be authenticated by a certificate as to the official character of the officer that took the acknowledgment.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the officer that took the acknowledgment is a clerk or deputy clerk of a court, the authenticating certificate shall be executed by the presiding judge of the court.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If the officer that took the acknowledgment is a notary public, the authenticating certificate shall be executed by a clerk of a court of record of the county, parish, or district in which the acknowledgment is taken.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">When the authenticating certificate bears the seal of the authenticating officer, the signature on the certificate may be a facsimile that is printed, stamped, photographed, or engraved on the certificate.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the acknowledgment is made outside the United States and by a notary public or a judge or clerk of a court of record of the country where the acknowledgment is made, the certificate shall be authenticated by:<section prefix="(1)">a certificate under the great seal of state of the country, affixed by the custodian of the seal, certifying as to the official character of the officer; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a certificate of a diplomatic, consular, or commercial officer of the United States accredited to that country, certifying as to the official character of the officer.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
