<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-2-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">All full-time permanent employees of the General Assembly of Maryland and the Department of Legislative Services shall be considered as full-time permanent State employees for the purposes of transferring to a position in the Executive or Judicial Branch of State government.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">These employees shall receive credit for service with the General Assembly for the purposes of transferring accumulated sick and vacation leave, service credit in the Employees' Retirement System, and all other benefits.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">These employees shall be granted the same salary consideration that would be provided to an employee transferring within the Executive or Judicial Branch.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On the transfer of a General Assembly employee or an employee of the Department of Legislative Services to a position in the Executive Branch, the Secretary of Budget and Management may request that the President of the Senate or the Speaker of the House of Delegates or their representative certify as to the full-time permanent status of that employee. The certification shall be satisfactory evidence for the purposes of subsection (a) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If any employee of the General Assembly transferred to a position in the Executive or Judicial Branch on or after July 1, 1977, and suffered any loss of compensation or benefits solely as a result of the employee's prior service with the General Assembly not being recognized as full-time permanent service, the employee's compensation and benefits shall be reinstated at the appropriate level and the employee shall be reimbursed for any loss in salary from the effective date of the transfer.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Any full-time permanent employee of the General Assembly of Maryland or the Department of Legislative Services who separates from State service and returns to State service in the Executive or Judicial Branch within 3 years from the time of separation from active duty shall be eligible for reinstatement and shall receive full credit for any prior State service.</section>
  </text>
</law>
