<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-10-220</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>220</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If the Office conducts a hearing under this subtitle, the Office shall prepare proposed findings of fact, conclusions of law, or orders in accordance with the agency's delegation under &#xA7; 10-205 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Office shall send its proposed findings, conclusions, or orders:<section prefix="(1)">to the parties and the agency directly; or</section><section prefix="(2)">if the agency's delegation under &#xA7; 10-205 of this subtitle requires, to the agency for distribution by the agency to the parties.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 60 days after receipt of the Office's proposed findings, conclusions, or order under subsection (b)(2) of this section, the agency shall:<section prefix="(i)">review the Office's proposed findings, conclusions, or order;</section><section prefix="(ii)">issue the proposed decision, which may include the Office's proposed findings, conclusions, or order with or without modification; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">send the proposed decision and a copy of the Office's proposed findings, conclusions, or order to the parties.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The time limit specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection may be extended by the agency head, board, or commission with written notice to the parties.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A proposed decision or order, including proposed decisions or orders issued for contested case hearings subject to this subtitle but not conducted by the Office, shall:<section prefix="(1)">be in writing or stated on the record;</section><section prefix="(2)">contain separate findings of fact and conclusions of law;</section><section prefix="(3)">include an explanation of procedures and time limits for filing exceptions; and</section><section prefix="(4)">if the Office conducted the hearing and the agency's proposed decision includes any changes, modifications, or amendments to the Office's proposed findings, conclusions, or orders, contain an explanation of the reasons for each change, modification, or amendment.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
