<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-15-513</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in paragraph (2) or (3) of this subsection, a member of the General Assembly, a f...</catch_line>
  <order_by>513</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) or (3) of this subsection, a member of the General Assembly, a filed candidate for election to the General Assembly, or a member-elect of the General Assembly may not receive earned income from:<section prefix="(i)">an Executive unit; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a political subdivision of the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Joint Ethics Committee may exempt an individual from the provisions of paragraph (1) of this subsection if the earned income is for:<section prefix="(i)">educational instruction provided by the member, candidate, or member-elect;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a position that is subject to a merit system hiring process;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a human services position; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">a career promotion, change, or progression that is a logical transition from a pre-existing relationship as described in paragraph (3)(ii) of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This subsection does not apply to compensation to a member, candidate, or member-elect pursuant to:<section prefix="(i)">employment as a nonelected law enforcement officer or a fire or rescue squad worker; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a transaction or relationship that existed prior to:<section prefix="1.">the filing of a certificate of candidacy for election to the General Assembly at a time when the individual was not an incumbent member of the General Assembly; or</section><section prefix="2.">in the case of a member who was appointed to fill a vacancy, the date of the appointment.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A legislator shall report the following information in writing to the Joint Ethics Committee at the times and in the manner required by the Joint Ethics Committee:<section prefix="(i)">subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, if representing a person for compensation before a State or local government agency, except in a judicial proceeding or in a quasi-judicial proceeding, the name of the person represented, the services performed, and the consideration. The Joint Ethics Committee may adopt procedures to keep confidential the name of the person represented if that information is privileged or confidential pursuant to any provision of law governing proceedings before that State agency.</section><section prefix="(ii)">if representing a State or local government agency for compensation, the name of the agency, the services performed, and the consideration.</section><section prefix="(iii)">the name of any business enterprise subject to regulation by a State agency in which the legislator and a member of the legislator's immediate family (spouse and children living with the legislator), together or separately, have:<section prefix="1.">the lesser of:</section><section prefix="2.">any interest in a partnership, limited liability partnership, or limited liability company.</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">details of any contractual relationship with the State or a State agency, or a local government in the State, including the subject matter and the consideration.</section><section prefix="(v)">details of any transaction with the State, or a local government in the State, involving a monetary consideration.</section><section prefix="(vi)">any primary employment or business interest and the employer of the legislator or the spouse of the legislator, except for employment as a legislator.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A legislator, on the written advice of the Counsel to the Joint Ethics Committee, is not required to report any information under this paragraph if reporting the information would violate standards of client confidentiality or professional conduct.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">All reports filed under this section shall be:<section prefix="(1)">filed electronically on a form required by the Joint Ethics Committee; and</section><section prefix="(2)">maintained as a matter of public record as required in subsection (d) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department of Legislative Services shall:<section prefix="(i)">compile the reports filed under this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">make the reports available for public inspection as provided in the Public Information Act; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">as to reports filed on or after January 1, 2013, and except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, make the reports freely available to the public on the Internet through an online registration program.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department of Legislative Services may not post on the Internet information related to consideration received that is reported under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
