<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-1A-02</section_number>
  <catch_line>This subtitle is statewide and exclusive in its effect....</catch_line>
  <order_by>02</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This subtitle is statewide and exclusive in its effect.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall regulate the operation of video lottery terminals in accordance with this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Maryland State Lottery Agency shall provide assistance to the Commission in the performance of the Commission's duties under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission shall regulate the operation of table games in accordance with this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subtitle authorizes the operation of video lottery terminals that are connected to a central monitor and control system owned or leased by the State that allows the Commission to monitor a video lottery terminal.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall provide and operate a single central monitor and control system into which all licensed video lottery terminals must be connected.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The central monitor and control system shall be capable of:<section prefix="(i)">continuously monitoring, retrieving, and auditing the operations, financial data, and program information of all video lottery terminals;</section><section prefix="(ii)">allowing the Commission to account for all money inserted in and payouts made from any video lottery terminal;</section><section prefix="(iii)">disabling from operation or play any video lottery terminal as the Commission deems necessary to carry out the provisions of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(iv)">supporting and monitoring a progressive jackpot system capable of operating one or more progressive jackpots; and</section><section prefix="(v)">providing any other function that the Commission considers necessary.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The central monitor and control system shall employ a widely accepted gaming industry communications protocol to facilitate the ability of video lottery terminal manufacturers to communicate with the statewide system.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the Commission may not allow a video lottery operation licensee to have access to, or obtain information from, the central monitor and control system.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Only if the access does not in any way affect the integrity or security of the central monitor and control system, may the Commission allow a video lottery operation licensee to have access to the central monitor and control system that allows the licensee to obtain information pertinent to the legitimate operation of a video lottery facility.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Only a person with a video lottery operation license issued under this subtitle may offer a video lottery terminal and table games for public use in the State under this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
