<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-1A-27" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-1A-27</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c) of this section and &#xA7; 9-1A-26(a)(3) of this subtitle, on a properly approved transmittal prepared by the Commission, the Comptroller shall pay the following amounts from the proceeds of video lottery terminals at each video lottery facility:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">on or before March 31, 2015, 2% to the State Lottery and Gaming Control Agency for costs as defined in &#xA7; 9-1A-01 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">beginning April 1, 2015, 1% to the State Lottery and Gaming Control Agency for costs as defined in &#xA7; 9-1A-01 of this subtitle;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">to the video lottery operation licensee, the percentage stated in the accepted application for the location, not to exceed, except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, 33%;</section><section prefix="(3)">5.5% in local impact grants, in accordance with &#xA7; 9-1A-31 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(4)">6% to the Purse Dedication Account established under &#xA7; 9-1A-28 of this subtitle, not to exceed a total of $100,000,000 to the Account annually;</section><section prefix="(5)"><section prefix="(i)">until the issuance of a video lottery operation license in Baltimore City, 1.75% to the Racetrack Facility Renewal Account established under &#xA7; 9-1A-29 of this subtitle and distributed in accordance with that section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">on or after the issuance of a video lottery operation license in Baltimore City, 1% to the Racetrack Facility Renewal Account established under &#xA7; 9-1A-29 of this subtitle and distributed in accordance with that section, not to exceed a total of $20,000,000 to the Account annually;</section></section><section prefix="(6)">1.5% to the Small, Minority, and Women-Owned Businesses Account established under &#xA7; 9-1A-35 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(7)"><section prefix="(i)">except as provided in item (ii) of this item, 6% to the video lottery operation licensee if the video lottery operation licensee owns or leases each video lottery terminal device and the associated equipment and software; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">8% to the video lottery operation licensee in Anne Arundel County;</section></section><section prefix="(8)">beginning after the issuance of a video lottery operation license for a video lottery facility in Prince George's County, 8% to the video lottery operation licensee in Anne Arundel County and 7% to the licensee in Baltimore City for:<section prefix="(i)">marketing, advertising, and promotional costs required under &#xA7; 9-1A-23 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">capital improvements at the video lottery facilities; and</section></section><section prefix="(9)">the remainder to the Education Trust Fund established under &#xA7; 9-1A-30 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Beginning July 1, 2013, for a video lottery facility in Worcester County with less than 1,000 video lottery terminals, the percentage in subsection (a)(2) of this section is equal to 43% provided that each year an amount equivalent to 2.5% of the proceeds from video lottery terminals at the video lottery facility is spent on capital improvements at the video lottery facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">After 1 year of operations at a video lottery facility in Allegany County, the percentage in subsection (c)(1)(ii) of this section is equal to 50%, provided that each year an amount equivalent to 0.5% of the proceeds from video lottery terminals at the video lottery facility is spent on capital improvements at the video lottery facility; or</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">after the first 10 years of operations at a video lottery facility in Allegany County, the percentage:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For a video lottery facility in Prince George's County, the percentage in subsection (a)(2) of this section stated in the accepted application for the location may not exceed 38%.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For the first 10 years of operations at a video lottery facility in Allegany County, on a properly approved transmittal prepared by the Commission, the Comptroller shall pay the following amounts from the proceeds of video lottery terminals at a video lottery facility in Allegany County:<section prefix="(i)">2% to the State Lottery and Gaming Control Agency for costs as defined in &#xA7; 9-1A-01 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">to the video lottery operation licensee, the percentage stated in the accepted application for the location, not to exceed 50%;</section><section prefix="(iii)">2.75% in local impact grants, in accordance with &#xA7; 9-1A-31 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(iv)">2.5% to the Purse Dedication Account established under &#xA7; 9-1A-28 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(v)">0.75% to the Small, Minority, and Women-Owned Businesses Account established under &#xA7; 9-1A-35 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">the remainder to the Education Trust Fund established under &#xA7; 9-1A-30 of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After the first 10 years of operations at a video lottery facility in Allegany County, the proceeds generated at the facility in Allegany County shall be allocated as provided in subsections (a) and (b) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each video lottery operation licensee shall retain 80% of the proceeds of table games at the video lottery facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On a properly approved transmittal prepared by the Commission, the Comptroller shall pay the following amounts from the proceeds of table games at each video lottery facility:<section prefix="(i)">5% to the local jurisdiction in which the video lottery facility is located, provided that:</section><section prefix="(ii)">15% to the Education Trust Fund established under &#xA7; 9-1A-30 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the costs of the State Lottery and Gaming Control Agency are less than the proceeds specified in subsection (a)(1) of this section, any amount not distributed to the State Lottery and Gaming Control Agency shall be paid to the Education Trust Fund established under &#xA7; 9-1A-30 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The costs of the Commission shall be as provided in the State budget.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">On or before December 1, 2019, and every year thereafter, the State Lottery and Gaming Control Commission shall report to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly on the distribution of proceeds of video lottery terminals to licensees for the procurement of video lottery terminals; marketing, advertising, and promotional costs; and capital improvements and the distributions of local impact grants to jurisdictions under &#xA7; 9-1A-31 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Baltimore City shall report to the Baltimore City Senate and House Delegations by December 31 of each year as to the distribution and use of the funds provided under subsection (d) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
