<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-20-1031</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1031</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may file a petition for the enforcement of an order of the Commission and for appropriate temporary relief or a restraining order.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The petition shall be filed in the circuit court for the county where the discriminatory housing practice is alleged to have occurred or where any respondent resides or transacts business.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The clerk of the court shall send a copy of the petition to the parties to the proceedings before the Commission under &#xA7; 20-1029 of this subtitle or before the administrative law judge.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Any party to the proceedings before the Commission under &#xA7; 20-1029 of this subtitle or before the administrative law judge may intervene in the circuit court in an enforcement proceeding brought under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Unless the failure or neglect to make the objection is excused because of extraordinary circumstances, an objection not made before the Commission under &#xA7; 20-1029 of this subtitle or before the administrative law judge may not be considered by the court in an enforcement proceeding brought under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a petition for judicial review is not filed under &#xA7; 20-1030 of this subtitle, the findings of fact and conclusions of law in the Commission's final order shall be conclusive in connection with any petition for enforcement filed by the Commission under subsection (a) of this section after the 45th day after the order is entered.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a petition for judicial review has not been filed under &#xA7; 20-1030 of this subtitle within 60 days after the date the Commission's final order is entered, and the Commission has not sought enforcement of the order under subsection (a) of this section, any person entitled to relief under the order may petition for enforcement of the order in the circuit court for the county in which the discriminatory housing practice is alleged to have occurred.</section>
  </text>
</law>
