<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-2-201</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The State of Maryland is divided into 47 districts for the election of members of the General Assembly of Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each legislative district shall elect 1 Senator and 3 Delegates.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each legislative district may be subdivided into 3 single member delegate districts or into 1 single member delegate district and 1 multimember delegate district.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In any legislative district which contains more than 2 counties:<section prefix="(1)">where Delegates are to be elected at large by the voters of the entire district, a county, or part of a county, may not have more than 1 Delegate residing in that district; and</section><section prefix="(2)">where Delegates are to be elected by the voters of a multimember subdistrict which contains more than 2 counties or parts of more than 2 counties, a county or a part of a county may not have more than 1 Delegate residing in that subdistrict.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The descriptions of legislative districts in this subtitle, including all references to:<section prefix="(i)">election districts and wards are to the geographical boundaries of the election districts and wards as they existed as of April 1, 2010; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">precincts are to the geographical boundaries of the precincts as reviewed and certified by the local board of supervisors of elections or their designees, before they were reported to the U.S. Bureau of the Census as part of the 2010 Census Redistricting Data Program and as those precinct lines are specifically indicated in the P.L. 94-171 data or shown on the P.L. 94-171 census block maps provided by the U.S. Bureau of the Census and as reviewed and corrected by the Maryland Department of Planning.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Where precincts are split between legislative districts, census tract and block numbers, as indicated in the P.L. 94-171 data or shown on the P.L. 94-171 census block maps provided by the U.S. Bureau of the Census and referred to in &#xA7; 2-202 of this subtitle, are used to define the boundaries of legislative districts.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">For purposes of elections, the provisions of this subtitle shall be applicable to elections for members of the General Assembly beginning with the primary and general elections of 2014 and, for purposes of representation, shall be applicable beginning with the second Wednesday of January 2015.</section>
  </text>
</law>
