<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-112" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-112</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "veterans' organization" means an organization that is tax exempt and organized as a veterans' organization under &#xA7; 501(c)(19) or &#xA7; 501(c)(4) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, in accordance with the regulations of the Agency and this subtitle, the Director shall issue licenses to the persons and governmental units that will best serve the public convenience and promote the sale of State lottery tickets or shares.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before issuing a license to an applicant, the Director shall consider such factors as:<section prefix="(1)">the financial responsibility and security of the applicant and the business or activity of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(2)">the accessibility of the place of business or activity to the public;</section><section prefix="(3)">the sufficiency of existing licenses to serve the public convenience; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the volume of expected sales.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply in:<section prefix="(i)">Caroline County;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Cecil County;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Dorchester County;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Kent County;</section><section prefix="(v)">Montgomery County;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Queen Anne's County;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Somerset County;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Talbot County;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Wicomico County; and</section><section prefix="(x)">Worcester County.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the Director may issue a license under this subtitle for not more than five instant ticket lottery machines to an applicant that is a veterans' organization.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A veterans' organization that is issued a license under this subsection shall locate and operate its instant ticket lottery machines at its principal meeting hall in the county in which the veterans' organization is located.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">After deduction of any commission and validation prize payout as provided under &#xA7; 9-117 of this subtitle, a veterans' organization issued a license under this subsection shall credit the remaining receipts from the sale of tickets from instant ticket lottery machines to the State Lottery Fund established under &#xA7; 9-118 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, a veterans' organization issued a license under this subsection shall purchase or lease from the Agency the instant ticket lottery machines to be used by the veterans' organization.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An organization may not use receipts from the sale of tickets from instant ticket lottery machines that would otherwise be credited to the State Lottery Fund for the costs of purchasing or leasing instant ticket lottery machines.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Director may adopt regulations to implement the provisions of this subsection that included restricting the location of instant ticket lottery machines in areas of a veterans' organization's public meeting hall that is accessible to the public.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The State Lottery and Gaming Control Agency shall ensure that the conduct of the gaming and the operation of the instant ticket lottery machines as established under this subsection are consistent with the holding in the case of Chesapeake Amusements Inc. v. Riddle, 363 Md. 16 (2001).</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Director may not issue a license to:<section prefix="(1)">a person or governmental unit to engage in business primarily as a licensed agent; or</section><section prefix="(2)">an individual who is under the age of 21 years.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commission may hear and decide an appeal of a denial of a license.</section>
  </text>
</law>
