<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-10-502.4</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>502.4</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board shall receive, review, and resolve complaints from any person alleging a violation of the provisions of this subtitle and issue a written opinion as to whether a violation has occurred.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board shall receive and review any complaint alleging a prospective violation of the provisions of this subtitle as provided under &#xA7; 10-502.6 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board shall study ongoing compliance with the provisions of this subtitle by public bodies and make recommendations to the General Assembly for improvements in this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board, in conjunction with the Office of the Attorney General and other interested organizations or persons, shall develop and conduct educational programs on the requirements of the open meetings law for the staffs and attorneys of:<section prefix="(1)">public bodies;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Maryland Municipal League; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the Maryland Association of Counties.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before October 1 of each year, the Board shall submit an annual report to the Governor and the General Assembly in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The report shall include a description of:<section prefix="(i)">the activities of the Board;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the opinions of the Board in any cases brought before it;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the number and nature of complaints filed with the Board, including a discussion of complaints concerning the reasonableness of the notice provided for meetings; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">any recommendations for improvements to the provisions of this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
