<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-704" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-15-704</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A regulated lobbyist shall file with the Ethics Commission, under oath and for each registration, a separate report concerning the regulated lobbyist's lobbying activities:<section prefix="(i)">by May 31 of each year, to cover the period from November 1 of the previous year through April 30 of the current year; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">by November 30 of each year, to cover the period from May 1 through October 31 of that year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the regulated lobbyist is not an individual, an authorized officer or agent of the regulated lobbyist shall sign the report.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a prorated amount is reported as compensation, it shall be labeled as prorated.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A report required by this section shall include:<section prefix="(1)">a complete, current statement of the information required under &#xA7; 15-703(b) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">total expenditures in connection with influencing executive action or legislative action in each of the following categories:<section prefix="(i)">total individual regulated lobbyist compensation, excluding expenses reported under this paragraph;</section><section prefix="(ii)">office expenses of the regulated lobbyist;</section><section prefix="(iii)">professional and technical research and assistance;</section><section prefix="(iv)">publications that expressly encourage communication with one or more officials or employees;</section><section prefix="(v)">witnesses, including the name of each and the fees and expenses paid to each;</section><section prefix="(vi)">except as otherwise reported under this paragraph, meals and beverages for officials, employees, or members of the immediate families of officials or employees;</section><section prefix="(vii)">except as provided in &#xA7; 15-708(d)(2) of this subtitle, food, beverages, and incidental expenses for officials of the Legislative Branch for meals and receptions to which all members of any legislative unit were invited;</section><section prefix="(viii)">food and beverages for members of the General Assembly at the respective times and geographic locations of meetings of legislative organizations, to which meetings those members' attendance at State expense has been approved by the appropriate presiding officer;</section><section prefix="(ix)">food, lodging, and scheduled entertainment for officials and employees at meetings at which the officials and employees were scheduled speakers or scheduled panel participants;</section><section prefix="(x)">tickets and free admission extended to members of the General Assembly as a courtesy or ceremony to the office to attend charitable, cultural, and political events sponsored or conducted by the reporting entity and to each of which all members of a legislative unit were invited;</section><section prefix="(xi)">other gifts to or for officials, employees, or members of the immediate families of officials or employees; and</section><section prefix="(xii)">other expenses; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">as to expenditures reported in paragraph (2)(vii), (viii), (ix), and (x) of this subsection, the date, location, and total expense of the regulated lobbyist for each meal, reception, event, or meeting.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a report required under this section also shall include the name of each official, employee, or member of the immediate family of an official or employee who has benefited from one or more gifts with a cumulative value of $75 during the reporting period from the regulated lobbyist, regardless of whether the gift:<section prefix="(i)">is attributable to more than one entity; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">was given in connection with lobbying activity.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The following gifts need not be allocated to individual recipients and reported by name:<section prefix="(i)">gifts reported under subsection (b)(2)(vii) and (viii) of this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">gifts reported under subsection (b)(2)(ix) of this section with a value of $200 or less; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">gifts reported under subsection (b)(2)(x) of this section, unless the recipient received from the regulated lobbyist during the reporting period two or more such gifts with a cumulative value of $100 or more.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only to a regulated lobbyist, other than an individual, that is organized and operated for the primary purpose of attempting to influence legislative action or executive action.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to the other reports required under this section, a regulated lobbyist subject to this subsection shall report the name and permanent address of each entity that provided at least 5% of the regulated lobbyist's total receipts during the preceding 12 months.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For the purpose of the reporting and registration requirements of this subtitle, receipts of a regulated lobbyist subject to this subsection include funds spent on the regulated lobbyist's behalf, at its direction, or in its name.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
