<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-222" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-10-222</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, a party who is aggrieved by the final decision in a contested case is entitled to judicial review of the decision as provided in this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An agency, including an agency that has delegated a contested case to the Office, is entitled to judicial review of a decision as provided in this section if the agency was a party before the agency or the Office.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Where the presiding officer has final decision-making authority, a person in a contested case who is aggrieved by an interlocutory order is entitled to judicial review if:<section prefix="(1)">the party would qualify under this section for judicial review of any related final decision;</section><section prefix="(2)">the interlocutory order:<section prefix="(i)">determines rights and liabilities; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">has immediate legal consequences; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">postponement of judicial review would result in irreparable harm.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Unless otherwise required by statute, a petition for judicial review shall be filed with the circuit court for the county where any party resides or has a principal place of business.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The court may permit any other interested person to intervene in a proceeding under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the agency has delegated to the Office the authority to issue the final administrative decision pursuant to &#xA7; 10-205(a)(3) of this subtitle, and there are 2 or more other parties with adverse interests remaining in the case, the agency may decline to participate in the judicial review. An agency that declines to participate shall inform the court in its initial response.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The filing of a petition for judicial review does not automatically stay the enforcement of the final decision.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided by law, the final decision maker may grant or the reviewing court may order a stay of the enforcement of the final decision on terms that the final decision maker or court considers proper.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Judicial review of disputed issues of fact shall be confined to the record for judicial review supplemented by additional evidence taken pursuant to this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court may order the presiding officer to take additional evidence on terms that the court considers proper if:<section prefix="(i)">before the hearing date in court, a party applies for leave to offer additional evidence; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the court is satisfied that:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On the basis of the additional evidence, the final decision maker may modify the findings and decision.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The final decision maker shall file with the reviewing court, as part of the record:<section prefix="(i)">the additional evidence; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any modifications of the findings or decision.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The court shall conduct a proceeding under this section without a jury.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A party may offer testimony on alleged irregularities in procedure before the presiding officer that do not appear on the record.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On request, the court shall:<section prefix="(i)">hear oral argument; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">receive written briefs.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">In a proceeding under this section, the court may:<section prefix="(1)">remand the case for further proceedings;</section><section prefix="(2)">affirm the final decision; or</section><section prefix="(3)">reverse or modify the decision if any substantial right of the petitioner may have been prejudiced because a finding, conclusion, or decision:<section prefix="(i)">is unconstitutional;</section><section prefix="(ii)">exceeds the statutory authority or jurisdiction of the final decision maker;</section><section prefix="(iii)">results from an unlawful procedure;</section><section prefix="(iv)">is affected by any other error of law;</section><section prefix="(v)">is unsupported by competent, material, and substantial evidence in light of the entire record as submitted; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">is arbitrary or capricious.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
