<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-15-706</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>706</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section only applies to an individual regulated lobbyist described in &#xA7; 15-701(a)(1), (2), (3), or (4) of this subtitle who lobbies the Executive or Legislative Branch.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section may not be construed to apply to an entity that employs an individual regulated lobbyist who is described in &#xA7; 15-701(a)(1), (2), (3), or (4) of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to any other report required under this subtitle, an individual regulated lobbyist shall file, with the report required by &#xA7; 15-704 of this subtitle, a report that discloses any business transaction or series of business transactions that the individual regulated lobbyist had with an individual or business entity listed in subsection (c) of this section that:<section prefix="(1)">involved the exchange of value of $1,000 or more for a single transaction or involved the exchange of value of $5,000 or more for a series of transactions; and</section><section prefix="(2)">occurred in the previous 6 months.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An individual regulated lobbyist is subject to the reporting requirements of this subtitle if the individual regulated lobbyist engages in a business transaction with:<section prefix="(1)">a member of the General Assembly;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Governor;</section><section prefix="(3)">the Lieutenant Governor;</section><section prefix="(4)">the Attorney General;</section><section prefix="(5)">the Secretary of State;</section><section prefix="(6)">the Comptroller of the Treasury;</section><section prefix="(7)">the State Treasurer;</section><section prefix="(8)">the Secretary of any principal State department;</section><section prefix="(9)">the spouse of an individual listed in items (1) through (8) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(10)">a business entity in which an individual listed in items (1) through (9) of this subsection participates as a proprietor or partner; or</section><section prefix="(11)">a business entity where an individual listed in items (1) through (9) of this subsection has an ownership interest of at least 30% in the entity.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The disclosure required under this subsection shall include:<section prefix="(1)">the date of the business transaction or dates of each of the series of transactions;</section><section prefix="(2)">the name and title of the official listed in subsection (b) of this section who was involved in each business transaction or series of transactions; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the nature and value of anything exchanged.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
