<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-20-1010</section_number>
  <catch_line>In the administration and enforcement of this title, the Commission may:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1010</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In the administration and enforcement of this title, the Commission may:<section prefix="(1)">administer oaths;</section><section prefix="(2)">issue subpoenas;</section><section prefix="(3)">compel the attendance and testimony of witnesses; and</section><section prefix="(4)">compel the production of books, papers, records, and documents relevant or necessary for proceedings under this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A subpoena issued by the Commission shall be served by:<section prefix="(1)">certified mail, requesting restricted delivery - show to whom, date, address of delivery; or</section><section prefix="(2)">personal service of process by:<section prefix="(i)">an employee of the Commission;</section><section prefix="(ii)">any adult who is not a party to the proceeding; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the sheriff or deputy sheriff of the county in which is located the residence or main office of the person to whom or which the subpoena is issued.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In case of failure to comply with a subpoena, the Commission may apply to a circuit court in any county for an order requiring the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of books, papers, records, and documents.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court may issue an order requiring the attendance and testimony of the witness and the production of the books, papers, records, and documents:<section prefix="(i)">after notice to the person subpoenaed as a witness or directed to produce books, papers, records, and documents; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">on a finding that the attendance and testimony of the witness or the production of the books, papers, records, and documents is relevant or necessary for the proceedings of the Commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An order issued by the court under this subsection shall be served on the person to whom it is directed by the sheriff or deputy sheriff of the county where the residence or main office of the person is located.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A failure to obey an order issued by the court under this subsection may be punished by the court as a contempt of court.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
