<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-205" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-3-205</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary of Budget and Management shall provide to a Governor-elect:<section prefix="(1)">the information requested by the Governor-elect that is the basis for the proposed budget to be submitted by the Governor-elect for the next fiscal year; and</section><section prefix="(2)">after completion of the proposed budget:<section prefix="(i)">a copy of the proposed budget; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">all facilities that the Governor-elect reasonably needs to become familiar with the proposed budget.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After the Governor-elect reviews the proposed budget, the Governor-elect may prepare proposed additions and other changes.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary of Budget and Management shall:<section prefix="(i)">on request of the Governor-elect, help prepare the proposed changes;</section><section prefix="(ii)">have printed as many copies of the proposed changes as the Governor-elect requests;</section><section prefix="(iii)">on or before the 1st day of the regular session of the General Assembly, compile a summary of the proposed changes; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">on request of the Governor-elect, distribute the copies of the proposed changes to the appropriate agencies and officials.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Immediately following the meeting of the Board of State Canvassers, the Governor-elect may call upon any unit of the Executive Branch to assist in developing the Governor-elect's budget for the next ensuing fiscal year.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The initial preparation of the budget shall be at the direction of the incumbent Governor. The preparation of the final budget shall be at the direction of the Governor-elect who shall submit it to the General Assembly as provided by Article III, &#xA7; 52 of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Governor whose term is ending may not submit a proposed budget to the General Assembly.</section>
  </text>
</law>
