<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-708" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-15-708</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A regulated lobbyist who invites all members of a legislative unit to a meal or reception shall, at least 5 days before the date of the meal or reception:<section prefix="(1)">extend a written invitation to all members of the legislative unit; and</section><section prefix="(2)">register the meal or reception with the Department of Legislative Services on a form prescribed by the Ethics Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A legislative unit registration report required under subsection (a) of this section shall contain the following information:<section prefix="(1)">the date and location of the meal or reception; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the legislative unit invited.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Based on information contained in a legislative unit registration report filed under subsection (a) of this section, the Department of Legislative Services shall publish once a week a list containing the date and location of each upcoming meal or reception and the identity of the legislative unit invited.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Department of Legislative Services shall allow public inspection of any legislative unit registration report required under this section during regular business hours.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Within 3 business days of receipt of a legislative unit registration report required under this section, the Department of Legislative Services shall forward the original registration report to the State Ethics Commission.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Department of Legislative Services shall maintain a photocopy or electronic copy of each registration report required under this section.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A regulated lobbyist who is required to register under subsection (a) of this section shall report the total cost of the meal or reception, including the identity of any sponsor who contributes to the cost and the amount of the contribution, to the Ethics Commission within 14 days after the date of the meal or reception.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Notwithstanding the provisions of subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, if any information required under subparagraph (i) is not known within 14 days after the date of the meal or reception, the regulated lobbyist shall, as to the information not known, specify the nature and estimate the amount of each item.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If all of the information required by paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection is reported accurately and completely, the regulated lobbyist is not required to report the cost of the meal or reception under &#xA7; 15-704(b)(2)(vii) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The State Ethics Commission shall allow public inspection of any registration report required under this subsection during regular business hours.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
