<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-1007</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1007</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to any powers set forth elsewhere, the State Archivist may:<section prefix="(1)">adopt regulations to:<section prefix="(i)">govern the Archives;</section><section prefix="(ii)">manage the Hall of Records Building and other real and personal property that the Archives acquires;</section><section prefix="(iii)">manage the records under the supervision of the Archives; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">define the categories of records in the report of the Records Management Division under &#xA7; 10-634 of this article;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">have a seal; and</section><section prefix="(3)">on request, or at the State Archivist's discretion, review, evaluate, and make recommendations to the General Assembly regarding State designations under Title 13 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">At the request of the President of the Senate, the Speaker of the House, the Chair of the Senate Education, Health, and Environmental Affairs Committee, or the Chair of the House Health and Government Operations Committee, the State Archivist shall review, evaluate, and make recommendations to the General Assembly regarding State designations under Title 13 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Archivist may establish reasonable fees for the care and preservation of records and other services provided by the Archives.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Fees may be in the form of:<section prefix="(i)">a percentage not to exceed 2% of an existing fee charged at the time of the creation of a record in any form or format; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a flat rate subscription charge for a publication of the Archives.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Of the fees collected, 7% shall be deposited in the Archives Endowment Account of the State Archives Fund established under &#xA7; 9-1013 of this subtitle as an educational and entrepreneurial reserve.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The State Archivist shall submit to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of this article, to the General Assembly an annual report on the activities of the Archives and the Commission during the preceding fiscal year.</section>
  </text>
</law>
