<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-10A-06" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-2-10A-06</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "conditions of well-being" means the desired results identified by the Maryland Partnership for Children, Youth, and Families based upon identified needs and used to improve quality.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Joint Committee on Children, Youth, and Families.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Committee consists of the following 20 members:<section prefix="(1)">from the Senate:<section prefix="(i)">the majority leader;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the minority leader; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">two members from each of the four standing committees; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">from the House:<section prefix="(i)">the majority leader;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the minority leader; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">eight other Delegates appointed by the Speaker from among the members of the House committees that deal with issues affecting children, youth, and families.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Members of the Committee shall be appointed on the basis of demonstrated ability and interest concerning issues affecting children, youth, and families.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In making appointments, the President and the Speaker shall provide for representation from:<section prefix="(i)">the committees that deal with issues affecting children, youth, and families; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the major areas of the State.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A member appointed by the President serves at the pleasure of the President.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A member appointed by the Speaker serves at the pleasure of the Speaker.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If a vacancy occurs among the Senators on the Committee, a successor promptly shall be appointed by the President.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a vacancy occurs among the Delegates on the Committee, a successor promptly shall be appointed by the Speaker.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">From among the membership of the Committee, the President shall appoint a Senator to serve as the Senate chairman of the Committee and the Speaker shall appoint a Delegate to serve as the House chairman of the Committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Senate chairman and the House chairman shall alternate annually as presiding chairman and cochairman of the Committee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A majority of the full authorized membership of the Committee is a quorum.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Department of Legislative Services, Office of Policy Analysis, shall provide staff assistance to the Committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Committee shall hold:<section prefix="(1)">an organizational meeting promptly after the appointment of its members; and</section><section prefix="(2)">any other meetings that the Committee considers necessary to carry out its duties efficiently.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The Committee may:<section prefix="(1)">hold a hearing on any matter relating to the functions of the Committee; and</section><section prefix="(2)">consider a vote on a bill or resolution referred to it by the President or the Speaker.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">In addition to any powers and duties set forth elsewhere, in an endeavor to achieve conditions of well-being for Maryland children, youth, and families, the Committee shall:<section prefix="(1)">investigate the problems that jeopardize the well-being of Maryland children, youth, and families;</section><section prefix="(2)">identify State policies and actions that, in conjunction with public and private partners and in support of families and communities, can work to achieve conditions of well-being for Maryland children, youth, and families;</section><section prefix="(3)">review and make recommendations to align State statutes, regulations, programs, services, and budgetary priorities with the State policies and actions described in paragraph (2) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(4)">search for any interdepartmental gaps, inconsistencies, and inefficiencies in the implementation or attainment of the State policies and actions described in paragraph (2) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(5)">identify any new laws, regulations, programs, services, and budgetary priorities that are needed to ensure and promote desired conditions of well-being for Maryland children, youth, and families;</section><section prefix="(6)">serve as an informational resource for the Senate and the House on legislative policy matters concerning children, youth, and families; and</section><section prefix="(7)">perform other activities, including improving public awareness of the special needs of Maryland children, youth, and families.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of this title, the Committee shall submit an annual report to the General Assembly on or before December 1 of each year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The report shall include:<section prefix="(i)">a description of the work of the Committee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any recommendations of the Committee.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
