<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-20B-05</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Maryland Strategic Energy Investment Fund....</catch_line>
  <order_by>05</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Maryland Strategic Energy Investment Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The purpose of the Fund is to implement the Strategic Energy Investment Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Administration shall administer the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Treasurer shall hold the Fund separately and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">all of the proceeds from the sale of allowances under &#xA7; 2-1002(g) of the Environment Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">money appropriated in the State budget to the Program;</section><section prefix="(3)">repayments and prepayments of principal and interest on loans made from the Fund;</section><section prefix="(4)">interest and investment earnings on the Fund;</section><section prefix="(5)">compliance fees paid under &#xA7; 7-705 of the Public Utilities Article; and</section><section prefix="(6)">money received from any public or private source for the benefit of the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Administration shall use the Fund:<section prefix="(1)">to invest in the promotion, development, and implementation of:<section prefix="(i)">cost-effective energy efficiency and conservation programs, projects, or activities, including measurement and verification of energy savings;</section><section prefix="(ii)">renewable and clean energy resources;</section><section prefix="(iii)">climate change programs directly related to reducing or mitigating the effects of climate change; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">demand response programs that are designed to promote changes in electric usage by customers in response to:<section prefix="1.">changes in the price of electricity over time; or</section><section prefix="2.">incentives designed to induce lower electricity use at times of high wholesale market prices or when system reliability is jeopardized;</section></section></section><section prefix="(2)">to provide targeted programs, projects, activities, and investments to reduce electricity consumption by customers in the low-income and moderate-income residential sectors;</section><section prefix="(3)">to provide supplemental funds for low-income energy assistance through the Electric Universal Service Program established under &#xA7; 7-512.1 of the Public Utilities Article and other electric assistance programs in the Department of Human Resources;</section><section prefix="(4)">to provide rate relief by offsetting electricity rates of residential customers, including an offset of surcharges imposed on ratepayers under &#xA7; 7-211 of the Public Utilities Article;</section><section prefix="(5)">to provide grants, loans, and other assistance and investment as necessary and appropriate to implement the purposes of the Program as set forth in &#xA7; 9-20B-03 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(6)">to implement energy-related public education and outreach initiatives regarding reducing energy consumption and greenhouse gas emissions; and</section><section prefix="(7)">to pay the expenses of the Program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Except as provided in subsection (g-1) of this section, proceeds received by the Fund from the sale of allowances under &#xA7; 2-1002(g) of the Environment Article shall be allocated to the following accounts:<section prefix="(1)">17% shall be credited to an energy assistance account to be used for the Electric Universal Service Program and other electricity assistance programs in the Department of Human Resources;</section><section prefix="(2)">except as provided in subsection (g-2) of this section, 23% shall be credited to a rate relief account to provide rate relief by offsetting electricity rates of residential customers, including an offset of surcharges imposed on ratepayers under &#xA7; 7-211 of the Public Utilities Article, on a per customer basis and in a manner prescribed by the Public Service Commission;</section><section prefix="(3)">at least 46% shall be credited to a low and moderate income efficiency and conservation programs account and to a general efficiency and conservation programs account for energy efficiency and conservation programs, projects, or activities and demand response programs, of which at least one-half shall be targeted to the low and moderate income efficiency and conservation programs account for:<section prefix="(i)">the low-income residential sector at no cost to the participants of the programs, projects, or activities; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the moderate-income residential sector;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">up to 10.5% shall be credited to a renewable and clean energy programs account for:<section prefix="(i)">subject to subsection (i) of this section, renewable and clean energy programs and initiatives;</section><section prefix="(ii)">energy-related public education and outreach; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">climate change programs; and</section></section><section prefix="(5)">up to 3.5%, but not more than $4,000,000, shall be credited to an administrative expense account for costs related to the administration of the Fund, including the review of electric company plans for achieving electricity savings and demand reductions that the electric companies are required under law to submit to the Administration.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g-1)">The proceeds described in subsection (g) of this section from the allowances sold between March 1, 2009, and June 30, 2012, shall be allocated as follows:<section prefix="(1)">up to 50% shall be credited to an energy assistance account to be used as described in subsection (g)(1) of this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">23% shall be credited to a rate relief account to be allocated as provided in subsection (g)(2) of this section;</section><section prefix="(3)">at least 17.5% shall be credited to a low and moderate income efficiency and conservation programs account and to a general efficiency and conservation programs account to be allocated as provided in subsection (g)(3) of this section;</section><section prefix="(4)">at least 6.5% shall be credited to a renewable and clean energy programs account to be allocated as provided in subsection (g)(4) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(5)">up to 3.0%, but not more than $4,000,000, shall be credited to an administrative expense account to be allocated as provided in subsection (g)(5) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g-2)">Subsection (g)(2) of this section does not apply to residential customers of a small rural electric cooperative, as defined in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Public Utilities Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Energy efficiency and conservation programs under subsection (g)(3) of this section include:<section prefix="(i)">low-income energy efficiency programs;</section><section prefix="(ii)">residential and small business energy efficiency programs;</section><section prefix="(iii)">commercial and industrial energy efficiency programs;</section><section prefix="(iv)">State and local energy efficiency programs;</section><section prefix="(v)">demand response programs;</section><section prefix="(vi)">loan programs and alternative financing mechanisms; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">grants to training funds and other organizations supporting job training for deployment of energy efficiency and energy conservation technology and equipment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Energy-related public education and outreach and renewable and clean energy programs and initiatives under subsection (g)(4)(i) and (ii) of this section include:<section prefix="(i)">production incentives for specified renewable energy sources;</section><section prefix="(ii)">expansion of existing grant programs for solar, geothermal, and wind programs;</section><section prefix="(iii)">loan programs and alternative financing mechanisms; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">consumer education and outreach programs that are designed to reach low-income communities.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, compliance fees paid under &#xA7; 7-705(b) of the Public Utilities Article may be used only to make loans and grants to support the creation of new Tier 1 renewable energy sources in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Compliance fees paid under &#xA7; 7-705(b)(1)(ii) of the Public Utilities Article shall be accounted for separately within the Fund and may be used only to make loans and grants to support the creation of new solar energy sources in the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Treasurer shall invest the money of the Fund in the same manner as other State money may be invested.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any investment earnings of the Fund shall be paid into an administrative expense account within the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any repayment of principal and interest on loans made from the Fund shall be paid into the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Balances in the Fund shall be held for the benefit of the Program, shall be expended solely for the purposes of the Program, and may not be used for the general obligations of government.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">Expenditures from the Fund shall be made by:<section prefix="(1)">an appropriation in the annual State budget; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a budget amendment in accordance with &#xA7; 7-209 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">An expenditure by budget amendment may be made under subsection (k) of this section only after:<section prefix="(1)">the Administration has submitted the proposed budget amendment and supporting documentation to the Senate Budget and Taxation Committee, Senate Finance Committee, House Appropriations Committee, and House Economic Matters Committee; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the committees have had 45 days for review and comment.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
