<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-20A-07</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>07</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Jane E. Lawton Conservation Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Administration shall administer the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Treasurer shall hold the Fund and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">money appropriated in the State budget to the Program;</section><section prefix="(2)">money received from any public or private source;</section><section prefix="(3)">interest and investment earnings on the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(4)">repayments and prepayments of principal and interest on loans made from the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Fund may be used only:<section prefix="(1)">to pay the expenses of the Program; and</section><section prefix="(2)">to provide loans to eligible borrowers and projects.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Treasurer shall invest and reinvest the money of the Fund in the same manner as other State money may be invested.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any investment earnings of the Fund shall be paid into the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any repayment of principal and interest on loans made from the Fund shall be paid into the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration shall annually reserve a portion of the money from the Fund that is available for financial assistance under the Program for loans to nonprofit organizations.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In a fiscal year in which requests for financial assistance from nonprofit organizations are less than the amount of money reserved under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Administration may make the unencumbered or noncommitted portion of the reserve available to other borrowers in the Program.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
