<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-10A-04" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-2-10A-04</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Joint Committee on Welfare Reform.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Committee consists of 10 members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 10 members:<section prefix="(i)">five shall be members of the Senate appointed by the President of the Senate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">five shall be members of the House of Delegates appointed by the Speaker of the House.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The members of the Committee serve at the pleasure of the presiding officer who appointed them.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The President and the Speaker shall jointly appoint a Senator and a Delegate each to serve as cochairman.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Department of Legislative Services shall provide staff assistance to the Committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Committee shall provide oversight of and study, as necessary, issues relating to the provision of FIP and related benefits and services, including:<section prefix="(1)">the provision of food stamps and housing benefits;</section><section prefix="(2)">the provision of medical benefits to the FIP-eligible population;</section><section prefix="(3)">current welfare demonstration projects; and</section><section prefix="(4)">development and implementation of additional welfare demonstration projects.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Secretary of Human Resources, in conjunction with the Secretary of Housing and Community Development and the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene, shall:<section prefix="(1)">cooperate fully with the Committee;</section><section prefix="(2)">keep the Committee fully informed as to the delivery in the State of FIP and related services; and</section><section prefix="(3)">submit an annual report, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of this title, to the Committee on or before October 1 of each year that incorporates the information described in subsection (f) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The report required under subsection (g)(3) of this section shall include:<section prefix="(1)">evaluations of any demonstration projects currently in operation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">descriptions of any plans of the Secretary of Human Resources to establish additional demonstration projects.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Committee shall submit an annual report to the General Assembly on or before January 1 of each year.</section>
  </text>
</law>
