<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9.5-303" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9.5-303</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission consists of nine members appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the nine Commission members:<section prefix="(i)">a majority shall be members of the Indian communities of the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">at least three shall be members of the Indian communities that are indigenous to the State.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each member shall:<section prefix="(1)">have a demonstrable knowledge of Indian culture and history; and</section><section prefix="(2)">be sensitive to the problems of Indian communities.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant for membership on the Commission shall submit under oath a list of the applicant's qualifications, including:<section prefix="(i)">educational history; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">employment background or other relevant experience.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An applicant for membership on the Commission as an Indian member shall submit documentation or proof of Indian status under the sworn and notarized signature of the custodian of records of the membership rolls of that Indian's community.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Governor may require the production of any other documents to prove:<section prefix="(i)">the qualifications of the applicant; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the standing or history of the Indian community to which the applicant claims membership.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member may not serve more than 6 years consecutively.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
