<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-10-135</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>135</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Pursuant to the work plan adopted under &#xA7; 10-134 of this subtitle, each unit shall complete an evaluation report on or before the deadline established by the executive order.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Consistent with the requirements of &#xA7; 10-132(1)(i) of this subtitle, the evaluation report shall contain:<section prefix="(i)">a list of any stakeholders invited to review the regulations and a summary of their participation in and input into the review process;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a list of any affected units invited to review the regulations and a summary of their participation in and input into the review process;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a description of the process used to solicit public comment, including:<section prefix="1.">any notice published in the Maryland Register;</section><section prefix="2.">any notice published in newspapers of general circulation;</section><section prefix="3.">any notice posted on the unit's website or on a statewide website created for units to post notices of regulations review;</section><section prefix="4.">any mailing by the adopting authority; and</section><section prefix="5.">any public hearing held;</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">summaries of:<section prefix="1.">all comments received from stakeholders, affected units, or the public; and</section><section prefix="2.">the adopting authority's responses to those comments;</section></section><section prefix="(v)">a description of any interunit conflict reviewed and the resolution or proposed resolution of that conflict;</section><section prefix="(vi)">a summary of any relevant scientific data gathered;</section><section prefix="(vii)">a summary of any relevant information gathered related to the regulations of other states or the federal government;</section><section prefix="(viii)">a summary of any other relevant information gathered;</section><section prefix="(ix)">a summary of any proposed amendments to the unit's regulations and the reason that the amendments are being proposed;</section><section prefix="(x)">a summary of any proposed repeal of those regulations and the reason that the repeal is being proposed; and</section><section prefix="(xi)">any proposed reorganization of those regulations and the reason that the reorganization is being proposed.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On completion of its evaluation report, a unit shall:<section prefix="(i)">provide a copy to the Committee which shall immediately provide copies thereof to the standing committees designated by the presiding officers for their review and comment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">provide sufficient copies to the State Library Resource Center for distribution to designated depository libraries in accordance with &#xA7; 23-303 of the Education Article; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">publish a notice in the Maryland Register that the evaluation report is available for public inspection and comment for 60 days.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The unit may hold a public hearing on the evaluation report at the discretion of the head of the unit.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Committee shall review the evaluation report.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">During the review, the Committee may solicit public comment through written comments or public hearings.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">During the 60-day review period established under subsection (b)(1) of this section, the Committee may submit to the unit comments on and recommendations for change in the unit's evaluation report.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 30 days after the termination of the 60-day review period, the unit shall:<section prefix="(i)">notify the Committee of the unit's agreement or disagreement with the Committee's recommendations; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">attempt to resolve any disagreements.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the Committee submits no comments or recommendations under this subsection, or if any disagreements have been resolved by the termination of the period provided in subsection (d)(2) of this section, the evaluation report is deemed approved.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
