<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-10A-07" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-2-10A-07</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Joint Committee on the Port of Baltimore.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Committee consists of 15 members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 15 members:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">10 shall be appointed jointly by the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House as follows:</section><section prefix="(iii)">1 shall be a representative of the United States Coast Guard, to be appointed by the Captain of the Port, United States Coast Guard, Baltimore.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The members of the Committee serve at the pleasure of the presiding officer who appointed them.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The President and the Speaker shall jointly appoint a Senator and a Delegate each to serve as cochairman.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Committee shall examine and evaluate issues affecting the competitive position of the Port of Baltimore within the international port industry.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This examination shall include the regulations adopted by the State Board of Pilots, the State Board of Docking Masters, and the Maryland Port Commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Secretary of the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation, the Secretary of the Department of Transportation, and the Executive Director of the Maryland Port Administration shall:<section prefix="(1)">cooperate fully with the Committee; and</section><section prefix="(2)">keep the Committee fully informed as to issues affecting the Port of Baltimore.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Committee shall report to the Governor and the Legislative Policy Committee on or before December 31 of each year.</section>
  </text>
</law>
