<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-714" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-15-714</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "candidate", "contribution", and "political committee" have the meanings provided in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Election Law Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only to a regulated lobbyist described in &#xA7; 15-701(a)(1), (2), (3), or (4) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The restrictions in this section apply from the starting date of the regulated lobbyist's registration to the end of the calendar year in which the registration period ends.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A regulated lobbyist who is subject to this section or a person acting on behalf of the regulated lobbyist may not, for the benefit of the Governor, Lieutenant Governor, Attorney General, or Comptroller, or a member of the General Assembly, or a candidate for election to the office of Governor, Lieutenant Governor, Attorney General, Comptroller, or member of the General Assembly, engage in the following activities:<section prefix="(i)">soliciting or transmitting a political contribution from any person, including a political committee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">serving on a fund-raising committee or a political committee;</section><section prefix="(iii)">acting as a treasurer for a candidate or official or as treasurer or chairman of a political committee;</section><section prefix="(iv)">organizing or establishing a political committee for the purpose of soliciting or transmitting contributions from any person; or</section><section prefix="(v)">forwarding tickets for fund-raising activities, or other solicitations for political contributions, to a potential contributor.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not prohibit a regulated lobbyist from:<section prefix="(i)">making a personal political contribution;</section><section prefix="(ii)">informing any entity of a position taken by a candidate or official; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">engaging in other activities not specifically prohibited under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This section does not apply to a regulated lobbyist who is a candidate with respect to the regulated lobbyist's own campaign.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
