<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-2-10A-14</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>14</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Joint Committee on Transparency and Open Government.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Committee consists of 12 members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 12 members:<section prefix="(i)">6 shall be members of the Senate of Maryland, appointed by the President of the Senate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">6 shall be members of the House of Delegates, appointed by the Speaker of the House.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">From among the membership of the Committee, the President of the Senate shall appoint a Senator to serve as the Senate Chair of the Committee, and the Speaker of the House shall appoint a Delegate to serve as the House Chair of the Committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department of Legislative Services shall provide staff assistance to the Committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The purposes of the Committee are to:<section prefix="(1)">provide continuing legislative oversight regarding transparency and open government; and</section><section prefix="(2)">make recommendations regarding initiatives that will increase citizen access to government resources, publications, and actions.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Committee shall hold:<section prefix="(1)">an organizational meeting promptly after the appointment of its members; and</section><section prefix="(2)">any other meetings that the Committee considers necessary to carry out its duties efficiently.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Committee may:<section prefix="(1)">hold a hearing on any matter relating to the functions of the Committee; and</section><section prefix="(2)">consider a vote on a bill or resolution referred to it by the President or the Speaker.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Committee shall:<section prefix="(1)">identify areas in which the State can improve its technology and Web sites to increase transparency and citizen engagement;</section><section prefix="(2)">make recommendations regarding State transparency goals and policies;</section><section prefix="(3)">consult with State entities that foster transparency, including the Governor's StateStat office:<section prefix="(i)">when developing State transparency goals and policies; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">to identify methods of coordinating transparency policies across State government;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">review State laws, programs, services, and policies and make recommendations to align them with State transparency policies and goals;</section><section prefix="(5)">determine whether there are interdepartmental gaps, inconsistencies, and inefficiencies in the implementation or attainment of State transparency policies and goals;</section><section prefix="(6)">identify laws, programs, services, or budgetary priorities that need to be adopted to ensure and promote transparency and open government in the State;</section><section prefix="(7)">survey transparency initiatives in other states that have proven effective at saving public funds and resources and assess whether those policies should be modified and adopted for use by the State;</section><section prefix="(8)">serve as an informational resource and liaison for advocates and citizens with ideas and suggestions for tools and practical implementation of initiatives that will increase transparency;</section><section prefix="(9)">review and make recommendations regarding actions suggested by advocates and citizens to increase citizen access to government resources, publications, and actions;</section><section prefix="(10)">recommend methods of increasing public awareness of government resources, publications, and Web sites; and</section><section prefix="(11)">perform any other activity that is required to fulfill the purposes of the Committee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of this title, the Committee shall submit a report to the General Assembly on or before December 1 each year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The report shall include:<section prefix="(i)">a description of the work of the Committee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any recommendations of the Committee.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
