<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-2-1608</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1608</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By a majority vote of all of the members of an investigating committee, the investigating committee may issue a subpoena that requires the appearance of a person, the production of relevant records, and the giving of relevant testimony.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A request to appear, appearance, or submission of evidence does not limit the subpoena power of the investigating committee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The subpoena shall be served:<section prefix="(1)">in the manner provided by law for service of a subpoena in a civil action;</section><section prefix="(2)">at least 7 days before the time that the subpoena sets for appearance or production of records; and</section><section prefix="(3)">with the following documents:<section prefix="(i)">a copy of the resolution that establishes the investigating committee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a copy of the rules of the investigating committee;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a statement of the subject of the investigation or inquiry of the investigating committee; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">if the subpoena requires the appearance of a person, notice that counsel may accompany the person.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person who is subpoenaed to appear at a hearing is entitled to receive the fees and allowances that are provided for a person who is subpoenaed by a circuit court.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may be held in contempt if the person unjustifiably:<section prefix="(i)">fails or refuses to comply with a subpoena for appearance;</section><section prefix="(ii)">appears but fails or refuses to testify under oath; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">unless the directive is overruled by a majority vote of the members of the investigating committee who are present at the hearing, disobeys a directive of the presiding officer at the hearing to answer a relevant question or to produce a relevant book, document, or paper that has been subpoenaed.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an investigating committee fails, in any material respect, to meet the requirements of this subtitle and the person who is subpoenaed is prejudiced by the failure:<section prefix="(i)">the person need not comply; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the failure is a complete defense in a proceeding against the person for contempt or other punishment.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By a majority vote of all of the members of an investigating committee, the investigating committee may apply for a contempt citation:<section prefix="(i)">when the General Assembly is not in session, to a circuit court; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">when the General Assembly is in session:<section prefix="1.">to the General Assembly;</section><section prefix="2.">to the Senate, if the Senate established the investigating committee; or</section><section prefix="3.">to the House, if the House established the investigating committee.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The General Assembly, the Senate, or the House:<section prefix="(i)">may consider the application as though the alleged contempt had been committed in or against that body; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">in addition to any penalty that a court imposes, may impose any other punishment that the body has the inherent power to impose.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
