<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-5-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Treasurer of the State, as provided in Article VI, &#xA7; 1 of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The General Assembly may designate a committee to consider the qualifications of the candidates and procedures for the casting of ballots for the appointment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A committee designated under this subsection shall consist of an equal number of Senators and Delegates.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The President and the Speaker shall each designate a cochairman of the committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">At least 7 days prior to the public hearing, staff shall advertise the position in newspapers of general circulation in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The committee shall conduct a public meeting at which time candidates for the Office of Treasurer shall present themselves.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The committee shall determine its procedures which shall include a secret ballot, limited to the members present and voting, to determine its nominee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the General Assembly designates a committee under subsection (b) of this section, the committee shall report to the General Assembly on the qualifications of the candidates for the Office of Treasurer and recommend one of the candidates to the General Assembly for the appointment as Treasurer.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">During the first session following the election of new members to the General Assembly, the General Assembly shall meet in joint session to appoint the Treasurer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the General Assembly does not appoint someone to the Office of Treasurer at the time of its first joint session to consider the appointment of a Treasurer, the General Assembly shall continue to meet in joint session on a daily basis until a Treasurer is appointed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The appointment of the Treasurer by the General Assembly shall be determined by a majority of the membership present and voting of the Senate and the House, sitting jointly.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each member of the General Assembly shall have 1 vote.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The name of each person who applies shall be placed on the ballot that is distributed at the joint session and the ballot shall contain a place for a write-in candidate. A candidate may withdraw his or her name at any time.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Before ballots are distributed, the Reading Clerk shall read the letter of recommendation, if any, from the joint committee for which provision is made in subsection (c) of this section. Once read, the joint session shall immediately proceed with the balloting. Nominating speeches may not be made from the floor.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The casting of ballots for the appointment of the Treasurer shall be by secret ballot.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Ballots shall be distributed by representatives of the Office of the Secretary of the Senate and of the Chief Clerk of the House of Delegates. The Secretary of the Senate shall open each ballot and hand it to the Chief Clerk of the House, who shall announce for whom the vote is cast.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The counting of ballots shall be observed by:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Rules of the House of Delegates, as adopted for the session at which the State Treasurer is appointed, shall govern the proceedings of the joint session or sessions. The members of the General Assembly, sitting jointly, shall determine any other procedure necessary for the casting of ballots for the appointment of the Treasurer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Staff to the joint committee shall be provided by the Department of Legislative Services.</section>
  </text>
</law>
