<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-7-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided by law, the Code of Maryland Regulations shall contain the text of:<section prefix="(1)">each executive order that is generally permanent in nature;</section><section prefix="(2)">each regulation;</section><section prefix="(3)">each document that the General Assembly requires to be published with a regulation; and</section><section prefix="(4)">unless otherwise privileged, each other document that the Committee permits to be published in the Code of Maryland Regulations.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least once each year, the Division shall integrate into the Code of Maryland Regulations each document that:<section prefix="(i)">is required to be included in the Code of Maryland Regulations; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">has not previously been integrated or included in the Code of Maryland Regulations.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This integration may be carried out by:<section prefix="(i)">publication of looseleaf pages for insertion in the Code of Maryland Regulations; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">other appropriate permanent supplements to the Code of Maryland Regulations.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each part of the Code of Maryland Regulations and each issue of its permanent supplements shall contain a certification of the Administrator that the part or issue includes all of the documents that are effective and have been codified, as of the date set by the Administrator.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each issue of the permanent supplements shall contain its issue date, which shall be its date of deposit in the United States mail. This date shall appear prominently on the first page.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Committee permits a unit to publish a document in the Code of Maryland Regulations and publication otherwise would not be required, the Committee may require the unit to reimburse the Division for the cost of the publication.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Division shall bill for and collect the reimbursement.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
