<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-206" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-7-206</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An issue of the Register shall contain:<section prefix="(1)">on the first page:<section prefix="(i)">the closing date and hour of the issue; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the issue date, which shall be the date of deposit in the United States mail and shall appear prominently;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the text of each of the following documents that has been submitted to the Division before the closing date and hour and has not been published previously:<section prefix="(i)">during each session of the General Assembly:</section><section prefix="(ii)">each proposed rule of court that the Chief Judge of the Court of Appeals directs to be published;</section><section prefix="(iii)">each rule of court that the Court of Appeals adopts or permits to be adopted;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the hearing calendar of the Court of Appeals;</section><section prefix="(v)">each administrative order or memorandum of the Chief Judge of the Court of Appeals or of the Administrative Office of the Courts that the Chief Judge directs to be published;</section><section prefix="(vi)">the hearing calendar of the Court of Special Appeals;</section><section prefix="(vii)">each administrative regulation that the Chief Judge of the District Court adopts;</section><section prefix="(viii)">each executive order;</section><section prefix="(ix)">each designation of an official State agency under a federal program;</section><section prefix="(x)">except for notaries public and special police, a list of gubernatorial appointments that states:</section><section prefix="(xi)">for a proposed regulation:</section><section prefix="(xii)">each notice of a public hearing that a unit issues;</section><section prefix="(xiii)">unless otherwise exempted, each other document that is required by law to be published in the Code of Maryland Regulations;</section><section prefix="(xiv)">each other document that is required to be published in the Register;</section><section prefix="(xv)">each notice or other document issued by an agency of a county or municipal government that the Committee permits to be published in the Register; and</section><section prefix="(xvi)">unless otherwise privileged, each other document that the Committee permits to be published in the Register;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">a table of contents; and</section><section prefix="(4)">an index to each title of the Code of Maryland Regulations that a document in the issue affects.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each issue of the Register shall contain a certification of the Administrator that the issue contains all of the documents that have been submitted to the Division as of the closing date and hour of the issue.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The certification of the Administrator in the Register is conclusive evidence of this fact.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Committee permits a unit or an agency of a county or municipal government to publish a document in the Register and publication otherwise would not be required, the Committee may require the unit or agency to reimburse the Division for the cost of the publication.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Division shall bill for and collect the reimbursement.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
