<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-2404</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>2404</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Maryland Advisory Council on the Deaf and Hard of Hearing.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Council consists of 18 members appointed by the Governor, with the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 18 Council members, at least five of the members shall be deaf and hard of hearing individuals.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Of the 18 Council members:<section prefix="(1)">one shall be the State Superintendent or a designee from the State Department of Education;</section><section prefix="(2)">one shall be the Secretary or a designee from the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene;</section><section prefix="(3)">one shall be the Secretary or a designee from the Department of Human Resources;</section><section prefix="(4)">one shall be the Secretary or a designee from the Department of Transportation;</section><section prefix="(5)">one shall be from the Commission on Civil Rights;</section><section prefix="(6)">one shall be the Secretary or a designee from the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation;</section><section prefix="(7)">one shall be the Secretary or a designee from the Department of Housing and Community Development;</section><section prefix="(8)">one shall be the Superintendent or a designee from the Maryland School for the Deaf;</section><section prefix="(9)">one shall be the Secretary or a designee from the Department of Aging; and</section><section prefix="(10)">nine shall be from the general public.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The nine members from the general public shall be chosen from different geographical areas of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the nine members from the general public:<section prefix="(i)">five shall be deaf and hard of hearing individuals;</section><section prefix="(ii)">one shall be a private citizen with special knowledge or expertise relating to services to deaf and hard of hearing individuals;</section><section prefix="(iii)">one shall be a parent of a deaf or hard of hearing child;</section><section prefix="(iv)">one shall be from a private agency providing services to deaf and hard of hearing individuals; and</section><section prefix="(v)">one shall be a person with special knowledge or expertise relating to services to individuals who are deafblind.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
