<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-848" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-15-848</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this Part VII the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Applicant" means an individual or a business entity that is, with regard to the land that is the subject of the application:<section prefix="(i)">a title owner, assignee, or contract purchaser of the land;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a trustee that has an interest in the land, other than as a trustee described in a mortgage or deed of trust; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a holder of a 5% or greater interest in the business entity that has an interest in the land if:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Applicant" includes:<section prefix="(i)">any other business entity in which an individual or business entity described in paragraph (1) of this subsection holds a 3% or greater interest;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an officer or director of a corporation who actually holds title to, or is the contract purchaser or assignee of, the land that is the subject of an application if:</section><section prefix="(iii)">as to an application for a zoning regulation, any person authorized to sign the application.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Applicant" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">a financial institution that has loaned money or extended financing for the acquisition, development, or construction of improvements on the land that is the subject of an application;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a municipal or public corporation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a public authority;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a public service company acting within the scope of Division I of the Public Utilities Article; or</section><section prefix="(v)">a person who is:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Application" means:<section prefix="(1)">an application for a zoning map amendment;</section><section prefix="(2)">an application for a zoning regulation amendment; or</section><section prefix="(3)">participation in the adoption and approval of a comprehensive zoning plan by appearing at a public hearing, filing a statement in an official record, or engaging in other similar communication to an elected official, where the intent is to change the classification or increase the density of the land of the applicant.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Business entity" means:<section prefix="(1)">a sole proprietorship;</section><section prefix="(2)">a corporation;</section><section prefix="(3)">a general partnership;</section><section prefix="(4)">a limited partnership;</section><section prefix="(5)">a limited liability company; or</section><section prefix="(6)">a joint venture.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Candidate" means a candidate for election as Howard County Executive or to the Howard County Council who becomes an elected official.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Contribution" means any payment or transfer of money or property or the incurring of any liability or promise of anything of value to the treasurer of a candidate, a political committee, or a slate.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Contributor" means an individual or business entity that makes a contribution.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Elected official" means an individual who serves as Howard County Executive or as a member of the Howard County Council.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Engaging in business" means entering into any:<section prefix="(i)">sale, purchase, lease, or other transaction involving goods, services, or real property; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">contract, award, loan, extension of credit, or any other financial transaction.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Engaging in business" does not include the sale of goods to an individual for the use or consumption of the individual or others for personal, family, or household purposes, as distinguished from industrial, commercial, or agricultural purposes.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Family member" means the spouse or child of either an applicant or a party of record who has made a contribution with the knowledge and consent of the applicant or party of record.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Party of record" means an individual or business entity that participates in a map amendment proceeding by the County Council or the zoning board, or who participates in the adoption and approval of a comprehensive zoning plan by appearing at a public hearing, filing a statement in an official record, or engaging in other similar communication to an elected official where the intent is to oppose a change in classification or an increase in density of the land of an applicant.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Political action committee" means a political committee that is not:<section prefix="(1)">a political party;</section><section prefix="(2)">a central committee;</section><section prefix="(3)">a slate; or</section><section prefix="(4)">a political committee organized and operated by, and solely on behalf of, an individual running for any elective office or a slate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Political committee" means a committee, continuing or noncontinuing, specifically created to promote the candidacy of a person running for elective office.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Slate" means a group, combination, or organization of candidates created under the provisions of the Election Law Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Treasurer" has the meaning provided in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Election Law Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Treasurer" includes a subtreasurer.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
