<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-1406</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1406</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Smart Growth Subcabinet.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Subcabinet consists of:<section prefix="(1)">the Special Secretary;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Secretary of Agriculture;</section><section prefix="(3)">the Secretary of Budget and Management;</section><section prefix="(4)">the Secretary of Business and Economic Development;</section><section prefix="(5)">the Secretary of the Environment;</section><section prefix="(6)">the Secretary of General Services;</section><section prefix="(7)">the Secretary of Higher Education;</section><section prefix="(8)">the Secretary of Housing and Community Development;</section><section prefix="(9)">the Assistant Secretary of the Office of Neighborhood Revitalization;</section><section prefix="(10)">the Secretary of Natural Resources;</section><section prefix="(11)">the Secretary of Planning;</section><section prefix="(12)">the Secretary of Transportation;</section><section prefix="(13)">a representative of the Governor's office;</section><section prefix="(14)">the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene;</section><section prefix="(15)">the Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation; and</section><section prefix="(16)">the Director of the Maryland Energy Administration.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Executive Director of the National Center for Smart Growth Education and Research at the University of Maryland, College Park shall serve as an ex officio member of the Subcabinet.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Special Secretary shall chair the Subcabinet and shall be responsible for the oversight, direction, and accountability of the work of the Subcabinet.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary of Planning shall be the vice chair of the Subcabinet.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Office shall provide the primary staff support for the Subcabinet.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Special Secretary and the Secretary of Planning may call upon any of the Subcabinet members to provide additional staff assistance as needed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Special Secretary and the Secretary of Planning may establish subcommittees to carry out the work of the Subcabinet.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Subcabinet shall meet regularly at such times and places as it determines.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Subcabinet shall:<section prefix="(i)">provide a forum for discussion of interdepartmental issues relating to activities that affect growth, development, neighborhood conservation, and resource management;</section><section prefix="(ii)">work together using all available resources to promote the understanding of smart growth;</section><section prefix="(iii)">work together to create, enhance, support, and revitalize sustainable communities across the State;</section><section prefix="(iv)">meet at least biannually with county and municipal elected leaders and planning officials to discuss local government issues relating to activities that affect smart growth, development, neighborhood conservation, and resource management;</section><section prefix="(v)">subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, make recommendations to:<section prefix="1.">the Department of Business and Economic Development in accordance with &#xA7; 5-1304 of the Economic Development Article;</section><section prefix="2.">the Department of Housing and Community Development in accordance with &#xA7; 6-206 of the Housing and Community Development Article;</section><section prefix="3.">the Department of Planning in accordance with &#xA7; 5A-303 of the State Finance and Procurement Article; and</section><section prefix="4.">the Department of Transportation in accordance with &#xA7; 7-101 of the Transportation Article;</section></section><section prefix="(vi)">in coordination with State agencies, evaluate and report annually to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of this article, to the General Assembly on the implementation of the State's smart growth policy; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">perform other duties assigned by the Governor.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The failure of the Subcabinet to make a recommendation under paragraph (1)(v) of this subsection may not be construed as prohibiting a department to act in accordance with the department's authority under State law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The annual report required in subsection (h)(1) of this section shall include:<section prefix="(1)">a description of the projects, programs, and costs of activities located in priority funding areas;</section><section prefix="(2)">a description of projects, programs, and costs of activities funded under the exceptions allowed in &#xA7; 5-7B-06 of the State Finance and Procurement Article;</section><section prefix="(3)">projects submitted to the Board of Public Works for funding outside priority funding areas under the extraordinary circumstances exception in accordance with &#xA7; 5-7B-05 of the State Finance and Procurement Article and the impact of these projects upon the State's smart growth policy;</section><section prefix="(4)">a list of programs and policies reviewed and changed to ensure compliance with the State's smart growth policy; and</section><section prefix="(5)">a list of projects or programs approved and funded under Chapter 759, &#xA7; 2 of the Acts of 1997.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
