<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-203" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-10-203</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This subtitle does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">the Legislative Branch of the State government or an agency of the Legislative Branch;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Judicial Branch of the State government or an agency of the Judicial Branch;</section><section prefix="(3)">the following agencies of the Executive Branch of the State government:<section prefix="(i)">the Governor;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Department of Assessments and Taxation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Insurance Administration except as specifically provided in the Insurance Article;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Maryland Parole Commission of the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services;</section><section prefix="(v)">the Public Service Commission;</section><section prefix="(vi)">the Maryland Tax Court;</section><section prefix="(vii)">the State Workers' Compensation Commission;</section><section prefix="(viii)">the Maryland Automobile Insurance Fund; or</section><section prefix="(ix)">the Patuxent Institution Board of Review, when acting on a parole request;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">an officer or unit not part of a principal department of State government that:<section prefix="(i)">is created by or pursuant to the Maryland Constitution or general or local law;</section><section prefix="(ii)">operates in only 1 county; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">is subject to the control of a local government or is funded wholly or partly from local funds;</section></section><section prefix="(5)">unemployment insurance claim determinations, tax determinations, and appeals in the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation except as specifically provided in Subtitle 5A of Title 8 of the Labor and Employment Article; or</section><section prefix="(6)">any other entity otherwise expressly exempted by statute.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This subtitle does apply to:<section prefix="(1)">the property tax assessment appeals boards; and</section><section prefix="(2)">as to requests for correction of certificates of death under &#xA7; 5-310(d)(2) of the Health - General Article, the office of the Chief Medical Examiner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A public hearing required or provided for by statute or regulation before an agency takes a particular action is not an agency hearing under &#xA7; 10-202(d) of this subtitle unless the statute or regulation:<section prefix="(1)">expressly requires that the public hearing be held in accordance with this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">expressly requires that any judicial review of the agency determination following the public hearing be conducted in accordance with this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, this subtitle does apply to a contested case that arises from a State program administered by the Montgomery County Department of Health and Human Services in the same manner as the subtitle applies to a county health department or local department of social services.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of this subtitle, the Office of the Attorney General, after consultation with the County Attorney for Montgomery County, shall determine if the Montgomery County Department of Health and Human Services administers a State program.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This subsection is not intended to extend or limit the authority of the Montgomery County Department of Health and Human Services to administer State programs in the manner of a county health department or local department of social services.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
