<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-1021" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-1021</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission is the official custodian of all valuable paintings and other objects of decorative art owned by or loaned to the State, except those located in a State room of the Government House. With respect to the objects subject to its official custody, the Commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">keep a continuing inventory of the objects; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">be responsible for and supervise the acquisition, custody, display, location, preservation, proper care, security, and restoration of the objects.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At such time as the State acquires the Peabody Art Collection from the Peabody Institute, the Commission shall become the official custodian of the Collection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In exercising its custodial responsibilities, the Commission may loan objects owned by the State to qualified institutions and may contract with such institutions for the performance of curatorial services.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each person or agency that desires to acquire a painting or object of decorative art for display in or on the premises of any State building, except in a room of the Government House, must receive both prior approval and final acceptance from the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before giving prior approval or final acceptance in accordance with this subsection, the Commission shall consider:<section prefix="(i)">the competence of the artist;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the proposed location of the object; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the quality, historical significance, and appropriateness of the work.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This subtitle does not apply to artwork acquired through the Maryland Public Art Initiative Program established under Title 4, Subtitle 6 of the Economic Development Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
