<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-2-506</section_number>
  <catch_line>In addition to any powers set forth elsewhere, the Committee may:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>506</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to any powers set forth elsewhere, the Committee may:<section prefix="(1)">review proposed or adopted regulations of a unit of the Executive Branch of the State government;</section><section prefix="(2)">consider requests for emergency adoption of regulations;</section><section prefix="(3)">inquire into an alleged failure of an officer or employee of any branch of the State government to comply with the laws of the State; and</section><section prefix="(4)">review the operations of any unit of the Executive Branch of the State government.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least once a year, the Committee shall submit a report to the Legislative Policy Committee and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of this title, to the General Assembly.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The report shall:<section prefix="(i)">describe the studies and other work of the Committee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">include any recommendations of the Committee on:<section prefix="1.">more effective operation of the branches of the State government, in accordance with the laws of the State; and</section><section prefix="2.">legislative action that is needed to change or reverse a regulation of a unit of the Executive Branch of the State government.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The failure of the Committee to comment on or to object to a proposed or adopted regulation is not an indication that:<section prefix="(1)">the Committee approves the regulation;</section><section prefix="(2)">the statute under which the regulation is adopted authorizes the adoption; or</section><section prefix="(3)">the regulation conforms to the legislative intent of the statute.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
