<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-6.5-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>The appropriate regulating entity may not approve an acquisition unless it finds the acquisition is ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The appropriate regulating entity may not approve an acquisition unless it finds the acquisition is in the public interest.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An acquisition is not in the public interest unless appropriate steps have been taken to:<section prefix="(1)">ensure that the value of public or charitable assets is safeguarded;</section><section prefix="(2)">ensure that the value of public or charitable assets is spent in a manner that corresponds with the potential risk associated with the acquisition;</section><section prefix="(3)">ensure that:<section prefix="(i)">the fair value of the public or charitable assets of a nonprofit health service plan or a health maintenance organization will be distributed to the Maryland Health Care Trust established under &#xA7; 6.5-401 of this title; or</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">40% of the fair value of the public or charitable assets of a nonprofit hospital will be distributed to the Maryland Health Care Trust established under &#xA7; 6.5-401 of this title; and</section><section prefix="2.">60% of the fair value of the public or charitable assets of a nonprofit hospital will be distributed to a public or nonprofit charitable entity or trust that is:</section></section></section><section prefix="(4)">ensure that no part of the public or charitable assets of the acquisition inure directly or indirectly to an officer, director, or trustee of a nonprofit health entity; and</section><section prefix="(5)">ensure that no officer, director, or trustee of the nonprofit health entity receives any immediate or future remuneration as the result of an acquisition or proposed acquisition except in the form of compensation paid for continued employment with the acquiring entity.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The regulating entity may determine that a distribution of assets of a nonprofit health entity is not required under this section if the transaction is:<section prefix="(1)">determined not to be an acquisition;</section><section prefix="(2)">in the ordinary course of business; and</section><section prefix="(3)">for fair value.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In determining fair value, the appropriate regulating entity may consider all relevant factors, including, as determined by the regulating entity:<section prefix="(1)">the value of the nonprofit health entity or an affiliate or the assets of such an entity that is determined as if the entity had voting stock outstanding and 100% of its stock was freely transferable and available for purchase without restriction;</section><section prefix="(2)">the value as a going concern;</section><section prefix="(3)">the market value;</section><section prefix="(4)">the investment or earnings value;</section><section prefix="(5)">the net asset value; and</section><section prefix="(6)">a control premium, if any.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In determining whether an acquisition is in the public interest, the appropriate regulating entity shall consider:<section prefix="(i)">whether the transferor exercised due diligence in deciding to engage in an acquisition, selecting the transferee, and negotiating the terms and conditions of the acquisition;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the procedures the transferor used in making the decision, including whether appropriate expert assistance was used;</section><section prefix="(iii)">whether any conflicts of interest were disclosed, including conflicts of interest of board members, executives, and experts retained by the transferor, transferee, or any other parties to the acquisition;</section><section prefix="(iv)">whether the transferor will receive fair value for its public or charitable assets;</section><section prefix="(v)">whether public or charitable assets are placed at unreasonable risk if the acquisition is financed in part by the transferor;</section><section prefix="(vi)">whether the acquisition has the likelihood of creating a significant adverse effect on the availability or accessibility of health care services in the affected community;</section><section prefix="(vii)">whether the acquisition includes sufficient safeguards to ensure that the affected community will have continued access to affordable health care; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">whether any management contract under the acquisition is for fair value.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In determining whether a nonprofit health entity has exercised due diligence as required under paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection, the appropriate regulating entity may not determine that due diligence was exercised unless the nonprofit health entity considered the risks of an acquisition, including whether an acquisition:<section prefix="(i)">would result in diseconomies of scale; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">would violate federal or State antitrust laws.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The public or charitable assets distributed to a public or nonprofit charitable entity or trust in accordance with subsection (b)(2) of this section shall be in the form of cash.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The appropriate regulating entity shall determine whether a payment by a nonprofit health entity, required under an agreement or contract for the acquisition of a nonprofit health entity if the agreement or contract is broken by the nonprofit health entity, is in the public interest.</section>
  </text>
</law>
