<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-10A-08" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-2-10A-08</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Joint Committee on Fair Practices and State Personnel Oversight.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Joint Committee consists of eight members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the eight members:<section prefix="(i)">four shall be members of the Senate, appointed by the President of the Senate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">four shall be members of the House of Delegates, appointed by the Speaker of the House.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The members of the Joint Committee serve at the pleasure of the presiding officer who appointed them.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The President and the Speaker jointly shall appoint a Senator and a Delegate to serve as cochairs.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Joint Committee shall have oversight over:<section prefix="(1)">employment policies and personnel systems in the Executive Branch of State government, including:<section prefix="(i)">the State Personnel Management System;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Maryland Department of Transportation's Human Resources Management System; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the personnel systems of State institutions of higher education;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">matters in State government of equal employment opportunity policies and practices; and</section><section prefix="(3)">procurement practices made under executive order.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The purposes of the Joint Committee are to:<section prefix="(1)">review reports;</section><section prefix="(2)">evaluate the effectiveness of programs, policies, and practices; and</section><section prefix="(3)">identify areas of concern and, as appropriate, recommend corrective measures to the Governor and the General Assembly.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
