<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-20-1009</section_number>
  <catch_line>If, after reviewing all of the evidence, the administrative law judge finds that the respondent has ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1009</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If, after reviewing all of the evidence, the administrative law judge finds that the respondent has engaged in a discriminatory act, the administrative law judge shall:<section prefix="(1)">issue a decision and order stating the judge's findings of fact and conclusions of law; and</section><section prefix="(2)">issue and cause to be served on the respondent an order requiring the respondent to:<section prefix="(i)">cease and desist from engaging in the discriminatory acts; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">take affirmative action to effectuate the purposes of the applicable subtitle of this title.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the respondent is found to have engaged in or to be engaging in an unlawful employment practice charged in the complaint, the remedy may include:<section prefix="(i)">enjoining the respondent from engaging in the discriminatory act;</section><section prefix="(ii)">ordering appropriate affirmative relief, including the reinstatement or hiring of employees, with or without back pay;</section><section prefix="(iii)">awarding compensatory damages; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">ordering any other equitable relief that the administrative law judge considers appropriate.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Compensatory damages awarded under this subsection are in addition to:<section prefix="(i)">back pay or interest on back pay that the complainant may recover under any other provision of law; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any other equitable relief that a complainant may recover under any other provision of law.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The sum of the amount of compensatory damages awarded to each complainant under this subsection for future pecuniary losses, emotional pain, suffering, inconvenience, mental anguish, loss of enjoyment of life, or nonpecuniary losses, may not exceed:<section prefix="(i)">$50,000, if the respondent employs not fewer than 15 and not more than 100 employees in each of 20 or more calendar weeks in the current or preceding calendar year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">$100,000, if the respondent employs not fewer than 101 and not more than 200 employees in each of 20 or more calendar weeks in the current or preceding calendar year;</section><section prefix="(iii)">$200,000, if the respondent employs not fewer than 201 and not more than 500 employees in each of 20 or more calendar weeks in the current or preceding calendar year; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">$300,000, if the respondent employs not fewer than 501 employees in each of 20 or more calendar weeks in the current or preceding calendar year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If back pay is awarded under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the award shall be reduced by any interim earnings or amounts earnable with reasonable diligence by the person discriminated against.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In addition to any other relief authorized by this subsection, a complainant may recover back pay for up to 2 years preceding the filing of the complaint, where the unlawful employment practice that has occurred during the complaint filing period is similar or related to an unlawful employment practice with regard to discrimination in compensation that occurred outside the time for filing a complaint.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, if the respondent is found to have engaged in or to be engaging in a discriminatory act other than an unlawful employment practice, in addition to an award of civil penalties as provided in &#xA7; 20-1016 of this subtitle, nonmonetary relief may be granted to the complainant.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An order may not be issued that substantially affects the cost, level, or type of any transportation services.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In cases involving transportation services that are supported fully or partially with funds from the Maryland Department of Transportation, an order may not be issued that would require costs, level, or type of transportation services different from or exceeding those required to meet U.S. Department of Transportation regulations adopted under 29 U.S.C. &#xA7; 794.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An order issued in violation of subparagraph (i) of this paragraph is not enforceable under &#xA7; 20-1011 of this subtitle.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If, after reviewing all of the evidence, the administrative law judge finds that the respondent has not engaged in an alleged discriminatory act, the administrative law judge shall:<section prefix="(1)">state findings of fact and conclusions of law; and</section><section prefix="(2)">issue an order dismissing the complaint.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Unless a timely appeal is filed with the Commission in accordance with the Commission's regulations, a decision and order issued by the administrative law judge under this section shall become the final order of the Commission.</section>
  </text>
</law>
