<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-6-110</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>110</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Chief Deputy Attorney General shall serve as acting Attorney General if the Attorney General temporarily is unable or unavailable to carry out the duties of office.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the Attorney General gives the Chief Deputy Attorney General written notice of a temporary inability or unavailability, the acting Attorney General shall serve:<section prefix="(1)">on and after the date that the Attorney General sets in the notice; and</section><section prefix="(2)">until the Attorney General gives the acting Attorney General written notice that the Attorney General is able to carry out the duties of office.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the Attorney General has not given notice, but the members of the Board of Public Works and the presiding officers of the General Assembly, by a majority vote, make a formal, written determination of a temporary inability or unavailability of the Attorney General, the Chief Deputy Attorney General shall serve as acting Attorney General:<section prefix="(1)">on and after the date of the determination; and</section><section prefix="(2)">until the members of the Board of Public Works and the presiding officers of the General Assembly, by a majority vote, determine and give the Attorney General and the acting Attorney General written notice that the Attorney General is able to carry out the duties of office.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On petition of any member of the Board of Public Works, a presiding officer of the General Assembly, the Attorney General, or the acting Attorney General, a circuit court has exclusive original jurisdiction to determine any issue that arises under this section and to pass any appropriate order.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except for cases that the court considers of greater importance, a proceeding under this section, including an appeal, shall:<section prefix="(i)">take precedence on the docket;</section><section prefix="(ii)">be heard at the earliest practicable date; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">be expedited in every way.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
