<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-1604</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Chief Administrative Law Judge shall:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1604</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Chief Administrative Law Judge shall:<section prefix="(1)">supervise the Office of Administrative Hearings;</section><section prefix="(2)">establish qualifications for administrative law judges;</section><section prefix="(3)">appoint and remove administrative law judges in accordance with &#xA7; 9-1605 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(4)">assign administrative law judges to conduct hearings in contested cases;</section><section prefix="(5)">if necessary, establish classifications for case assignment on the basis of subject matter, expertise, and case complexity;</section><section prefix="(6)">establish and implement standard and specialized training programs and provide materials for administrative law judges;</section><section prefix="(7)">provide and coordinate continuing education programs and services for administrative law judges, including research, technical assistance, technical and professional publications, compiling and disseminating information, and advise of changes in the law relative to their duties;</section><section prefix="(8)">develop model rules of procedure and other guidelines for administrative hearings;</section><section prefix="(9)">develop a code of professional responsibility for administrative law judges; and</section><section prefix="(10)">monitor the quality of State administrative hearings.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Chief Administrative Law Judge may:<section prefix="(i)">serve as an administrative law judge in a contested case;</section><section prefix="(ii)">furnish administrative law judges on a contractual basis to other governmental entities;</section><section prefix="(iii)">accept and expend funds, grants, and gifts and accept services from any public or private source;</section><section prefix="(iv)">enter into agreements and contracts with any public or private agencies or educational institutions;</section><section prefix="(v)">adopt regulations to implement this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">assess fees to cover administrative expenses as follows:<section prefix="1.">to file an appeal, a fee not exceeding:</section><section prefix="2.">to process a subpoena, a fee not exceeding $5.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Fees charged under paragraph (1) of this subsection for administrative expenses may not be charged to:<section prefix="(i)">State agencies; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">petitioners who are determined by the Office of Administrative Hearings to be unable to pay the fees.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A fee charged under paragraph (1) of this subsection for filing an appeal shall be refunded to a party who initiates the appeal if the party receives a favorable decision from the administrative law judge.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Chief Administrative Law Judge shall submit an annual report on the activities of the Office to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of this article, to the General Assembly.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This report may be prepared in conjunction with the annual report required under &#xA7; 9-1610 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Chief Administrative Law Judge shall meet and confer regularly with the Advisory Council on Administrative Hearings.</section>
  </text>
</law>
