<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-512" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-15-512</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the disqualification arising under &#xA7; 15-511 of this subtitle may not be suspended if the conflict is direct and personal to:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">This paragraph does not apply to a vote on:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">As to any other conflict, the disqualification arising under &#xA7; 15-511 of this subtitle is suspended if a legislator with an apparent or presumed conflict files with the Joint Ethics Committee a sworn statement that describes the circumstances of the apparent or presumed conflict and the legislation or class of legislation to which it relates and asserts the legislator is able to vote and otherwise participate in action relating to the legislation, fairly, objectively, and in the public interest.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whenever a legislator files a statement for the suspension of the disqualification, the Joint Ethics Committee on its own motion may issue a statement concerning the propriety of the legislator's participation in the particular legislative action, with reference to the applicable ethical standards of this matter.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The suspension of the disqualification by the filing of the statement is subject to further action by the Joint Ethics Committee if the question of conflict comes before it as to the same circumstances and the same legislator.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A member who is disqualified from participating in legislative action under subsection (a)(1) of this section, or who chooses to be excused from participating in legislative action on a bill or class of bills because of the appearance or presumption of a conflict, shall file in a timely manner a statement with the Joint Ethics Committee that describes the circumstances of the apparent or presumed conflict.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">All statements filed under this section shall be:<section prefix="(1)">filed electronically on a form prescribed by the Joint Ethics Committee; and</section><section prefix="(2)">maintained as a matter of public record as prescribed in subsection (e) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department of Legislative Services shall:<section prefix="(i)">compile the statements filed under this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">make the statements available for public inspection as provided in the Public Information Act; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">as to statements filed on or after January 1, 2013, make the statements freely available to the public on the Internet through an online registration program.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">As to each statement, the Internet posting shall indicate:<section prefix="(i)">whether the Joint Ethics Committee has made a determination under subsection (b) of this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the determination made, if any; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the date, if any, on which the determination was made.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
