<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-521" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-11-521</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A State unit is entitled to an extension of the time specified in &#xA7; 11-515 of this subtitle, if the State unit:<section prefix="(1)">determines, in writing, that:<section prefix="(i)">the application and appendices are lacking in specific required information; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">technical information, tests, or studies are needed for consideration of the application;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">states the specific information, tests, and studies needed;</section><section prefix="(3)">states the time required for their completion, if the information, tests, or studies are not required to be submitted by or for the applicant; and</section><section prefix="(4)">delivers the written determination to the Coordinator and to the applicant at least 10 days before the scheduled hearing date.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A State unit is entitled to an extension of the time specified in &#xA7; 11-520 of this subtitle, if the State unit:<section prefix="(1)">determines, in writing, that:<section prefix="(i)">the application and appendices are lacking in specific required information;</section><section prefix="(ii)">technical information, tests, or studies are needed for consideration of the application; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">new information requiring further evaluation has been obtained from the public hearing;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">states the specific information, tests, and studies needed;</section><section prefix="(3)">states the time required for their completion, if the information, tests, or studies are not required to be submitted by or for the applicant; and</section><section prefix="(4)">delivers the written determination to the Coordinator and to the applicant at least 10 days before the expiration of the time specified in &#xA7; 11-520 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to &#xA7; 11-522 of this subtitle, on timely delivery of the written determination, the time limit shall be extended until 30 days after the information required from the applicant is received or 30 days after the time specified in the determination for the completion of the other information, tests, and studies not required from the applicant, as the case may be.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If new information is obtained from a public hearing, the Coordinator and the State unit involved shall jointly agree to a reasonable extension of time before the unit must act on the development permit.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
