<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-15-829</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this Part IV the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>829</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this Part IV the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Agent" means any individual or business entity hired or retained by an applicant for any purpose relating to the land that is the subject of an application if the individual or business entity is:<section prefix="(i)">an accountant;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an attorney;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an architect;</section><section prefix="(iv)">an engineer;</section><section prefix="(v)">a land use consultant;</section><section prefix="(vi)">an economic consultant;</section><section prefix="(vii)">a real estate agent;</section><section prefix="(viii)">a real estate broker;</section><section prefix="(ix)">a traffic consultant; or</section><section prefix="(x)">a traffic engineer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Agent" includes:<section prefix="(i)">as to a corporation described in paragraph (1) of this subsection, its officers, directors, and majority stockholders who are engaged in substantive activities pertaining specifically to land development in Prince George's County as a regular part of their ongoing business activities;</section><section prefix="(ii)">as to a partnership or limited partnership described in paragraph (1) of this subsection, its general partners and limited partners who are engaged in substantive activities pertaining specifically to land development in Prince George's County as a regular part of their ongoing business activities; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">as to a joint venture described in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the principal members of the joint venture who are engaged in substantive activities pertaining specifically to land development in Prince George's County as a regular part of their ongoing business activities.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Applicant" means an individual or business entity that is:<section prefix="1.">a title owner or contract purchaser of land that is the subject of an application;</section><section prefix="2.">a trustee that has an interest in land that is the subject of an application, excluding trustees described in a mortgage or deed of trust; or</section><section prefix="3.">a holder of 5 percent or greater interest in a business entity that has an interest in land that is the subject of an application but only if:</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Where the applicant is a corporation, the term also includes the directors and officers of the corporation which actually holds title to the land, or is a contract purchaser of the land, which is the subject of an application, but does not include the directors and officers of any entity which does not hold title to, or is not the contract purchaser of, land which is the subject of an application.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Applicant" includes any business entity in which a person described in paragraph (1) of this subsection holds a 5 percent or greater interest.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Applicant" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">a bank, savings and loan institution, or other financial institution which has loaned money or extended financing for the acquisition, development, or construction of improvements upon any land that is the subject of an application;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a municipal or public corporation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a public authority; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">a public utility regulated by the Public Service Commission in any instance where the utility is engaged in or conducting regulated activities that have been approved by the Public Service Commission or are permitted under Division I of the Public Utilities Article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Application" means:<section prefix="(1)">an application for a zoning map amendment, special exception, departure from design standards, revision to a special exception site plan, expansion of a legal nonconforming use, revision to a legal nonconforming use site plan, or a request for a variance from the zoning ordinance;</section><section prefix="(2)">an application to approve a comprehensive design plan, a conceptual site plan, or a specific design plan; or</section><section prefix="(3)">participation in adopting and approving an area master plan or sectional map amendment by appearance at a public hearing, filing a statement in the official record, or other similar communication to a member of the County Council or the Planning Board, where the intent is to intensify the zoning category applicable to the land of the applicant.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Business entity" means:<section prefix="(1)">a sole proprietorship;</section><section prefix="(2)">a corporation;</section><section prefix="(3)">a general partnership;</section><section prefix="(4)">a limited partnership;</section><section prefix="(5)">a limited liability company; or</section><section prefix="(6)">a joint venture.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Candidate" means a candidate for election to the County Council who becomes a member.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Continuing political committee" means a committee specifically created to promote the candidacy of a member running for any elective office.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Contributor" means a person or business entity that makes a payment.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"County Council" means the County Council of Prince George's County.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"County Executive" means the County Executive of Prince George's County.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"District Council" means the County Council of Prince George's County sitting as the District Council for the Prince George's County portion of the Maryland-Washington Regional District.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Member of the County Council" includes any candidate or person duly elected or appointed who takes the oath of office as a member of the County Council for Prince George's County and who thereby serves on the District Council.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Payment" means any payment or contribution of money or property or the incurring of any liability or promise of anything of value to a treasurer of a candidate, a candidate's continuing political committee, or a slate to which the candidate belongs.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Pendency of the application" means any time between the acceptance of a filing of an application by the appropriate agency and, subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, expiration of the time under which an appeal on the application may be taken.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Pendency of the application" does not include a period during which:<section prefix="(i)">action on the application is under judicial review; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">judicial review may be requested.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Political action committee" means a political committee that is not:<section prefix="(1)">a political party;</section><section prefix="(2)">a central committee;</section><section prefix="(3)">a slate; or</section><section prefix="(4)">a political committee organized and operated by, and solely on behalf of, an individual running for any elective office or a slate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Slate" means a group, combination, or organization of candidates created under the provisions of the Election Law Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Treasurer" has the meaning provided in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Election Law Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Treasurer" includes a subtreasurer.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
