<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-105" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-4-105</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If the Comptroller temporarily is unable or unavailable to carry out the duties of office, an acting comptroller shall have the powers and duties of the office, as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Chief Deputy Comptroller shall be the acting comptroller under this section, unless the members of the Board of Public Works, other than the Comptroller, appoint another individual as acting comptroller and give the Chief Deputy Comptroller written notice of the appointment.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the Comptroller gives the Board of Public Works and the Chief Deputy Comptroller written notice of a temporary inability or unavailability, the acting comptroller shall serve:<section prefix="(1)">on and after the date that the Comptroller sets in the notice; and</section><section prefix="(2)">until the Comptroller gives the Board of Public Works and the acting comptroller written notice that the Comptroller is able to carry out the duties.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the Comptroller has not given notice, but the other members of the Board of Public Works make a formal, written determination of a temporary inability or unavailability of the Comptroller, the acting comptroller shall serve:<section prefix="(1)">on and after the date of the determination; and</section><section prefix="(2)">until the members determine and give the Comptroller and the acting comptroller written notice that the Comptroller is able to carry out the duties.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Court of Appeals has exclusive original jurisdiction, on petition of the Governor, the Comptroller, the Treasurer, or the acting comptroller, to determine any issue that arises under this section and to pass any appropriate order.</section>
  </text>
</law>
