<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-15-807</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>807</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In Baltimore City, "local official" includes:<section prefix="(1)">city employees and officials of the Baltimore City Health Department;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Police Commissioner of Baltimore City and the civilian employees and police officers of the Police Department of Baltimore City; and</section><section prefix="(3)">each member of and the employees of the Civilian Review Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In Baltimore County, "local official" includes:<section prefix="(1)">each board member and the chief executive of the Baltimore County Revenue Authority; and</section><section prefix="(2)">for the purpose of the financial disclosure provisions enacted by the governing body of Baltimore County, except for a member of the Baltimore County Board of Education, each member of a board of a State agency that is wholly or partly funded by Baltimore County, regardless of whether the member is compensated.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In Montgomery County, "local official" includes:<section prefix="(1)">each member and employee of the Montgomery County Revenue Authority;</section><section prefix="(2)">each commissioner and employee of the Montgomery County Housing Opportunities Commission; and</section><section prefix="(3)">county employees of the Montgomery County Department of Health and Human Services.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to Prince George's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Local official" includes:<section prefix="(i)">each member of the Board of License Commissioners;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the chief inspector and any other inspector of the Board of License Commissioners;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the administrator of the Board of License Commissioners; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the attorney to the Board of License Commissioners.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The conflict-of-interest provisions required under &#xA7; 15-803(a)(1) of this subtitle:<section prefix="(i)">shall prohibit the county government from issuing a credit card to an elected county official or a member of the county school board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall prohibit an elected county official from directly or indirectly soliciting a person to enter into a business relationship with or provide anything of monetary value to a specific individual or entity, if the person being solicited is seeking:<section prefix="1.">the success or defeat of county legislation;</section><section prefix="2.">a county contract; or</section><section prefix="3.">any other county benefit.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Any conflict-of-interest provision enacted in accordance with paragraph (3)(ii) of this subsection may not be construed to affect the validity of any legally enacted requirement or condition, proposed and adopted on the public record at a public hearing, the purpose of which is to mitigate the impact of a development on the property owners in the areas surrounding the development, including:<section prefix="(i)">an adequate public facilities requirement;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a minority business requirement; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a community benefit requirement.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The lobbying provisions required under &#xA7; 15-803(a)(3) of this subtitle shall prohibit a person from being engaged for lobbying purposes for compensation that is dependent in any manner on the outcome of executive or legislative action before the county government.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The county's ethics enactments shall provide for:<section prefix="(i)">a county board of ethics composed of five members appointed by the county executive, subject to the advice and consent of the county council;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an executive director of the board of ethics who:<section prefix="1.">shall meet individually with each elected official of the county at least annually to advise the official regarding the requirements of any applicable ethics law, rule, or standard of conduct;</section><section prefix="2.">shall assist each elected official of the county in preparing any affidavit or other document required to be filed under the county's ethics enactments;</section><section prefix="3.">shall conduct ethics-related briefings for the benefit of elected officials of the county; and</section><section prefix="4.">may provide information to any person regarding laws, rules, and other standards of ethical conduct applicable to elected officials of the county; and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">the county board of ethics to meet at least two times each year.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In St. Mary's County, "local official" includes each commissioner and employee of the St. Mary's County Metropolitan Commission.</section>
  </text>
</law>
