<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-15-820</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>820</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, as to the Washington Suburban Transit Commission, "commissioner" includes the members appointed from Prince George's County or Montgomery County and the members appointed by the Governor.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each commissioner and each applicant for appointment to a bicounty commission shall file the financial disclosure statement required by &#xA7; 15-601(a) of this title, except that:<section prefix="(i)">references to "business with the State" are deemed to refer to "business with the State, the appropriate bicounty commission, Montgomery County, or Prince George's County"; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">references to "employed by the State" are deemed to refer to "employed by the State, the appropriate bicounty commission, Montgomery County, or Prince George's County".</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the statement shall be filed as prescribed in &#xA7; 15-602 of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The executive director of a bicounty commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">provide forms for the statements required by this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">make the forms available in the office of the executive director; and</section><section prefix="(3)">provide a sufficient number of forms to the chief administrative officers of Montgomery and Prince George's counties for use by applicants and commissioners.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each commissioner shall file the statement with the chief administrative officer of the county from which the commissioner is appointed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Commissioners of the Washington Suburban Transit Commission shall also file a financial disclosure statement with the State Ethics Commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a commissioner of the Washington Suburban Transit Commission holds another public office and is required to file a financial disclosure statement under another State or local law, the commissioner may comply with subsection (b) of this section by submitting a copy of the statement filed in accordance with the other law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The statement shall be supplemented to include any additional information required by this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
