<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="20-1036" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-20-1036</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission may commence a civil action in the appropriate circuit court if the Commission has probable cause to believe that:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">a person or group of persons is engaged in a pattern or practice of resistance to the full enjoyment of any of the rights granted by this part and Subtitle 7 of this title; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">any group of persons has been denied any of the rights granted by this part and Subtitle 7 of this title; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the resistance or denial raises an issue of general public importance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission or other party at whose request a subpoena is issued under this part may enforce a subpoena in appropriate proceedings in the circuit court for the county in which the person to whom the subpoena was addressed resides, was served, or transacts business.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In a civil action under subsection (a) of this section, the court may:<section prefix="(i)">award preventive relief, including a permanent or temporary injunction, restraining order, or other order against the person responsible for a violation of Subtitle 7 of this title as necessary to assure the full enjoyment of the rights granted by Subtitle 7 of this title;</section><section prefix="(ii)">award other relief the court considers appropriate, including monetary damages to aggrieved persons; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">to vindicate the public interest, assess a civil penalty against the respondent:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In a civil action under this section, the court may allow the prevailing party, including the Commission, reasonable attorney's fees and costs.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On timely application, a person may intervene in a civil action commenced by the Commission under subsection (a) or (b) of this section, if the action involves:<section prefix="(i)">an alleged discriminatory housing practice to which the person is an aggrieved person; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a conciliation agreement to which the person is a party.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court may grant any appropriate relief to any intervening party that is authorized to be granted to a plaintiff in a civil action under &#xA7; 20-1035 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
