<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-1214" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-2-1214</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Office shall receive and analyze requests from members of the General Assembly for reimbursement and from other persons for payment of legislative expenses, including:<section prefix="(i)">office rent;</section><section prefix="(ii)">secretarial and other services;</section><section prefix="(iii)">telephone and other communication expenses;</section><section prefix="(iv)">equipment;</section><section prefix="(v)">supplies; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">travel.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Office shall provide the reimbursement or make payments as provided in the State budget and account for the reimbursements and payments.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Office shall make payments and reimbursements consistent with the policies of the President and the Speaker, the Management Subcommittee, and the Legislative Policy Committee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The President and the Speaker may authorize the Office to create accounts for revenues received from payment of fees or charges and to utilize the funds to provide services to individuals, organizations, or other units of State or local governments.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Funds in the accounts may only be expended in accordance with the budget or by budget amendment.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On directive by the President and the Speaker, unexpended revenues in the accounts may revert to the State or may be retained for expenditure in a subsequent budget.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Comptroller's Office shall be notified of accounts created in accordance with this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
