<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-10-625</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>625</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person in interest may request a unit of the State government to correct inaccurate or incomplete information in a public record that:<section prefix="(1)">the unit keeps; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the person in interest is authorized to inspect.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A request under this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">be in writing;</section><section prefix="(2)">describe the requested change precisely; and</section><section prefix="(3)">state the reasons for the change.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 30 days after receiving a request under this section, a unit shall:<section prefix="(i)">make or refuse to make the requested change; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">give the person in interest written notice of the action taken.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A notice of refusal shall contain the unit's reasons for the refusal.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the unit finally refuses a request under this section, the person in interest may submit to the unit a concise statement that, in 5 pages or less, states the reasons for the request and for disagreement with the refusal.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Whenever the unit provides the disputed information to a third party, the unit shall provide to that party a copy of the statement submitted to the unit by the person in interest.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a unit is subject to Subtitle 2 of this title, a person or governmental unit may seek administrative and judicial review in accordance with that subtitle of:<section prefix="(1)">a decision of the unit to deny:<section prefix="(i)">a request to change a public record; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a right to submit a statement of disagreement; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the failure of the unit to provide the statement to a third party.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
