<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-2007</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>2007</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Installed electricity generation capacity" means the maximum direct current power output in watts of the array of photovoltaic modules rated under standard test condition.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Photovoltaic property" means solar energy property with an installed electricity generation capacity of 20 kilowatts or less that uses a solar photovoltaic process to generate electricity and that meets applicable performance and quality standards and certification requirements in effect at the time of acquisition of the property, as specified by the Maryland Energy Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Program" means the Solar Energy Grant Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Solar energy property" means equipment that uses solar energy:<section prefix="1.">to generate electricity;</section><section prefix="2.">to heat or cool a structure or provide hot water for use in a structure; or</section><section prefix="3.">to provide solar process heat.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Solar energy property" does not include a swimming pool, hot tub, or any other energy storage medium that has a function other than storage.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Solar water heating property" means solar energy property that:<section prefix="(i)">when installed in connection with a structure, uses solar energy for the purpose of providing hot water for use within the structure; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">meets applicable performance and quality standards and certification requirements in effect at the time of acquisition of the property, as specified by the Maryland Energy Administration.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Solar Energy Grant Program in the Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The purpose of the Program is to provide grants to individuals, local governments, and businesses for a portion of the costs of acquiring and installing photovoltaic property and solar water heating property.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Administration shall:<section prefix="(1)">administer the Program;</section><section prefix="(2)">establish application procedures for the Program; and</section><section prefix="(3)">award grants from the Program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A grant awarded under the Program may not exceed:<section prefix="(1)">for photovoltaic property, the lesser of $2,500 per kilowatt of installed electricity generation capacity or $10,000; and</section><section prefix="(2)">for solar water heating property, the lesser of $3,000 or 30% of the total installed cost of the solar water heating property.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Subject to the limitations in subsection (e) of this section, the Administration may adjust the grant amounts under the Program to reflect market conditions and the prevailing prices of photovoltaic property and solar water heating property.</section>
  </text>
</law>
