<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-1A-01" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-9-1A-01</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Applicant" means a person who applies for any license required under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Associated equipment" means hardware located on the licensee's premises that is connected to the video lottery system for the purpose of performing communication, validation, or other functions, but not including the communication facilities of a regulated utility or the video lottery terminals.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Average payout percentage" means the average percentage of money used by players to play a video lottery terminal that is returned to players of that video lottery terminal.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Award" means the act, by the Video Lottery Facility Location Commission, of approving the issuance of a video lottery operation license by the State Lottery Commission to an applicant for the operation of video lottery terminals at a specified location.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Background investigation" means a security, criminal, and credit investigation of a person who applies for or who is granted a license under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Career offender" means a person whose behavior is pursued in an occupational manner or context for the purpose of economic gain and who utilizes methods that are deemed by the Commission as criminal violations inimical to the interest of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Career offender cartel" means a group of persons who operate together as career offenders.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Central monitor and control system" means a central system provided to and controlled by the Commission to which video lottery terminals communicate for purposes of:<section prefix="(1)">information retrieval;</section><section prefix="(2)">retrieval of the win and loss determination from video lottery terminals; and</section><section prefix="(3)">programs to activate and disable video lottery terminals.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Central Repository" means the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository of the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Commission" means the State Lottery and Gaming Control Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Control" means the authority to direct the management and policies of an applicant or licensee.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Costs" means, unless the context otherwise requires, the expenses incurred by the Commission in the administration of this subtitle, including:<section prefix="(1)">the costs of leasing or the capitalized cost of purchasing the video lottery terminals, central monitor and control system, and associated equipment and software;</section><section prefix="(2)">the costs to repair and maintain the video lottery terminals, central monitor and control system, and associated equipment and software to the extent these costs are not included in the costs of leasing or purchasing the video lottery terminals, central monitor and control system, and associated equipment and software;</section><section prefix="(3)">the costs of testing and examination of video lottery terminals and the central monitor and control system; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the costs of performing background investigations and other related activities.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Family" means spouse, parents, grandparents, children, grandchildren, siblings, uncles, aunts, nephews, nieces, fathers-in-law, mothers-in-law, daughters-in-law, sons-in-law, brothers-in-law, and sisters-in-law, whether by whole blood or half blood,  marriage, adoption, or natural relationship.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Institutional investor" means:<section prefix="(1)">a retirement fund administered by a public agency for the exclusive benefit of federal, state, or local public employees;</section><section prefix="(2)">an investment company registered under the Investment Company Act of 1940;</section><section prefix="(3)">a collective investment trust organized by banks under Part 9 of the rules of the Comptroller of the Currency;</section><section prefix="(4)">a closed end investment trust;</section><section prefix="(5)">a chartered or licensed life insurance company;</section><section prefix="(6)">a property and casualty insurance company;</section><section prefix="(7)">a banking or other chartered or licensed lending institution;</section><section prefix="(8)">an investment advisor registered under the Investment Advisors Act of 1940; or</section><section prefix="(9)">any other person registered in any foreign jurisdiction and regulated in accordance with a statute of any foreign jurisdiction that the Commission determines to be substantially similar to that regulated by the Investment Company Act of 1940 or the Investment Advisors Act of 1940.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"License" means, unless the context otherwise requires, a license required under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Licensee" means an applicant who has been issued a license required under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Manufacturer" means a person:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">that is engaged in the business of designing, building, constructing, assembling, manufacturing, or distributing a central monitor and control system, video lottery terminals, associated equipment or software, or the cabinet in which a video lottery terminal is housed;</section><section prefix="(ii)">that produces a product that is intended for sale, lease, or other assignment to the Commission or a licensee; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">that contracts with the Commission or a licensee for the sale, lease, or other assignment of a product described in  item (i) of this item; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">that is engaged in the business of designing, building, constructing, assembling, manufacturing, or distributing table games or table game equipment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">that produces a product related to table games that is intended for sale, lease, or other assignment to a licensee; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">that contracts with a licensee for the sale, lease, or other assignment of a product described in item (i) of this item.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Own" means having a beneficial or proprietary interest of at least 5% in the property or business of an applicant or licensee.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Player" means an individual who plays a video lottery terminal at a video lottery facility licensed by the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Proceeds" means the part of the amount of money bet through video lottery terminals and table games that is not returned to successful players but is otherwise allocated under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, "proceeds" does not include money given away by a video lottery operation licensee as free promotional play and used by players to bet in a video lottery terminal.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">After the first fiscal year of operations, the exclusion specified in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph may not exceed a percentage established by the Commission by regulation of the proceeds received from video lottery terminals in the prior fiscal year by the video lottery operation licensee under &#xA7; 9-1A-27(a)(2) and (c)(1)(ii) of this subtitle.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(v)">"Progressive jackpot" means a prize that increases as one or more video lottery terminals are connected to a progressive jackpot system.</section>
    <section prefix="(w)">"Progressive jackpot system" means a system capable of linking one or more video lottery terminals in one or more licensed facilities and offering one or more common progressive jackpots.</section>
    <section prefix="(w-1)">"Table game equipment" means equipment that is related to the operation of table games and that is owned or leased by the video lottery facility and located on the video lottery facility's premises.</section>
    <section prefix="(w-2)">"Table games" means:<section prefix="(1)">roulette, baccarat, blackjack, craps, big six wheel, minibaccarat, poker, pai gow poker, and sic bo, or any variation and composites of such games; and</section><section prefix="(2)">gaming tournaments in which players compete against one another in one or more of the games authorized under item (1) of this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(x)">"Video lottery" means gaming or betting conducted using a video lottery terminal.</section>
    <section prefix="(y)">"Video lottery destination location" means a location that is eligible for or has been awarded in the manner provided by law a video lottery operation license.</section>
    <section prefix="(z)">"Video lottery employee" means an employee of a person who holds a license.</section>
    <section prefix="(aa)">"Video lottery facility" means a facility at which players play video lottery terminals under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(bb)">"Video lottery operation license" means a license awarded by the Video Lottery Facility Location Commission and issued by the State Lottery Commission to a person that allows players to operate video lottery terminals.</section>
    <section prefix="(cc)">"Video lottery operator" means a person licensed to operate a video lottery facility under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(dd)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Video lottery terminal" means any machine or other device that, on insertion of a bill, coin, token, voucher, ticket, coupon, or similar item, or on payment of any consideration:<section prefix="(i)">is available to play or simulate the play of any game of chance in which the results, including the options available to the player, are randomly determined by the machine or other device; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">by the element of chance, may deliver or entitle the player who operates the machine or device to receive cash, premiums, merchandise, tokens, or anything of value, whether the payout is made automatically from the device or in any other manner.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Video lottery terminal" includes a machine or device:<section prefix="(i)">that does not directly dispense money, tokens, or anything of value to winning players; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">described under paragraph (1) of this subsection that uses an electronic credit system making the deposit of bills, coins, or tokens unnecessary.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Video lottery terminal" does not include an authorized slot machine operated by an eligible organization under Title 12, Subtitle 3 of the Criminal Law Article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
