<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-15-853</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this part the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>853</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this part the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Aggrieved party" means:<section prefix="(1)">a property owner whose property:<section prefix="(i)">adjoins, fronts, or is located near the subject property; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">is located within sight or sound of the subject property; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">an individual  located within the same subdivision as the subject property or who lives up to three-quarters of a mile by road or otherwise one-half mile away from the subject property.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Applicant" means a person that is:<section prefix="(i)">a title owner or contract purchaser of land that is the subject of an application;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a trustee who has an interest in land that is the subject of an application, excluding trustees described in a mortgage or deed of trust; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a holder of  at least a 10% interest in land that is the subject of an application.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Applicant" includes a person that is an officer or director of a corporation that actually holds title to the land or is a contract purchaser of the land that is the subject of an application.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Applicant" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">a financial institution that has loaned money or extended financing for the acquisition, development, or construction of or improvements on the land that is the subject of an application;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a municipal or public corporation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a public authority;</section><section prefix="(iv)">an electric company or electric supplier applying for a certificate of public convenience and necessity under &#xA7; 7-207 or &#xA7; 7-208 of the Public Utilities Article; or</section><section prefix="(v)">a person that is hired or retained as an accountant, attorney, architect, engineer, land use consultant, economic consultant, real estate agent, real estate broker, traffic consultant, or traffic engineer.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Application" means:<section prefix="(1)">an application for a zoning map amendment as part of  a piecemeal or floating zone rezoning proceeding;</section><section prefix="(2)">a formal application for a comprehensive map planning change or zoning change during the county comprehensive land use plan update;</section><section prefix="(3)">an application for a map amendment to the county water and sewerage plan;</section><section prefix="(4)">a request made under Article 23A, &#xA7; 9(c) of the Code for the Board to approve the placement of annexed land in a zoning classification that allows a land use that is substantially different from the use for the land authorized in the zoning classification of the county applicable at the time of annexation; or</section><section prefix="(5)">an application to create a district or easement or other interest in real property as part of an agricultural land preservation program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Board" means the Board of County Commissioners for Frederick County.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Board member" includes an individual elected or appointed to the Board or a candidate who takes the oath of office for the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Business entity" means:<section prefix="(1)">a sole proprietorship;</section><section prefix="(2)">a corporation;</section><section prefix="(3)">a partnership; or</section><section prefix="(4)">a limited liability company.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Candidate" means a candidate for the Board who becomes a member of the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Contribution" means a payment or transfer of money or property worth at least $100, calculated cumulatively during the pendency of the application, to a candidate or a treasurer or political committee of a candidate.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Partnership" includes a general partnership, a limited liability partnership, a limited partnership, a limited liability limited partnership, or a joint venture.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Party of record" means a person that participated in a proceeding on an application before the Board by appearing at a public hearing or filing a statement in an official record.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Pendency of the application" means any time between the acceptance by the County Department of Planning and Zoning of a filing of an application and the earlier of:<section prefix="(1)">2 years; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the expiration of 30 days after:<section prefix="(i)">the Board has taken final action on the application; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the application is withdrawn.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Political committee" means a committee specifically created to promote the candidacy of a Board member who is running for an elective office.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Treasurer" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Election Law Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
