<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-2-1246</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "publication" includes any report, study, or notification....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1246</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "publication" includes any report, study, or notification.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For each publication that an official or unit of the State government intends to distribute or submit to the General Assembly or to any committee, staff agency, or employee of the General Assembly, the official or unit shall:<section prefix="(1)">submit one copy to the President and one copy to the Speaker in the format requested by the President and the Speaker;</section><section prefix="(2)">submit five printed copies to the library of the Department; and</section><section prefix="(3)">in the case of a publication to be distributed to a committee of the General Assembly:<section prefix="(i)">unless the publication is being submitted to the committee as specifically required by law, obtain approval for the distribution from the committee chair; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">comply with the distribution requirements of the committee.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An official or unit:<section prefix="(1)">shall submit to the library of the Department, in addition to the copies of a publication required under subsection (b)(2) of this section, any additional copies of the publication requested by the library on behalf of a member of the General Assembly; and</section><section prefix="(2)">may give a publication directly to a member of the General Assembly only if:<section prefix="(i)">the President and the Speaker have given written approval for distribution of the publication to each member of the General Assembly; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the member asks for the publication.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">To assist the Department in carrying out its duties under subsection (f) of this section, each publication submitted to the General Assembly or to any committee, staff agency, or employee of the General Assembly in fulfillment of a duty imposed by law shall specify the law under which the publication is being submitted.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">keep a list of the publications of the officials and units;</section><section prefix="(2)">periodically send the list to each member of the General Assembly; and</section><section prefix="(3)">on request of a member of the General Assembly, obtain a publication of an official or unit for the member.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The library of the Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">catalog and preserve the publications that officials and units submit as required by law; and</section><section prefix="(2)">collect, catalog, and preserve any other publication that the Department considers necessary or that the Department is directed by the President or the Speaker to collect, catalog, and preserve.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
