<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-2-1702</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1702</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not willfully disrupt, interfere with, attempt to disrupt, or attempt to interfere with a session, meeting, or proceeding of the General Assembly, the Senate, or the House or any of their committees, by:<section prefix="(1)">making, alone or with another person, a noise that tends to be disruptive;</section><section prefix="(2)">using abusive or obscene language;</section><section prefix="(3)">making an obscene gesture;</section><section prefix="(4)">engaging in violent, tumultuous, or threatening behavior;</section><section prefix="(5)">refusing to comply with the lawful order of the police to disperse; or</section><section prefix="(6)">doing any other disruptive or interfering act.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not picket willfully in a building where:<section prefix="(1)">the Senate or the House has a chamber;</section><section prefix="(2)">a member of the General Assembly has an official office; or</section><section prefix="(3)">a committee of the General Assembly, the Senate, or the House has an office.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not prevent or attempt to prevent, willfully and with force, the performance of a function, power, or duty by a member, officer, or employee of the General Assembly, the Senate, or the House or any of their committees.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person may not:<section prefix="(1)">willfully and without legal authority, obtain, withhold, destroy, deface, or alter an official document or record of the General Assembly, the Senate, or the House or any of their committees; or</section><section prefix="(2)">without legal authority, possess, withhold, destroy, or deface real or personal property that the General Assembly, the Senate, or the House or any of their committees owns or uses.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">a law enforcement officer of any state or of the federal government who is carrying out duties of the office; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a person whom the officer summons to help in making an arrest or in preserving the peace.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not willfully bring an assault weapon or other firearm or destructive device, as defined in &#xA7; 4-501 of the Criminal Law Article, into or have an assault weapon or other firearm or destructive device in a building where:<section prefix="(i)">the Senate or the House has a chamber;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a member, officer, or employee of the General Assembly has an official office; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a committee of the General Assembly, the Senate, or the House has an office.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person who violates any provision of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $1,000 or imprisonment not exceeding 1 year or both.</section>
  </text>
</law>
