<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-2-706</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>706</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Committee shall:<section prefix="(1)">perform all duties assigned to it by law or by legislative rules;</section><section prefix="(2)">from time to time, recommend to the presiding officers any changes in or amendments to the rules of legislative ethics;</section><section prefix="(3)">on request of a member of the General Assembly, issue an advisory opinion regarding the legislative ethics of an action taken or contemplated to be taken by the member;</section><section prefix="(4)">on its own motion, issue advisory opinions as it deems necessary;</section><section prefix="(5)">at the request of the President or the Speaker, make recommendations concerning matters referred to the Committee;</section><section prefix="(6)">as it deems necessary, issue guidelines and establish procedures for the implementation of the rules of legislative ethics; and</section><section prefix="(7)">maintain public records as the rules require.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Committee shall maintain the statements filed by members of the General Assembly under Title 15, Subtitle 5 of this article and, during normal office hours, make the statements available to the public for examination and copying.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Committee shall maintain a record of:<section prefix="(i)">the name and home address of each individual who examines or copies a statement filed with the Committee by a member of the General Assembly; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the name of the member whose statement was examined or copied.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On the request of the member whose statement was examined or copied, the Committee shall forward to the member a copy of the record maintained by the Committee under paragraph (2)(i) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
