<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-502" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-10-502</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Administrative function" means the administration of:<section prefix="(i)">a law of the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a law of a political subdivision of the State; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a rule, regulation, or bylaw of a public body.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Administrative function" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">an advisory function;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a judicial function;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a legislative function;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a quasi-judicial function; or</section><section prefix="(v)">a quasi-legislative function.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Advisory function" means the study of a matter of public concern or the making of recommendations on the matter, under a delegation of responsibility by:<section prefix="(1)">law;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Governor or an official who is subject to the policy direction of the Governor;</section><section prefix="(3)">the chief executive officer of a political subdivision of the State or an official who is subject to the policy direction of the chief executive officer; or</section><section prefix="(4)">formal action by or for a public body that exercises an administrative, judicial, legislative, quasi-judicial, or quasi-legislative function.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Board" means the State Open Meetings Law Compliance Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Judicial function" means the exercise of any power of the Judicial Branch of the State government.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Judicial function" includes the exercise of:<section prefix="(i)">a power for which Article IV, &#xA7; 1 of the Maryland Constitution provides;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a function of a grand jury;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a function of a petit jury;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a function of the Commission on Judicial Disabilities; and</section><section prefix="(v)">a function of a judicial nominating commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Judicial function" does not include the exercise of rulemaking power by a court.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Legislative function" means the process or act of:<section prefix="(1)">approving, disapproving, enacting, amending, or repealing a law or other measure to set public policy;</section><section prefix="(2)">approving or disapproving an appointment;</section><section prefix="(3)">proposing or ratifying a constitution or constitutional amendment; or</section><section prefix="(4)">proposing or ratifying a charter or charter amendment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Meet" means to convene a quorum of a public body for the consideration or transaction of public business.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Public body" means an entity that:<section prefix="(i)">consists of at least 2 individuals; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is created by:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Public body" includes:<section prefix="(i)">any multimember board, commission, or committee appointed by the Governor or the chief executive authority of a political subdivision of the State, or appointed by an official who is subject to the policy direction of the Governor or chief executive authority of the political subdivision, if the entity includes in its membership at least 2 individuals not employed by the State or the political subdivision;</section><section prefix="(ii)">any multimember board, commission, or committee that:</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Maryland School for the Blind.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Public body" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">any single member entity;</section><section prefix="(ii)">any judicial nominating commission;</section><section prefix="(iii)">any grand jury;</section><section prefix="(iv)">any petit jury;</section><section prefix="(v)">the Appalachian States Low Level Radioactive Waste Commission established in &#xA7; 7-302 of the Environment Article;</section><section prefix="(vi)">except when a court is exercising rulemaking power, any court established in accordance with Article IV of the Maryland Constitution;</section><section prefix="(vii)">the Governor's cabinet, the Governor's Executive Council as provided in Title 8, Subtitle 1 of this article, or any committee of the Executive Council;</section><section prefix="(viii)">a local government's counterpart to the Governor's cabinet, Executive Council, or any committee of the counterpart of the Executive Council;</section><section prefix="(ix)">except as provided in paragraph (1) of this subsection, a subcommittee of a public body as defined under paragraph (2)(i) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(x)">the governing body of a hospital as defined in &#xA7; 19-301 of the Health - General Article; and</section><section prefix="(xi)">a self-insurance pool that is established in accordance with Title 19, Subtitle 6 of the Insurance Article or &#xA7; 9-404 of the Labor and Employment Article by:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Quasi-judicial function" means a determination of:<section prefix="(1)">a contested case to which Subtitle 2 of this title applies;</section><section prefix="(2)">a proceeding before an administrative agency for which Title 7, Chapter 200 of the Maryland Rules would govern judicial review; or</section><section prefix="(3)">a complaint by the Board in accordance with this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Quasi-legislative function" means the process or act of:<section prefix="(1)">adopting, disapproving, amending, or repealing a rule, regulation, or bylaw that has the force of law, including a rule of a court;</section><section prefix="(2)">approving, disapproving, or amending a budget; or</section><section prefix="(3)">approving, disapproving, or amending a contract.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Quorum" means:<section prefix="(1)">a majority of the members of a public body; or</section><section prefix="(2)">any different number that law requires.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
