<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-15-504</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>504</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to members of the General Assembly.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, an official or employee may not, for contingent compensation, assist or represent a party in any matter before or involving any unit of the State or a political subdivision of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Paragraph (2) of this subsection does not apply to assistance to or representation of a party:<section prefix="(i)">in a judicial or quasi-judicial proceeding, including a proceeding before an administrative law judge in the Office of Administrative Hearings, or a matter preliminary, incidental, or collateral to a judicial or quasi-judicial proceeding; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">in a matter before or involving the Workers' Compensation Commission, the Maryland Automobile Insurance Fund, or the Criminal Injuries Compensation Board.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a member of the General Assembly may not, for compensation, assist or represent a party in any matter before or involving any unit of the State or a political subdivision of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Paragraph (1) of this subsection does not apply to assistance to or representation of a party:<section prefix="(i)">in matters relating to the performance of ministerial acts by a governmental unit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">in matters involving the member's regular business, employment, or profession, in which contact with a governmental unit:<section prefix="1.">is an incidental part of the business, employment, or profession;</section><section prefix="2.">is made in the manner that is customary for persons in that business, employment, or profession; and</section><section prefix="3.">is not for contingent compensation;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">in a judicial or quasi-judicial proceeding, including a proceeding before an administrative law judge in the Office of Administrative Hearings, or a matter preliminary, incidental, or collateral to a judicial or quasi-judicial proceeding;</section><section prefix="(iv)">in a matter before or involving the Workers' Compensation Commission, the Maryland Automobile Insurance Fund, or the Criminal Injuries Compensation Board; or</section><section prefix="(v)">in a matter in which the assistance or representation, other than for contingent compensation, was commenced by the member of the General Assembly before:<section prefix="1.">the member filed a certificate of candidacy for election to the General Assembly at a time when the member was not an incumbent; or</section><section prefix="2.">if the member was appointed to fill a vacancy, the date of appointment.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A member of the General Assembly may not assist or represent a person, including himself or herself, for compensation before a State or local governmental agency in any matter involving:<section prefix="(i)">procurement; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the adoption of regulations.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Paragraph (1) of this subsection does not apply to an administrative proceeding conducted in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 (Administrative Procedure Act -- Contested Cases) of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for a former member of the General Assembly, who shall be subject to the restrictions provided under paragraph (2) of this subsection, a former official or employee may not assist or represent a party, other than the State, in a case, contract, or other specific matter for compensation if:<section prefix="(i)">the matter involves State government; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the former official or employee participated significantly in the matter as an official or employee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, until the conclusion of the next regular session that begins after the member leaves office, a former member of the General Assembly may not assist or represent another party for compensation in a matter that is the subject of legislative action.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The limitation under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph on representation by a former member of the General Assembly does not apply to the former member's representation of a municipal corporation, county, or State governmental entity.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Notwithstanding subsection (a)(3) of this section or &#xA7; 15-502 of this subtitle, a full-time official or employee in the Judicial Branch may not represent a party before a court or unit of the Judicial Branch except in the discharge of official duties.</section>
  </text>
</law>
