<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsg" order_by="gsg" level="1">State Government</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsg-6.5-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this title the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Acquisition" means:<section prefix="(1)">a sale, lease, transfer, merger, or joint venture that results in the disposal of the assets of a nonprofit health entity to a for-profit corporation or entity or to a mutual benefit corporation or entity when a substantial or significant portion of the assets of the nonprofit health entity are involved or will be involved in the agreement or transaction;</section><section prefix="(2)">a transfer of ownership, control, responsibility, or governance of a substantial or significant portion of the assets, operations, or business of the nonprofit health entity to any for-profit corporation or entity or to any mutual benefit corporation or entity;</section><section prefix="(3)">a public offering of stock; or</section><section prefix="(4)">a conversion to a for-profit entity.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Administration" means the Maryland Insurance Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Department" means the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Health maintenance organization" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 19-701 of the Health - General Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Hospital" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 19-301 of the Health - General Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Nonprofit health entity" means:<section prefix="(1)">a nonprofit hospital;</section><section prefix="(2)">a nonprofit health service plan; or</section><section prefix="(3)">a nonprofit health maintenance organization.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Nonprofit health service plan" means a corporation without capital stock with a certificate of authority from the Insurance Commissioner to operate as a nonprofit health service plan or a nonprofit dental plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Public assets" include:<section prefix="(1)">assets held for the benefit of the public or the community;</section><section prefix="(2)">assets in which the public has an ownership interest; and</section><section prefix="(3)">assets owned by a governmental entity.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Regulating entity" means:<section prefix="(1)">for an acquisition of a nonprofit hospital, the Attorney General in consultation with the Department;</section><section prefix="(2)">for an acquisition of a nonprofit health service plan, the Administration; and</section><section prefix="(3)">for an acquisition of a nonprofit health maintenance organization, the Administration.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Transferee" means the person in an acquisition that receives the ownership or control of the nonprofit health entity that is the subject of the acquisition.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Transferor" means the nonprofit health entity that is the subject of the acquisition, or the corporation that owns the nonprofit health entity that is the subject of the acquisition.</section>
  </text>
</law>
