<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-23-215.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>215.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to a member who:<section prefix="(1)">on or before June 30, 2011, is subject to the Alternate Contributory Pension Selection;</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">is separated from employment for 4 years or less; or</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">is separated from employment for more than 4 years for military service that meets the requirements of the federal Uniformed Services Employment and Reemployment Rights Act; and</section><section prefix="2.">resumes employment within 1 year of leaving military service in a position that is included in the Employees' Pension System or Teachers' Pension System;</section></section></section><section prefix="(3)">does not withdraw the member's accumulated contributions; and</section><section prefix="(4)">does not become a retiree.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A member described in subsection (a) of this section who on or before June 30, 2016, resumes employment and is rehired into a position that is included in the Employees' Pension System or Teachers' Pension System, shall resume participation in the Alternate Contributory Pension Selection.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">On or before October 1, 2012, and each October 1 through October 1, 2016, the Board of Trustees shall submit a report in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article to the Joint Committee on Pensions that provides the number of members described under subsection (a) of this section who were:<section prefix="(1)">rehired in the preceding fiscal year into a position included in the Employees' Pension System or Teachers' Pension System; and</section><section prefix="(2)">participating in the Alternate Contributory Pension Selection.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
