<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-511" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-2-511</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to employees of:<section prefix="(1)">the Maryland Environmental Service;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Northeast Maryland Waste Disposal Authority; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the Baltimore Metropolitan Council.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to the regulations adopted under &#xA7; 2-503 of this subtitle, an employee or, while receiving an allowance under the Employees' Retirement System of the State of Maryland or the Employees' Pension System of the State of Maryland, an employee's surviving spouse:<section prefix="(1)">may enroll and participate in the health insurance or other benefit options established under the Program; and</section><section prefix="(2)">except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, is subject to the same terms and conditions as those provided under &#xA7; 2-507 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">While receiving an allowance under the Employees' Retirement System of the State of Maryland or the Employees' Pension System of the State of Maryland, a former employee or a former employee's surviving spouse or dependent child:<section prefix="(1)">may enroll and participate in the health insurance benefit options established under the Program; and</section><section prefix="(2)">except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, is subject to the same terms and conditions as those provided under &#xA7; 2-508 of this subtitle, with the employee's service with the Maryland Environmental Service, Northeast Maryland Waste Disposal Authority, and the Baltimore Metropolitan Council being included as part of the employee's State service.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For each participant under this section, the Maryland Environmental Service, the Northeast Maryland Waste Disposal Authority, and the Baltimore Metropolitan Council or any successor agency, shall pay to the State the respective employer share of the cost of the Program based on the State subsidy allowed under this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
