<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-21-116</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>116</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">By resolution, the Board of Trustees shall specify the powers of the Investment Committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Investment Committee shall advise the Board of Trustees and make recommendations on:<section prefix="(1)">the investment programs;</section><section prefix="(2)">compliance of the investment programs with the policies of the Board of Trustees; and</section><section prefix="(3)">bonding for employees of the State Retirement Agency in the form and amount required by law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to subsection (d) of this section, the Board of Trustees shall adopt an investment policy manual that details:<section prefix="(i)">the functions of the Investment Division of the State Retirement Agency;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the goals and objectives of the several investment programs; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the policies that govern the selection and retention of investments.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Investment Committee shall:<section prefix="(i)">prepare and maintain the investment policy manual; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">submit the investment policy manual, and any subsequent amendments to the manual, to the Board of Trustees for approval.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Consistent with minority business purchasing standards applicable to units of State government under the State Finance and Procurement Article and consistent with the fiduciary duties of the Board of Trustees, the Board of Trustees shall direct the Investment Committee to attempt to use to the greatest extent feasible minority business enterprises to provide brokerage and investment management services to the Board.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For purposes of this subsection, brokerage and investment management services shall include services relating to all allocated asset classes.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">To assist it in achieving the goal described under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Investment Committee shall undertake measures to remove any barriers that limit full participation by minority business enterprises in brokerage and investment management services opportunities afforded under this title.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The measures undertaken by the Investment Committee shall include the use of a wide variety of media, including the State Retirement Agency's website, to provide notice to a broad and varied range of potential providers about the brokerage and investment management services opportunities afforded by the State Retirement Agency.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In consultation with the Governor's Office of Minority Affairs and the Investment Committee, the Board of Trustees shall develop guidelines to assist the Investment Committee in identifying and evaluating qualified minority business enterprises in order to help the State Retirement Agency achieve the objective for greater use of minority business enterprises for brokerage and investment management services.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On or before September 1 each year, the Investment Committee shall submit a report to the Board of Trustees, the Governor's Office of Minority Affairs and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly on:<section prefix="(i)">the identity of the minority business enterprise brokerage and investment management services firms used by the Investment Committee in the immediately preceding fiscal year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the percentage and dollar value of the assets that are under the control of the Investment Committee that are under the investment control of minority business enterprise brokerage and investment management services firms for each allocated asset class; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the measures the Investment Committee undertook in the immediately preceding fiscal year in accordance with paragraph (2)(ii) of this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
