<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-28-402</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in subsection (g) of this section, an individual who is receiving a service retir...</catch_line>
  <order_by>402</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (g) of this section, an individual who is receiving a service retirement allowance or vested allowance may accept employment with a participating employer on a permanent, temporary, or contractual basis, without any reduction in the allowance, if:<section prefix="(1)">the individual immediately notifies the Board of Trustees of the individual's intention to accept the employment; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the individual specifies the compensation to be received.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of Trustees shall reduce the allowance of an individual who accepts employment as provided under subsection (a) of this section if the individual's current employer is a participating employer other than the State and is the same participating employer that employed the individual at the time of the individual's last separation from employment with a participating employer before the individual commenced receiving a service retirement allowance or vested allowance.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The reduction required under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall equal the amount that the sum of the individual's initial annual basic allowance and the individual's annual compensation exceeds the average final compensation used to compute the basic allowance.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except for an individual whose allowance is subject to a reduction as provided under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the reduction of an allowance under this subsection does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">an individual whose average final compensation was less than $10,000 and who is reemployed on a temporary or contractual basis;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an individual who is serving in an elected position as an official of a participating governmental unit or as a constitutional officer for a county that is a participating governmental unit; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">an individual who has been retired for 9 years, beginning on January 1 after the date the individual retires.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An individual who is receiving a service retirement allowance or a vested allowance and who is reemployed by a participating employer may not receive creditable service or eligibility service during the period of reemployment.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The individual's compensation during the period of reemployment may not be subject to the employer pickup provisions of &#xA7; 21-303 of this article or any reduction or deduction as a member contribution for pension or retirement purposes.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The State Retirement Agency shall institute appropriate reporting procedures with the affected payroll systems to ensure compliance with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Immediately on the employment of any individual receiving a service retirement allowance or a vested allowance, a participating employer shall notify the State Retirement Agency of the type of employment and the anticipated earnings of the individual.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At least once each year, in a format specified by the State Retirement Agency, each participating employer shall provide the State Retirement Agency with a list of all employees included on any payroll of the employer, the Social Security numbers of the employees, and their earnings for that year.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">An individual who is rehired under this section may not be rehired within 45 days of the date the individual retired if the individual's current employer is a participating employer other than the State and is the same participating employer that employed the individual at the time of the individual's last separation from employment with a participating employer before the individual commenced receiving a service retirement allowance.</section>
  </text>
</law>
