<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="30-210.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-30-210.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "covered individual" means an employee of an employing institution with discretionary authority over the management or administration of any of the supplemental retirement plans or the management or disposition of the assets of any of the supplemental retirement plans.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to the provisions of this section, the State shall indemnify a covered individual who is, or is threatened to be made, a party to an action or proceeding, including an administrative or investigative proceeding, by reason of the covered individual's service as an employee of an employing institution with discretionary authority over the management or administration of any of the supplemental retirement plans or the management or disposition of the assets of any of the supplemental retirement plans.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "expenses" include:<section prefix="(i)">reasonable attorney's fees;</section><section prefix="(ii)">judgments;</section><section prefix="(iii)">fines; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">other expenses that were actually and reasonably incurred by the individual in connection with the action or proceeding.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">With respect to a civil, administrative, or investigative action or proceeding, the State shall indemnify a covered individual for the expenses of the action or proceeding if the covered individual acted:<section prefix="(i)">in good faith; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">in a manner the covered individual reasonably believed to be in or not opposed to the best interest of the supplemental retirement plans.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">With respect to a criminal action or proceeding, the State shall indemnify a covered individual for the expenses of the action or proceeding if the covered individual:<section prefix="(i)">acted in good faith;</section><section prefix="(ii)">acted in a manner the covered individual reasonably believed to be in or not opposed to the best interest of the supplemental retirement plans; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">did not have reasonable cause to believe that the covered individual's conduct was unlawful.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Any termination of an action or proceeding does not, of itself, create a presumption that the covered individual did not meet the standards for indemnification described in subsection (b)(2) and (3) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The State may not indemnify:<section prefix="(1)">a covered individual with respect to an action or proceeding as to which the covered individual was held liable for gross negligence or willful misconduct in the performance of the covered individual's duty to the supplemental retirement plans; or</section><section prefix="(2)">an independent contractor furnishing services to the supplemental retirement plans.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State shall provide insurance for a covered individual eligible for indemnification under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For the purpose of paragraph (1) of this subsection, the State may provide self-insurance under terms and conditions satisfactory to the State Treasurer.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A covered individual may not be required to pay amounts attributable to liability described in this section because the State does not provide adequate insurance coverage or otherwise fails to indemnify in accordance with this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
