<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-5-207</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>207</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The head of each principal unit shall appoint:<section prefix="(i)">a fair practices officer who:<section prefix="1.">reports directly to the head of the unit; and</section><section prefix="2.">is an assistant secretary or an employee of the unit with stature similar to that of an assistant secretary; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">an appropriate number of equal employment opportunity officers for the unit.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If necessary, the fair practices officer of a unit may also be the unit's equal employment opportunity officer.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">All appointments under this subsection shall be made in accordance with position descriptions approved by the Secretary.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department shall provide training, assistance, and advice for equal employment opportunity officers and fair practices officers.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each fair practices officer shall:<section prefix="(1)">implement the Program within the unit;</section><section prefix="(2)">investigate and, as appropriate, resolve complaints filed under &#xA7; 5-211 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(3)">coordinate activities of equal employment opportunity officers in the unit.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An equal employment opportunity officer shall:<section prefix="(1)">monitor all personnel actions adopted by the unit;</section><section prefix="(2)">attest that procedures consistent with this article, the Governor's Code on Fair Practices, and other State and federal equal employment opportunity laws were followed by the unit in taking a personnel action; and</section><section prefix="(3)">perform the duties assigned by the fair practices officer and any other duty required by this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An appointing authority shall delay the effective date of any adverse personnel action that directly affects an equal employment opportunity officer for up to 45 days, pending review and resolution by the Coordinator.</section>
  </text>
</law>
