<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-309" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-5-309</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An employee subject to this subtitle may file with the Secretary a complaint that alleges a violation of &#xA7; 5-305 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A complaint under this subtitle must be filed within 6 months after the complainant first knew of or reasonably should have known of the violation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">When a complaint is received, the Secretary or designee promptly shall:<section prefix="(1)">send a copy of the complaint to the head of the principal unit named in the complaint; and</section><section prefix="(2)">advise the head of the principal unit to respond in writing to the complaint within 20 days after receiving the copy.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Within 60 days after a complaint is received:<section prefix="(1)">the complaint shall be investigated to determine whether a violation of &#xA7; 5-305 of this subtitle has occurred:<section prefix="(i)">by the Secretary or designee of the Secretary; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the Department is charged in the complaint, by a designee of the Governor; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the Secretary or designee or the Governor's designee shall:<section prefix="(i)">take the action described in subsection (d)(1) or (2) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">issue to the complainant and head of the principal unit a written decision that includes any remedial action taken.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Secretary or designee or the Governor's designee determines that a violation has not occurred, the Secretary or Governor's designee shall dismiss the complaint.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Secretary or designee or the Governor's designee determines that a violation has occurred, the Secretary or designee shall take appropriate remedial action.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">As a remedial action for a violation of &#xA7; 5-305 of this subtitle, the Secretary or designee may:<section prefix="(1)">order the removal of any related detrimental information from the complainant's State personnel records;</section><section prefix="(2)">require the head of the principal unit to:<section prefix="(i)">hire, promote, or reinstate the complainant or end the complainant's suspension from employment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">award the complainant back pay to the day of the violation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">grant the complainant leave or seniority;</section><section prefix="(iv)">take appropriate disciplinary action against any individual who caused the violation; and</section><section prefix="(v)">take any other remedial action consistent with the purposes of this subtitle.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
