<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-37-203.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>This subsection applies to an individual who:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This subsection applies to an individual who:<section prefix="(1)">has accrued service credit in a State or local retirement or pension system;</section><section prefix="(2)">has accepted new employment in a position requiring membership in one of the several systems; and</section><section prefix="(3)">did not make a claim under &#xA7; 37-203 or &#xA7; 37-203.1 of this subtitle to transfer the previous service credit within 1 year of transferring into one of the several systems.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual described under subsection (a) of this section may request the Executive Director to accept the individual's claim to transfer service credit accrued in the previous system.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Executive Director denies a request for a waiver, the denial shall be presented to the Board of Trustees for review.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board of Trustees may overturn the Executive Director's decision under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">On or before October 1 of each year, the Board of Trustees shall submit a report to the Joint Committee on Pensions in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, that provides:<section prefix="(1)">the number of requests made by individuals to the Executive Director requesting a waiver of the 1-year requirement to claim transferred service credit;</section><section prefix="(2)">the number of requests granted and denied by the Executive Director; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the number of requests granted by the Board of Trustees following a denial by the Executive Director.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board of Trustees shall adopt regulations to carry out this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
