<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-29-115</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only to a disability retiree who is not eligible to receive a normal service re...</catch_line>
  <order_by>115</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section applies only to a disability retiree who is not eligible to receive a normal service retirement.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not apply to a disability retiree who is:<section prefix="(i)">a retiree of:<section prefix="1.">the State Police Retirement System;</section><section prefix="2.">the Law Enforcement Officers' Pension System;</section><section prefix="3.">the Local Fire and Police System; or</section><section prefix="4.">the Employees' Retirement System or the Employees' Pension System, if at the time of retirement the retiree was a law enforcement officer for a participating employer under &#xA7; 26-201(a) of this article; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">reemployed by a participating employer in any position other than a probationary status law enforcement officer, a law enforcement officer, or chief, as defined in &#xA7; 3-101 of the Public Safety Article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board of Trustees shall, after giving notice, temporarily suspend the retiree's allowance if the retiree:<section prefix="1.">began receiving a disability retirement allowance on or after July 1, 1998; and</section><section prefix="2.">is employed by a participating employer at an annual compensation that is at least equal to the retiree's average final compensation at retirement.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A temporary suspension under this subsection shall begin as of the date the retiree is reemployed by a participating employer under subparagraph (i)2 of this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A retiree whose allowance is temporarily suspended under this subsection is not subject to a reduction as provided in &#xA7; 29-116 of this subtitle during the period of employment by a participating employer.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Upon receiving satisfactory documentation that the retiree is no longer employed by a participating employer, the Board of Trustees shall reinstate the retiree's allowance with accumulated cost-of-living adjustments from the date the allowance was temporarily suspended.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The retiree's allowance will be reinstated on the first day of the month following the month in which the retiree ceased employment with the participating employer.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
