<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="24-405.2" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-24-405.2</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL JUNE 30, 2014 PER CHAPTERS 643 AND 644 OF 2009 //<section prefix="(a)"><section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to a retiree who:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">while reemployed under item (i) of this paragraph is totally and permanently incapacitated for duty in the course of the actual performance of duty without willful negligence by the retiree; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the medical board certifies that:</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The normal service retirement allowance that a retiree described under paragraph (1) of this subsection is receiving at the time the retiree is determined to be disabled under this subsection shall be readjusted to equal two-thirds of the retiree's average final compensation at the time the retiree retired, with accumulated cost-of-living adjustments from the date the retiree retired.</section></section><section prefix="(b)"><section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to a retiree who:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">dies without willful negligence by the retiree; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">is killed in the course of the actual performance of duty.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">When the Board of Trustees receives proof of death of a retiree and finds that the death has occurred in the manner described in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Board of Trustees shall pay the balance of the retiree's accumulated contributions and a special death benefit allowance equal to two-thirds of the retiree's average final compensation at the time of retirement, with accumulated cost-of-living adjustments from the date the retiree retired:<section prefix="(i)">to the surviving spouse;</section><section prefix="(ii)">if there is no surviving spouse or if the surviving spouse dies before the youngest child of the member is 18 years old, to all children under the age of 18 years; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">if there is no surviving spouse or children younger than 18 years of age, to the member's dependent parent to continue as the Board of Trustees may direct for the rest of the parent's life.</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Any benefits under Title 21, Subtitle 4 of this article or &#xA7; 24-403 of this subtitle may not be paid if a special death benefit is paid under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section></section></text>
</law>
