<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-2-509</section_number>
  <catch_line>This subsection applies to a retiree of an optional retirement program under Title 30 of this articl...</catch_line>
  <order_by>509</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to a retiree of an optional retirement program under Title 30 of this article who began service as an employee of the State in the Executive, Legislative, or Judicial Branch of government on or before June 30, 2011.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, an individual may enroll and participate in the health insurance benefit options established under the Program if the individual retired under an optional program under Title 30 of this article and:<section prefix="1.">ended service with a State institution of higher education with at least 10 years of service and was at least age 57;</section><section prefix="2.">ended service with a State institution of higher education with at least 16 years of service; or</section><section prefix="3.">retired directly from and had at least 5 years of service with a State institution of higher education with a periodic distribution of benefits on or after July 1, 1984.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">For purposes of this subsection only, years of service shall be calculated as follows:</section>
          <section prefix="2.">To determine eligibility for health insurance benefits under this section, each year of service shall be multiplied by the participant's percentage of full-time employment for that year of service.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The surviving spouse or dependent child of a deceased individual who was eligible to enroll may enroll and participate in the health insurance benefit options established under the Program as long as the spouse or child is receiving a periodic distribution of benefits under an optional retirement program under Title 30 of this article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An enrollee under this section who was in service with a State institution of higher education at the time of the retirement is entitled to the same State subsidy allowed a retiree under &#xA7; 2-508(b)(4) of this subtitle. However, except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the subsidy shall apply only to the costs of coverage for the enrollee and may not apply to any additional costs of coverage for the enrollee's spouse or children.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the enrollee has 25 or more years of service as an employee of the State in the Executive, Legislative, or Judicial Branch of government, the enrollee or the enrollee's surviving spouse or dependent child is entitled to the same State subsidy allowed a retiree with 16 or more years of creditable service under &#xA7; 2-508(b)(4)(i) of this subtitle.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to a retiree of an optional retirement program under Title 30 of this article who begins service as an employee of the State in the Executive, Legislative, or Judicial Branch of government on or after July 1, 2011.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, an individual may enroll and participate in the health insurance benefit options established under the Program if the individual retired under an optional program under Title 30 of this article and:<section prefix="1.">ended service with a State institution of higher education with at least 10 years of service and was at least age 57;</section><section prefix="2.">ended service with a State institution of higher education with at least 25 years of service; or</section><section prefix="3.">retired directly from and had at least 10 years of service with a State institution of higher education with a periodic distribution of benefits on or after July 1, 2011.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">For purposes of this paragraph only, years of service shall be calculated as follows:</section>
          <section prefix="2.">To determine eligibility for health insurance benefits under this section, each year of service shall be multiplied by the participant's percentage of full-time employment for that year of service.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The surviving spouse or dependent child of a deceased individual who was eligible to enroll may enroll and participate in the health insurance benefit options established under the Program as long as the spouse or child is receiving a periodic distribution of benefits under an optional retirement program under Title 30 of this article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An enrollee under this subsection who was in service with a State institution of higher education at the time of the retirement is entitled to the same State subsidy allowed a retiree under &#xA7; 2-508(c)(4) of this subtitle. However, except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the subsidy shall apply only to the costs of coverage for the enrollee and may not apply to any additional costs of coverage for the enrollee's spouse or children.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the enrollee has 25 or more years of service as an employee of the State in the Executive, Legislative, or Judicial Branch of government, the enrollee or the enrollee's surviving spouse or dependent child is entitled to the same State subsidy allowed a retiree with 25 or more years of creditable service under &#xA7; 2-508(c)(4)(i) of this subtitle.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
