<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="21-403" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-21-403</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Under Option 1, if a retiree dies before receiving payments equal to the actuarial equivalent present value of the retiree's basic allowance computed at the time of retirement, the Board of Trustees shall pay the balance as a single payment:<section prefix="(i)">to the designated beneficiary; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if there is no designated beneficiary, to the retiree's estate.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">At the time of retirement, a member of the Judges' Retirement System described in &#xA7; 21-401(a)(2) of this subtitle may designate more than one beneficiary for the optional benefit provided in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If, at the time of retirement, a member of the Judges' Retirement System does designate more than one beneficiary for the optional benefit provided in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the single payment will be paid in equal shares to each of the designated beneficiaries.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Under Option 2, when a retiree dies, the Board of Trustees shall pay the retiree's reduced allowance to the designated beneficiary for the designated beneficiary's life.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Under Option 3, when a retiree dies, the Board of Trustees shall pay 50% of the retiree's reduced allowance to the designated beneficiary for the designated beneficiary's life.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Under Option 4, if a retiree dies before receiving payments equal to the value of the retiree's accumulated contributions at the time of retirement, the Board of Trustees shall pay the balance as a single payment:<section prefix="(1)">to the designated beneficiary; or</section><section prefix="(2)">if there is no designated beneficiary, to the retiree's estate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, under Option 5, when a retiree dies, the Board of Trustees shall pay the retiree's reduced allowance to the designated beneficiary for the designated beneficiary's life.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the designated beneficiary dies before the retiree, then:<section prefix="(i)">beginning in the month following the date of death of the designated beneficiary, the Board of Trustees shall pay the retiree the basic allowance; or</section><section prefix="(ii)"/></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, under Option 6, when a retiree dies, the Board of Trustees shall pay 50% of the retiree's reduced allowance to the designated beneficiary for the designated beneficiary's life.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the designated beneficiary dies before the retiree, then:<section prefix="(i)">beginning in the month following the date of death of the designated beneficiary, the Board of Trustees shall pay the retiree the basic allowance; or</section><section prefix="(ii)"/></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
