<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-29-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only to a member of the Judges' Retirement System who becomes a member on or af...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only to a member of the Judges' Retirement System who becomes a member on or after July 1, 2012.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A member may elect to receive a vested allowance if:<section prefix="(i)">the member is separated from employment other than by death or retirement; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the member has at least 5 years of eligibility service.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member is deemed to have elected a vested allowance, unless the member requests the return of the accumulated contributions before membership ends.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A vested allowance is a deferred allowance starting at age 60.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A vested allowance:<section prefix="(1)">is computed as a retirement allowance under &#xA7; 27-402 of this article on the basis of the former member's creditable service at the time of separation from employment; and</section><section prefix="(2)">may be paid in one of the optional forms of allowances under &#xA7; 21-403 of this article, if at retirement, the member does not have a spouse or child under the age of 18.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a former member who elected a vested allowance requests the return of accumulated contributions before payment of the vested allowance begins, the Board of Trustees shall return the accumulated contributions to the former member.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When accumulated contributions are returned to a former member, the former member is not entitled to further benefits on account of the former member's previous membership.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
