<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-28-308</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>308</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">For the purpose of computing benefits under this title, creditable service consists of:<section prefix="(1)">eligibility service as adjusted under subsection (b) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">credit for unused sick leave as provided in &#xA7; 20-206 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to eligibility service that consists of:<section prefix="(i)">service credit transferred from another retirement or pension system;</section><section prefix="(ii)">military service credit granted under Title 38 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">service credit purchased under this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board of Trustees shall adjust a member's eligibility service as provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board of Trustees shall adopt regulations to determine for any fiscal year the amount of creditable service that equals the eligibility service for a member who has completed less than the normal hours of employment for the member's position.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The normal hours of employment for a position equals the minimum number of hours to be completed by a full-time employee serving in the member's position.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The creditable service recognized for a fiscal year may not be less than the eligibility service for the member multiplied by a fraction, not to exceed one, that has:<section prefix="1.">as its numerator, the number of hours of employment as a member that the member has completed during that year; and</section><section prefix="2.">as its denominator, the normal number of hours for the member's position.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
