<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-302" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-4-302</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to the University System of Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Secretary shall submit to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly an annual report covering all units of the Executive Branch of State government, including a unit with an independent personnel system, for each fiscal year that:<section prefix="(1)">provides information about:<section prefix="(i)">employee performance and efficiency;</section><section prefix="(ii)">use of leave by State employees;</section><section prefix="(iii)">incentive awards;</section><section prefix="(iv)">whistleblower proceedings;</section><section prefix="(v)">each denial of a pay increase, each disciplinary suspension, each grievance, each involuntary demotion, and each rejection on probation; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">a summary of the equal employment opportunity report required under &#xA7; 5-204 of this article, including hiring, firing, promotions, terminations, and rejections on probation, by race, sex, and age;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">provides statistics and rankings that compare minority group State employees to all State employees in all job categories;</section><section prefix="(3)">provides information about part-time work and, in the Secretary's discretion, alternate work schedules, work days, and work locations;</section><section prefix="(4)">provides information on the total number of positions designated as special appointments, including special appointments designated with regard to political affiliation, belief, or opinion; and</section><section prefix="(5)">makes any recommendations about conditions in State employment that the Secretary considers advisable.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The report required by this section shall be submitted on or before January 1 following the fiscal year to which it applies.</section>
  </text>
</law>
