<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="27-402" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-27-402</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section and subject to subsections (c) and (d) of this section, on retirement under this subtitle, a retiree is entitled to receive a retirement allowance that equals two-thirds of the salary payable in that fiscal year to a member holding the same level judicial position as that held by the retiree on termination of service.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only to a retiree who is a master in chancery or juvenile causes at the time of termination of service.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to subsections (c) and (d) of this section, on retirement under this subtitle, a retiree is entitled to receive a retirement allowance that equals:<section prefix="(i)">two-thirds of the salary payable at the time of termination of service; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">for a retiree who was receiving a retirement allowance as of June 30, 1993, the retirement allowance being received as of that date.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A retirement allowance computed under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be increased each fiscal year that circuit court judges receive salary increases, at a rate equal to the average rate of increase of salaries of all circuit court judges for that fiscal year.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies only to an individual who is a member of the Judges' Retirement System on or before June 30, 2012.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">On retirement under this subtitle by a retiree who has less than 16 years of service credit as a member, the retiree is entitled to a reduced retirement allowance that equals the retirement allowance computed under subsection (a) or (b) of this section multiplied by a fraction that has:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies only to an individual who becomes a member of the Judges' Retirement System on or after July 1, 2012.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">On retirement under this subtitle by a retiree who has at least 5 years but less than 16 years of service credit as a member, the retiree is entitled to a reduced retirement allowance that equals the retirement allowance computed under subsection (a) or (b) of this section multiplied by a fraction that has:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to a member or former member who:<section prefix="(i)">retires on disability; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">is deemed to retire on disability under paragraph (3) of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a member or former member has at least 3 years of service credit as a member, the member or former member is entitled to a retirement allowance that is at least one-third of the member's or former member's salary at retirement.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member who dies after submitting an application for disability but before the medical board approves the application is deemed retired on disability.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
