<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="21-315" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-21-315</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board of Trustees shall credit to the expense fund of each State system its pro rata share of:<section prefix="(1)">the amount provided in the annual State budget to pay the administrative and operational expenses of the Board of Trustees and the State Retirement Agency;</section><section prefix="(2)">the amounts authorized by the Board of Trustees under this section for investment management services; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the amount authorized by the Board of Trustees to implement a closing agreement with the Internal Revenue Service regarding former members of the Employees' Retirement System or the Teachers' Retirement System who elected to become members of or participate in those State systems under former Article 73B, &#xA7;&#xA7; 2-206 and 3-206 of the Code.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board of Trustees shall pay from the expense fund of each State system its pro rata share of:<section prefix="(1)">the administrative and operational expenses of the Board of Trustees and the State Retirement Agency, in accordance with the annual State budget;</section><section prefix="(2)">the amounts as authorized by the Board of Trustees necessary for investment management services; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the amounts as authorized by the Board of Trustees necessary to implement a closing agreement with the Internal Revenue Service regarding former members of the Employees' Retirement System or the Teachers' Retirement System who elected to become members of or participate in those State systems under former Article 73B, &#xA7;&#xA7; 2-206 and 3-206 of the Code.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each year the Board of Trustees shall estimate the amount, not exceeding 0.22% of the payroll of members, necessary for the administrative and operational expenses of the Board of Trustees and the State Retirement Agency.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each quarter of the fiscal year the Board of Trustees shall estimate one-fourth of an amount, not exceeding 0.5% of the market value as of the last day of the preceding quarter of invested assets that are externally managed exclusive of assets invested in real estate or alternative investments, necessary to procure and retain investment management services other than external real estate or alternative investment management services.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board of Trustees is not limited in the amount of investment manager fees that the Board of Trustees may pay as necessary for external real estate or alternative investment management services.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The amounts estimated under subsection (c) of this section shall be paid into the expense funds of the several systems during the ensuing year on a pro rata basis according to the total membership of each system.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The amounts estimated under subsection (d) of this section shall be paid into the expense funds of the several systems during the ensuing year on a pro rata basis according to the total assets held by each system.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Board of Trustees may combine the expense funds of the several systems for budgetary and administrative efficiency.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">On or before December 31 of each year, the Board of Trustees shall report to the General Assembly the actual amount spent for investment management services during the preceding fiscal year.</section>
  </text>
</law>
