<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-9-1203</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Sick Leave Incentive Program consists of the following two incentives:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Sick Leave Incentive Program consists of the following two incentives:<section prefix="(1)">payment for up to 40 hours of unused sick leave per calendar year if an employee has used no more than 40 hours of sick leave during the calendar year and has a sick leave balance of at least 240 hours on December 31 of that calendar year; and</section><section prefix="(2)">payment for up to 56 hours of unused sick leave per calendar year if an employee has used no more than 24 hours of sick leave during the calendar year and has a sick leave balance of at least 240 hours on December 31 of that calendar year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To be eligible for the Program, an employee shall maintain a sick leave balance of at least 240 hours after payment is received for leave.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For the purpose of determining eligibility for the Program, the following use of leave does not qualify as sick leave usage:<section prefix="(i)">sick leave that is used for a death in the immediate family;</section><section prefix="(ii)">sick leave that is donated to another employee in accordance with the provisions of the Employee-to-Employee Leave Donation Program;</section><section prefix="(iii)">sick leave that is donated to the State Employees' Leave Bank; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">sick leave that is taken in accordance with the Family and Medical Leave Act.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Leave used for the purpose stated in paragraph (1)(iv) of this subsection shall not be used to determine an employee's leave balance under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
