<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-2-507</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>507</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the regulations adopted under &#xA7; 2-503 of this subtitle, a State employee may enroll and participate in any of the health insurance or other benefit options established under the Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The surviving spouse of a State employee who died while employed by the State may enroll and participate in the health insurance benefit options established under the Program as long as the surviving spouse:<section prefix="(1)">is receiving an allowance under Title 29, Subtitle 2 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(2)">is the sole primary designated beneficiary and receiving a periodic distribution of benefits under an optional retirement program under Title 30 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The surviving minor child or dependent parent of a State Police officer who died while employed by the State may enroll and participate in the health insurance benefit options established under the Program as long as the child or parent is receiving an allowance under Title 29, Subtitle 2 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The surviving minor child of a correctional officer who at the time of death was a member of the Correctional Officers' Retirement System and who died while employed by the State may enroll and participate in the health insurance benefit options established under the Program as long as the child is receiving an allowance under Title 29, Subtitle 2 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The surviving minor child or dependent parent of a State employee who at the time of death was a member of the Employees' Retirement System, Employees' Pension System, Teachers' Retirement System, or Teachers' Pension System and who was killed while employed by the State may enroll and participate in the health insurance benefit options established under the Program as long as the child or parent is receiving an allowance under Title 29, Subtitle 2 of this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
