<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-35-302</section_number>
  <catch_line>Assets of the supplemental retirement plans may be deposited and invested in accordance with the inv...</catch_line>
  <order_by>302</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Assets of the supplemental retirement plans may be deposited and invested in accordance with the investment elections allowed under the supplemental retirement plans notwithstanding any other law limiting the types of investments that may be made with State funds or imposing conditions on the deposit of State funds.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board shall attempt to use to the greatest extent feasible minority business enterprises to provide brokerage and investment management services to the Board consistent with minority business purchasing standards applicable to units of State government under the State Finance and Procurement Article and consistent with the fiduciary duties of the Board.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For purposes of this subsection, brokerage and investment management services shall include services relating to all allocated asset classes.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">To assist it in achieving the goal described under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Board shall undertake measures to remove any barriers that limit full participation by minority business enterprises in brokerage and investment management services opportunities afforded under this title.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The measures undertaken by the Board shall include the use of a wide variety of media, including the Maryland Teachers and State Employees Supplemental Retirement Plans' Web site, to provide notice to a broad and varied range of potential providers about the brokerage and investment management services opportunities afforded by the Maryland Teachers and State Employees Supplemental Retirement Plans.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In consultation with the Governor's Office of Minority Affairs, the Board shall develop guidelines to assist the Board in identifying and evaluating qualified minority business enterprises in order to help the Maryland Teachers and State Employees Supplemental Retirement Plans achieve the objective for greater use of minority business enterprises for brokerage and investment management services.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On or before September 1 each year, the Board shall submit a report to the Governor's Office of Minority Affairs and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly on:<section prefix="(i)">the identity of the minority business enterprise brokerage and investment management services firms used by the Board in the immediately preceding fiscal year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the percentage and dollar value of the assets that are under the control of the Board that are under the investment control of minority business enterprise brokerage and investment management services firms for each allocated asset class; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the measures the Board undertook in the immediately preceding fiscal year in accordance with paragraph (2)(ii) of this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
