<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-20-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this Division II the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this Division II the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Accumulated contributions" means the amounts credited to a member's individual account in the annuity savings fund of the appropriate State system.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Accumulated contributions" includes:<section prefix="(i)">member contributions;</section><section prefix="(ii)">additional contributions; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">regular interest.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Additional contribution" means a contribution that is made voluntarily by a member.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Allowance" means a benefit that is payable in equal monthly installments for the life of the recipient, except as otherwise provided for an optional form of an allowance under &#xA7; 21-403 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d-1)">"Alternate Contributory Pension Selection" means the part of the Employees' Pension System and the Teachers' Pension System that provides the Alternate Contributory Pension Selection under Title 23, Subtitle 2, Part III of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Annuity" means the part of an allowance that is derived from the accumulated contributions of a member.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Annuity reserve" means the present value of an annuity computed on the basis of actuarial assumptions adopted by the Board of Trustees.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Average final compensation" means the average annual earnable compensation that is computed as provided in &#xA7; 20-204, &#xA7; 20-205, or &#xA7; 20-205.1 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Basic allowance" means an allowance computed without modification under &#xA7; 21-403 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Beneficiary" means a person, other than a retiree, in receipt of a benefit under this Division II.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Board of Trustees" means the Board of Trustees for the State Retirement and Pension System.</section>
    <section prefix="(j-1)">"Contributory pension benefit" means the part of the Employees' Pension System and the Teachers' Pension System that provides the contributory pension benefit under Title 23, Subtitle 2, Part II of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Correctional Officers' Retirement System" means the Correctional Officers' Retirement System of the State of Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"County" means a county of the State and, unless expressly provided otherwise, Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Creditable service" means the service credit of a member that is recognized for computing a benefit under this Division II.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Designated beneficiary" means a person named as beneficiary in an acknowledged written designation filed with the Board of Trustees by a member, former member, or a retiree.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Earnable compensation" means one-twelfth of the member's annual salary rate payable for working the normal time in the member's position, including:<section prefix="(1)">the employer pickup contribution provided for in &#xA7; 21-312 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a contribution made under a salary reduction or supplemental retirement plan in accordance with Title 35 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Eligibility service" means the service credit of a member that is recognized for determining eligibility for a benefit under this Division II.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Employees' Pension System" means the Employees' Pension System of the State of Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Employees' Retirement System" means the Employees' Retirement System of the State of Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Employer pickup contribution" means a contribution made through a reduction in a member's compensation under &#xA7; 21-313 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Former member" means an individual who:<section prefix="(1)">has been a member;</section><section prefix="(2)">has separated from employment with a participating employer; and</section><section prefix="(3)">is not currently a member or retiree.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(u)">"Judges' Retirement System" means the Judges' Retirement System of the State of Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(v)">"Law Enforcement Officers' Pension System" means the Law Enforcement Officers' Pension System of the State of Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(w)">"Legislative Pension Plan" means the Legislative Pension Plan of the State of Maryland as provided by the joint resolution submitted to the General Assembly by the General Assembly Compensation Commission under Article III, &#xA7; 15 of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
    <section prefix="(x)">"Local Fire and Police System" means the Local Fire and Police Pension System of the State of Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(y)">"Medical board" means a board of physicians provided for in &#xA7; 21-126 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(z)">"Member" means, unless a different meaning is plainly required by the context, an individual:<section prefix="(1)">for whom membership in a State system is a condition of employment; or</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">for whom membership in a State system is optional; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">who has elected to become a member of that State system.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(aa)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Member contribution" means:<section prefix="(i)">a contribution that is deducted from a member's compensation as required by this Division II;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a contribution that is designated as a member contribution under &#xA7; 22-212 or &#xA7; 22-213 of this article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a contribution that is redeposited as a member contribution;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the part attributable to a member contribution of any payment for the purchase of service credit under this Division II; and</section><section prefix="(v)">an employer pickup contribution.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Member contribution" does not include any additional contribution.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(aa-1)">"Noncontributory pension benefit" means the part of the Employees' Pension System and the Teachers' Pension System that does not provide the contributory pension benefit under Title 23, Subtitle 2, Part II of this article or the Alternate Contributory Pension Selection under Title 23, Subtitle 2, Part III of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(bb)">"Normal retirement age" means:<section prefix="(1)">50 years old, for a member of:<section prefix="(i)">the State Police Retirement System; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Law Enforcement Officers' Pension System;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">60 years old, for a member of:<section prefix="(i)">the Correctional Officers' Retirement System, for the purpose of disability retirement only;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Employees' Retirement System;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Judges' Retirement System;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Local Fire and Police System, who transferred from the Employees' Retirement System; or</section><section prefix="(v)">the Teachers' Retirement System;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">62 years old, for a member of:<section prefix="(i)">the Employees' Pension System who is a member on or before June 30, 2011;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Local Fire and Police System, who has not transferred from the Employees' Retirement System; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Teachers' Pension System who is a member on or before June 30, 2011; or</section></section><section prefix="(4)">65 years old, for a member of the Employees' Pension System or Teachers' Pension System who begins membership on or after July 1, 2011.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(cc)">"Participant" means a beneficiary, designated beneficiary, former member, member, or retiree who is or may become eligible to receive a benefit of any type from the several systems.</section>
    <section prefix="(dd)">"Participating employer" means the employer of an individual who, because of the employment relationship, is eligible for membership in a State system.</section>
    <section prefix="(ee)">"Participating governmental unit" means a governmental unit that participates in a State system under Title 31 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(ff)">"Pension" means the part of an allowance that is derived from employer contributions.</section>
    <section prefix="(gg)">"Pension reserve" means the present value of a pension, computed on the basis of actuarial assumptions adopted by the Board of Trustees.</section>
    <section prefix="(hh)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Person" means an individual, receiver, trustee, guardian, personal representative, fiduciary, or representative of any kind and any partnership, firm, association, corporation, or other entity.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless expressly provided otherwise, "person" does not include a governmental entity or a unit or instrumentality of a governmental entity.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(hh-1)">"Reformed contributory pension benefit" means the part of the Employees' Pension System and the Teachers' Pension System that provides the reformed contributory pension benefit under Title 23, Subtitle 2, Part IV of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(ii)">"Regular interest" means interest at the rate payable on accumulated contributions as provided under this Division II for each State system.</section>
    <section prefix="(jj)">"Retiree" means an individual who:<section prefix="(1)">has separated from employment with a participating employer; and</section><section prefix="(2)">receives a retirement allowance under this Division II.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(kk)">"Retirement" means the grant of a retirement allowance under this Division II after separation from employment with a participating employer.</section>
    <section prefix="(ll)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Retirement allowance" means an allowance that is payable at the time of separation from employment with a participating employer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Retirement allowance" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a service retirement allowance; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a disability retirement allowance.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Retirement allowance" does not include a vested allowance.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(mm)">"Several systems" means the State systems specified in &#xA7; 21-102 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(nn)">"Social Security integration level" means, with respect to the calendar year in which a member retires or otherwise separates from employment, the average yearly amount of earnings for which old age and survivors benefits would be provided under Title II of the federal Social Security Act for an employee who is eligible to receive full old age and survivors benefits provided under Title II of the federal Social Security Act in that calendar year that is:<section prefix="(1)">computed as though for each previous year yearly earnings are at least equal to the maximum amount of yearly earnings subject to tax under the Federal Insurance Contributions Act; and</section><section prefix="(2)">rounded to the next lower multiple of $100.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(oo)">"State Police Retirement System" means the State Police Retirement System of the State of Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(pp)">"State system" means a retirement or pension system that is included in the State Retirement and Pension System under &#xA7; 21-102 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(qq)">"Taxable wage base" means, with respect to each calendar year, the maximum amount of annual earnings for employees subject to tax under the federal Old Age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(rr)">"Teachers' Pension System" means the Teachers' Pension System of the State of Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(ss)">"Teachers' Retirement System" means the Teachers' Retirement System of the State of Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(tt)">"Vested allowance" means an allowance that is not payable at the time of separation from employment with a participating employer, but is deferred until the former member becomes eligible for immediate payment.</section>
  </text>
</law>
