<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="29-108" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-29-108</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only to members of:<section prefix="(1)">the Employees' Pension System;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Local Fire and Police System;</section><section prefix="(3)">the Law Enforcement Officers' Pension System; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the Teachers' Pension System.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsections (c), (d), and (e) of this section, an ordinary disability retirement allowance equals:<section prefix="(1)">if the member is at least normal retirement age, a normal service retirement allowance; or</section><section prefix="(2)">if the member is under normal retirement age, a normal service retirement allowance that is computed by using:<section prefix="(i)">the number of years of creditable service the member would have received if the member continued employment until normal retirement age; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">an average final compensation the member would have received if the member continued employment without a change in earnable compensation.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A member of the Employees' Pension System or the Teachers' Pension System who has transferred from the Employees' Retirement System or the Teachers' Retirement System shall receive the benefits provided under the State system from which the member transferred, offset by any refunded contributions including any interest received in connection with the transfer, if:<section prefix="(1)">the member applies for the retirement allowance within 2 years after the transfer; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the Board of Trustees grants a disability retirement allowance to the member.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only to:<section prefix="(i)">a member of the Local Fire and Police Pension System who has transferred from the Employees' Retirement System; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a member of the Law Enforcement Officers' Pension System who has transferred from the Employees' Retirement System after electing to receive benefits in accordance with Selection A (Additional member contributions) as defined in &#xA7; 22-101(b) of this article or Selection B (Limited cost-of-living adjustment) as defined in &#xA7; 22-101(c) of this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An ordinary disability retirement allowance equals the greater of:<section prefix="(i)">a normal service retirement allowance; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">25% of the member's average final compensation.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only to a member of the Employees' Pension System who:<section prefix="(i)">is promoted within the Department of Corrections to a position that no longer is eligible for membership in the Correctional Officers' Retirement System as provided in &#xA7; 25-201 of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">elects not to transfer the years of creditable service the individual accrued in the Correctional Officers' Retirement System to the Employees' Pension System; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">is eligible to receive a vested allowance from the Correctional Officers' Retirement System.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An ordinary disability retirement allowance equals:<section prefix="(i)">a normal service retirement allowance in the Correctional Officers' Retirement System based on the member's total years of creditable service accrued in the Correctional Officers' Retirement System; plus</section><section prefix="(ii)">an ordinary disability retirement allowance based on the member's total years of creditable service accrued in the Employees' Pension System.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
