<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-29-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>This subsection applies only to an individual who dies while employed as a member of the State Polic...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only to an individual who dies while employed as a member of the State Police Retirement System:<section prefix="(i)">without willful negligence by the member; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">with more than 2 years of eligibility service.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When the Board of Trustees receives proof of death of a member and finds that the death has occurred in the manner described in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Board of Trustees shall pay:<section prefix="(i)">if the member is survived by a spouse, a child under the age of 18 years, or a dependent parent:<section prefix="1.">the member's accumulated contributions to the designated beneficiary, or otherwise to the member's estate; and</section><section prefix="2.">an allowance of 50% of the member's average final compensation:</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">if the member is not survived by a spouse, a child under the age of 18 years, or a dependent parent, the death benefit under &#xA7; 29-202 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only to an individual who dies while employed as a member of the State Police Retirement System:<section prefix="(i)">without willful negligence by the member; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">with death arising out of or in the course of the actual performance of duty.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When the Board of Trustees receives proof of death of a member and finds that the death has occurred in the manner described in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Board of Trustees shall pay:<section prefix="(i)">if the member is survived by a spouse, a child under the age of 18 years, or a dependent parent:<section prefix="1.">the member's accumulated contributions to the designated beneficiary, or otherwise to the member's estate; and</section><section prefix="2.">an allowance of two-thirds of the member's average final compensation:</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">if the member is not survived by a spouse, a child under the age of 18 years, or a dependent parent, the death benefit under &#xA7; 29-202 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the Board of Trustees pays an allowance under this section to more than one child, the Board of Trustees shall divide the allowance among the children under the age of 18 years in a manner that provides for payments to continue until each child dies or becomes 18 years old.</section>
  </text>
</law>
