<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-205" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-3-205</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board is responsible for administering and enforcing provisions of this title relating to employees described in &#xA7; 3-102(a)(1)(i) through (iv) and (vi) through (ix) and (2) of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to any other powers or duties provided for elsewhere in this title, the Board may:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">establish guidelines for creating new bargaining units that include a consideration of:</section><section prefix="(ii)">establish standards for determining an appropriate bargaining unit; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">investigate and resolve disputes about appropriate bargaining units;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">establish procedures for, supervise the conduct of, and resolve disputes about elections for exclusive representatives; and</section><section prefix="(3)">investigate and take appropriate action in response to complaints of unfair labor practices and lockouts.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may not designate a unique bargaining unit for each of the units of government identified in &#xA7; 3-102(a)(1)(vi) through (ix) of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the request of the exclusive representative, the Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">determine the appropriate existing bargaining unit into which to assign each employee in the units of government identified in &#xA7; 3-102(a)(1)(vi) through (ix) of this title; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">accrete all positions to appropriate existing bargaining units.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Notwithstanding Subtitle 4 of this title, at the request of the exclusive representative, the Board shall conduct a self-determination election for each bargaining unit representative for the accreted employees in units of government identified in &#xA7; 3-102(a)(1)(vi) through (ix) of this title.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">All elections shall be conducted by secret ballot.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">For each election, the Board shall place the following choices on the ballot:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
