<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="21-126" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-21-126</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board of Trustees shall establish one or more medical boards.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each medical board consists of three members and not more than three alternates.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each medical board member and alternate shall be a physician who is not eligible to be a member of a State system.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board of Trustees shall appoint the medical board members and any alternates.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Notwithstanding paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Board of Trustees may appoint a physician who is a participating employee in the Optional Retirement Program under Title 30 of this article to a medical board if the physician is not eligible to receive a disability benefit under Title 29, Subtitle 1 of this article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In the absence of a medical board member, an alternate may serve on a medical board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Two members of a medical board are a quorum for the conduct of business.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A medical board shall:<section prefix="(1)">arrange for and approve all medical examinations required under this Division II;</section><section prefix="(2)">investigate all essential certificates and statements by or on behalf of a member concerning the application of the member for disability retirement; and</section><section prefix="(3)">submit written reports to the Board of Trustees, with conclusions and recommendations, on all matters that the Board of Trustees refers to the medical board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board of Trustees may employ other physicians to report on special cases.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A member of a medical board appointed under subsection (b)(3)(ii) of this section may not participate in a case concerning the application of a member for disability retirement if the applicant is an employee of the same institution that is the employing institution, as defined in &#xA7; 30-101 of this article, of the member of the medical board.</section>
  </text>
</law>
