<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="23-303" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-23-303</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "break in service" means a period of separation from employment in a fiscal year after the one in which a member first becomes employed, if during that fiscal year the member does not complete more than 350 hours of employment while a member.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section applies to a member of the Employees' Pension System or the Teachers' Pension System who was a member of one of those State systems.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">a retiree of the Employees' Pension System or the Teachers' Pension System; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a member of the Employees' Pension System or Teachers' Pension System who is subject to the contributory pension benefit or the Alternate Contributory Pension Selection.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A member is entitled to the eligibility service to which the member was entitled before the separation from employment if:<section prefix="(1)">the member has not incurred a break in service;</section><section prefix="(2)">the member was entitled to a vested allowance at the time of the separation from employment; or</section><section prefix="(3)"><section prefix="(i)">the member has completed 1 year of eligibility service after a break in service; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the number of consecutive years in which the member incurred a break in service is less than the years of eligibility service as a member before the break in service.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">To determine if a member is eligible for prior eligibility service under subsection (c)(3)(ii) of this section, the Board of Trustees shall determine the number of years of prior eligibility service:<section prefix="(1)">as of the day the member separated from employment; but</section><section prefix="(2)">excluding any eligibility service lost because of a prior break in service.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">When a member receives credit for eligibility service under subsection (c) of this section from the other system, the member has no further rights in the other system.</section>
  </text>
</law>
