<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-30-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An individual is eligible to participate in the program if the individual is eligible for membership in a retirement system or a pension system and is:<section prefix="(1)">a member of the faculty of an employing institution;</section><section prefix="(2)">a professional employee at a community college or regional community college established under Title 16 of the Education Article;</section><section prefix="(3)">an employee of the University System of Maryland who is in a position designated as exempt under a policy adopted by the University System of Maryland Board of Regents;</section><section prefix="(4)">an employee of Morgan State University who is in a position designated as professional or administrative by the Board of Regents of Morgan State University;</section><section prefix="(5)">an employee of St. Mary's College of Maryland who is in a position determined by the Board of Trustees of the College to be a professional or faculty position; or</section><section prefix="(6)">an employee of the Maryland Higher Education Commission who is in a position determined by the Secretary of Higher Education to be a professional position.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to an individual who:<section prefix="(i)">on August 22, 2004, was eligible to participate in the program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is in a position that, as of August 23, 2004, was reclassified by the University System of Maryland Board of Regents or the Board of Regents of Morgan State University and would no longer be eligible for participation in the program under subsection (a) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual described under paragraph (1) of this subsection may continue to participate in the program if the individual:<section prefix="(i)">would otherwise be eligible for membership in a system under the State Retirement and Pension System; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is employed by an employing institution.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
