<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-30-401</section_number>
  <catch_line>An employing institution may:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>401</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An employing institution may:<section prefix="(1)">establish supplemental retirement plans that provide supplemental retirement accounts offered by a designated company in accordance with &#xA7; 401(a), &#xA7; 403(b), or &#xA7; 457 of the Internal Revenue Code, or any other provision of federal law that authorizes supplemental retirement accounts; and</section><section prefix="(2)">authorize its employees or the employees of an institution over which it has administrative authority to participate in one or more of the supplemental retirement plans.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, if an employing institution authorizes its employees or the employees of an institution over which it has administrative authority to participate in a supplemental retirement plan, the employing institution shall select one or more of the designated companies under &#xA7; 30-202 of this title that may offer supplemental retirement accounts to those employees and shall administer the participation of those employees in the supplemental retirement plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">With respect to a community or regional college established under Title 16 of the Education Article, other than a community college established under Title 16, Subtitle 5 of the Education Article, if an employing institution authorizes its employees or the employees of an institution over which it has administrative authority to participate in a supplemental retirement plan, the employing institution shall select one or more companies that may offer supplemental retirement accounts to those employees and shall administer the participation of those employees in the supplemental retirement plan.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Contributions authorized under this section to a supplemental retirement account on behalf of an employee may be made by payroll deduction, a reduction in salary, deferral in compensation in accordance with &#xA7; 403(b), &#xA7; 457, or &#xA7; 414(h) of the Internal Revenue Code, or as otherwise permitted by the Internal Revenue Code and authorized by the employing institution.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Assets of the supplemental retirement plans may be deposited and invested in accordance with the investment elections allowed under the supplemental retirement plans notwithstanding any other law limiting the types of investments that may be made with State funds or imposing conditions on the deposit of State funds.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An employee of an employing institution with discretionary authority over the management or administration of any of the supplemental retirement plans or the management or disposition of the assets of any of the supplemental retirement plans is entitled to indemnification and insurance as provided under &#xA7; 30-210.1 of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
