<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-404" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-13-404</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department may certify a service contract to the Board of Public Works as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department may certify a service contract as being exempt from the preference stated in &#xA7; 13-402 of this subtitle if:<section prefix="(1)">State employees are not available to perform the services;</section><section prefix="(2)">a conflict of interest would result if a State employee were to perform the services;</section><section prefix="(3)">the nature of the services meets the standards set by the Department for emergency appointments;</section><section prefix="(4)">the services are incidental to the purchase or lease of personal property or real property, such as a service agreement that is part of the purchase or rental of computers or office equipment; or</section><section prefix="(5)">a clear need exists to obtain an unbiased finding or opinion, such as an expert witness in litigation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department may certify a service contract that is not exempt under subsection (b) of this section only if:<section prefix="(1)">the unit that seeks to enter into the service contract has complied with &#xA7; 13-405 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the Department finds that:<section prefix="(i)">the potential economic advantage of entering into the service contract is not outweighed by the preference stated in &#xA7; 13-402 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the service contract does not adversely affect the affirmative action efforts of this State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the service contract includes adequate control mechanisms to ensure that the services will be performed in accordance with the service contract; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the service contract complies with all of the requirements of Division II of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
