<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-29-111</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>111</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to the State Police Retirement System.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 24-401.1(k) of this article, the Board of Trustees shall grant a special disability retirement allowance to a member if:<section prefix="(1)">the member is totally and permanently incapacitated for duty arising out of or in the course of the actual performance of duty without willful negligence by the member; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the medical board certifies that:<section prefix="(i)">the member is totally incapacitated, either mentally or physically, for the further performance of duty;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the incapacity is likely to be permanent; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the member should be retired.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, a special disability retirement allowance equals the lesser of:<section prefix="(1)">the member's average final compensation; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the sum of:<section prefix="(i)">an annuity that is the actuarial equivalent of the member's accumulated contributions at retirement; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a pension equal to two-thirds of the member's average final compensation.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to a member who is at least normal retirement age.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A special disability retirement allowance equals the greater of:<section prefix="(i)">a normal service retirement allowance; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a special disability retirement allowance computed in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
