<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-38-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only to a member of a State or local retirement or pension system who:<section prefix="(1)">does not withdraw any of the member's accumulated contributions, unless the member redeposits the sum withdrawn as provided under subsection (b) of this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">within 1 year after the member leaves military service, is employed by the State or a political subdivision of the State;</section><section prefix="(3)">does not take any employment other than the employment described in item (2) of this subsection, except for temporary employment after the member:<section prefix="(i)">applied for reemployment in the member's former classification or position in the State service; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">was refused immediate reemployment for causes beyond the member's control; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">applies for service credit with the State or local retirement or pension system in which the member held membership before the member's military service began.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a member of a State or local retirement or pension system who is absent from employment for military service withdraws any of the member's accumulated contributions and redeposits the sum withdrawn with regular interest into the State or local retirement or pension system, the member, if otherwise qualified, is entitled to the benefits of this section as if the withdrawal had not been made.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, a member of a State or local retirement or pension system who is actively reemployed under subsection (a)(2) of this section retains the status and rights as a member during a period of absence from employment for military service.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2)(i) of this subsection, a member of a State or local retirement or pension system shall receive service credit for a period of absence from employment while in military service if:<section prefix="(i)">the employment of the member under subsection (a)(2) of this section is active or the employee is reinstated as a regular employee on a leave of absence; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">membership in a State or local retirement or pension system is a requirement of employment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">For an absence for military service, service credit for the military service may not exceed 5 years.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">This subparagraph applies only to a member of a State system.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">Subject to subparagraph (i) of this paragraph and in addition to any service credit received under paragraph (1) of this subsection, a member of the Maryland National Guard or of a reserve component of the armed forces of the United States who has been activated under Title 10 of the United States Code and who is on active or inactive duty for training that interrupts the member's service shall receive service credit at the rate of 4 months for each full year for military service, not to exceed a total of 36 months.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A member of a State or local retirement or pension system who receives service credit for military service under this section may transfer the credit to another State or local retirement or pension system.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The service credit for military service that a member of a State system receives under this section shall be applied to the individual's retirement allowance using the accrual rate at the time the individual retires from a State system.</section>
  </text>
</law>
