<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-23-402</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>402</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, a member may retire with an early service retirement allowance if:<section prefix="(1)">the member completes and submits a written application to the Board of Trustees stating the date when the member desires to retire; and</section><section prefix="(2)">on or before the date of retirement, the member:<section prefix="(i)">has at least 15 years but less than 30 years of eligibility service; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is at least 55 but less than 62 years old.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A member who begins membership on or after July 1, 2011, may retire with an early service retirement allowance if:<section prefix="(1)">the member completes and submits a written application to the Board of Trustees stating the date when the member desires to retire; and</section><section prefix="(2)">on or before the date of retirement, the member:<section prefix="(i)">has at least 15 years of eligibility service; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is at least 60 but less than 65 years old.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, on retirement under this section, a member is entitled to receive an early service retirement allowance that equals the normal service retirement allowance under &#xA7; 23-401 of this subtitle, reduced by 0.5% for each month that the member's early retirement date precedes the date the member will be 62 years old.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On retirement under this section, a member who begins membership on or after July 1, 2011, is entitled to receive an early service retirement allowance that equals the normal service retirement allowance to which the member would otherwise be entitled under &#xA7; 23-401 of this subtitle, reduced by 0.5% for each month that the member's early retirement date precedes the date the member will be 65 years old.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
