<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="22-305" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-22-305</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A member may purchase service credit as provided in this section for periods of employment described in subsection (c) or (d) of this section for which the member is not otherwise entitled to service credit.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A member who purchases service credit under this section shall:<section prefix="(i)">complete a claim for the service credit and file it with the Board of Trustees on a form that the Board of Trustees provides; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">pay to the Board of Trustees an amount equal to the annuity reserve and pension reserve required to fund the additional allowance.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraphs (3) and (4) of this subsection, the member shall pay for service credit purchased under this section at retirement.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The surviving spouse of a member of the Teachers' Retirement System may pay for the appropriate final adjustment under paragraph (3) of this subsection if:<section prefix="(i)">the member dies while employed as a member;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the member was purchasing service credit through a payroll deduction; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the service credit qualifies for benefits under &#xA7; 29-205 of this article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A member of the Employees' Retirement System may purchase service credit for a period of employment:<section prefix="(1)">not exceeding 10 years of out-of-state public school teaching service;</section><section prefix="(2)">not exceeding 10 years for public or nonpublic school teaching service;</section><section prefix="(3)">not exceeding 5 years for postsecondary school teaching service;</section><section prefix="(4)">not exceeding 10 years of federal service or out-of-state service with a political subdivision; or</section><section prefix="(5)">as an employee of a political subdivision of the State if:<section prefix="(i)">the member is not otherwise entitled to receive service credit for the same period under this Division II;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the member is not receiving retirement benefits from a political subdivision of the State for the same period; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the member, the political subdivision, or both, pay the amount required under subsection (b)(1) of this section.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A member of the Teachers' Retirement System may purchase service credit for a period of employment:<section prefix="(1)">not exceeding 10 years of out-of-state public school teaching service;</section><section prefix="(2)">not exceeding 10 years of public or nonpublic school teaching service;</section><section prefix="(3)">not exceeding 5 years of postsecondary school teaching service;</section><section prefix="(4)">on or before December 31, 1970, with Baltimore City as a teacher on a verified leave of absence not exceeding 2 years that is similar in all respects to leaves of absence approved by the Board of Trustees;</section><section prefix="(5)">not exceeding 10 years of federal or out-of-state municipal service; or</section><section prefix="(6)">employment as an employee of a municipal corporation of the State if the member is not otherwise entitled to receive service credit under this Division II.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
