<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-35-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board shall meet at least quarterly at the times and places it determines.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each member of the Board is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may employ a staff in accordance with the State budget.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may hire consultants, administrators, and other professionals as necessary to help implement, maintain, and administer the supplemental retirement plans.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph or otherwise by law, employees of the Board are subject to the provisions of Division I of this article that govern nontemporary employees.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Employees of the Board whose labor is predominately intellectual and who hold positions that the Board designates as professional or technical positions involving specialized skill, education, and knowledge are in the executive service, management service, or are special appointments of the skilled service or the professional service in the State Personnel Management System.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in paragraph (5) of this subsection, all expenses, including employee costs, incurred to implement, maintain, and administer the supplemental retirement plans shall be paid from the contributions to or the income or assets of the supplemental retirement plans.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Each supplemental retirement plan shall pay a proportionate share of the expenses specified in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Administrative expenses to implement, maintain, and administer the supplemental retirement plans shall be as provided in the State budget.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">At the request of the Board, and subject to an agreement governing the payment of costs, a unit of State government shall help to implement, maintain, and administer the supplemental retirement plans.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
