<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-110" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-11-110</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 10 days after receiving a decision under &#xA7; 11-109 of this subtitle, an employee or an employee's representative may appeal the decision in writing to the Secretary.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An appeal shall state, to the extent possible, the issues of fact and law that are the basis for the appeal.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Within 30 days after receiving an appeal, the Secretary or designee shall:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">mediate a settlement between the employee and the unit; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">refer the appeal to the Office of Administrative Hearings; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">advise the employee in writing of the Secretary's action.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 30 days after receiving the appeal, the Office of Administrative Hearings shall schedule a hearing and notify the parties of the hearing date.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Office of Administrative Hearings shall dispose of the appeal or conduct a hearing on each appeal in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article. The Office is bound by any regulation, declaratory ruling, prior adjudication, or other settled, preexisting policy, to the same extent as the Department is or would have been bound if it were hearing the case.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided by this subtitle, the Office of Administrative Hearings may:<section prefix="(i)">uphold the disciplinary action;</section><section prefix="(ii)">rescind or modify the disciplinary action taken and restore to the employee any lost time, compensation, status, or benefits; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">order:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 45 days after the close of the hearing record, the Office of Administrative Hearings shall issue to the parties a written decision.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The decision of the Office of Administrative Hearings is the final administrative decision.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The principal unit that employs the employee shall pay all costs related to the appeal that are incurred by the Office of Administrative Hearings.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a written decision issued under subsection (d) of this section is not appealed in accordance with &#xA7; 10-222 of the State Government Article, within 45 days after issuance of a decision to rescind a disciplinary action, the disciplinary action shall be expunged from the employee's personnel records.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a written decision issued under subsection (d) of this section is appealed in accordance with &#xA7; 10-222 of the State Government Article, within 45 days after the issuance of a final decision on appeal to rescind a disciplinary action, the disciplinary action shall be expunged from the employee's personnel records.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
