<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-10-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "innovative idea" means an invention, innovative suggestion, or any other innovativ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "innovative idea" means an invention, innovative suggestion, or any other innovative idea.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is an Innovative Idea Awards Program for employees.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An innovative idea award may be awarded for an innovative idea that, if implemented, would:<section prefix="(i)">increase revenue to the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">save money for the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">improve the quality of services delivered to the public; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">otherwise significantly benefit the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except under exceptional circumstances, an award may not be made for an innovative idea that is under active study or continual review by a unit of State government.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The head of each principal unit shall establish a labor-management review committee, with half of the members being selected from the exclusive representatives, if any, to evaluate and recommend awards for innovative ideas by employees of that unit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">To the extent possible, within 60 days after an innovative idea is submitted to the labor-management review committee, the head of the unit shall decide whether to give an innovative idea award.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The innovative idea may be received directly from an employee through an application, or forwarded by the employee's supervisor.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">For an innovative idea, the head of a principal unit may give an employee of that unit a cash award of not more than:<section prefix="(1)">$1,000 for an innovative idea with a reasonably ascertainable monetary savings or gain to the State; or</section><section prefix="(2)">$300 for any other innovative idea.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Governor's Award Panel.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Governor's Award Panel consists of five members appointed by the Governor, at least three of whom shall be public members who serve without compensation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The head of a principal unit, in consultation with the labor-management review committee, shall submit to the Governor's Award Panel each innovative idea for which an award is made under subsection (e) of this section, with a recommendation for any additional award by the Governor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Governor's Award Panel shall:<section prefix="(i)">review each innovative idea submitted to it;</section><section prefix="(ii)">at least once a year, make a recommendation to the Governor about additional awards for the innovative ideas; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">recommend to the Governor either monetary or nonmonetary awards for the employees' innovative ideas.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor may make an additional cash award for an innovative idea.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The cash award may not exceed $20,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Governor may grant paid administrative leave, not exceeding 20 workdays.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The State's use of an innovative idea:<section prefix="(1)">does not entitle the employee submitting the innovative idea to an award under this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">does not give rise to any claim by the employee or the heirs or assigns of the employee.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
