<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-11-113</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section only applies to an employee:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>113</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section only applies to an employee:<section prefix="(1)">in the management service;</section><section prefix="(2)">in executive service; or</section><section prefix="(3)">under a special appointment described in &#xA7; 6-405 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An employee or an employee's representative may file a written appeal of a disciplinary action with the head of the principal unit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An appeal:<section prefix="(i)">must be filed within 15 days after the employee receives notice of the disciplinary action; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">may only be based on the grounds that the disciplinary action is illegal or unconstitutional.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The employee has the burden of proof in an appeal under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The head of the principal unit may confer with the employee before making a decision.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The head of the principal unit may:<section prefix="(i)">uphold the disciplinary action; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">rescind or modify the disciplinary action and restore to the employee any lost time, compensation, status, or benefits.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 15 days after receiving an appeal, the head of the principal unit shall issue the employee a written decision.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The decision of the head of the principal unit is the final administrative decision.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Within 15 days after issuance of a decision to rescind a disciplinary action, the disciplinary action shall be expunged from the employee's personnel records.</section>
  </text>
</law>
