<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-31-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Agency on aging" means:<section prefix="(1)">an area agency on aging;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Dorchester County Commission on Aging, Inc.;</section><section prefix="(3)">the Somerset County Commission on Aging, Inc.;</section><section prefix="(4)">the Washington County Commission on Aging, Inc.; and</section><section prefix="(5)">the Worcester County Commission on Aging, Inc.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Effective date" means the date that an eligible governmental unit commenced or commences participation in an employees' system.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Eligible governmental unit" means a governmental unit that is eligible to participate in the employees' systems under &#xA7; 31-102 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Employee" means a regular employee of an eligible governmental unit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Employee" includes an officer of an eligible governmental unit.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Employee" does not include a contractual, emergency, or temporary extra employee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Employees' system" means the Employees' Retirement System or the Employees' Pension System.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Legislative body" means the entity with legislative authority or control over an eligible governmental unit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Legislative body" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a board of county commissioners;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a county council;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the legislative body of a municipal corporation;</section><section prefix="(iv)">for a community action agency, a governing body as defined in &#xA7; 8-101 of the Housing and Community Development Article;</section><section prefix="(v)">for an agency on aging:<section prefix="1.">the legislative body of the county that the agency on aging represents; or</section><section prefix="2.">for an area agency on aging that represents more than one county, the legislative body of each of the counties included in the jurisdiction of the area agency on aging;</section></section><section prefix="(vi)">for the University of Maryland Medical System Corporation, the Board of Directors of the corporation; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">for the Garrett County Office for Children, Youth and Families, the Board of County Commissioners for Garrett County.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Local pension system" means a retirement or pension system established by the legislative body of an eligible governmental unit.</section>
  </text>
</law>
