<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="21-309" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-21-309</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "participating governmental unit" includes a county required to pay the employer contribution or part of the employer contribution under &#xA7; 21-307 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each year, the Board of Trustees shall certify to the chief fiscal officer of each participating governmental unit:<section prefix="(1)">the normal contribution rates, accrued liability contribution rates, special accrued liability contribution rate, and withdrawal liability contribution rate for the participating governmental unit; and</section><section prefix="(2)">any amount payable by the participating governmental unit for a master under &#xA7; 21-307(b)(2) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each participating governmental unit shall:<section prefix="(1)">include an amount determined based on the rates certified by the Board of Trustees as payable by the participating governmental unit under this section in the next budget, appropriation, or levy of the participating governmental unit after the certification by the Board of Trustees; and</section><section prefix="(2)">levy and collect those amounts in the same manner as any other tax.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, within 30 days after receiving the certification by the Board of Trustees of the amount payable by the participating governmental unit under this section, the proper fiscal officer of each participating governmental unit shall pay that amount to the Board of Trustees.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A participating governmental unit that does not pay the amounts certified under this subsection within the time required is liable for:<section prefix="(i)">a penalty of 10% of the amount due; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">interest on delinquent amounts at 10% a year until payment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary of the Board of Trustees may allow a grace period for payment of the amounts certified under this section not to exceed 10 calendar days.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On notification by the Secretary of the Board of Trustees that a delinquency exists, the State Comptroller immediately shall exercise the right of setoff against any money due or coming due to the delinquent participating governmental unit.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">On receipt of the payments from the fiscal officer of each participating governmental unit, the Board of Trustees shall credit these amounts to the accumulation fund of the appropriate State system.</section>
  </text>
</law>
