<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-26-203.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to a member of the Maryland Transit Administration Police Force who:<section prefix="(1)">has the powers granted to a police officer under &#xA7; 7-207 of the Transportation Article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">who transfers to the Law Enforcement Officers' Pension System on or before December 31, 2005.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Before the transfer of a member to the Law Enforcement Officers' Pension System, the Maryland Transit Administration shall perform all calculations and compile all necessary information and documentation as directed or required by the State Retirement and Pension System for the transfer of each individual account.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 60 days before transferring to the Law Enforcement Officers' Pension System, a member of the Maryland Transit Administration Police Force may elect to pay all or a portion of the member contribution that would have been paid by a member of the Law Enforcement Officers' Pension System for the period of time the member of the Maryland Transit Administration Police Force was employed with the Maryland Transit Administration from July 1, 2000 through December 31, 2005.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member who elects to pay all or a portion of the member contributions under paragraph (1) of this subsection, shall pay the Maryland Transit Administration in accordance with subsection (e)(1) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The member shall complete and file with the Maryland Transit Administration a form stating the member's intent to pay all or a portion of the member contributions under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Maryland Transit Administration shall coordinate and manage the member's election to pay all or a portion of the member contributions under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a member elects not to pay all or a portion of the member contributions as provided in subsection (c) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">the Maryland Transit Administration may not pay any amount of member contributions due for prior service credit for that member to the Board of Trustees; and</section><section prefix="(2)">on retirement from the Law Enforcement Officers' Pension System, the member's retirement allowance shall be reduced by the actuarial equivalent of the member contributions that would have been deducted if the member had earned the service credit under the Law Enforcement Officers' Pension System, including interest on those contributions.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a member elects to pay for all or a portion of the member contributions as provided in subsection (d) of this section, the member shall pay the Maryland Transit Administration 4% of the member's Maryland Transit Administration annual salary on February 23, 2005, multiplied by 50% of the member's number of years of service, including partial years, from July 1, 2000 through July 1, 2005.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Payments made under this subsection shall begin the first pay period of 2006 and continue until the total amount owed by the member is paid.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Maryland Transit Administration shall administer and manage the payments as follows:<section prefix="(i)">the member shall pay to the Maryland Transit Administration, through payroll deductions, the sum of $30 per week until the amount as calculated by the Maryland Transit Administration is paid;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the member shall pay the Maryland Transit Administration any remaining balance due at the time of separation from service with the Maryland Transit Administration; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">any amount remaining to be paid by a member who dies while still employed by the Maryland Transit Administration shall be forgiven by the Maryland Transit Administration.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">For a member who elects to pay a portion of the member contributions under this section, the State Retirement and Pension System shall bill the Maryland Transit Administration, and the Maryland Transit Administration shall pay, the entire amount of member contributions due for the period of July 1, 2000 through July 1, 2005, including interest, no later than January 1, 2006, as specified by the State Retirement and Pension System.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a member participated in the Maryland Transit Administration's Supplemental Pension Plan in addition to the Maryland Transit Administration's Pension System, the member's retirement allowance shall be reduced by the set-off amount that was fixed upon termination of the Supplemental Pension Plan in December 2003.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Maryland Transit Administration shall provide the names and set-off amounts for all members to the State Retirement and Pension System at the time of retirement.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
