<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-21-128</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "retiree organization" means an organization in which State retirees participate an...</catch_line>
  <order_by>128</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "retiree organization" means an organization in which State retirees participate and that has as one of its primary purposes, representing or providing services to State retirees.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to any retiree organization that has the legal authority to provide services to retirees of the several systems.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A retiree organization may submit only one request in both April and October of each year to the Board of Trustees to assist the retiree organization in performing direct mailings to retirees of the several systems who are members of the retiree organization or eligible to become members of the retiree organization.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The direct mailings may not be for the purpose of supporting or opposing any political party, ballot measure, or candidate in any election, including any State general or primary election or any election within the retiree organization.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board of Trustees shall provide the retiree data for addressing envelopes only to the mail processing center under a secure data share agreement with the mail processing center under which neither the retiree organization nor any other entity has direct access to any names or addresses.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the Board of Trustees provides any retiree data to a mail processing center under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the Board of Trustees is not required to notify a retiree whose data is released of the provisions of &#xA7; 21-504 of this title.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A retiree organization shall provide the Board of Trustees with copies of all materials that will be included in the direct mailing.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Board of Trustees shall review the materials provided under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph before providing any retiree data to a mail processing center.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The direct mailing shall provide retirees of the several systems who are members of the retiree organization or eligible to become members of the retiree organization with information that explains the services offered by the retiree organization.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A retiree organization is solely responsible for the procurement of a mail processing center under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The retiree organization shall provide all printed materials to be mailed and envelopes to a mail processing center.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The retiree organization is responsible for paying all costs for generating mailing labels, inserting materials into envelopes, sealing, labeling, and delivering materials to be mailed to a bulk mail center or post office.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The retiree organization is responsible for all postage costs involved for the direct mailings.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Board of Trustees is not liable for the content of any direct mailing sent under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">On or before December 31 of each year, the Board of Trustees shall submit a report in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article to the Joint Committee on Pensions that includes a summary of any complaints received by the State Retirement Agency regarding any mailing received by a retiree under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
