<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-21-125.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>Beginning on or before September 1, 2008, and every 5 years thereafter, the Joint Committee on Pensi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>125.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Beginning on or before September 1, 2008, and every 5 years thereafter, the Joint Committee on Pensions shall commission an actuarial consulting firm to conduct a study of the several systems in addition to the actuarial investigation and valuation performed by the actuary under &#xA7; 21-125 of this subtitle and a comparison of the several systems with other similarly situated public pension plans.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The actuarial consulting firm shall consider the following issues with regard to the several systems and other similarly situated public pension plans:<section prefix="(1)">the funding status of the State Retirement and Pension System, including its current unfunded accrued liability;</section><section prefix="(2)">the composition of the several systems, including:<section prefix="(i)">the number of active members, retirees, disability retirees, and beneficiaries of all retirees;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the average annual salaries of the active members in the various plans in the State Retirement and Pension System;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the average annual benefits of the retirees and beneficiaries of the State Retirement and Pension System; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the average age, life expectancy, and years of service of active members retiring from the various plans in the State Retirement and Pension System; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">the benefit levels provided by the various State systems, including a comparison of member contribution rates and the accrual rates.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The findings of the actuarial consulting firm shall be submitted to the Joint Committee on Pensions on or before December 31, of the year of study, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
