<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="21-305.5" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-21-305.5</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Complement of the participant funding ratio" is a ratio equal to 100% minus the participant funding ratio, and may not be less than zero.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Employees' systems" means the Employees' Pension System and the Employees' Retirement System.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Noncontributory participating governmental unit" means a participating governmental unit that did not elect to provide its employees with the contributory pension benefit or the Alternate Contributory Pension Selection as provided in &#xA7; 31-116 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Noncontributory system funding ratio" means the ratio determined by the actuary as provided under subsection (e) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Participant funding ratio" means the ratio determined under subsection (d) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Transition amount" means the amount determined by the actuary as provided under subsection (i) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only to a participating governmental unit that on or after July 1, 2001, elects to withdraw from participation in the employees' systems and transfer to a local pension system all employees of the participating governmental unit who consent to the withdrawal.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On and after the date of a participating governmental unit's withdrawal from the employees' systems under &#xA7; 31-302(1) of this article, the participating governmental unit and its employees are not required to make any further contributions to the employees' systems for those employees who elect to withdraw from the employees' systems.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">As of the effective date of withdrawal, the participating governmental unit shall continue to make any contributions required under &#xA7; 21-305(b)(1) and (2) of this subtitle on behalf of those employees who do not elect to withdraw from the employees' systems.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">As of the effective date of withdrawal of a participating governmental unit, the Board of Trustees shall transfer to the administrative board of the local pension system the assets that are allocable to the employees of the participating governmental unit who elect to withdraw from the employees' systems as determined under either subsection (f) or (g) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to a participating governmental unit that elected to provide its employees with the contributory pension benefit or the Alternate Contributory Pension Selection as provided in &#xA7; 31-116 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">As of June 30 of each fiscal year, the actuary shall determine the participant funding ratio for the participating governmental units as provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The participant funding ratio shall be a fraction that has:<section prefix="(i)">as its numerator, the assets to the credit of the participating governmental units in the accumulation fund and the annuity savings fund of the employees' systems as adjusted under paragraph (4) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">as its denominator, the actuarial liabilities of the participating governmental units.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The assets to the credit of the participating governmental units as of the valuation date shall be:<section prefix="(i)">increased by the sum of the outstanding balances of:</section><section prefix="(ii)">decreased by the sum of the outstanding balances of the surplus allocated to each participating governmental unit under &#xA7; 21-305.4(b) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to a noncontributory participating governmental unit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">As of June 30 of each fiscal year, the actuary shall determine the noncontributory system funding ratio for the noncontributory participating governmental units as provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The noncontributory system funding ratio shall be a fraction that has:<section prefix="(i)">as its numerator, the assets to the credit of the participating governmental units in the accumulation fund and the annuity savings fund of the employees' systems as adjusted under paragraph (4) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">as its denominator, the actuarial liabilities of the participating governmental units calculated as if all of the participating governmental units are noncontributory participating governmental units.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The assets to the credit of the participating governmental units as of the valuation date shall be:<section prefix="(i)">increased by the sum of the outstanding balances of:</section><section prefix="(ii)">decreased by the sum of the outstanding balances of the surplus allocated to each participating governmental unit under &#xA7; 21-305.4(b) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to a participating governmental unit that elected to provide its employees with the contributory pension benefit or the Alternate Contributory Pension Selection as provided in &#xA7; 31-116 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The assets that are allocable to the employees of a participating governmental unit who elect to withdraw from the employees' systems shall be computed by the actuary as provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the participant funding ratio for the fiscal year preceding the effective date of withdrawal of the participating governmental unit is less than 100%, the actuary shall multiply the participant funding ratio for the fiscal year preceding the effective date of withdrawal of the participating governmental unit by the actuarial liability allocable to the employees of the participating governmental unit who elect to withdraw.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the participant funding ratio for the fiscal year preceding the effective date of withdrawal of the participating governmental unit is 100% or greater and less than 110%, the actuary shall multiply the actuarial liability allocable to the employees of the participating governmental unit who elect to withdraw by 100%.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If the participant funding ratio for the fiscal year preceding the effective date of withdrawal of the participating governmental unit is 110% or greater, the actuary shall multiply the actuarial liability allocable to the employees of the participating governmental unit who elect to withdraw by the difference between the participant funding ratio and 10%.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Any assets computed under paragraph (3), (4), or (5) of this subsection shall be reduced by the sum of:<section prefix="(i)">the outstanding balance of the deficit allocable to the participating governmental unit as of the effective date of withdrawal;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the outstanding balance of the special accrued liability contribution allocable to the participating governmental unit as of the effective date of withdrawal; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">any transition amount as determined under subsection (i) of this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to a noncontributory participating governmental unit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The assets that are allocable to the employees of a noncontributory participating governmental unit who elect to withdraw from the employees' systems shall be computed by the actuary as provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the noncontributory system funding ratio for the fiscal year preceding the effective date of withdrawal of the noncontributory participating governmental unit is less than 100%, the actuary shall multiply the noncontributory system funding ratio for the fiscal year preceding the effective date of withdrawal of the noncontributory participating governmental unit by the actuarial liability allocable to the employees of the noncontributory participating governmental unit who elect to withdraw.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the noncontributory system funding ratio for the fiscal year preceding the effective date of withdrawal of the noncontributory participating governmental unit is 100% or greater and less than 110%, the actuary shall multiply the actuarial liability allocable to the employees of the noncontributory participating governmental unit who elect to withdraw by 100%.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If the noncontributory system funding ratio for the fiscal year preceding the effective date of withdrawal of the noncontributory participating governmental unit is 110% or greater, the actuary shall multiply the actuarial liability allocable to the employees of the noncontributory participating governmental unit who elect to withdraw by the difference between the noncontributory system funding ratio and 10%.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Any assets computed under paragraph (3), (4), or (5) of this subsection shall be reduced by the sum of:<section prefix="(i)">the outstanding balance of the deficit allocable to the noncontributory participating governmental unit as of the effective date of withdrawal;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the outstanding balance of the special accrued liability contribution allocable to the noncontributory participating governmental unit as of the effective date of withdrawal; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">any transition amount as determined under subsection (i) of this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The withdrawal liability contribution of a participating governmental unit shall be computed by the actuary as provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The actuary shall:<section prefix="(i)">multiply the complement of the participant funding ratio for the fiscal year preceding the effective date of withdrawal of the participating governmental unit by the actuarial liability allocable to the employees of the participating governmental unit who elect to remain members of the employees' systems; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">reduce the amount determined under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph by the outstanding balance of the surplus allocable to the participating governmental unit as of the effective date of withdrawal.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The amount determined under paragraph (2) of this subsection may not be less than zero.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the annual withdrawal liability contribution of a participating governmental unit shall be the annual payment that is sufficient to liquidate, over not more than 25 years, the withdrawal liability contribution by means of annual payments that increase each year based on the actuarial assumptions adopted by the Board of Trustees on the recommendation of the actuary.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subject to the approval of the Board of Trustees and the actuary's concurrence, a participating governmental unit:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section applies only to a participating governmental unit with a deficit as determined under &#xA7; 21-305.4(c) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The transition amount of a participating governmental unit shall be computed by the actuary as provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The actuary shall determine the pre-June 30, 1995 status and the post-June 30, 1995 status of a participating governmental unit using the assumptions that:<section prefix="(i)">the participating governmental unit elects to withdraw from the employees' systems as of June 30, 1995;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the employees of the withdrawing participating governmental unit who are members of the Employees' Retirement System elect to remain in the employees' systems; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the employees of the withdrawing participating governmental unit who are members of the Employees' Pension System elect to withdraw from the employees' systems.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The pre-June 30, 1995 status of a participating governmental unit is an amount equal to the difference between:<section prefix="(i)">the assets transferable to a participating governmental unit that are allocable to the employees of the participating governmental unit who elect to withdraw from the employees' systems as determined by the actuary applying the provisions of former &#xA7; 21-305(f) of this article as of June 30, 1995; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the withdrawal liability of a participating governmental unit that is attributable to the employees of the participating governmental unit who elect to remain members of the employees' systems as determined by the actuary applying the provisions of former &#xA7; 21-305(f) of this article as of June 30, 1995.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The post-June 30, 1995 status of a participating governmental unit is an amount equal to the difference between:<section prefix="(i)">the assets transferable to a participating governmental unit that are allocable to the employees who elect to withdraw from the employees' systems as determined under subsection (d) of this section as of June 30, 1995; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the withdrawal liability of a participating governmental unit that is attributable to the employees of the participating governmental unit who elect to remain in the employees' systems as determined under subsection (f) of this section as of June 30, 1995.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the transition amount of a participating governmental unit is the amount determined by the actuary as of June 30, 1995, equal to the difference between:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The transition amount of a participating governmental unit may not be less than zero.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">As of June 30 of each fiscal year, the transition amount of a participating governmental unit shall decrease by writing down the transition amount in equal annual installments over the 25-year term beginning on July 1, 1995.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">On the recommendation of the actuary, the Board of Trustees shall adopt regulations that are necessary to carry out this section, and that set forth a schedule reflecting:<section prefix="(i)">any transition amount allocable to a participating governmental unit; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the outstanding balance of the transition amount each year.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
