<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-402" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-10-402</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to a temporary employee.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When a principal unit plans the closure of a facility where 50 or more employees regularly work, that unit shall give the employees of that facility notice of the planned closure of the facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the notice shall be given at least 6 months before closing a facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In any year in which the Governor fails to include sufficient funds in the annual budget to operate a facility, thereby precipitating the closure of the facility, the notice shall be given no later than 30 days following the submission of the annual budget bill to the General Assembly.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Whenever the General Assembly in any year fails to appropriate sufficient funds in the annual budget to operate a facility, thereby precipitating the closure of the facility, the notice shall be given no later than 30 days following the close of that session of the General Assembly.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If requested by an employee who is to be laid off, immediately following the notice, the department or other independent unit that plans the closure shall:<section prefix="(1)">begin to provide intensive job counseling and training referral for the affected employees;</section><section prefix="(2)">make efforts to relocate or transfer the affected employees to other departmental positions in the State; and</section><section prefix="(3)">notify the Department of Budget and Management and the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation of any employees who are adversely affected.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department of Budget and Management shall:<section prefix="(1)">develop a list of State classifications with their comparable classifications, if any; and</section><section prefix="(2)">with the assistance of the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation, make efforts to relocate the affected State employees to vacant State positions.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation shall develop a program to assist adversely affected State employees by providing retraining and other appropriate employment and training services.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Secretary shall adopt rules and regulations to implement this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
