<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-23-404</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>404</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Appointed official" means an individual appointed to a public office of the State who meets the legal criteria for an appointed official as determined by the Office of the Attorney General.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Unclassified service of the State" means the unclassified service in the State Personnel Management System or a comparable position in an independent personnel system of a participating employer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board of Trustees shall pay a member of the Employees' Pension System who qualifies under subsection (c) of this section a normal service retirement allowance, regardless of age, if the member:<section prefix="(1)">has at least 16 years of creditable service; and</section><section prefix="(2)">elects to have the member's accumulated contributions paid as an annuity of equivalent actuarial value instead of withdrawing the accumulated contributions.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A member qualifies for a normal service retirement allowance under subsection (b) of this section if the member:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">is an elected or appointed official of the State at the time of application for retirement; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">was initially an elected or appointed official of the State before July 22, 1981;</section></section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">is an elected or appointed official of the State when separating from employment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">was initially an elected or appointed official of the State during the period from July 22, 1981, through June 30, 1982, both inclusive; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">separated from employment involuntarily, as certified by the Secretary of Budget and Management;</section></section><section prefix="(3)"><section prefix="(i)">was promoted to a position in the unclassified service of the State on or before June 30, 1982;</section><section prefix="(ii)">has been in the unclassified service or its equivalent in the State continuously from June 30, 1982, until separating from employment; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">separated from employment involuntarily, as certified by the Secretary of Budget and Management; or</section></section><section prefix="(4)"><section prefix="(i)">is a deputy clerk of the court at the time of application for retirement; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">was initially a deputy clerk of the court before July 22, 1981.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to a retiree who:<section prefix="(i)">retires as an elected or appointed official under this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is appointed or elected to an office for which the State pays the compensation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On the appointment or election of a retiree described in paragraph (1) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">the retiree's retirement allowance shall stop;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the retiree may rejoin the Employees' Pension System;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the retiree shall make member contributions as provided in this title; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Board of Trustees shall restore any creditable service or eligibility service to the retiree's credit at the time of retirement.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection, on subsequent retirement of a retiree described in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Board of Trustees shall credit the retiree with all of the retiree's creditable service and eligibility service as a member.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The allowance, on the subsequent retirement, may not exceed the sum of:<section prefix="(i)">the allowance the retiree was receiving during the previous retirement; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the allowance that has accrued on account of creditable service earned after the previous retirement.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
