<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-29-110</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section does not apply to the State Police Retirement System....</catch_line>
  <order_by>110</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to the State Police Retirement System.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, an accidental disability retirement allowance equals the lesser of:<section prefix="(1)">the member's average final compensation; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the sum of:<section prefix="(i)">an annuity that is the actuarial equivalent of the member's accumulated contributions at retirement; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a pension equal to two-thirds of the member's average final compensation.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to a member of a State system other than the Law Enforcement Officers' Pension System who is at least normal retirement age.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An accidental disability retirement allowance equals the greater of:<section prefix="(i)">a normal service retirement allowance; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an accidental disability retirement allowance computed in accordance with subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only to a member of the Employees' Pension System who:<section prefix="(i)">is promoted within the Department of Corrections to a position that no longer is eligible for membership in the Correctional Officers' Retirement System as provided in &#xA7; 25-201 of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">elects not to transfer the years of creditable service the individual accrued in the Correctional Officers' Retirement System to the Employees' Pension System; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">is eligible to receive a vested allowance from the Correctional Officers' Retirement System.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member may receive an accidental disability retirement allowance under this section if the member:<section prefix="(i)">does not elect to receive a vested allowance from the Correctional Officers' Retirement System; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">transfers the member's accumulated contributions in the Correctional Officers' Retirement System to the Employees' Pension System.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
