<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-20-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only to an individual who on or before June 30, 2011, is a member of:<section prefix="(1)">the Employees' Pension System;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Local Fire and Police System;</section><section prefix="(3)">the Law Enforcement Officers' Pension System; or</section><section prefix="(4)">the Teachers' Pension System.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "break in service" means a period of employment in which the member's employer did not:<section prefix="(i)">deduct the member contributions from the compensation of the member; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">report the hours worked by the member.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">For the purpose of computing benefits under this Division II, the average final compensation of a member equals the average annual earnable compensation of the member, adjusted as provided in this section, during the 3 consecutive years that provide the highest average earnable compensation.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the member experienced any break in service during the 3 consecutive years that provide the member's highest average earnable compensation, the Board of Trustees:<section prefix="1.">may not include in the computation of average final compensation the period of months of the breaks in service, that otherwise would be included in the computation; and</section><section prefix="2.">in order to generate the highest average earnable compensation for the member, shall extend the 3-year period by an equal number of months immediately preceding or following that period.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to a member of the Employees' Pension System or Teachers' Pension System who is subject to the noncontributory pension benefit and who was on authorized leave of absence at partial pay or without pay during the last 3 years of employment as a member.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the period used to determine average final compensation is the period that immediately precedes the date of retirement or other separation from employment, the Board of Trustees:<section prefix="(i)">may not include in the computation of average final compensation the period of months of the leave of absence, not exceeding 12, that otherwise would be included in the computation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall substitute an equal number of months immediately preceding that period.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to a member whose eligibility service has been adjusted under this Division II to compute creditable service, on the basis of the member having completed less than the normal hours of service for the member's position.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member's earnable compensation shall be adjusted to a full-time basis for any period included in the computation of average final compensation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except for a salary increase because of a member's promotion, the member's average final compensation does not include a salary increase in the last 3 years of employment if it is an extraordinary salary increase according to regulations that the Board of Trustees adopts.</section>
  </text>
</law>
