<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-22-209</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>209</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to subsection (c) of this section, as a condition of an individual's employment contract, an individual may remain a member of the Employees' Retirement System or the Teachers' Retirement System without change in the benefits under that retirement system as of December 31, 1979, if:<section prefix="(1)">the individual is a member of that retirement system on December 31, 1979; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the individual's membership does not terminate under &#xA7; 22-217 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to subsection (c) of this section, an individual receiving benefits under this title on December 31, 1979, shall continue to receive the benefits provided as of December 31, 1979.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The benefits that an individual may continue to receive include:<section prefix="(i)">eligibility for service retirement on or after 30 years of eligibility service or age 60;</section><section prefix="(ii)">eligibility for a reduced service retirement allowance after a certain length of eligibility service;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a normal service retirement allowance of one fifty-fifth of average final compensation multiplied by the number of years of creditable service;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the retirement allowances provided for ordinary or accidental disability;</section><section prefix="(v)">the selection of options for allowances;</section><section prefix="(vi)">the adjustment of the allowance for increases in the Consumer Price Index;</section><section prefix="(vii)">the death benefit;</section><section prefix="(viii)">the level of member contributions; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">the length of eligibility service for members to vest benefits in the system.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For a member who receives creditable service under this title on or after July 1, 1984, &#xA7;&#xA7; 22-219 through 22-221 of this subtitle determine:<section prefix="(1)">the rate of earnable compensation that is payable as member contributions;</section><section prefix="(2)">the computation of the member's allowance; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the cost-of-living adjustment of the member's allowance.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
