<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="21-125" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-21-125</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board of Trustees shall designate an actuary who shall:<section prefix="(1)">give technical advice to the Board of Trustees on the operation of the funds of the several systems; and</section><section prefix="(2)">perform other related duties that the Board of Trustees requires.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On the basis of actuarial assumptions that the Board of Trustees adopts, each year the actuary shall make a valuation of the assets and liabilities of the funds of the several systems.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each year the Board of Trustees shall certify to the Secretary of Budget and Management and to the Governor the rates of employer contributions.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For purposes of actuarial valuation, the Board of Trustees may adopt a generally accepted method for determining the value of the assets held by the several systems.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">For general ledger accounting and financial reporting, the Board of Trustees shall use generally accepted accounting principles.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least once in each 5-year period, the actuary shall make:<section prefix="(i)">actuarial investigations into the compensation, mortality, and service experience of the participants of each of the several systems; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a valuation of the assets and liabilities of the funds of each of the several systems.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board of Trustees shall:<section prefix="(i)">review the results of the investigations and valuations of the actuary; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">adopt the actuarial assumptions for each of the several systems as the Board of Trustees considers necessary.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
