<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-3-2A-02</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Board consists of the following five members:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>02</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board consists of the following five members:<section prefix="(1)">four members with expertise in higher education, appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate from a list provided by the Maryland Higher Education Commission:<section prefix="(i)">who are not officers or employees of a State institution of higher education or an employee organization;</section><section prefix="(ii)">who are known for objective and independent judgment; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">two of whom have knowledge of labor issues; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">one member of the general public, appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate from a list provided by the Maryland Higher Education Commission, who is known for objective and independent judgment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Before taking office, each member shall take the oath required by Article I, &#xA7; 9 of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">With the advice of the governing boards of State institutions of higher education, the Governor shall designate a chairman from among the members of the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 6 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Board on July 1, 2001.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A vacancy shall be filled for an unexpired term in the same manner as an original appointment.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the remainder of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Governor may remove a member for incompetence or misconduct.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In making appointments to the Board, the Governor shall ensure, to the extent practicable, that:<section prefix="(1)">the ratio of male to female members and the racial makeup of the Board is reflective of the general population of the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">each major geographic area of the State is represented on the Board.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
