<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-24-401</section_number>
  <catch_line>This paragraph applies to an individual who is a member on or before June 30, 2011....</catch_line>
  <order_by>401</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies to an individual who is a member on or before June 30, 2011.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A member may retire with a normal service retirement allowance if:<section prefix="1.">on or before the date of retirement, the member:</section><section prefix="2.">the member completes and submits a written application to the Board of Trustees, on the form that the Board of Trustees provides, stating the date when the member desires to retire.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies to an individual who becomes a member on or after July 1, 2011.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A member may retire with a normal service retirement allowance if:<section prefix="1.">on or before the date of retirement, the member:</section><section prefix="2.">the member completes and submits a written application to the Board of Trustees, on the form that the Board of Trustees provides, stating the date when the member desires to retire.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the approval of the Board of Trustees, the Secretary of State Police may order a member who is at least 50 years old to retire on the first day of the month after the member is notified of the Secretary's order.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before approving the Secretary's order, the Board of Trustees shall give the member at least 30 days' notice and an opportunity to be heard.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except for the Secretary of State Police, a member shall retire with a normal service retirement allowance not later than the first day of the month after the member becomes 60 years old.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, on retirement under this section, a member is entitled to receive a normal service retirement allowance that equals 2.55% of the member's average final compensation multiplied by each year of the member's years of creditable service.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member's normal service retirement allowance may not exceed 71.4% of the member's average final compensation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, a retiree, or a beneficiary of a retiree, who retires on or before June 30, 1999 with a service retirement allowance, shall receive an annual retirement allowance adjustment as of July 1, 1999, as follows:<section prefix="(i)">for a retiree who has been retired not more than 5 years, $1,200;</section><section prefix="(ii)">for a retiree who has been retired more than 5 years but not more than 10 years, $1,500;</section><section prefix="(iii)">for a retiree who has been retired more than 10 years but not more than 15 years, $1,800; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">for a retiree who has been retired more than 15 years, $2,100.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, each fiscal year, the Board of Trustees shall adjust the adjustment received by the retiree or the beneficiary as of July 1, 1999, by multiplying the adjustment by a fraction that has:<section prefix="(i)">as its numerator, the Consumer Price Index for the calendar year ending December 31 of the preceding fiscal year; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">as its denominator, the Consumer Price Index for the calendar year ending December 31, 1998.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this paragraph, "zero-adjustment fiscal year" means any fiscal year when the allowance adjustment as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection is less than the allowance adjustment paid for the preceding fiscal year.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For any fiscal year, the allowance adjustment may not be less than the allowance adjustment paid for the preceding fiscal year.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">
          <section prefix="1.">This subparagraph applies only to a fiscal year that is not a zero-adjustment fiscal year.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">Subject to subsubparagraph 3 of this subparagraph:</section>
          <section prefix="3.">If the amount of the reduction required for any fiscal year under subsubparagraph 2 of this subparagraph exceeds the difference between the allowance adjustment as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection for the fiscal year and the allowance adjustment  paid in the preceding fiscal year, the excess shall be deducted in future fiscal years, subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, until the difference is fully recovered.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
