<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-3-601</section_number>
  <catch_line>A memorandum of understanding shall contain all matters of agreement reached in the collective barga...</catch_line>
  <order_by>601</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A memorandum of understanding shall contain all matters of agreement reached in the collective bargaining process.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The memorandum shall be in writing and signed by the exclusive representative involved in the collective bargaining negotiations and:<section prefix="(i)">for a memorandum of understanding relating to the State, the Governor or the Governor's designee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">for a memorandum of understanding relating to a system institution, the president of the system institution or the president's designee; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">for a memorandum of understanding relating to Morgan State University, St. Mary's College of Maryland, or Baltimore City Community College, the governing board of the institution or the governing board's designee.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">No memorandum of understanding is valid if it extends for less than 1 year or for more than 3 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a memorandum of understanding is not effective until it is ratified by the Governor and a majority of the votes cast by the employees in the bargaining unit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the case of a State institution of higher education, a memorandum of understanding is not effective until it is ratified by the institution's governing board and a majority of the votes cast by the employees in the bargaining unit.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
