<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-10-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is an Incentive Performance Awards Program for employees.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An incentive performance award for extraordinary service may be awarded for extraordinary performance in the public interest in connection with an employee's State employment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For extraordinary service, the head of a principal unit may make the following awards to an employee or members of a group of employees in that unit:<section prefix="(i)">cash of not more than $300;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a gift of not more than $300 in value;</section><section prefix="(iii)">paid administrative leave of not more than 3 days; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">any combination of cash, gift, and leave of not more than $300 in value.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An employee may only receive one incentive performance award under this subsection in any 12-month period.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An incentive performance award for outstanding service in connection with State employment over a sustained period or a special State project may be awarded for:<section prefix="(i)">exceptional performance that exceeds the knowledge, skill, or ability required by the employee's position; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">exceptionally meritorious acts or services in the public interest.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For outstanding service, the head of a principal unit may make a cash award of not more than $3,000 to an employee of that unit.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An employee may only receive one incentive performance award under this subsection in any 24-month period.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before making an award, the head of a principal unit shall:<section prefix="(i)">establish criteria for administering the Incentive Performance Awards Program, including standards of eligibility; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">ensure that the employees in the unit have copies of the criteria.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The head of the unit may amend the criteria at any time, but an amendment is not effective until the employees in the unit have been sent a copy of the amendment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The head of a principal unit may delegate to any subordinate supervising unit head the authority to make awards under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
