<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-21-123</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except for those assets that the law requires another entity or person to control, the State Retirem...</catch_line>
  <order_by>123</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except for those assets that the law requires another entity or person to control, the State Retirement Agency, under the supervision of the Board of Trustees, shall manage all assets of the several systems.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board of Trustees:<section prefix="(1)">is deemed the owner of all the assets of the several systems; but</section><section prefix="(2)">may delegate some or all incidents of ownership to the State Retirement Agency to administer the investment portfolios of the several systems.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of Trustees may invest assets of the several systems subject to the conditions that it imposes.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board of Trustees shall include the conditions that it adopts under paragraph (1) of this subsection in the investment policy manual required by &#xA7; 21-116(c) of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only to the execution of:<section prefix="(i)">ground rent redemption deeds;</section><section prefix="(ii)">releases or reassignments of mortgages; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">satisfactions or reassignments of notes conveying, releasing, or reassigning any interest owned by the State for the use of a fund of the several systems.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An instrument must be executed by any two of:<section prefix="(i)">the State Treasurer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Executive Director of the State Retirement Agency;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Chief Investment Officer of the State Retirement Agency; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">another employee of the State Retirement Agency as the Executive Director designates with the approval of the Board of Trustees.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of Trustees may commingle assets of the several systems, including the Postretirement Health Benefits Trust Fund, if the Board of Trustees keeps seven sets of records that show:<section prefix="(i)">the percentage of participation of each State system or group of State systems, including the Postretirement Health Benefits Trust Fund;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the percentage of income, gains, and losses applicable to each State system or group of State systems, including the Postretirement Health Benefits Trust Fund; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the total contributions and disbursements applicable to each State system or group of State systems, including the Postretirement Health Benefits Trust Fund.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board of Trustees shall keep records required by paragraph (1) of this subsection for each of the following:<section prefix="(i)">the group that consists of the Correctional Officers' Retirement System, the Employees' Pension System, the Employees' Retirement System, and the Legislative Pension Plan;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Judges' Retirement System;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Local Fire and Police System;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Law Enforcement Officers' Pension System;</section><section prefix="(v)">the State Police Retirement System;</section><section prefix="(vi)">the group that consists of the Teachers' Pension System and the Teachers' Retirement System; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">the Postretirement Health Benefits Trust Fund.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other law in force on or after July 1, 1988, unless the law makes specific reference to this subsection, and subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Board of Trustees may keep all analyses, forecasts, negotiations, papers, records, recommendations, and reports closed to public inspection until:<section prefix="(i)">the release of the information would not adversely affect the negotiation for or market price of a security; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">completion of:<section prefix="1.">a proposed purchase or program of purchases leading to a cumulative position in a security;</section><section prefix="2.">the making, sale, or prepayment of a loan;</section><section prefix="3.">any proposed sale or program of sales leading to the elimination of a position in a security; or</section><section prefix="4.">the sale or purchase of real estate.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The sale or purchase of real estate shall be subject to the approval of a majority of the Comptroller, Treasurer, and Secretary of Budget and Management, in their capacity as members of the Board of Trustees.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">On or before October 1 of each year, the Board of Trustees shall submit a report in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article to the Board of Public Works, the Senate Budget and Taxation Committee, the House Appropriations Committee, and the Joint Committee on Pensions that provides a list of all sales or purchases of directly held real estate approved by the Board of Trustees for the immediately preceding fiscal year.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Any direct owned real estate purchased as an investment by the State Retirement and Pension System shall be managed by an external investment manager selected by the Chief Investment Officer.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Title 4, Subtitle 3, Part III and &#xA7; 10-305 of the State Finance and Procurement Article do not apply to the sale, acquisition, lease, transfer, exchange, or other disposition of any real or personal property acquired by the Board of Trustees in any transaction authorized under this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
