<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-24-405</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in &#xA7; 24-405.1 of this subtitle and subject to subsections (b) and (c) of this se...</catch_line>
  <order_by>405</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 24-405.1 of this subtitle and subject to subsections (b) and (c) of this section, an individual who is receiving a service retirement allowance or vested allowance may accept employment with a participating employer on a temporary basis, if:<section prefix="(1)">the employment is not in a regularly allocated position; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the individual immediately notifies the Board of Trustees:<section prefix="(i)">of the individual's intention to accept the employment; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">of the compensation that the individual will receive.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">an individual who has been retired for 5 years, beginning on January 1, after the date the individual retires; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an individual who participates in the Deferred Retirement Option Program established under &#xA7; 24-401.1 of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the Board of Trustees shall reduce an individual's allowance by the amount that the sum of the individual's initial annual basic allowance and the individual's annual compensation exceeds the average final compensation used to compute the basic allowance.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">Any reduction taken to a retiree's allowance under this subsection may not exceed an amount that would reduce the retiree's allowance to less than what is required to be deducted for the retiree's monthly State-approved medical insurance premiums.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">If a reduction for a calendar year taken under subsubparagraph 1 of this subparagraph is less than the reduction required under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the Board of Trustees shall recover from the retiree an amount equal to the reduction required under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph less the reduction taken under subsubparagraph 1 of this subparagraph.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For purposes of this section, employment is not on a temporary basis if, in any 12-month period, an individual works:<section prefix="(1)">full time for more than 6 months; or</section><section prefix="(2)">part time for the equivalent of more than 6 months of full-time work.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
