<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-3-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided in this title, the Board shall determine the appropriateness of each ba...</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, the Board shall determine the appropriateness of each bargaining unit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If there is no dispute about the appropriateness of the establishment of the bargaining unit, the Board shall issue an order defining an appropriate bargaining unit.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If there is a dispute about the appropriateness of the establishment of the bargaining unit, the Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">conduct a hearing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">issue an order defining an appropriate bargaining unit.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the appropriate bargaining unit as determined by the Board differs from the bargaining unit described in the petition, the Board may:<section prefix="(1)">dismiss the petition; or</section><section prefix="(2)">direct an election in the appropriate bargaining unit if the signatures included in the petition include those of at least 30% of the employees in the appropriate bargaining unit.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A bargaining unit shall consist only of employees defined in regulations adopted by the Secretary and not specifically excluded by &#xA7; 3-102(b) of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each system institution, Morgan State University, St. Mary's College of Maryland, and Baltimore City Community College shall have separate bargaining units.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The presidents of the system institutions may agree to cooperate for the purpose of collective bargaining:<section prefix="(i)">before the election of exclusive representatives; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">after the certification of exclusive representatives under &#xA7; 3-406(a) of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Appropriate bargaining units shall consist of:<section prefix="(i)">all eligible nonexempt employees, as described in the federal Fair Labor Standards Act, except eligible sworn police officers;</section><section prefix="(ii)">all eligible exempt employees, as described in the federal Fair Labor Standards Act; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">all eligible sworn police officers.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Secretary or the Secretary's designee shall have the authority to assign classification titles and positions to bargaining units as appropriate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The following individuals and entities shall assign classification titles and positions to bargaining units at the following institutions:<section prefix="(i)">at a system institution, the President of the system institution; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">at Morgan State University, St. Mary's College of Maryland, or Baltimore City Community College, the governing board of the institution.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, Maryland Transportation Authority police officers at the rank of first sergeant and below shall have a separate bargaining unit.</section>
  </text>
</law>
