<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-21-305.3</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>305.3</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Employees' systems" means the Employees' Pension System and the Employees' Retirement System.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Special accrued liability" means, as to any participating governmental unit, the liability of the employees' systems on account of the employees of the participating governmental unit who elect to become members under &#xA7; 23-204(b) of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each participating governmental unit shall make a special accrued liability contribution on account of its participation in the employees' systems.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The special accrued liability contribution shall be determined by an actuarial valuation of the special accrued liability as of the date of approval of participation by the legislative body of the participating governmental unit.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, the annual special accrued liability contribution of each participating governmental unit shall be the level annual payment that is sufficient to liquidate, over 25 years beginning on the date of approval by the legislative body of the participating governmental unit, the amount by which the special accrued liability of the participating governmental unit exceeds the sum of:<section prefix="(1)">the present value, as of the date of approval, of future normal contributions, future accrued liability contributions, future contributions for members of the Employees' Retirement System required under &#xA7; 21-305(b)(2)(iii) of this subtitle, future member contributions on behalf of or by members who are employees of the participating governmental unit; and</section><section prefix="(2)">any cash and securities transferred to the Employees' Pension System in accordance with &#xA7; 31-113(d) of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Subject to the approval of the Board of Trustees, a participating governmental unit may liquidate its unfunded special accrued liability:<section prefix="(1)">over a period not to exceed 40 years; or</section><section prefix="(2)">subject to the actuary's concurrence, by means of annual payments other than level annual payments.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A participating governmental unit may prepay the special accrued liability in whole or in part at any time with interest at the annual rate established by the Board of Trustees as of the date of payment.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The expense of making the initial special accrued liability actuarial valuation shall be assessed against and paid by the participating governmental unit on whose account it is necessary.</section>
  </text>
</law>
