<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-2-707</section_number>
  <catch_line>A member of a reserve component of the armed forces of the United States is eligible for the reinsta...</catch_line>
  <order_by>707</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A member of a reserve component of the armed forces of the United States is eligible for the reinstatement rights and benefits specified in &#xA7;&#xA7; 2-705 and 2-706(a), (b), and (c) of this subtitle if the reservist:<section prefix="(1)">performed active duty for training of a nature and length that meet the requirements for eligibility under Title 38 U.S.C. &#xA7; 4301 et seq.;</section><section prefix="(2)">was released from that duty after satisfactory service; and</section><section prefix="(3)">except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, submits an application for reinstatement within 31 days after the reservist was released from that duty.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An otherwise eligible member of a reserve component who was hospitalized at the time the reservist was scheduled to be released from active duty for training may apply for reinstatement if:<section prefix="(1)">the application is submitted within 31 days after the reservist is discharged from the hospital; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the hospitalization:<section prefix="(i)">is connected to the reservist's active duty for training; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">does not last more than 1 year from the date on which the reservist was scheduled to be released from that duty.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A member of a reserve component who is reinstated to a position under this section may not be discharged from that position within 6 months after reinstatement without substantial cause and, if the position is a skilled service or professional service position, with the exception of special appointments, only for the reasons and in the manner provided for skilled service or professional service employees.</section>
  </text>
</law>
