<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-4-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary may delegate authority to the head of a principal unit to classify positions for the principal unit in accordance with standards and procedures established by the Secretary in accordance with &#xA7; 4-202(2) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Secretary delegates classification authority to the head of a principal unit under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the head of the principal unit shall:<section prefix="(i)">submit for the Secretary's approval a position classification plan for classifying positions in the principal unit that are in the skilled service, professional service, and management service; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">classify skilled service positions, professional service positions, and management service positions in the principal unit in accordance with the approved classification plan.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each employee in a position shall assume the classification title given the class to which that position belongs.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary, the Comptroller, and the Treasurer shall use these classification titles in all relevant records and communications.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To ensure that positions in the State Personnel Management System are classified properly, the Secretary:<section prefix="(1)">shall conduct position classification audits at least once every 3 years for any classification activity performed in accordance with subsection (a)(2) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">may conduct operational audits of classification practices and records in principal units at least once every 3 years.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
