<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-308" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-8-308</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 8-305(c) of this subtitle, a law enforcement employee of any unit of State government or a State Police cadet who works more than 8 hours in a normal 8-hour workday is entitled to be paid at the rate of one and one-half times the employee's or cadet's regular hourly rate of pay for time worked in excess of 8 hours.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "off-duty hours" means any hours:<section prefix="(i)">during a law enforcement employee's scheduled off-duty day; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">during a law enforcement employee's on-duty day after the employee has gone off duty.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, a law enforcement employee of any unit of State government who is called to duty on the employee's scheduled off-duty day is entitled to be paid at the rate of one and one-half times the employee's regular hourly rate of pay for each hour worked on the off-duty day.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, a law enforcement employee of the Department of State Police holding a noncommissioned rank or a law enforcement employee of the Department of Natural Resources holding a rank of sergeant or below, park ranger supervisor or below, or park services supervisor or below who is called to duty during the employee's off-duty hours is entitled to be paid at the rate of one and one-half times the employee's regular hourly rate of pay for the greater of:<section prefix="(i)">the hours worked during the off-duty hours; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">4 hours.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A law enforcement employee of the Department of State Police holding a noncommissioned rank or a law enforcement employee of the Department of Natural Resources holding a rank of sergeant or below who makes an appearance in court on official duty during the employee's off-duty hours is entitled to be paid at the rate of one and one-half times the employee's regular hourly rate of pay for the greater of:<section prefix="(i)">the hours worked during the off-duty hours; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">2 hours.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A law enforcement employee of the Department of State Police holding a noncommissioned rank, a law enforcement employee of the Department of Natural Resources holding a rank of sergeant or below, or a police communications operator of the Department of State Police or Natural Resources Police who is required to work 4 or more hours on New Year's Day, Thanksgiving Day, or Christmas Day, or who is scheduled to be off duty on New Year's Day, Thanksgiving Day, or Christmas Day and is called to duty on any part of that day is entitled to:<section prefix="(1)">compensatory time of 1 day; and</section><section prefix="(2)">payment at the rate of one and one-half times the employee's regular hourly rate of pay for each hour worked on that day.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
