<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-7-102</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>102</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each employee in the skilled service, professional service, and management service, including special appointments in each classification of each of those services, shall be provided with a written position description which describes the essential duties and responsibilities the employee is expected to perform and the standards for satisfactory performance on a form approved by the Secretary.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A successful applicant for a position in the skilled service, professional service, or management service shall be provided with a position description for review before accepting appointment to the position.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The appointing authority or designee shall approve position descriptions and revised position descriptions for the positions in the unit.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A supervisor shall:<section prefix="(i)">ensure the preparation of a position description for each position over which the supervisor has primary direct responsibility;</section><section prefix="(ii)">maintain position descriptions for the positions under the supervisor's jurisdiction; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">give each supervised employee a copy of the position description for the employee's position.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The supervisor and employee shall review the position description for the employee's position and make any necessary revision:<section prefix="(i)">whenever there is a change in the essential functions of the position; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">as part of the employee's performance appraisal.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">When there is no position description for a new or vacant position, the primary direct supervisor of the position shall:<section prefix="(i)">prepare a position description for the position; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">submit it as part of the selection plan to fill the position.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A position description shall contain information required by the Secretary, including a description of the essential functions of the position.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The duties and responsibilities assigned to a position shall be consistent with the duties and responsibilities for the position's assigned class.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An employee may grieve the assignment of duties and responsibilities only if those assigned duties and responsibilities clearly are applicable to a different class.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
