<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-7-501</section_number>
  <catch_line>The performance of each employee in the skilled service, professional service, and management servic...</catch_line>
  <order_by>501</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The performance of each employee in the skilled service, professional service, and management service, including special appointments in each classification of each  of those services, shall be evaluated in accordance with this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The appointing authority shall ensure that each of the unit's employees who is subject to this subtitle has performance evaluations in accordance with this subtitle and procedures established by the Secretary.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each supervisor of an employee subject to this subtitle shall attend mandatory training by the Department on the methods and procedures required in the performance appraisal process.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Factors in evaluating a manager's or supervisor's performance shall include:<section prefix="(1)">attendance at any required performance appraisal training;</section><section prefix="(2)">adherence to established methods and procedures in conducting performance appraisals;</section><section prefix="(3)">the timely completion of performance appraisals for employees assigned to the manager or supervisor; and</section><section prefix="(4)">subject to subsection (e) of this section, if required by the manager's or supervisor's supervisor, the results of an anonymous survey of employees assigned to the manager or supervisor in accordance with procedures established by the Secretary.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An anonymous survey of the employees of a manager or supervisor may be performed only if more than five employees are assigned to the manager or supervisor.</section>
  </text>
</law>
