<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-23-401</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>401</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (f) of this section, a member may retire with a normal service retirement allowance if:<section prefix="(1)">the member completes and submits a written application to the Board of Trustees stating the date when the member desires to retire; and</section><section prefix="(2)">on or before the date of retirement, the member:<section prefix="(i)">has at least 30 years of eligibility service;</section><section prefix="(ii)">has a combined total of at least 30 years of eligibility service from the Employees' Pension System, the Teachers' Pension System, the Employees' Retirement System, or the Teachers' Retirement System; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">has attained the age and the years of eligibility service as follows:</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsections (c), (d), (e), and (f) of this section, on retirement under this section, a member is entitled to receive a normal service retirement allowance that equals the number of years of the member's creditable service multiplied by:<section prefix="(1)">0.8% of the member's average final compensation that is not in excess of the Social Security integration level; and</section><section prefix="(2)">1.5% of the member's average final compensation that exceeds the Social Security integration level.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, on retirement under this section, a member who is subject to the contributory pension benefit under Subtitle 2, Part II of this title is entitled to receive a normal service retirement allowance that equals the sum of:<section prefix="(1)">the number of years of the member's creditable service on or after July 1, 1998 multiplied by 1.4% of the member's average final compensation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the greater of:<section prefix="(i)">the number of years of the member's creditable service on or before June 30, 1998 multiplied by 1.2% of the member's average final compensation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the number of years of the member's creditable service on or before June 30, 1998 multiplied by:<section prefix="1.">0.8% of the member's average final compensation that is not in excess of the Social Security integration level; and</section><section prefix="2.">1.5% of the member's average final compensation that exceeds the Social Security integration level.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, a member who is subject to the Alternate Contributory Pension Selection under Subtitle 2, Part III of this title is entitled to receive a normal service retirement allowance that equals the sum of:<section prefix="(1)">the greater of:<section prefix="(i)">the number of years of the member's creditable service on or before June 30, 1998 multiplied by 1.2% of the member's average final compensation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the number of years of the member's creditable service on or before June 30, 1998 multiplied by:<section prefix="1.">0.8% of the member's average final compensation that is not in excess of the Social Security integration level; and</section><section prefix="2.">1.5% of the member's average final compensation that exceeds the Social Security integration level; and</section></section></section><section prefix="(2)">the number of years of the member's creditable service on or after July 1, 1998 multiplied by 1.8% of the member's average final compensation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only to a member who has a combined total of 30 years of eligibility service as provided in subsection (a)(2)(ii) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member is entitled to receive a normal service retirement allowance that equals:<section prefix="(i)">an allowance based on the creditable service the member earned in the Employees' Pension System;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an allowance based on the creditable service the member earned in the Employees' Retirement System;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an allowance based on the creditable service the member earned in the Teachers' Pension System; plus</section><section prefix="(iv)">an allowance based on the creditable service the member earned in the Teachers' Retirement System.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A member who begins membership on or after July 1, 2011, may retire with a normal service retirement allowance if:<section prefix="(i)">the member completes and submits a written application to the Board of Trustees stating the date when the member desires to retire; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">on or before the date of retirement, the member:<section prefix="1.">has at least 90 years of combined age and years of eligibility service; or</section><section prefix="2.">is at least 65 years old and has at least 10 years of eligibility service.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member who is subject to the reformed contributory pension benefit under Subtitle 2, Part IV of this title is entitled to receive a normal service retirement that equals the number of years of the member's creditable service multiplied by 1.5% of the member's average final compensation.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
