<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-3-2A-08</section_number>
  <catch_line>On written request of an exclusive representative, for each employee in the bargaining unit represen...</catch_line>
  <order_by>08</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">On written request of an exclusive representative, for each employee in the bargaining unit represented by the exclusive representative, the University System of Maryland system institutions, Morgan State University, St. Mary's College of Maryland, and Baltimore City Community College shall provide the exclusive representative with the employee's:<section prefix="(1)">name;</section><section prefix="(2)">position classification;</section><section prefix="(3)">unit;</section><section prefix="(4)">home and work site addresses where the employee receives interoffice or United States mail; and</section><section prefix="(5)">home and work site telephone numbers.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An exclusive representative may present a request for employee information, as provided under subsection (a) of this section, twice every calendar year.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Names or lists of employees provided to the Board in connection with an election under this title are not subject to disclosure in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 6 of the State Government Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Thirty days before providing an employee's name, addresses, telephone numbers, and work information to an exclusive representative, the employer shall notify the employee of the provisions of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The employee may, within 15 days of the employer's notice under paragraph (1) of this subsection, notify the employer that the employee does not want the employee's name, addresses, telephone numbers, or work information to be provided to an exclusive representative.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If an employee provides timely notification to the employer under paragraph (2) of this subsection, the employer may not provide the employee's name, addresses, telephone numbers, or work information.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The notification of an employee to the employer under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall remain in effect until the employee otherwise notifies the employer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An incumbent exclusive representative for a bargaining unit that is the subject of an election under &#xA7; 3-405 of this title may not request or receive any employee information as provided under subsections (a) and (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An employer may charge an exclusive representative a fee not to exceed the actual cost of providing a list of employees' names, addresses, telephone numbers, and work information to the exclusive representative.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, an exclusive representative shall consider the information that it receives under this section as confidential and may not release the information to any person.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An exclusive representative may authorize third party contractors to use the information that it receives under this section, as directed by the exclusive representative, to carry out the exclusive representative's statutory duties under this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An exclusive representative may not use the information that it receives under this section for the purpose of increasing employee membership in an employee organization.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An exclusive representative may use the information that it receives under this section only to carry out its statutory duties under this title.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
