<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-9-602</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>602</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a State Employees' Leave Bank.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">There is an Employee-to-Employee Leave Donation Program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Secretary shall administer the State Employees' Leave Bank and the Employee-to-Employee Leave Donation Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary shall adopt regulations that:<section prefix="(1)">govern donations to and grants of leave from the Leave Bank;</section><section prefix="(2)">govern donations and receipts of leave under the Leave Donation Program; and</section><section prefix="(3)">provide for participation in the Leave Bank and the Leave Donation Program by employees in units of State government with independent personnel systems that elect to participate in the State Employees' Leave Bank in accordance with subsection (e) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each employee, except a temporary employee, in the State Personnel Management System may voluntarily participate in the Leave Bank and the Leave Donation Program in accordance with this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A principal unit in the Executive, Judicial, or Legislative branches of State government with an independent personnel system may allow its employees to voluntarily participate in the Leave Bank and the Leave Donation Program in accordance with this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A unit that elects to participate under this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">keep a record of the employee leave donated; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">at the end of each fiscal year, submit to the Secretary a report containing the following information:<section prefix="1.">the number of employees who donated leave;</section><section prefix="2.">the kind of leave and number of hours donated by each employee;</section><section prefix="3.">the number of employees who received donated leave; and</section><section prefix="4.">the number of hours of donated leave used by each employee to whom leave was donated.</section></section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
