<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-2-503</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>503</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary shall:<section prefix="(1)">adopt regulations for the administration of the Program;</section><section prefix="(2)">ensure that the Program complies with all federal and State laws governing employee benefit plans; and</section><section prefix="(3)">each year, recommend to the Governor the State share of the costs of the Program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary may arrange as the Secretary considers appropriate any benefit option for inclusion in the Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary shall include in the Program an option to purchase up to $200,000 of additional life insurance coverage for employees who:<section prefix="(i)">fly in a helicopter in the course of their employment with the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">scuba dive in the course of their employment with the State; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">as a result of their employment with the State, face a significant likelihood of receiving a less favorable life insurance rating than an individual employed in a nonhazardous position.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary shall specify by regulation the types or categories of State employees who:<section prefix="(1)">are eligible to enroll and participate in the Program with State subsidies;</section><section prefix="(2)">are eligible to enroll and participate in the Program without State subsidies; and</section><section prefix="(3)">are not eligible to enroll or participate in the Program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The regulations adopted by the Secretary shall include provisions for the enrollment and participation of employees of all:<section prefix="(i)">organizations and entities that were participating in the Program as satellite organizations on January 1, 1993; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">employee organizations that qualify for payroll deductions under the provisions of &#xA7; 2-403 of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Employees of organizations and entities covered by this section may participate:<section prefix="(i)">without State subsidies; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">with payment by the organization or entity of administrative costs resulting from the participation of its employees in the Program.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The regulations adopted by the Secretary under this subsection shall provide that an employee organization specified in paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">may not enroll or participate in the Program unless the organization has notified the Secretary, in writing, on or before July 1, 1994 of the organization's intent to enroll and participate in the Program during calendar year 1994; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">may not enroll or participate in the Program on or after January 1, 1995 unless the organization has participated in the Program during calendar year 1994.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
