<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-21-305</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "employees' systems" means the Employees' Pension System and the Employees' Retirem...</catch_line>
  <order_by>305</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "employees' systems" means the Employees' Pension System and the Employees' Retirement System.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each fiscal year, on behalf of its employees who are members of one of the employees' systems, a participating governmental unit shall pay an amount equal to or greater than the product of multiplying:<section prefix="(i)">the aggregate annual earnable compensation of those members; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the sum of the normal contribution rate and the accrued liability contribution rate, as determined under &#xA7;&#xA7; 21-305.1 and 21-305.2 of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each fiscal year, in addition to the amounts required to be paid under paragraph (1) of this subsection, a participating governmental unit shall pay:<section prefix="(i)">the special accrued liability contribution required by &#xA7; 21-305.3 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">any withdrawal liability contribution required by &#xA7; 21-305.5 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an amount equal to 5% of the aggregate earnable compensation of its employees who are members of the Employees' Retirement System; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">any annual deficit payment required under &#xA7; 21-305.4(c) of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each fiscal year, a participating governmental unit shall reduce the amounts required to be paid under paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection by any annual credit allowed to the participating governmental unit under &#xA7; 21-305.4(b) of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The amount determined under subsection (b) of this section for the employees' systems shall be based on an actuarial determination of the amounts that are required to preserve the integrity of the accumulation fund of the employees' systems, using:<section prefix="(i)">the entry-age actuarial cost method;</section><section prefix="(ii)">actuarial assumptions adopted by the Board of Trustees; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the asset valuation method recommended by the actuary and adopted by the Board of Trustees.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in subsection (b)(2)(iii) of this section, for the purpose of making the determinations required under this section, the Employees' Retirement System and the Employees' Pension System shall be considered together as one State system.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The actuary shall compute the contributions payable under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The amounts computed under this section are a charge against the participating governmental unit to be paid in accordance with &#xA7; 21-309 of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
