<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-21-309.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>309.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Local employee" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 21-304 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Local employer" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 21-304 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On or before December 1 of each year, the Board of Trustees shall determine and certify the amounts payable by each local employer under &#xA7; 21-304(b)(4) of this subtitle for the next fiscal year.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">On or before October 1, January 1, April 1, and June 1 of each fiscal year, each local employer shall pay to the Board of Trustees 25% of the amount of the charges certified to the local employer by the Board of Trustees under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary of the Board of Trustees may allow a grace period not to exceed 10 calendar days for payment of the amounts certified under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a local employer does not pay the amounts required under this section within the time required, on notification by the Secretary of the Board of Trustees that a delinquency exists, the State Comptroller immediately:<section prefix="(i)">shall withhold the delinquent amounts, including interest on the delinquent amounts at a rate of 7.75% a year, from any installment due the local employer from the General State School Fund; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall pay to the Board of Trustees the delinquent amounts, including interest, withheld under this paragraph.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">On receipt of the payments from each local employer or the State Comptroller, the Board of Trustees shall credit these amounts to the accumulation fund of the appropriate State system.</section>
  </text>
</law>
