<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-508" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-2-508</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Creditable service" means:<section prefix="(i)">service credited toward a retirement allowance under Division II of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">service while a member of the Judges' Retirement System under Title 27 of this article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">service while an employee was employed by the Domestic Relations Division of the Anne Arundel County Circuit Court, prior to transfer on or before July 1, 2002 into the State Personnel Management System, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-510 of the Courts Article; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">service while a member of the Maryland Transit Administration Retirement Plan under &#xA7; 7-206 of the Transportation Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Retiree" means:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Retiree" does not include:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"State service" means service with the State by:<section prefix="(i)">an employee while a member of the Employees' Retirement System or the Employees' Pension System under Title 22 or Title 23 of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a member of the Judges' Retirement System under Title 27 of this article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a teacher while a member of the Teachers' Retirement System or Teachers' Pension System under Title 22 or Title 23 of this article;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a correctional officer, while a member of the Correctional Officers' Retirement System under Title 25 of this article;</section><section prefix="(v)">an employee of the Medical System Corporation, as defined in &#xA7; 13-301 or &#xA7; 13-401 of the Education Article, while a member of the Employees' Retirement System of the State of Maryland or the Employees' Pension System of the State of Maryland under Title 22 or Title 23 of this article;</section><section prefix="(vi)">a State Police officer while a member of the State Police Retirement System under Title 24 of this article;</section><section prefix="(vii)">a law enforcement officer while a member of the Law Enforcement Officers' Pension System under Title 26 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(viii)">an employee while a member of the Maryland Transit Administration Plan under &#xA7; 7-206 of the Transportation Article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to a retiree who:<section prefix="(i)">began State service on or before June 30, 2011; or</section><section prefix="(ii)"/></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A retiree may enroll and participate in the health insurance benefit options established under the Program if the retiree:<section prefix="(i)">ended State service with at least 10 years of creditable service and within 5 years before the age at which a vested retirement allowance normally would begin;</section><section prefix="(ii)">ended State service with at least 16 years of creditable service;</section><section prefix="(iii)">ended State service on or before June 30, 1984;</section><section prefix="(iv)">retired directly from State service with a State retirement allowance on or after July 1, 1984, and had at least 5 years of creditable service; or</section><section prefix="(v)">retired directly from State service with a State disability retirement allowance on or after July 1, 1984.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The surviving spouse or dependent child of a deceased retiree who was eligible to enroll may enroll and participate in the health insurance benefit options established under the Program as long as the spouse or child is receiving a periodic allowance under Division II of this article or the Maryland Transit Administration Retirement Plan under &#xA7; 7-206 of the Transportation Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subparagraph (i) of this paragraph does not apply to a deceased retiree's spouse or dependent child who receives an Option 1, Option 4, or Option 7 benefit under Division II of this article or a lump-sum payment of benefits under the Maryland Transit Administration Retirement Plan under &#xA7; 7-206 of the Transportation Article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If a retiree receives a State disability retirement allowance or has 16 or more years of creditable service, the retiree or the retiree's surviving spouse or dependent child is entitled to the same State subsidy allowed a State employee.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In all other cases, if a retiree has at least 5 years of creditable service, the retiree or the retiree's surviving spouse or dependent child is entitled to 1/16 of the State subsidy allowed a State employee for each year of the retiree's creditable service up to 16 years.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Notwithstanding subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph and subsection (a)(4)(i) of this section, if a retiree is an additional employee or agent of the State Racing Commission, for the purposes of determining a retiree's State subsidy, creditable service shall be determined with respect to service as an additional employee or agent beginning from the initial date of employment or January 1, 1986, whichever is later.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, this subsection applies to a retiree who begins State service on or after July 1, 2011.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">This subsection does not apply to a retiree of the Judges' Retirement System.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A retiree may enroll and participate in the health insurance benefit options established under the Program if the retiree:<section prefix="(i)">ends State service with at least 25 years of creditable service;</section><section prefix="(ii)">ends State service with a least 10 years of creditable service within 5 years before the age at which a vested retirement allowance normally would begin;</section><section prefix="(iii)">retires directly from State service with a State retirement allowance and has 10 years of creditable service; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">retires directly from State service with a State disability retirement allowance.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The surviving spouse or dependent child of a deceased retiree who was eligible to enroll may enroll and participate in the health insurance benefit options established under the Program as long as the spouse or child is receiving a periodic allowance under Division II of this article or the Maryland Transit Administration Retirement Plan under &#xA7; 7-206 of the Transportation Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subparagraph (i) of this paragraph does not apply to a deceased retiree's spouse or dependent child who receives an Option 1, Option 4, or Option 7 benefit under Division II of this article or a lump-sum payment of benefits under the Maryland Transit Administration Retirement Plan under &#xA7; 7-206 of the Transportation Article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If a retiree receives a State disability retirement allowance or has 25 or more years of creditable service, the retiree or the retiree's surviving spouse or dependent child is entitled to the same State subsidy allowed a State employee.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In all other cases, if a retiree has at least 10 years of creditable service, the retiree or the retiree's surviving spouse or dependent child is entitled to 1/25 of the State subsidy allowed a State employee for each year of the retiree's creditable service up to 25 years.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Notwithstanding subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph and subsection (a)(4)(i) of this section, if a retiree is an additional employee or agent of the State Racing Commission, for the purposes of determining a retiree's State subsidy, creditable service shall be determined with respect to service as an additional employee or agent beginning from the initial date of employment.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding subsections (b) and (c) of this section and &#xA7;&#xA7; 2-509 and 2-509.1 of this subtitle, the State may establish separate health insurance benefit options for retirees that differ from those for active State employees.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to &#xA7; 2-509.1 of this subtitle, on or after July 1, 2011, the health insurance benefit option for retirees shall include a prescription drug benefit that:<section prefix="(i)">has the same co-payments, coinsurance, and deductible that apply to the prescription drug benefit for active State employees;</section><section prefix="(ii)">requires</section><section prefix="(iii)">requires retirees to pay out-of-pocket limits equal to:</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
