<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-7-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "Central Repository" means the Criminal Justice Information System Central Reposito...</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Central Repository" means the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository of the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An appointing authority may request a State and national criminal history records check from the Central Repository for:<section prefix="(i)">a person who is selected for a position in the State Personnel Management System; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a current employee who is eligible and is being recommended for transfer, promotion, or reassignment to a position in the State Personnel Management System.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The appointing authority shall apply to the Central Repository for a State and national criminal history records check for each prospective or current employee for whom a records check is sought under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">As part of the application for a criminal history records check, the appointing authority shall submit to the Central Repository:<section prefix="(i)">two complete sets of the prospective or current employee's legible fingerprints taken in a format approved by the Director of the Central Repository and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the fee authorized under &#xA7; 10-221(b)(7) of the Criminal Procedure Article for access to criminal history record information; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the mandatory processing fee required by the Federal Bureau of Investigation for a national criminal history records check.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the Criminal Procedure Article, the Central Repository shall forward to the prospective or current employee and the appointing authority the prospective or current employee's criminal history record information.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Information obtained from the Central Repository under this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">is confidential and may not be redisseminated; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">may be used only for employment purposes authorized under Division I of this article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person who is the subject of a criminal history records check under this section may contest the contents of the printed statement issued by the Central Repository as provided in &#xA7; 10-223 of the Criminal Procedure Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary may adopt regulations, guidelines, and policies to carry out this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
