<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-5-213</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>213</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Within 10 days after receiving a decision under &#xA7; 5-212 of this subtitle, a complainant may appeal the decision in writing to the Secretary.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Within 30 days after an appeal is received:<section prefix="(1)">the Coordinator:<section prefix="(i)">shall review the complaint and the decision being appealed;</section><section prefix="(ii)">may conduct any necessary investigation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">shall recommend to the Secretary or designee a finding of whether a violation of this subtitle has occurred; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the Secretary or designee shall:<section prefix="(i)">take the action described in subsection (c)(1) or (c)(2) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">issue to the parties a written decision that includes notice of any remedial action taken.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Secretary or designee determines that a violation has not occurred, the Secretary or designee shall dismiss the complaint.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Secretary or designee determines that a violation has occurred, the Secretary or designee shall take appropriate remedial action.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">As remedial action for a violation of &#xA7; 5-208 of this subtitle, the Secretary or designee may:<section prefix="(1)">order the removal of detrimental information from the complainant's State personnel records;</section><section prefix="(2)">require the head of the principal unit to:<section prefix="(i)">hire, promote, or reinstate the complainant or end the complainant's suspension from employment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">award the complainant back pay up to the day of the violation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">grant the complainant leave or seniority;</section><section prefix="(iv)">take appropriate disciplinary action against any individual who caused the violation; or</section><section prefix="(v)">take any other remedial action that the Secretary or designee considers appropriate.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The decision of the Secretary or designee is final.</section>
  </text>
</law>
