<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-21-304</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">With respect to local employees, "aggregate annual earnable compensation" means the total annual earnable compensation payable by a local employer to all of its local employees, calculated as of June 30 of the second prior fiscal year before the fiscal year for which the calculation is made under this section, adjusted by any actuarial assumed salary increases that were used in the actuarial valuation prepared under &#xA7; 21-125(b) of this title for the immediate prior fiscal year.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Full funding rate" means the sum of:<section prefix="(i)">the aggregate normal rate that is based on the normal contribution rate calculated under subsection (c) of this section and adjusted to incorporate legislative changes in benefits to reflect changes to the normal cost; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the aggregate unfunded accrued liability contribution rate that is based on the unfunded accrued liability contribution rate under subsection (d)(1) and (2) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Funding ratio for the employees' systems" means the actuarial value of assets for the employees' systems divided by the actuarial accrued liability for the employees' systems.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Funding ratio for the teachers' systems" means the actuarial value of assets for the teachers' systems divided by the actuarial accrued liability for the teachers' systems.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Local employee" means a member of the Teachers' Retirement System or the Teachers' Pension System who is an employee of a day school in the State under the authority and supervision of a county board of education or the Baltimore City Board of School Commissioners, employed as:<section prefix="(i)">a clerk;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a helping teacher;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a principal;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a superintendent;</section><section prefix="(v)">a supervisor; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">a teacher.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Local employer" means a county board of education or the Baltimore City Board of School Commissioners.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"New legislative change" means a legislative change that results in an adjustment to the normal cost or accrued liabilities that has not previously been recognized in an actuarial valuation under &#xA7; 21-125(b) of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">"Preliminary funding rate" means the full funding rate without any adjustment to the normal cost or accrued liabilities for a new legislative change.</section>
      <section prefix="(10)">"State member" does not include a member on whose behalf a participating governmental unit is required to make an employer contribution under &#xA7; 21-305 or &#xA7; 21-306 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(11)">"Total employer contribution for local employees" means that portion of the employer contribution calculated under subsection (b) of this section that is attributable to all local employees.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraphs (4) and (5) of this subsection, each fiscal year, on behalf of the State members of each State system, the State shall pay to the appropriate accumulation fund an amount equal to or greater than the sum of the amount, if any, required to be included in the budget bill under &#xA7; 3-501(c)(2)(ii) of this article and the product of multiplying:<section prefix="(i)">the aggregate annual earnable compensation of the State members of that State system; and</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">for State members of the Law Enforcement Officers' Retirement System, State Police Retirement System, and the Judges' Retirement System, the sum of the normal contribution rate and the accrued liability contribution rate, as determined under this section;</section><section prefix="2.">for State members of the Employees' Pension System, Employees' Retirement System, Correctional Officers' Retirement System, and Legislative Pension Plan, the employees' systems contribution rate determined under subsection (e) of this section; or</section><section prefix="3.">for State members of the Teachers' Pension System and Teachers' Retirement System, the teachers' systems contribution rate determined under subsection (f) of this section.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The amount determined under paragraph (1) of this subsection for each State system shall be based on an actuarial determination of the amounts that are required to preserve the integrity of the funds of the several systems using:<section prefix="(i)">the entry-age actuarial cost method; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">actuarial assumptions adopted by the Board of Trustees.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For the purpose of making the determinations required under this section:<section prefix="(i)">the Employees' Retirement System, the Employees' Pension System, the Correctional Officers' Retirement System, and the Legislative Pension Plan shall be considered together as one State system; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Teachers' Retirement System and the Teachers' Pension System shall be considered together as one State system.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to &#xA7; 21-309.1 of this subtitle, beginning on July 1, 2012 and each fiscal year thereafter, each local employer shall pay to the appropriate accumulation fund an amount equal to the local share of the total employer contribution for local employees as provided in this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For fiscal years 2013 through 2016, each local employer shall pay to the Board of Trustees its local share, which shall be equal to the following amounts:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Beginning in fiscal year 2017, each local employer shall pay to the Board of Trustees its local share equal to the normal contribution rate for the Teachers' Retirement System and the Teachers' Pension System multiplied by the aggregate annual earnable compensation of the local employees of that local employer.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The difference between the total employer contribution for local employees and the local share of the total employer contribution for all local employees shall be the obligation of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">As part of each actuarial valuation, the actuary shall determine the normal contributions, net of member contributions, on account of the State members of each State system.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For each State system, the normal contribution rate equals the fraction that has:<section prefix="(i)">as its numerator, the sum of the normal contributions determined under this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">as its denominator, the aggregate annual earnable compensation of the State members of the State system.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Beginning July 1, 2001, each year the Board of Trustees shall set contribution rates for each State system that shall amortize:<section prefix="(i)">all unfunded liabilities or surpluses accrued as of June 30, 2000, over 20 years; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any new unfunded liabilities or surpluses that have accrued from July 1 of the preceding fiscal year over 25 years to reflect:<section prefix="1.">experience gains and losses;</section><section prefix="2.">the effect of changes in actuarial assumptions; and</section><section prefix="3.">the effect of legislation effective on or after July 1, 2001.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the accrued liability is increased by legislation that provides for early retirement of State employees, the additional liability shall be funded over a period of 5 years beginning on:<section prefix="(i)">July 1, 1997 for legislation effective June 1, 1996; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">July 1, 1998 for legislation effective June 1, 1997.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the accrued liability is increased by legislation effective June 1, 1998, that provides for the early retirement of employees of the University System of Maryland who are members of the Employees' Pension System or the Employees' Retirement System, the additional liability shall be determined by the actuary and funded over a period of 5 years beginning on July 1, 1999 by payment of an annual accrued liability contribution by the University System of Maryland and the Medical System as provided in &#xA7; 21-307(h) and (i) of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When the funding ratio for the employees' systems is between 90% and 110%, inclusive, the employees' system contribution rate is the rate for the previous fiscal year, adjusted to reflect legislative changes that result in changes in normal cost and to amortize over 25 years any actuarial liabilities of the employees' systems.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection, when the funding ratio for the employees' systems is below 90%, the employees' system contribution rate shall be the sum of:<section prefix="(i)">the employees' system contribution rate for the previous fiscal year; and</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">20% of the difference between the full funding rate for the current fiscal year and the employees' system contribution rate for the previous fiscal year; or</section><section prefix="2.">for a fiscal year for which an adjustment to normal cost or accrued liabilities for  a new legislative change is first determined as a result of an actuarial valuation under &#xA7; 21-125(b) of this title, 20% of the difference between the preliminary funding rate for the current fiscal year and the employees' system contribution rate for the previous fiscal year.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection, when the funding ratio for the employees' systems is above 110%, the employees' system contribution rate shall be the difference between:<section prefix="(i)">the employees' system contribution rate for the previous fiscal year; and</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">20% of the difference between the employees' system contribution rate for the previous fiscal year and the full funding rate for the current fiscal year; or</section><section prefix="2.">for a fiscal year for which an adjustment to normal cost or accrued liabilities for a new legislative change is first determined as a result of an actuarial valuation under &#xA7; 21-125(b) of this title, 20% of the difference between the employees' system contribution rate for the previous fiscal year and the preliminary funding rate for the current fiscal year.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">For a fiscal year for which an adjustment to normal cost or accrued liabilities for a new legislative change is determined as a result of an actuarial valuation under &#xA7; 21-125(b) of this title, the contribution rate for the employees' systems under paragraph (2) or (3) of this subsection shall be adjusted to fully reflect the cost or savings of the new legislative changes that result in changes in normal contributions or accrued liabilities and to amortize over 25 years any changes in accrued liabilities of the employees' systems.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When the funding ratio for the teachers' systems is between 90% and 110%, the teachers' system contribution rate is the rate for the previous fiscal year, adjusted to reflect legislative changes that result in changes in normal cost and to amortize over 25 years any actuarial liabilities of the teachers' systems.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection, when the funding ratio for the teachers' systems is below 90%, the teachers' system contribution rate shall be the sum of:<section prefix="(i)">the teachers' system contribution rate for the previous fiscal year; and</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">20% of the difference between the full funding rate for the current fiscal year and the teachers' system contribution rate for the previous fiscal year; or</section><section prefix="2.">for a fiscal year for which an adjustment to normal cost or accrued liabilities for a new legislative change is first determined as a result of an actuarial valuation under &#xA7; 21-125(b) of this title, 20% of the difference between the preliminary funding rate for the current fiscal year and the teachers' system contribution rate for the previous fiscal year.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection, when the funding ratio for the teachers' systems is above 110%, the teachers' system contribution rate shall be the difference between:<section prefix="(i)">the teachers' system contribution rate for the previous fiscal year; and</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">20% of the difference between the teachers' system contribution rate for the previous fiscal year and the full funding rate for the current fiscal year; or</section><section prefix="2.">for a fiscal year for which an adjustment to normal cost or accrued liabilities for a new legislative change is first determined as a result of an actuarial valuation under &#xA7; 21-125(b) of this title, 20% of the difference between the teachers' system contribution rate for the previous fiscal year and the preliminary funding rate for the current fiscal year.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">For a fiscal year for which an adjustment to normal cost or accrued liabilities for a new legislative change is determined as a result of an actuarial valuation under &#xA7; 21-125(b) of this title, the contribution rate for the teachers' systems under paragraph (2) or (3) of this subsection shall be adjusted to fully reflect the cost or savings of the new legislative changes that result in changes in normal contributions or accrued liabilities and to amortize over 25 years any changes in accrued liabilities of the teachers' systems.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
