<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="23-407" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-23-407</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "area of critical shortage" means an academic field identified by the State Department of Education in accordance with the provisions of &#xA7; 18-703(g)(1) of the Education Article as having projected employment vacancies that substantially exceed projected qualified graduates.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (m) of this section, an individual who is receiving a service retirement allowance or a vested allowance may accept employment with a participating employer on a permanent, temporary, or contractual basis, if:<section prefix="(1)">the individual immediately notifies the Board of Trustees of the individual's intention to accept this employment; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the individual specifies the compensation to be received.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 23-408 of this subtitle, the Board of Trustees shall reduce the allowance of an individual who accepts employment as provided under subsection (b) of this section if:<section prefix="(i)">the individual's current employer is a participating employer other than the State and is the same participating employer that employed the individual at the time of the individual's last separation from employment with a participating employer before the individual commenced receiving a service retirement allowance or vested allowance;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the individual's current employer is any unit of State government and the individual's employer at the time of the individual's last separation from employment with the State before the individual commenced receiving a service retirement allowance or vested allowance was also a unit of State government; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the individual becomes reemployed within 12 months of receiving an early service retirement allowance or an early vested allowance computed under &#xA7; 23-402 of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph and subject to subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph, the reduction required under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall equal:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iii)"/>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A reduction of an early service retirement allowance or an early vested allowance under paragraph (1)(iii) of this subsection shall be applied only until the individual has received an allowance for 12 months.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Except for an individual whose allowance is subject to a reduction as provided under paragraphs (1)(iii) and (3) of this subsection, the reduction of an allowance under this subsection does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">an individual whose average final compensation was less than $25,000 and who is reemployed on a permanent, temporary, or contractual basis;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an individual who is serving in an elected position as an official of a participating governmental unit or as a constitutional officer for a county that is a participating governmental unit;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an individual who has been retired for 5 years, beginning on January 1 after the date the individual retires;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a retiree of the Teachers' Pension System who:</section><section prefix="(v)">a retiree of the Teachers' Pension System who:</section><section prefix="(vi)">a retiree of the Employees' Pension System who is reemployed on a contractual basis by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene as a health care practitioner, as defined in &#xA7; 1-301 of the Health Occupations Article in:</section><section prefix="(vii)">a retiree of the Employees' Pension System and the Judges' Retirement System who is temporarily assigned to sit in a court of this State under the authority of Article IV, &#xA7; 3A of the Maryland Constitution; or</section><section prefix="(viii)">a retiree of the Employees' Pension System who is reemployed on a contractual basis for not more than 4 years as a parole and probation employee in a position authorized under Title 6, Subtitle 1 of the Correctional Services Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An individual who is rehired under paragraph (4)(iv) of this subsection shall be employed as a classroom teacher, substitute classroom teacher, or teacher mentor in:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An individual rehired at a school described under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph shall teach:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">An individual who is rehired under paragraph (4)(v) of this subsection shall be employed as a principal at:<section prefix="(i)">a public school that:</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Maryland School for the Deaf.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">An individual who is reemployed under paragraph (4)(iv) or (v) of this subsection at a school described under paragraph (5) or (6) of this subsection may not continue that reemployment after the school makes adequate yearly progress for 4 consecutive years.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Notwithstanding paragraph (5) of this subsection, each superintendent of a local school system and the superintendent of the Maryland School for the Deaf may rehire an additional number of individuals described under paragraph (4)(v) of this subsection equal to the greater of:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">At any one time, the total number of individuals rehired by a superintendent of a local school system or the superintendent of the Maryland School for the Deaf under this paragraph may not exceed the number determined under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">An individual rehired under this paragraph:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(9)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The superintendent of the local school system or the superintendent of the Maryland School for the Deaf rehiring an individual under paragraph (4)(iv) or (v) of this subsection shall:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Within 30 days after rehiring an individual, the superintendent of a local school system or the superintendent of the Maryland School for the Deaf shall complete and file with the Board of Trustees and the State Department of Education a form provided by the Board of Trustees that certifies that the individual rehired by the local school system or the Maryland School for the Deaf under paragraph (4)(iv) or (v) of this subsection:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iv)">If a superintendent of a local school system or the superintendent of the Maryland School for the Deaf rehires an individual that satisfies the criteria provided in paragraphs (4)(iv) or (v) and (5), (6), or (8) of this subsection and the Board of Trustees and the State Department of Education do not receive certification from the superintendent in the time required under subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph:</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The local school system or the Maryland School for the Deaf shall make the reimbursement on or before December 31 of the year the local school system or the Maryland School for the Deaf receives notice from the Board of Trustees under subparagraph (iii)2A of this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(10)">On or before August 1 of each year, the local superintendent and the superintendent of the Maryland School for the Deaf shall report to the State Department of Education for the previous school year:<section prefix="(i)">the number of individuals rehired under paragraph (4)(iv) or (v) or (8) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)"/><section prefix="(iii)">the original date of rehire for each individual;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the subject matter taught by each individual;</section><section prefix="(v)">the annual salary of each individual; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">the percentage of student population composed of children in poverty that is required to be present in a school in that school system in order for that school to qualify as a Title 1 school.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An individual who is rehired under this section may not be rehired within 45 days of the date the individual retired if:<section prefix="(1)">the individual's current employer is a participating employer other than the State and is the same participating employer that employed the individual at the time of the individual's last separation from employment with a participating employer before the individual commenced receiving a service retirement allowance;</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">at the time of retirement, the individual was a member of the Employees' Pension System as an employee of a withdrawn governmental unit; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the individual's current employer is the same withdrawn governmental unit that employed the individual at the time of the individual's last separation from employment with a withdrawn governmental unit before the individual commenced receiving a service retirement allowance; or</section></section><section prefix="(3)">the individual's current employer is any unit of State government and the individual's employer at the time of the individual's last separation from employment with the State before the individual commenced receiving a service retirement allowance was also a unit of State government.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An individual who is receiving a service retirement allowance or a vested allowance and who is reemployed by a participating employer may not receive creditable service or eligibility service during the period of reemployment.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The individual's compensation during the period of reemployment may not be subject to the employer pickup provisions of &#xA7; 21-303 of this article or any reduction or deduction as a member contribution for pension or retirement purposes.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The State Retirement Agency shall institute appropriate reporting procedures with the affected payroll systems to ensure compliance with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Immediately on the employment of any individual receiving a service retirement allowance or a vested allowance, a participating employer shall notify the State Retirement Agency of the type of employment and the anticipated earnings of the individual.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At least once each year, in a format specified by the State Retirement Agency, each participating employer shall provide the State Retirement Agency with a list of all employees included on any payroll of the employer, the Social Security numbers of the employees, and their earnings for that year.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The State Department of Education shall adopt regulations to carry out this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">At the request of the State Retirement Agency:<section prefix="(1)">a participating employer shall certify to the State Retirement Agency that it is not the same participating employer that employed an individual at the time of the individual's last separation from employment before the individual commenced receiving a service retirement allowance or a vested allowance; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a unit of State government shall certify to the State Retirement Agency that the individual was not employed by any unit of State government at the time of the individual's last separation from employment before the individual commenced receiving a service retirement allowance or a vested allowance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The Department of Health and Mental Hygiene shall notify the State Retirement Agency of any retirees who qualify under subsection (c)(4)(vi) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">On or before September 1 of each year, the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene shall submit a report in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article to the Joint Committee on Pensions that provides:<section prefix="(1)">the number of rehired retirees under subsection (c)(4)(vi) of this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">the annual salary of each rehired retiree at the time of retirement and the current annual salary of each rehired retiree;</section><section prefix="(3)">the number of health care practitioners hired who are not retirees; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the annual salary of each health care practitioner who is hired.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">An individual who is rehired under this section may not be rehired within 45 days of the date the individual retired if:<section prefix="(1)">the individual's current employer is a participating employer other than the State and is the same participating employer that employed the individual at the time of the individual's last separation from employment with a participating employer before the individual commenced receiving a service retirement allowance; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the individual's current employer is any unit of State government and the individual's employer at the time of the individual's last separation from employment with the State before the individual commenced receiving a service retirement allowance was also a unit of State government.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(n)">On or before October 1 of each year, the State Superintendent of Schools shall submit a report for the previous school year, to the Joint Committee on Pensions, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, that provides:<section prefix="(1)">the number of rehired retirees under subsection (c)(4)(iv) and (v) and (8) of this section;</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">the school and school system where each retiree was rehired; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">whether the school:</section></section><section prefix="(3)">a copy of the annual staffing report generated by the State Superintendent of Schools in accordance with &#xA7; 18-703(g)(1) of the Education Article certifying areas of critical shortage for the previous school year as evidenced by projected employment vacancies substantially exceeding projected qualified graduates;</section><section prefix="(4)">the subject matter that each rehired retiree was teaching;</section><section prefix="(5)">the salary of each rehired retiree;</section><section prefix="(6)">the total number of years each retiree has been reemployed at the school where the retiree was rehired for the previous school year; and</section><section prefix="(7)">the percentage of student population composed of children in poverty that is required to be present in a school in that school system in order for that school to qualify as a Title 1 school.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(o)">On or before October 1 of each year, the Board of Trustees shall submit a report for the previous calendar year to the Joint Committee on Pensions, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, that provides:<section prefix="(1)">the number of individuals in each local school system that the Board of Trustees and the State Department of Education agree were rehired and did not satisfy the criteria provided in subsection (c)(4)(iv) or (v) and (5), (6), or (8) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">any reimbursements a local school system made under subsection (c)(9)(ii) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(p)">On or before September 1 of each year, the Secretary of Public Safety and Correctional Services shall submit a report in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article to the Joint Committee on Pensions that provides:<section prefix="(1)">the number of rehired retirees under subsection (c)(4)(viii) of this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">the annual salary of each rehired retiree at the time of retirement and the current annual salary of each rehired retiree;</section><section prefix="(3)">the number of parole and probation employees hired who are not retirees; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the annual salary of each parole and probation employee who is hired.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
