<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="24-401.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-24-401.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"DROP" means the Deferred Retirement Option Program established under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"DROP member" means a member of the State Police Retirement System who:<section prefix="(i)">is eligible to participate in the DROP as provided in subsection (c) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">elects to participate in the DROP as provided in subsection (e) of this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a DROP for eligible members of the State Police Retirement System.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies to an individual who is a member of the State Police Retirement System on or before June 30, 2011.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Except for the Secretary of State Police, a member of the State Police Retirement System is eligible to participate in the DROP if the member:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Secretary of State Police is eligible to participate in the DROP if the Secretary has at least 22 years of eligibility service.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies to an individual who becomes a member of the State Police Retirement System on or after July 1, 2011.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Except for the Secretary of State Police, a member of the State Police Retirement System is eligible to participate in the DROP if the member:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Secretary of State Police is eligible to participate in the DROP if the Secretary has at least 25 years of eligibility service.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An eligible member may elect to participate in the DROP for a period not to exceed the lesser of:<section prefix="(1)">4 years;</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">the difference between 28 years and the member's eligibility service as of the date of the member's election to participate in the DROP and retire from the State Police Retirement System, if the member is a member of the State Police Retirement System on or before June 30, 2011; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the difference between 29 years and the member's eligibility service as of the date of the member's election to participate in the DROP and retire from the State Police Retirement System, if the member becomes a member of the State Police Retirement System on or after July 1, 2011;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">the difference between age 60 and the member's age as of the date of the member's election to participate in the DROP and retire from the State Police Retirement System; or</section><section prefix="(4)">a term selected by the member.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An eligible member who elects to participate in the DROP shall:<section prefix="(i)">complete and submit a written election form to the Board of Trustees, on the form that the Board of Trustees provides, stating:</section><section prefix="(ii)">complete and submit a written retirement application form to the Board of Trustees, on the form that the Board of Trustees provides.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An eligible member's election to participate in the DROP is irrevocable.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A DROP member's participation in the DROP shall commence on the first day of the month following acceptance by the Board of Trustees of the DROP member's completed election form, retirement application form, and any other information required by the Board of Trustees.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A DROP member is a retiree of the State Police Retirement System.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Participation in the DROP ends if the DROP participant:<section prefix="(1)">separates from employment in accordance with the binding letter of resignation submitted with the member's election form;</section><section prefix="(2)">except for the Secretary of State Police, attains age 60;</section><section prefix="(3)">dies;</section><section prefix="(4)">is terminated from employment by the Maryland State Police at any time before the date specified on the member's election form;</section><section prefix="(5)">shortens the time period for participation in the DROP by delivering to the Maryland State Police and the Board of Trustees written notice of the intent of the DROP member to terminate employment; or</section><section prefix="(6)">accepts a special disability retirement allowance as provided in subsection (k) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">As of the effective date of participation in the DROP, the Board of Trustees shall determine the DROP member's normal service retirement allowance under &#xA7; 24-401 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">During the period that a DROP member participates in the DROP, the Board of Trustees shall:<section prefix="(i)">deposit the DROP member's normal service retirement allowance in the DROP for the DROP member's benefit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">adjust the DROP member's normal service retirement allowance each fiscal year as provided in Title 29, Subtitle 4, Part III of this article; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">accrue interest on the amounts calculated under items (i) and (ii) of this paragraph for the DROP member into the DROP at the rate of:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A DROP member may not receive creditable service or eligibility service during the period that the DROP member participates in the DROP.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A DROP member's compensation during the period that the DROP member participates in the DROP may not be:<section prefix="(i)">subject to the employer pickup provisions of &#xA7; 21-303 of this article or any reduction or deduction as a member contribution for pension or retirement purposes; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">used to increase the DROP member's average final compensation except as provided in subsection (k) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">During the period that a DROP member participates in the DROP, the DROP member shall:<section prefix="(i)">continue to receive compensation, health insurance and other benefit options established under the State Employee and Retiree Health and Welfare Benefit Program administered by the Secretary of Budget and Management, and any other benefits as an employee of the Maryland State Police;</section><section prefix="(ii)">be subject to the personnel law, regulations, and policies applicable to an employee of the Maryland State Police; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">receive retirement benefits only to the extent provided in this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Board of Trustees is not required to establish an individual DROP account for each DROP member.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Each year, the Board of Trustees shall provide a DROP member with a written accounting of the DROP member's account balance in the DROP.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) of this subsection, on termination of a DROP member's participation in the DROP, the Board of Trustees shall pay to the DROP member or, if the DROP member has died, the designated beneficiary of the DROP member, the amount accrued in the DROP for the DROP member under subsection (h)(2) of this section, reduced by any withholding taxes remitted to the Internal Revenue Service or other taxing authority, in a lump sum.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The designated beneficiary of a DROP member is:<section prefix="(i)">the DROP member's surviving spouse;</section><section prefix="(ii)">if there is not a surviving spouse or if the surviving spouse dies before the youngest child is 18 years old, each child of the deceased DROP member who is under 18 years old; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">if there is not a surviving spouse or a child who is under 18 years old, the person named as a beneficiary in an acknowledged written designation filed with the Board of Trustees by the DROP member.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A DROP member or designated beneficiary of a DROP member may direct the Board of Trustees to pay all or a portion of the amount accrued for the DROP member's benefit under subsection (h)(2) of this section directly to the custodian of an eligible retirement plan as provided in Title 21, Subtitle 6 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A DROP member or designated beneficiary of a DROP member is eligible to receive the amount due under this subsection within 90 days after the:<section prefix="(i)">date of termination of the DROP member's participation in the DROP;</section><section prefix="(ii)">receipt by the Board of Trustees of a completed application to receive the DROP amount, on the form that the Board of Trustees provides; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">receipt by the Board of Trustees of any other information that the Board of Trustees requires to process payment of the DROP member's account balance to the DROP participant, the designated beneficiary of the DROP participant, or the custodian of an eligible retirement plan.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, as of the first day of the month following termination of a DROP member's participation in the DROP, the Board of Trustees shall commence and continue payment of the normal service retirement allowance, including the cost of living adjustments as provided in Title 29, Subtitle 4, Part III of this article, to the member as provided in &#xA7;&#xA7; 24-401 and 24-403 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a DROP member dies before termination of the DROP member's participation in the DROP, the Board of Trustees shall pay 50% of the normal service retirement allowance, including the cost of living adjustments as provided in Title 29, Subtitle 4, Part III of this article, to the beneficiary as provided in &#xA7; 24-403 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A DROP member is eligible to apply for a special disability retirement allowance under &#xA7; 29-111 of this article if after the DROP member commences participation in the DROP:<section prefix="(i)">the member is totally and permanently incapacitated for duty arising out of or in the course of the actual performance of duty that occurs while participating in DROP, and without willful negligence of the member; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the medical board certifies that:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Board of Trustees grants a DROP member a special disability retirement allowance, the DROP member may elect to receive the special disability retirement allowance or continue to participate in the DROP.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If a DROP member elects to receive a special disability retirement allowance instead of continuing to participate in the DROP, the DROP member shall:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">On acceptance of the application for payment and application to retire, the Board of Trustees shall commence payment of a special disability allowance to the DROP member as provided in &#xA7; 29-111(c) of this article, except that the DROP member's average final compensation shall be computed as of the effective date of the DROP member's application for a special disability retirement allowance.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
