<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-21-207</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>207</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the provisions of this section, the State shall indemnify a fiduciary who is, or is threatened to be made, a party to an action or proceeding, including an administrative or investigative proceeding, by reason of the fiduciary's service as a fiduciary.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "expenses" include:<section prefix="(i)">reasonable attorney's fees;</section><section prefix="(ii)">judgments;</section><section prefix="(iii)">fines; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">other expenses that were actually and reasonably incurred by the fiduciary in connection with the action or proceeding.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">With respect to a civil, administrative, or investigative action or proceeding, the State shall indemnify a fiduciary for the expenses of the action or proceeding if the fiduciary acted:<section prefix="(i)">in good faith; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">in a manner the fiduciary reasonably believed to be in or not opposed to the best interest of the several systems.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">With respect to a criminal action or proceeding, the State shall indemnify a fiduciary for the expenses of the action or proceeding if the fiduciary:<section prefix="(i)">acted in good faith;</section><section prefix="(ii)">acted in a manner the fiduciary reasonably believed to be in or not opposed to the best interest of the several systems; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">did not have reasonable cause to believe that the fiduciary's conduct was unlawful.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any termination of an action or proceeding does not, of itself, create a presumption that the fiduciary did not meet the standards for indemnification described in subsection (b) (2) and (3) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The State may not indemnify:<section prefix="(1)">a fiduciary with respect to an action or proceeding as to which the fiduciary was held liable for gross negligence or willful misconduct in the performance of the fiduciary's duty to the several systems; or</section><section prefix="(2)">an independent contractor furnishing services to the several systems.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State shall provide insurance for a fiduciary eligible for indemnification under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For the purpose of paragraph (1) of this subsection, the State may provide self-insurance under terms and conditions satisfactory to the State Treasurer.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A fiduciary may not be required to pay amounts attributable to liability described in this section because the State does not provide adequate insurance coverage or otherwise fails to indemnify in accordance with this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
