<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="29-303" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-29-303</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only to members of:<section prefix="(1)">the Employees' Pension System;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Local Fire and Police System;</section><section prefix="(3)">the Law Enforcement Officers' Pension System; or</section><section prefix="(4)">the Teachers' Pension System.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to an individual who is a member on or before June 30, 2011.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member is eligible to receive a vested allowance if:<section prefix="(i)">the member separated from employment other than by death or retirement; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the member has at least 5 years of eligibility service.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b-1)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to an individual who becomes a member on or after July 1, 2011.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member is eligible to receive a vested allowance if:<section prefix="(i)">the member separated from employment other than by death or retirement; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the member has at least 10 years of eligibility service.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as provided in subsections (e), (f), and (g) of this section, a vested allowance:<section prefix="(1)">is a deferred allowance that begins at normal retirement age;</section><section prefix="(2)">is computed as a normal service retirement allowance on the basis of the member's average final compensation and eligibility service at separation from employment; and</section><section prefix="(3)">may be paid in one of the optional forms of allowances under &#xA7; 21-403 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a member of the Employees' Pension System or the Teachers' Pension System separated from employment on or before June 30, 1990, unused sick leave reported by the member's employer at the time of separation from employment is creditable service for computing the vested allowance.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except as provided in subsection (f) of this section, a former member of the Employees' Pension System or the Teachers' Pension System who has separated from employment before the age of 55 with at least 15 years of eligibility service is eligible to receive a vested allowance that:<section prefix="(1)">begins on the first day of the month following the member's 55th birthday; and</section><section prefix="(2)">equals the reduced allowance computed under &#xA7; 23-402 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The vested allowance of a former member of the Employees' Pension System or the Teachers' Pension System who separates from employment on or before June 30, 1998:<section prefix="(i)">is a deferred allowance that begins at normal retirement age;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is computed on the basis of the member's average final compensation and eligibility service at separation from employment;</section><section prefix="(iii)">shall equal the number of years of the member's creditable service multiplied by:</section><section prefix="(iv)">may be paid in one of the optional forms of allowances under &#xA7; 21-403 of this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A former member of the Employees' Pension System or the Teachers' Pension System who has separated from employment on or before June 30, 1998 and before the age of 55 with at least 15 years of eligibility service is eligible to receive a vested allowance that:<section prefix="(i)">begins on the first day of the month following the member's 55th birthday; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">equals the allowance under paragraph (1) of this subsection, reduced by 0.5% for each month that the member's early retirement date precedes the date the member will be 62 years old.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection and subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, the vested allowance of a former member of the Law Enforcement Officers' Pension System who separates from employment on or before June 30, 2000:<section prefix="(i)">is a deferred allowance that begins at normal retirement age;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is computed on the basis of the member's average final compensation and eligibility service at separation from employment; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">shall equal the number of years of the member's creditable service multiplied by:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This subsection applies only to a former member of the Law Enforcement Officers' Pension System who:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The vested allowance of a former member:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies only to a former member who is:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">On receipt of a vested allowance, a former member shall receive a supplemental deferred allowance that equals the difference between:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Payment of the supplemental deferred allowance ends when the former member:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
