<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-3-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means:<section prefix="(1)">with regard to any matter relating to employees of any of the units of State government described in &#xA7; 3-102(a)(1)(i) through (iv) and (vi) through (ix) of this subtitle and employees described in &#xA7; 3-102(a)(2) of this subtitle, the State Labor Relations Board; and</section><section prefix="(2)">with regard to any matter relating to employees of any State institution of higher education described in &#xA7; 3-102(a)(1)(v) of this subtitle, the State Higher Education Labor Relations Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Collective bargaining" means:<section prefix="(1)">good faith negotiations by authorized representatives of employees and their employer with the intention of:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">clarifying terms and conditions of employment;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">administration of terms and conditions of employment; or</section><section prefix="(3)">the voluntary adjustment of a dispute or disagreement between authorized representatives of employees and their employer that arises under a memorandum of understanding or other written understanding.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Employee organization" means a labor or other organization in which State employees participate and that has as one of its primary purposes representing employees.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Exclusive representative" means an employee organization that has been certified by the Board as an exclusive representative under Subtitle 4 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"President" means:<section prefix="(1)">with regard to a constituent institution, as defined in &#xA7; 12-101 of the Education Article, the president of the constituent institution;</section><section prefix="(2)">with regard to a center or institute, as those terms are defined in &#xA7; 12-101 of the Education Article, the president of the center or institute;</section><section prefix="(3)">with regard to the University System of Maryland Office, the Chancellor of the University System of Maryland; and</section><section prefix="(4)">with regard to Morgan State University, St. Mary's College of Maryland, and Baltimore City Community College, the president of the institution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"System institution" means:<section prefix="(1)">a constituent institution, as defined in &#xA7; 12-101 of the Education Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">a center or institute, as those terms are defined in &#xA7; 12-101 of the Education Article; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the University System of Maryland Office.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
