<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="29-302" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-29-302</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only to members of:<section prefix="(1)">the Correctional Officers' Retirement System;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Employees' Retirement System;</section><section prefix="(3)">the State Police Retirement System; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the Teachers' Retirement System.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to an individual who is a member on or before June 30, 2011.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member may elect to receive a vested allowance if:<section prefix="(i)">the member is separated from employment other than by death or retirement; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, the member has at least 5 years of eligibility service.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A former member of the State Police Retirement System who separated from employment on or before June 30, 1989, must have at least 15 years of eligibility service to elect a vested allowance.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member is deemed to have elected a vested allowance, unless the member requests the return of the accumulated contributions before membership ends.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b-1)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to an individual who becomes a member on or after July 1, 2011.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member is eligible to receive a vested allowance if:<section prefix="(i)">the member separated from employment other than by death or retirement; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the member has at least 10 years of eligibility service.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A vested allowance is a deferred allowance starting at:<section prefix="(1)">normal retirement age for members of:<section prefix="(i)">the Employees' Retirement System;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the State Police Retirement System; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Teachers' Retirement System;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">age 55 for a member of the Correctional Officers' Retirement System who is:<section prefix="(i)">a correctional officer in the first six job classifications;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a detention center officer employed by a participating governmental unit who has elected to participate in the Correctional Officers' Retirement System;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an individual serving as a correctional dietary, maintenance, laundry, or supply officer; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">an individual serving as a Maryland Correctional Enterprises officer, officer trainee, plant supervisor, plant manager, or regional manager; or</section></section><section prefix="(3)">age 60 for a member of the Correctional Officers' Retirement System who is a maximum security attendant at the Clifton T. Perkins Hospital Center.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A vested allowance:<section prefix="(1)">is computed as a normal service retirement allowance on the basis of the former member's creditable service and average final compensation at the time of separation from employment; and</section><section prefix="(2)">may be paid in one of the optional forms of allowances under &#xA7; 21-403 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a member separated from employment on or before June 30, 1990, unused sick leave reported by the member's employer at the time of separation from employment is creditable service for computing the vested allowance.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a former member who elected a vested allowance requests the return of accumulated contributions before payment of the vested allowance begins, the Board of Trustees shall return the accumulated contributions to the former member.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When accumulated contributions are returned to a former member, the former member is not entitled to further benefits on account of the former member's previous membership.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
