<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="38-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-38-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Accumulated contributions":<section prefix="(1)">when used in relation to a State system, has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 20-101 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">when used in relation to a local retirement or pension system, has the meaning most closely analogous to the meaning stated in &#xA7; 20-101 of this article within the context of the local retirement or pension system.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Member":<section prefix="(1)">when used in relation to a State system, has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 20-101 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">when used in relation to a local retirement or pension system, has the meaning most closely analogous to the meaning stated in &#xA7; 20-101 of this article within the context of the local retirement or pension system.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Military service" means:<section prefix="(1)">induction into the armed forces of the United States for training and service under the Selective Training and Service Act of 1940 or a subsequent act of a similar nature;</section><section prefix="(2)">membership in a reserve component of the armed forces of the United States:<section prefix="(i)">on active duty or ordered or assigned to active duty; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">on active duty for training or inactive duty for training that interrupts a member's service;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">enlistment into the armed forces of the United States;</section><section prefix="(4)">membership in the Maryland National Guard; or</section><section prefix="(5)">with respect to a person separated from employment on or after July 1, 1991, active duty with the commissioned corps of the Public Health Service, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, or the Coast and Geodetic Survey from:<section prefix="(i)">December 7, 1941, to December 31, 1946, both inclusive;</section><section prefix="(ii)">June 25, 1950, to January 31, 1955, both inclusive; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">December 22, 1961, to May 7, 1975, both inclusive.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Regular interest":<section prefix="(1)">when used in relation to a State system, has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 20-101 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">when used in relation to a local retirement or pension system, has the meaning most closely analogous to the meaning stated in &#xA7; 20-101 of this article within the context of the local retirement or pension system.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"State or local retirement or pension system" means a retirement or pension system operated under the laws of the State or a political subdivision of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"State system" means a retirement or pension system that is included in the State Retirement and Pension System under &#xA7; 21-102 of this article other than the Legislative Pension Plan except to the extent provided by the joint resolution submitted to the General Assembly by the General Assembly Compensation Commission under Article III, &#xA7; 15 of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
  </text>
</law>
