<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="29-412" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-29-412</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section and subject to &#xA7; 29-413 of this subtitle, each fiscal year, the Board of Trustees shall adjust an initial allowance by multiplying the initial allowance by the fraction that has:<section prefix="(1)">as its numerator, the Consumer Price Index for the calendar year ending December 31 of the preceding fiscal year; and</section><section prefix="(2)">as its denominator:<section prefix="(i)">for a retiree, the beneficiary of a retiree, or the surviving spouse of a member, the Consumer Price Index for the calendar year ending December 31 of the fiscal year in which the retiree or member was last employed; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">for a former member or the beneficiary of a former member, the Consumer Price Index for the calendar year ending December 31 of the fiscal year in which the former member reaches normal retirement age.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "zero-adjustment fiscal year" means any fiscal year when the allowance adjusted as provided in subsection (a) of this section results in an allowance that is less than the allowance payable for the preceding fiscal year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For any fiscal year, the allowance payable may not be less than the allowance paid for the preceding fiscal year.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies only to a fiscal year that is not a zero-adjustment fiscal year.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subject to subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If the amount of the reduction required for any fiscal year under subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph exceeds the difference between the allowance as provided in subsection (a) of this section for the fiscal year and the allowance paid in the preceding fiscal year, the excess shall be deducted in future years, subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, until the difference is fully recovered.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
