<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-29-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to &#xA7; 29-104 of this subtitle, an application for disability retirement may be submitted:<section prefix="(1)">by a member;</section><section prefix="(2)">by a former member;</section><section prefix="(3)">by a surviving beneficiary of a deceased member; or</section><section prefix="(4)">for a member, as provided in subsections (b) through (d) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to members of:<section prefix="(i)">the State Police Retirement System;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Teachers' Pension System; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Teachers' Retirement System.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a member is unable to apply, the member's department head may complete and submit an application to the Board of Trustees for the member.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to a member of the State Police Retirement System.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary of State Police may complete an application and submit it to the Board of Trustees for a member if:<section prefix="(i)">the member is unable or refuses to submit an application for disability retirement;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Secretary believes the member to be permanently physically or mentally incapable of performing assigned duties;</section><section prefix="(iii)">there is sufficient medical evidence in the form of a professional opinion of an independent medical practitioner who has recognized expertise in the diagnosis and treatment of the specified illness of the officer to support the Secretary's determination of permanent disability;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the onset of the disability occurred at least 1 year earlier; and</section><section prefix="(v)">any administrative leave granted under &#xA7; 2-410 of the Public Safety Article has expired.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This subsection does not prevent an officer from exercising rights granted under &#xA7; 21-111(b) of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to members of:<section prefix="(i)">the Teachers' Pension System; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Teachers' Retirement System.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a member is unable to apply, the member's State or county superintendent may complete and submit an application to the Board of Trustees for the member.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
