<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-21-115</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>115</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board of Trustees shall:<section prefix="(1)">specify by resolution the number of members of the Investment Committee; and</section><section prefix="(2)">except as provided in subsection (b)(2) of this section, appoint annually the members of the Investment Committee from the members of the Board of Trustees.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board of Trustees shall ensure that the membership of the Investment Committee includes:<section prefix="(1)">a representative of each of:<section prefix="(i)">the Employees' Pension System or the Employees' Retirement System;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Teachers' Pension System or the Teachers' Retirement System; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the State Police Retirement System; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">three representatives from the public appointed by the Board of Trustees with the approval of the Board of Public Works for staggered 3-year terms who:<section prefix="(i)">are not members, retirees, or beneficiaries under any of the several systems;</section><section prefix="(ii)">have had experience in the management and control of large investments; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">have at least 10 years of substantial experience as any one or a combination of the following:<section prefix="1.">a portfolio manager acting in a fiduciary capacity;</section><section prefix="2.">an employee or principal of a trust institution, investment organization, or endowment fund acting either in a management-related capacity or an investment-related capacity;</section><section prefix="3.">a chartered financial analyst in good standing; or</section><section prefix="4.">a professional engaged in a public or private financial or investment field that is comparable to the fields listed in this item.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board of Trustees may:<section prefix="(1)">set additional qualifications for public members; and</section><section prefix="(2)">adopt regulations on ethical standards and conflicts of interest for public members.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">By resolution, the Board of Trustees shall designate the chairman of the Investment Committee.</section>
  </text>
</law>
