<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-21-124</section_number>
  <catch_line>The State Treasurer is the custodian of:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>124</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Treasurer is the custodian of:<section prefix="(i)">the accumulation, annuity savings, and expense funds of the several systems; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the assets of the Board of Trustees.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Retirement Agency shall make all payments from the accumulation, annuity savings, and expense funds of the several systems in accordance with regulations that the Board of Trustees adopts with the approval of the State Treasurer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Treasurer may make arrangements with one or more duly qualified banks or trust companies in this State, organized under the laws of this State or of the United States, for:<section prefix="(i)">safe custody of investments;</section><section prefix="(ii)">banking services; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">any other function that the State Treasurer considers necessary to safeguard physically the assets that the Board of Trustees manages.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Treasurer:<section prefix="(i)">may deposit any of the securities that the Board of Trustees purchases in vaults or in other safe depositories outside the office of the State Treasurer, whether or not in this State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall deliver to the Board of Trustees a safekeeping receipt that:<section prefix="1.">describes the securities that the State Treasurer deposits; and</section><section prefix="2.">is payable on demand and without conditions to the Board of Trustees, to any designated fund of the several systems that the Board of Trustees controls, or to the State Treasurer.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board of Trustees shall keep on file any safekeeping receipt that the State Treasurer delivers.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, to make disbursements, the State Treasurer may keep cash on deposit in one or more duly qualified banks or trust companies in this State that are organized under the laws of this State or of the United States.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Treasurer may not:<section prefix="(i)">keep more than 10% of the total amount in the funds of the several systems on deposit as cash; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">keep cash that exceeds 25% of the paid-up capital and surplus of the bank or trust company in that bank or trust company.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
