<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-30-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board of Trustees may designate not more than four companies, in addition to the company that was designated by a governing board of an employing institution on or before March 1, 1993, from which annuity contracts are to be purchased under the program.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of Trustees shall approve the form and contents of annuity contracts to be offered by a company that is designated by the Board of Trustees under subsection (a) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board of Trustees may also approve the form and contents of additional types of annuity contracts to be offered for the first time after October 1, 1993, by the company designated by the governing board of an employing institution on or before March 1, 1993.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In making the designation and giving approval under this section, the Board of Trustees shall consider:<section prefix="(1)">the nature and extent of the rights and benefits to be provided by the annuity contracts for participating employees and their beneficiaries;</section><section prefix="(2)">the relation of those rights and benefits to the amount of contributions to be made;</section><section prefix="(3)">the suitability of the rights and benefits to the needs of the participating employees and the interests of the employing institutions in the recruitment and retention of participating employees;</section><section prefix="(4)">the ability of the company to provide for suitable rights and benefits under the annuity contracts;</section><section prefix="(5)">the selection of annuity contracts offered by the company;</section><section prefix="(6)">the financial stability of the company and whether the company meets minimum financial criteria, if any, including a minimum net worth requirement, if any, established by the Board of Trustees; and</section><section prefix="(7)">the effect of any fees, commissions, or other charges imposed or collected in connection with an annuity contract.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
