<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="29-116" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-29-116</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to a retiree who is:<section prefix="(1)">a retiree of:<section prefix="(i)">the State Police Retirement System;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Law Enforcement Officers' Pension System;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Local Fire and Police System; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Employees' Retirement System or the Employees' Pension System, if at the time of retirement the retiree was a law enforcement officer for a participating employer under &#xA7; 26-201(a) of this article; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">reemployed by a participating employer in any position other than a probationary status law enforcement officer, a law enforcement officer, or chief, as defined in &#xA7; 3-101 of the Public Safety Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board of Trustees shall reduce the pension of a retiree on ordinary disability if:<section prefix="(1)">the retiree is under normal retirement age;</section><section prefix="(2)">the medical board certifies in a report to the Board of Trustees that the retiree is employed by a participating employer at an annual compensation that is greater than the difference between:<section prefix="(i)">the retiree's retirement allowance at retirement; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the retiree's average final compensation plus $5,000;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">the Board of Trustees agrees with the medical board's report; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the retiree's allowance has not been temporarily suspended as provided in &#xA7; 29-115 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board of Trustees shall reduce the pension of a retiree who has been receiving an ordinary disability retirement allowance for:<section prefix="(1)">less than 10 years, by $1 for every $2 that the retiree's current compensation exceeds the limit under subsection (b) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(2)">at least 10 years, by $1 for every $5 that the retiree's current compensation exceeds the limit under subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The pension to be reduced under this section is the pension at retirement without any cost-of-living adjustment.</section>
  </text>
</law>
