<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-23-306.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>A member who is subject to the contributory pension benefit or the Alternate Contributory Pension Se...</catch_line>
  <order_by>306.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A member who is subject to the contributory pension benefit or the Alternate Contributory Pension Selection may purchase service credit as provided in subsection (b) of this section for periods of employment described in subsection (c) of this section for which the member is not otherwise entitled.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A member who purchases service credit under this section shall:<section prefix="(i)">complete a claim for the service credit and file it with the Board of Trustees on a form that the Board of Trustees provides; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">pay to the Board of Trustees in a single payment the member contributions the member would have made for the period of employment for which service credit is being purchased if the member had earned the prior service in the same part of the Employees' Pension System or Teachers' Pension System in which the member is currently enrolled, plus regular interest to the date of payment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member may pay for service credit purchased under this section at any time before retirement.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to &#xA7; 414(h)(2) of the Internal Revenue Code, an individual's accumulated contributions in excess of the amount determined under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be refunded on request.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a member may purchase service credit for a period of employment as a member of the Employees' Pension System or Teachers' Pension System if the member:<section prefix="(i)">has withdrawn the member's accumulated contributions after a prior termination of membership; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">was subject to the contributory pension benefit or the Alternate Contributory Pension Selection when the member previously terminated membership in the Employees' Pension System or the Teachers' Pension System.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member may not purchase eligibility service credit that exceeds the member's creditable service credit.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
