<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-29-204.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only to an individual who dies while employed as a member of the Correctional O...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only to an individual who dies while employed as a member of the Correctional Officers' Retirement System:<section prefix="(1)">without willful negligence by the member; and</section><section prefix="(2)">with death arising out of or in the course of the actual performance of duty.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">When the Board of Trustees receives proof of death of a member and finds that the death has occurred in the manner described in subsection (a) of this section, the Board of Trustees shall pay:<section prefix="(1)">if the member is survived by a spouse or a child under the age of 18 years:<section prefix="(i)">the member's accumulated contributions to the designated beneficiary, or otherwise to the member's estate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">an allowance of two-thirds of the member's average final compensation:<section prefix="1.">to the surviving spouse; or</section><section prefix="2.">if there is no surviving spouse or if the surviving spouse dies before the youngest child of the member is 18 years old, to any children of the deceased member who are under the age of 18 years; or</section></section></section><section prefix="(2)">if the member is not survived by a spouse or a child under the age of 18 years, the death benefit under &#xA7; 29-202 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the Board of Trustees pays an allowance under this section to more than one child, the Board of Trustees shall divide the allowance among the children under the age of 18 years in a manner that provides for payments to continue until each child dies or becomes 18 years old.</section>
  </text>
</law>
