<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-29-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>When the Board of Trustees receives proof of death of an individual who died while employed as a mem...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When the Board of Trustees receives proof of death of an individual who died while employed as a member, the Board of Trustees shall pay to the designated beneficiary or, if there is no designated beneficiary, to the member's estate the amounts specified in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Board of Trustees shall pay the member's accumulated contributions.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Board of Trustees shall pay an amount equal to the member's annual earnable compensation at death if the member dies in the course of the performance of duty or the member has at least 1 year of eligibility service.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A death benefit under this section may not be paid for the death of a member of the State Police Retirement System if a special death benefit under &#xA7; 29-204 of this subtitle is payable or has been paid for that death.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A death benefit under this section may not be paid for the death of a member of the Correctional Officers' Retirement System if a special death benefit under &#xA7; 29-204.1 of this subtitle is payable or has been paid for that death.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A death benefit under this section may not be paid for the death of a member of the Employees' Retirement System, Employees' Pension System, Teachers' Retirement System, or Teachers' Pension System if a special death benefit under &#xA7; 29-204.2 of this subtitle is payable or has been paid for that death.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A death benefit under this section may not be paid for the death of a member of the Law Enforcement Officers' Pension System if a special death benefit under &#xA7; 29-203 of this subtitle is payable or has been paid for that death.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board of Trustees may provide the death benefit as group life insurance if the Board of Trustees finds that the designated beneficiaries would receive a more favorable tax treatment of the death benefit.</section>
  </text>
</law>
