<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-23-307</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>307</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, in the year of retirement, a member of the Employees' Pension System may purchase credit for eligibility service of up to 10 years for periods of employment described in paragraph (3) of this subsection for which the member is not otherwise entitled to service credit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To purchase service credit under this subsection, a member must:<section prefix="(i)">complete a claim for the service credit and file it with the Board of Trustees on the form that the Board of Trustees provides; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">pay to the Board of Trustees an amount equal to the annuity reserve and pension reserve required to fund the additional allowance.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member may only purchase service credit under this subsection for employment with:<section prefix="(i)">the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a political subdivision in the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an out-of-state school as a teacher;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the federal government;</section><section prefix="(v)">an out-of-state political subdivision;</section><section prefix="(vi)">a public or nonpublic school as a teacher; or</section><section prefix="(vii)">a postsecondary school as a teacher.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to an employee of a participating governmental unit or a former participating governmental unit that has withdrawn.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the year of retirement, a member of the Employees' Pension System may purchase credit for eligibility service for periods of employment with the State for which the member is not otherwise entitled to service credit in a State system.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, a member who purchases service credit under this subsection, may not purchase:<section prefix="(i)">more than a total of 10 years of service credit in the Employees' Pension System;</section><section prefix="(ii)">service credit for any period of employment during which the member participated in the optional retirement program; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">more than a total of 5 years of service credit in the Employees' Pension System for employment as a postsecondary school teacher.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">To purchase service credit under this subsection, a member must:<section prefix="(i)">complete a claim for the service credit and file it with the Board of Trustees on the form that the Board of Trustees provides; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">pay to the Board of Trustees an amount equal to one-half of the annuity reserve and one-half of the pension reserve required to fund the additional allowance.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A member of the Employees' Pension System may purchase credit for eligibility service for previous service in a position described in &#xA7; 23-204(a) of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To purchase the service credit, the member must pay in a single payment, the contributions, with interest, that the Board of Trustees considers appropriate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A member of the Employees' Pension System who is employed by a member of the State Senate or House of Delegates for at least 130 days per year as a legislative employee before becoming a member is considered to have been a permanent part-time legislative employee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member described in paragraph (1) of this subsection may purchase credit for eligibility service for that period of legislative employment by paying to the Board of Trustees:<section prefix="(i)">for a period of employment on or before December 31, 1979, the sum of:<section prefix="1.">the amount that the member would have been required to contribute for that period of employment; and</section><section prefix="2.">interest on the member's contributions, compounded annually; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">for a period of employment on or after January 1, 1980, the sum of:<section prefix="1.">the amount that the member would have been required to contribute for that period of employment;</section><section prefix="2.">the amount that the State would have been required to contribute for the member for that period of employment; and</section><section prefix="3.">interest on the member's and State's contributions, compounded annually.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The rate of interest to be paid under this subsection is the average for the 5 years preceding the year of payment of the yearly rate of interest computed as the sum of the investment income and the realized gains and losses divided by the book value of the total investments.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
