<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="gsp" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-7-201</section_number>
  <catch_line>This subtitle does not apply to a special appointment position in the skilled service or professiona...</catch_line>
  <order_by>201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subtitle does not apply to a special appointment position in the skilled service or professional service.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This subtitle does not apply to the recruitment for or the appointment to a position in the skilled service or professional service if the appointing authority:<section prefix="1.">decides to recruit for the position under &#xA7; 7-203(2) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="2.">demonstrates that the position, based on the position description, is difficult to fill;</section><section prefix="3.">demonstrates that the recruitment must occur in a timely manner; and</section><section prefix="4.">notifies the Department of the recruitment.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A recruitment and appointment under this paragraph shall occur in accordance with regulations adopted by the Department.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">
          <section prefix="1.">The Department shall adopt regulations to implement this paragraph.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The regulations adopted under this subparagraph shall provide, at a minimum, that for positions designated as special appointments on January 1, 2009, an appointing authority shall retain the same recruitment authority that the appointing authority possessed on January 1, 2009.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each unit shall fill vacant skilled service and professional service positions in accordance with a position selection plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To ensure compliance with State and federal employment laws and to ensure consistency in recruitment and hiring practices in the State Personnel Management System, the Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">assist units in developing application forms, position selection plans, selection tests, and announcement forms; and</section><section prefix="(2)">review and audit recruitment and hiring practices of all appointing authorities at least once every 3 years.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">On request of a unit that is not able to conduct all or part of its own recruitment or selection testing for a position because it lacks the appropriate resources, the Department, consistent with its resources, shall assist the unit in conducting the requested recruitment and selection testing.</section>
  </text>
</law>
