<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-20-206</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>206</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "unused sick leave" means sick leave credit that has not been used before retirement.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">the Judges' Retirement System; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the Legislative Pension Plan.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A member is entitled to receive creditable service for unused sick leave if the member retires on or before 30 days after the member is separated from employment with a participating employer or a participating governmental unit that has withdrawn from one of the several systems under Title 31 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At retirement, a member is entitled to receive creditable service for unused sick leave, on verification of the unused sick leave to the Board of Trustees.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This subsection does not apply to the Local Fire and Police System or the Law Enforcement Officers' Pension System.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A member who separates from employment for reasons other than retirement on or before June 30, 1990, is entitled to receive creditable service for unused sick leave that is reported by the member's employer at the member's separation from employment if the member was entitled to a vested allowance at the time of separation.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, for 22 days of unused sick leave a member is entitled to receive 1 month of creditable service.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If fractional days totaling 11 or more result from the application of the formula described in paragraph (1) of this subsection, a member is entitled to receive 1 additional month of creditable service.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For the purposes of this section:<section prefix="(i)">a member may not accumulate more than 15 days of sick leave per year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">unless sick leave credit is accepted and credited by the current participating employer, a member may not receive credit for unused sick leave granted by a former employer; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">if a participating employer provides a member with more than 15 days of sick leave per year, before crediting the member with additional sick leave for a year, the Board of Trustees shall reduce the member's accumulated sick leave by the lesser of:<section prefix="1.">the days of sick leave used by the member in that year; or</section><section prefix="2.">the number of days of sick leave provided by the participating employer for the year, less 15.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Credit for unused sick leave may not be used under this section:<section prefix="(1)">to determine years of eligibility service required for a benefit under this Division II; or</section><section prefix="(2)">to compute average final compensation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A State employee who came into the State system while retaining sick leave and annual leave benefits under a county system and who came under the provisions of Chapter 423 of the Acts of 1971 shall be entitled to the same full credit toward retirement as provided by this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
