<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gsp" order_by="" level="1">State Personnel and Pensions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gsp-30-307</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>307</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, an election to participate in the program is a waiver of all rights and benefits provided by the retirement or pension system in which the participating employee was a member on the effective date of the election.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For the purpose of determining eligibility for immediate vested rights or benefits in a retirement system or pension system, an eligible employee who is a member of that State system when the employee elects to participate in the program is deemed to have separated from employment on the effective date of the election.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board of Trustees may only compute retirement system or pension system benefits on the basis of years of creditable service as a member of that State system.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section applies only to a participating employee whose last employer prior to joining the program was a participating employer that does not participate in the employer pick-up program as defined in &#xA7; 414(h)(2) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A participating employee may withdraw any accumulated contributions in the annuity savings fund on or after the effective date of the participating employee's election to join the program.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a participating employee withdraws the accumulated contributions, the participating employee forfeits any right to a benefit in the State system from which the accumulated contributions were withdrawn.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A participating employee is ineligible for membership in a retirement system or pension system while the participating employee is employed in any eligible position by any employing institution.</section>
  </text>
</law>
