<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-11-215</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>215</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The sales and use tax does not apply to a sale of photographic material for use in the production of an item that is used in:<section prefix="(1)">composition or printing; or</section><section prefix="(2)">production of another item used in printing.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The sales and use tax does not apply to a sale of art works, electros, electrotypes, hand or machine compositions, lithographic plates or negatives, mats, photoengravings, stereotypes, or typographies:<section prefix="(i)">to a person engaged in the printing of tangible personal property for sale; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">for direct use by the person to produce that property for sale.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A vendor who sells any item under paragraph (1) of this subsection is not entitled to any exclusion under &#xA7; 11-101(h)(3)(ii) or (n)(3)(ii) of this title for material that the vendor buys to produce that item.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The sales and use tax does not apply to the printing and sale of newspapers that are distributed by the publisher at no charge.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A publication is not a newspaper unless it is published and distributed at least once per month and it meets other criteria as defined by the Comptroller.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The sales and use tax does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">a sale of direct mail advertising literature and mail order catalogues that will be distributed outside the State, and a sale of computerized mailing lists to the extent used for the purpose of providing addresses to which direct mail advertising literature and mail order catalogues will be distributed outside the State; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a sale of government documents, publications, records, or copies by the federal or State or a local government or an instrumentality of the federal or State or a local government.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
