<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-9-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Blend" means to mix together any combination of:<section prefix="(i)">alkylate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">aromatic;</section><section prefix="(iii)">cracked gasoline;</section><section prefix="(iv)">natural gasoline;</section><section prefix="(v)">polymer gasoline; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">straight-run gasoline.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Blend" does not include adding alcohol to gasoline.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Dealer" means a person who engages in the business of a dealer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Dealer" includes:<section prefix="(i)">the State when it engages in the business of a dealer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a political subdivision of the State when the subdivision engages in the business of a dealer.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Distributor" means a person who engages in the business of a distributor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Distributor" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">a licensed dealer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a licensed special fuel seller;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a licensed special fuel user;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a licensed turbine fuel seller;</section><section prefix="(v)">a marina; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">a retail service station dealer.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Engage in the business of a dealer" means to:<section prefix="(i)">import any gasoline into the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">blend, in the State, any gasoline on which the motor fuel tax has not been paid;</section><section prefix="(iii)">refine, in the State, any gasoline on which the motor fuel tax has not been paid; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">acquire, in the State, any gasoline on which the motor fuel tax has not been paid, for:<section prefix="1.">export; or</section><section prefix="2.">wholesale distribution.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Engage in the business of a dealer" does not include bringing gasoline into the State in the fuel supply tank of an aircraft, motor vehicle, or vessel.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Engage in the business of a distributor" means to buy for resale motor fuel on which the motor fuel tax has been paid from a licensed dealer, licensed special fuel seller, licensed special fuel user, or licensed turbine fuel seller.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Engage in the business of a special fuel seller" means, with respect to special fuel other than turbine fuel, to:<section prefix="(i)">import any special fuel into the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">sell, in the State, any special fuel on which the motor fuel tax has not been paid; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">deliver, in the State, any special fuel on which the motor fuel tax has not been paid.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Engage in the business of a special fuel seller" does not include bringing special fuel into the State in the fuel supply tank of a motor vehicle or vessel.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Engage in the business of a special fuel user" means to:<section prefix="(1)">buy special fuel on which the motor fuel tax has not been paid; and</section><section prefix="(2)">use it in a motor vehicle that is:<section prefix="(i)">owned or operated by the special fuel user; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">registered to operate on a public highway.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Engage in the business of a turbine fuel seller" means to:<section prefix="(i)">import any turbine fuel into the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">sell, in the State, any turbine fuel on which the motor fuel tax has not been paid; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">deliver, in the State, any turbine fuel on which the motor fuel tax has not been paid.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Engage in the business of a turbine fuel seller" does not include bringing turbine fuel into the State in the fuel supply tank of an aircraft.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"License" means a license issued by the Comptroller under this subtitle to engage in the business of a dealer, distributor, special fuel seller, special fuel user, or turbine fuel seller.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Licensed dealer" means a person who is licensed to engage in the business of a dealer.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Licensed distributor" means a person who is licensed to engage in the business of a distributor.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Licensed special fuel seller" means a person who is licensed to engage in the business of a special fuel seller.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Licensed special fuel user" means a person who is licensed to engage in the business of a special fuel user.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Licensed turbine fuel seller" means a person who is licensed to engage in the business of a turbine fuel seller.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Marina" means a person who maintains a place of business where motor fuel is sold primarily to vessels.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Refine" means to make crude oil into gasoline or special fuel by changing the physical or chemical characteristics of the crude oil.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Retail service station dealer" means a person who operates a retail place of business where motor fuel is sold and delivered into the fuel supply tanks of motor vehicles.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Special fuel seller" means a person who engages in the business of a special fuel seller.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Special fuel seller" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">a retail service station dealer who pays the motor fuel tax on special fuel to the supplier of the special fuel; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a marina that sells special fuel only to vessels.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(t)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Special fuel user" means a person who engages in the business of a special fuel user.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Special fuel user" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">a person whose only storage for special fuel is the fuel supply tank of a motor vehicle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a volunteer fire or nonprofit volunteer rescue company that is incorporated in the State and buys special fuel from a licensed special fuel seller to operate fire fighting vehicles or equipment; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a person who pays the motor fuel tax on all special fuels to the supplier of the special fuels.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(u)">"Turbine fuel seller" means a person who engages in the business of a turbine fuel seller.</section>
  </text>
</law>
