<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-7-210</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>210</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an application to prepay inheritance tax for a subsequent interest in property is filed under &#xA7; 7-219 of this subtitle, the value of the subsequent interest is determined by subtracting the value of all preceding and concurrent interests from the value of the whole property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The total inheritance tax on all interests in the property valued shall equal the inheritance tax that would have been due if an absolute interest in the property passed from the decedent.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a subsequent interest in property ultimately vests in possession in a person other than the person by or for whom an application to prepay the inheritance tax was filed under &#xA7; 7-219 of this subtitle and if the inheritance tax determined under the prepayment application was paid:<section prefix="(i)">the subsequent interest shall be revalued when it vests in possession; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the inheritance tax due on the subsequent interest shall be redetermined based on the value of the interest when it vests in possession and on the relationship of the original decedent to the person in whom the interest ultimately vests in possession.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A deduction from the inheritance tax calculated under paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection for prepaid inheritance tax on the interest shall be allowed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an application to prepay the inheritance tax for a subsequent interest is not filed in accordance with &#xA7; 7-219 of this subtitle or if the inheritance tax determined for the subsequent interest under a prepayment application is not paid when due under &#xA7; 7-217(d) of this subtitle:<section prefix="(i)">the whole property shall be valued when the subsequent interest vests in possession;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the value of the subsequent interest shall be valued when it vests in possession in the manner stated in subsection (a) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the inheritance tax due on the subsequent interest shall be determined based on the value of the interest when it vests in possession and on the relationship of the original decedent to the person in whom the interest ultimately vests in possession.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A deduction for inheritance tax previously paid on any interest in the property may not be allowed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the inheritance tax applies to 1 or more of the persons by or for whom an application to prepay the inheritance tax is filed under &#xA7; 7-219 of this subtitle and the exemption under &#xA7; 7-203(b) of this subtitle applies to others, the inheritance tax applies to the subsequent interest.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">On application of a party in interest, the inheritance tax due may be apportioned among the persons by or for whom the application to prepay the inheritance tax is filed.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">After the apportionment, each of those persons is responsible only for the amount of the inheritance tax apportioned to that person.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
