<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-9-201</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Commercial motor vehicle" means any motor vehicle used or maintained for the transportation of persons or property that:<section prefix="(i)">has 2 axles and an operating or registered gross vehicle weight that exceeds 26,000 pounds;</section><section prefix="(ii)">has 3 or more axles; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">is used in combination with another vehicle and has an operating or registered gross combined weight that exceeds 26,000 pounds.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Commercial motor vehicle" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">a privately owned antique truck that:<section prefix="1.">is registered as a historic motor vehicle under &#xA7; 13-936 of the Transportation Article; and</section><section prefix="2.">displays appropriate registration plates that the Motor Vehicle Administration issues;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">a commercial motor vehicle that is operated:<section prefix="1.">by a state or a subdivision of a state;</section><section prefix="2.">by the United States;</section><section prefix="3.">by a joint unit of:</section><section prefix="4.">by or for a state, political subdivision of a state, or private school as a school bus;</section><section prefix="5.">by a volunteer or paid fire department or rescue squad as fire or rescue equipment;</section><section prefix="6.">by a licensed vehicle dealer during a road test for sale, if the vehicle displays dealer registration plates that the Motor Vehicle Administration issues; or</section><section prefix="7.">by a person as a privately owned bus used only in the transportation system of a county, municipal corporation, special taxing district, or other political subdivision to transport the public on a regular schedule between fixed termini as those terms are defined in the Transportation Article;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">a multipurpose passenger vehicle as defined in &#xA7; 11-136.2 of the Transportation Article;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a multipurpose passenger vehicle or truck that does not exceed 3/4 ton capacity when towing:<section prefix="1.">a camping trailer as defined in &#xA7; 11-106 of the Transportation Article; or</section><section prefix="2.">a travel trailer as defined in &#xA7; 11-170 of the Transportation Article; or</section></section><section prefix="(v)">a farm truck as defined in &#xA7; 13-921 of the Transportation Article or a farm area motor vehicle as defined in &#xA7; 13-935 of the Transportation Article that has 2 axles and a registered or operating gross or combination weight of less than 40,001 pounds.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Motor carrier" means a person who operates or causes the operation of a commercial motor vehicle on a highway in this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Motor carrier" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a lessor of a commercial motor vehicle who provides or buys the motor fuel used to operate the vehicle or pays for it as a part of rental or other costs; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a lessee whose lease entitles the lessee to receive a credit or refund for motor fuel that the lessor buys.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
