<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-7-225</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>225</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person required to file an inventory shall have the property appraised in the manner provided in Title 7, Subtitle 2 of the Estates and Trusts Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each personal representative shall file the inventory required by &#xA7; 7-201 of the Estates and Trusts Article with the register within 3 months after appointment.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If there is no formal administration of an estate, each person other than a personal representative who distributes property that passes from the decedent shall file the inventory required by &#xA7; 7-201 of the Estates and Trusts Article, within 3 months after the death of the decedent and before distributing the property:<section prefix="(1)">for personal property, with the register in the county where the decedent resided at the time of death; and</section><section prefix="(2)">for real property, with the register in the county where the real property is located.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If there is no formal administration of an estate, each person who receives property that passes from a decedent without distribution shall file the inventory required by &#xA7; 7-201 of the Estates and Trusts Article, within 3 months after the death of the decedent:<section prefix="(1)">for personal property, with the register in the county where the decedent resided at the time of death; and</section><section prefix="(2)">for real property, with the register in the county where the real property is located.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A foreign personal representative who administers an estate with property that is located in this State and subject to the inheritance tax shall file with the register of the county where the foreign personal representative believes the largest part, in value, of the property is located:<section prefix="(1)">a copy of the appointment as personal representative;</section><section prefix="(2)">a copy of the will of the decedent, if any, authenticated in accordance with 28 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1738; and</section><section prefix="(3)">an inventory of all of the property that the estate owns in this State that:<section prefix="(i)">is made under oath;</section><section prefix="(ii)">describes each item in reasonable detail; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">indicates the fair market value of each item and the basis on which the value is determined.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
