<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="gtg" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-11-216</section_number>
  <catch_line>The sales and use tax does not apply to:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>216</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The sales and use tax does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">a sale for use of tangible personal property that:<section prefix="(i)">is bought outside this State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is intended solely for use in another state; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">is stored in this State pending shipment to another state;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">a sale of tangible personal property to a person obligated under a contract to incorporate that property into real property located in another state where the purchase or use of that property would not be subject to a sales tax, use tax, or similar tax; or</section><section prefix="(3)">except for that portion of the purchase price allocable to intended viewing in this State, a sale of a series of images stored on video tape or in other optical or digital forms or electronic signals generated from these images to a cable or other nonbroadcast television network, if the images are intended for viewing by television viewers located outside the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The sales and use tax shall be paid:<section prefix="(1)">on a sale under subsection (a)(1) of this section, when the tangible personal property is imported or stored in the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">on a sale under subsection (a)(2) of this section, when the sale is made.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person who pays the sales and use tax under subsection (b) of this section may obtain the exemption by:<section prefix="(1)">filing a claim for refund with the Comptroller when the property is removed from the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">providing the Comptroller with the evidence that the Comptroller requires by regulation, including:<section prefix="(i)">evidence of use or removal of the property from the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">satisfactory proof of entitlement to exemption in another state.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
