<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-10-106</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>106</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each county shall set, by ordinance or resolution, a county income tax equal to at least 1% but not more than the percentage of an individual's Maryland taxable income as follows:<section prefix="(i)">3.05% for a taxable year beginning after December 31, 1998 but before January 1, 2001;</section><section prefix="(ii)">3.10% for a taxable year beginning after December 31, 2000 but before January 1, 2002; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">3.20% for a taxable year beginning after December 31, 2001.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A county income tax rate continues until the county changes the rate by ordinance or resolution.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A county may not increase its county income tax rate above 2.6% until after the county has held a public hearing on the proposed act, ordinance, or resolution to increase the rate.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The county shall publish at least once each week for 2 successive weeks in a newspaper of general circulation in the county:<section prefix="1.">notice of the public hearing; and</section><section prefix="2.">a fair summary of the proposed act, ordinance, or resolution to increase the county income tax rate above 2.6%.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) or (2) of this subsection, in Howard County, the county income tax rate may be changed only by ordinance and not by resolution.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a county changes its county income tax rate, the county shall:<section prefix="(1)">increase or decrease the rate in increments of one one-hundredth of a percentage point, effective on January 1 of the year that the county designates; and</section><section prefix="(2)">give the Comptroller notice of the rate change and the effective date of the rate change on or before July 1 prior to its effective date.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
