<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="gtg" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-13-510</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section and subject to &#xA7; 13-514 of this subtitle, with...</catch_line>
  <order_by>510</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section and subject to &#xA7; 13-514 of this subtitle, within 30 days after the date on which a notice is mailed, a person or governmental unit that is aggrieved by the action in the notice may appeal to the Tax Court from:<section prefix="(1)">a final assessment of tax, interest, or penalty under this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">a final determination on an application for revision or claim for refund under &#xA7; 13-508 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">an inheritance tax determination by a register or by an orphans' court other than a circuit court sitting as an orphans' court;</section><section prefix="(4)">a denial of an alternative payment schedule for inheritance tax or Maryland estate tax;</section><section prefix="(5)">a final determination on a claim for return of seized property under &#xA7; 13-839 or &#xA7; 13-840 of this title; or</section><section prefix="(6)">a disallowance of a claim for refund under &#xA7; 13-904 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a tax collector does not make a determination on a claim for refund within 6 months after the claim is filed, the claimant may:<section prefix="(1)">consider the claim as being disallowed; and</section><section prefix="(2)">appeal the disallowance to the Tax Court.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An appeal to the Maryland Tax Court under this section shall be deemed to be filed within the time allowed for the appeal if a written petition is mailed to the Maryland Tax Court with a postmark date within the time allowed for the appeal.</section>
  </text>
</law>
