<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="gtg" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-13-825</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Comptroller may require a person whose gross receipts are subject to admissions and amusement ta...</catch_line>
  <order_by>825</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Comptroller may require a person whose gross receipts are subject to admissions and amusement tax and whose business is not a permanent operation in the State to post security for the tax in the amount that the Comptroller determines.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Comptroller shall require:<section prefix="(1)">a manufacturer, wholesaler, or nonresident winery permit holder who sells or delivers beer or wine to retailers in the State to post security for the alcoholic beverage tax:<section prefix="(i)">in an amount not less than:<section prefix="1.">$1,000 for beer; and</section><section prefix="2.">$1,000 for wine; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">if the alcoholic beverage tax on beer and wine paid in any 1 month exceeds $1,000, in an additional amount at least equal to the excess;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">a manufacturer or wholesaler who sells or delivers any distilled spirits or any wine and distilled spirits in the State to post a security for the alcoholic beverage tax:<section prefix="(i)">in an amount not less than $5,000; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">in an additional amount:<section prefix="1.">equal to twice the amount of its largest monthly alcoholic beverage tax liability for wine and distilled spirits in the preceding calendar year less $5,000; or</section><section prefix="2.">if the information for the preceding calendar year is not available or cannot be provided, equal to the amount that the Comptroller requires; and</section></section></section><section prefix="(3)">except as provided in subsection (i) of this section, a holder of a direct wine shipper's permit to post security for the alcoholic beverage tax in an amount not less than $1,000.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Comptroller may require a person whose gross receipts are subject to the boxing and wrestling tax to post security for the boxing and wrestling tax in the amount that the Comptroller determines.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Comptroller may require a real estate investment trust to post security for income tax in the amount that the Comptroller requires, if the trust:<section prefix="(1)">does not hold property in the State; or</section><section prefix="(2)">holds insufficient property in the State to provide adequate security for the income tax if the property were to become subject to a lien under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Comptroller may require a person seeking a refund of motor carrier tax to post security for the tax in an amount of not less than $5,000 but not more than $100,000.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Comptroller shall require an applicant for any license under Title 9 of this article, except for a Class "W" license, to post security for the motor fuel tax in the amount that the Comptroller requires, but not less than:<section prefix="(1)">$200,000 for a Class "A" license;</section><section prefix="(2)">$50,000 for a Class "B" license;</section><section prefix="(3)">$10,000 for a Class "C" license;</section><section prefix="(4)">$200,000 for a Class "D" license;</section><section prefix="(5)">$1,000 for a Class "F" license;</section><section prefix="(6)">$10,000 for a Class "G-Temporary" license;</section><section prefix="(7)">$1,000 for a Class "S" license; and</section><section prefix="(8)">$1,000 for a Class "U" license.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Comptroller may require a person subject to the sales and use tax to post security for the tax in the amount that the Comptroller determines.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Comptroller may require a person subject to the tobacco tax to post security for the tax in the following amounts:<section prefix="(i)">for a manufacturer or wholesaler:<section prefix="1.">$10,000, plus</section><section prefix="2.">the amount, if any, by which the tobacco tax due for any 1 month exceeds $10,000;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">for a subwholesaler or vending machine operator:<section prefix="1.">$1,000, plus</section><section prefix="2.">the amount, if any, by which the tobacco tax due for any 1 month exceeds $1,000; and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">for an other tobacco products wholesaler:<section prefix="1.">$5,000, plus</section><section prefix="2.">the amount, if any, by which the tobacco tax due for any 1 month exceeds $5,000.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraph (5) of this subsection, the Comptroller may exempt a person from posting security for the tobacco tax if the person is and has been for the past 5 years:<section prefix="(i)">licensed as required under &#xA7; 16-202 of the Business Regulation Article to act as a wholesaler or &#xA7; 16.5-201 to act as an other tobacco products wholesaler; and</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">in continuous compliance with the tobacco tax laws, as determined under paragraph (3) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="2.">in continuous compliance with the conditions of the person's security posted under this subsection.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For purposes of paragraph (2) of this subsection, a person is in continuous compliance with the tobacco tax laws for a period if the person has not, at any time during that period:<section prefix="(i)">failed to pay any tobacco tax or any tobacco tax assessment when due;</section><section prefix="(ii)">failed to file a tobacco tax return when due; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">otherwise violated any of the provisions of Title 12 or Title 13 of this article or Title 16 or Title 16.5 of the Business Regulation Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An exemption granted under paragraph (2) of this subsection is effective only to the extent that a person's potential tobacco tax liability does not exceed an amount determined by the Comptroller based on the person's experience during the 5-year compliance period under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Comptroller may revoke an exemption granted to a person under paragraph (2) of this subsection if the person at any time fails to be in continuous compliance with the tobacco tax laws, as described in paragraph (3) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Comptroller may reinstate an exemption revoked under subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph if the person meets the requirements of paragraph (2)(i) and (ii) of this subsection for a period of 2 years following the revocation.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Comptroller may not exempt a person from posting a bond or other security for the tobacco tax unless the Comptroller determines that the person is solvent and financially able to pay the person's potential tobacco tax liability.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">If a corporation is granted an exemption from posting a bond or other security for the tobacco tax, any officer of the corporation who exercises direct control over its fiscal management is personally liable for any tobacco tax, interest and penalties owed by the corporation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A person need not post security under subsection (b)(3) of this section if:<section prefix="(1)">the person is a manufacturer that has posted security under subsection (b)(2) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(2)">at any time starting 3 years after the Comptroller first issues a direct wine shipper's permit to the person, the Comptroller:<section prefix="(i)">determines that the person has a substantial record of tax and reporting compliance; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">waives the security requirement.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
