<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="gtg" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-10-805</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section and except for a fiduciary, each resident shall...</catch_line>
  <order_by>805</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section and except for a fiduciary, each resident shall file an income tax return if, after exclusion of Social Security and railroad retirement benefits that are included in federal gross income, the resident:<section prefix="(1)">would be required to file a federal income tax return under &#xA7; 6012(a) of the Internal Revenue Code; or</section><section prefix="(2)">would have federal gross income that exceeds the amount specified in &#xA7; 6012(a) of the Internal Revenue Code after the federal gross income is increased by the modifications in &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-204 and 10-205 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A resident dependent shall file an income tax return if the dependent:<section prefix="(1)">would have federal gross income that exceeds the amount specified in &#xA7; 6012(a)(1)(A)(i) of the Internal Revenue Code after the federal gross income is modified under Subtitle 2, Part II of this title; and</section><section prefix="(2)">otherwise would be described in &#xA7; 6012(a)(1)(A)(i) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If an individual whose status changes, during a taxable year, from resident to nonresident or nonresident to resident is required to file an income tax return under subsection (a) or subsection (b) of this section or &#xA7; 10-806 of this subtitle, the individual shall report on the return the Maryland taxable income:<section prefix="(1)">received during the part of the taxable year that the individual was a resident; and</section><section prefix="(2)">derived as a nonresident.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
