<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-804" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-10-804</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each person required under this subtitle to file an income tax return or estimated income tax declaration or return shall file a return or declaration with the Comptroller, whether or not:<section prefix="(1)">the person owes income tax; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the Comptroller sends the person a form or otherwise requests that the return or declaration be filed.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each income tax return and estimated income tax declaration and return shall be:<section prefix="(i)">signed in the same manner required for the signing of a federal return under &#xA7;&#xA7; 6061 through 6064 of the Internal Revenue Code; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">made under oath.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An individual who is an income tax return preparer with respect to a return or claim for refund of tax shall sign the return or claim for refund after it is completed and before it is presented to the taxpayer or nontaxable entity for signature.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the preparer is unavailable for signature, another preparer shall review the entire preparation of the return or claim for refund, and then shall sign the return or claim for refund. The preparer shall sign the return in the manner prescribed by the Comptroller in forms, instructions, or other appropriate guidance.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If more than one income tax return preparer is involved in the preparation of the return or claim for refund, the individual preparer who has the primary responsibility as between or among the preparers for the overall substantive accuracy of the preparation of the return or claim for refund shall be considered to be the income tax return preparer for purposes of paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To properly identify persons listed in a return or other document, a person shall include in the document the Social Security or other identifying number that the Comptroller requires:<section prefix="(i)">of the person required to file the return or document; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">of the person on whose behalf the return or document is filed.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a return or document is filed on behalf of a person, that person shall provide the identifying number required in a return or document to the person who files the return or document.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any return or claim for refund prepared by an income tax return preparer shall bear the identifying number for securing proper identification of the preparer, the preparer's employer, or both, as prescribed under &#xA7; 6109(a)(4) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each resident shall include on the income tax return of the resident:<section prefix="(1)">for an individual other than a fiduciary, the name of the county and municipal corporation, if any, where the resident resides; and</section><section prefix="(2)">for a personal representative, the name of the county where the decedent was domiciled on the date of the decedent's death; or</section><section prefix="(3)">for a fiduciary other than a personal representative, the name of:<section prefix="(i)">the county where the trust is principally administered; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the trust is not principally administered in the State, the county to which the trust is otherwise principally connected.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each person required under this subtitle to file an income tax return or estimated income tax declaration or return shall:<section prefix="(1)">comply with the regulations of the Comptroller;</section><section prefix="(2)">keep the records that the Comptroller requires; and</section><section prefix="(3)">attach to an income tax return or otherwise file with the Comptroller any records or statements that the Comptroller requires, including:<section prefix="(i)">for an individual who has income tax withheld from salary, wages, or other compensation for personal services, or other payments, a copy of the statement from the person who withholds the tax that states:</section><section prefix="(ii)">a copy of the federal income tax return:</section><section prefix="(iii)">for a corporation, the statements required under &#xA7; 10-804.1 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">if the Comptroller requests, for a corporation that is a member of an affiliated group or controlled group under &#xA7; 1504 or &#xA7; 1563 of the Internal Revenue Code, a statement of all intermember costs or expenses and all intermember sales, exchanges, or other transactions involving tangible or intangible property for the taxable year.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An individual may designate a contribution to the State Chesapeake Bay and Endangered Species Fund, established under &#xA7;&#xA7; 1-701 through 1-706 of the Natural Resources Article, by the checkoff system on the return.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Comptroller shall provide that an income tax return may be completed using whole dollar amounts instead of expressing amounts in exact dollars and cents by:<section prefix="(1)">disregarding a fractional part of a dollar less than 50 cents; and</section><section prefix="(2)">increasing to 1 dollar a fractional part of a dollar of at least 50 cents.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">An individual may designate a contribution to the Maryland Cancer Fund, established under &#xA7; 20-117 of the Health - General Article, by the checkoff system on the return.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">An individual may designate a contribution to the Waiting List Equity Fund, established under &#xA7; 7-205 of the Health - General Article, by the checkoff system on the return.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A taxpayer claiming any of the following tax credits shall submit a claim for the credit by electronic means as required by the Comptroller by regulation:<section prefix="(i)">the Job Creation Tax Credit, as provided under Title 6, Subtitle 2 of the Economic Development Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the One Maryland Tax Credit, as provided under Title 6, Subtitle 4 of the Economic Development Article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Biotechnology Investment Incentive Tax Credit, as provided under &#xA7; 10-725 of this title;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Enterprise Zone Income Tax Credit, as provided under &#xA7; 10-702 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(v)">any other tax credit specified by the Comptroller through regulation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before adding any tax credit not listed in paragraph (1)(i) through (iv) of this subsection to the requirement of this subsection, the Comptroller shall determine whether the addition of the tax credit will have a material adverse impact or undue administrative burden on the Comptroller.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
