<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="gtg" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-13-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subsection, "taxing official" means:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "taxing official" means:<section prefix="(i)">a unit or official of another state whom the laws of that state charge with the imposition, assessment, or collection of state taxes;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an employee of the United States Treasury Department; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a collector of United States taxes.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Comptroller or Department may disclose to a taxing official tax information that is contained in any tax report or return, audit of a tax return, or report of a tax investigation and relates to the imposition, assessment, and collection of taxes or to any other matter about taxation generally if:<section prefix="(i)">the Comptroller or Department is satisfied that the tax information is to be used only for tax purposes;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the taxing official's jurisdiction makes similar information available to the appropriate officials of this State; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">in the case of another state, its laws provide for adequate confidentiality of Maryland tax returns or other information.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Tax information may be disclosed in accordance with a proper judicial order or a legislative order.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Tax information may be disclosed to:<section prefix="(1)">an employee or officer of the State who, by reason of that employment or office, has the right to the tax information;</section><section prefix="(2)">another tax collector;</section><section prefix="(3)">the Maryland Tax Court;</section><section prefix="(4)">a legal representative of the State, to review the tax information about a taxpayer:<section prefix="(i)">who applies for review under this title;</section><section prefix="(ii)">who appeals from a determination under this title; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">against whom an action to recover tax or a penalty is pending or will be initiated under this title;</section></section><section prefix="(5)">any license issuing authority of the State required by State law to verify through the Comptroller that an applicant has paid all undisputed taxes and unemployment insurance contributions payable to the Comptroller or the Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation or that the applicant has provided for payment in a manner satisfactory to the unit responsible for collection;</section><section prefix="(6)">a local official as defined in &#xA7; 13-925 of this title to the extent necessary to administer Subtitle 9, Part V of this title;</section><section prefix="(7)">a federal official as defined in &#xA7; 13-930 of this title to the extent necessary to administer Part VI of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(8)">the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene in accordance with:<section prefix="(i)">the federal Children's Health Insurance Program Reauthorization Act of 2009; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">&#xA7; 10-211.1 of this article.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Tax information may be disclosed and published as statistics that are classified in a manner that prevents the identification of a particular return and the information contained in a particular return.</section>
  </text>
</law>
