<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-836" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-13-836</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If contraband alcoholic beverages or contraband tobacco products are seized:<section prefix="(i)">the Comptroller or police officer shall give a notice of seizure to the person from whom the property is seized at the time of the seizure; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Comptroller shall:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If contraband motor fuel is seized, within 48 hours after the seizure, not including weekends and holidays, the Comptroller shall give a notice of seizure to:<section prefix="(i)">the owner of the contraband motor fuel;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the registered owner of the seized conveyance; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">any secured party noted in the records of the Motor Vehicle Administration.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A notice of seizure shall state the right of an owner or other interested person, including a secured party of record, to file a claim for the return of the seized property.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A police officer who seizes a conveyance used to transport contraband alcoholic beverages promptly shall notify the Comptroller of the seizure.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A police officer who seizes any contraband tobacco products or conveyance used to transport contraband tobacco products shall deliver the seized cigarettes or other tobacco products and conveyance to the Comptroller.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A police officer who seizes any contraband motor fuel shall:<section prefix="(i)">deliver the seized contraband motor fuel and conveyance to the Comptroller; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the seized conveyance is operated by a common carrier, regulated by either the Maryland Public Service Commission or the Interstate Commerce Commission, and transports motor fuel for another person, for a fee, direct the operator of the conveyance to take it to a location that the Comptroller designates.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For a seized conveyance transporting contraband motor fuel that is operated by a common carrier, the Comptroller shall:<section prefix="(1)">remove the contraband from the conveyance at the location that the Comptroller designates;</section><section prefix="(2)">retain the contraband, subject to &#xA7;&#xA7; 13-840 and 13-841 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">after removing the contraband, release the conveyance to its operator; and</section><section prefix="(4)">reimburse the common carrier for all tariff charges applicable to the movement of the conveyance from:<section prefix="(i)">the place of seizure to the location where the contraband motor fuel was removed; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the place where the contraband motor fuel was removed to the nearer of the common carrier's home terminal or the place of seizure.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
