<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-722" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-10-722</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Administration" means the Maryland Energy Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Allowable costs" means amounts properly chargeable to capital account, other than for land, that are paid or incurred on or after July 1, 2001, for:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Allowable costs" does not include:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Applicable energy efficiency standards" means ASHRAE/IESNA Standard 90.1-1999, Energy Standard for Buildings Except Low-Rise Residential Buildings, published by the American Society of Heating, Refrigerating and Air-Conditioning Engineers.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Base building" means all areas of a building not intended for occupancy by a tenant or owner, including the structural components of the building, exterior walls, floors, windows, roofs, foundations, chimneys and stacks, parking areas, mechanical rooms and mechanical systems, and owner-controlled or operated service spaces, sidewalks, main lobby, shafts and vertical transportation mechanisms, stairways, and corridors.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Commissioning" means:<section prefix="(i)">the testing and fine-tuning of heat, ventilating, and air-conditioning systems and other systems to assure proper functioning and adherence to design criteria; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the preparation of system operation manuals and instruction of maintenance personnel.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Credit allowance year" means the later of:<section prefix="(i)">the taxable year during which:</section><section prefix="(ii)">the earliest taxable year for which the credit may be claimed under the initial credit certificate issued under subsection (k) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Eligible building" means a building located in the State that:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">in the case of a newly constructed building for which a certificate of occupancy was not issued before July 1, 2001:</section><section prefix="(iii)">in the case of a rehabilitation of a building:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(9)">"Fuel cell" means a device that produces electricity directly from hydrogen or hydrocarbon fuel through a noncombustive electrochemical process.</section>
      <section prefix="(10)">"Green base building" means a base building that is part of an eligible building and meets the requirements set out in subsection (i) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(11)">"Green whole building" means a building for which the base building is a green base building and all tenant space is green tenant space.</section>
      <section prefix="(12)">"Green tenant space" means tenant space in a building if the building is an eligible building and the tenant space meets the requirements of subsection (j) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(13)">"Incremental cost of building-integrated photovoltaic modules" means:<section prefix="(i)">the cost of building-integrated photovoltaic modules and any associated inverter, additional wiring or other electrical equipment for the photovoltaic modules, or additional mounting or structural materials, less the cost of spandrel glass or other building material that would have been used if building-integrated photovoltaic modules were not installed;</section><section prefix="(ii)">incremental labor costs properly allocable to on-site preparation, assembly, and original installation of photovoltaic modules; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">incremental costs of architectural and engineering services and designs and plans directly related to the construction or installation of photovoltaic modules.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(14)">"Qualifying alternate energy sources" means building-integrated and nonbuilding-integrated photovoltaic modules, wind turbines, and fuel cells installed to serve the base building or tenant space that:<section prefix="(i)">have the capability to monitor their actual power output;</section><section prefix="(ii)">are fully commissioned upon installation, and annually thereafter, to ensure that the systems meet their design specifications; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">in the case of wind turbines, meet any applicable noise ordinances.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(15)">"Tenant improvements" means improvements that are necessary or appropriate to support or conduct the business of a tenant or occupying owner.</section>
      <section prefix="(16)">"Tenant space" means the portion of a building intended for occupancy by a tenant or occupying owner.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual or a corporation may claim a credit against the State income tax as provided under this section for green buildings and green building components.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the credit allowed under this section exceeds the State income tax, any unused credit may be carried forward and applied for succeeding taxable years until the earlier of:<section prefix="(i)">the full amount of the credit is used; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the expiration of the 10th year after the taxable year for which the credit was allowed.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For each of the credits under subsections (c) through (h) of this section, the credit may not be allowed for any taxable year unless:<section prefix="(i)">the taxpayer has obtained and filed an initial credit certificate and an eligibility certificate issued under subsection (k) of this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a certificate of occupancy for the building has been issued; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the property with respect to which the credit is claimed is in service during the taxable year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The total amount allowed in the aggregate for all credits under this section may not exceed the maximum set forth in the initial credit certificate obtained under subsection (k) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In determining the amount of the credits under this section, a cost paid or incurred may not be the basis for more than one credit.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For the taxable year that is the credit allowance year, an owner or tenant may claim a credit in an amount equal to 8% of the allowable costs paid or incurred by the owner or tenant for the construction of a green whole building or the rehabilitation of a building that is not a green whole building to be a green whole building.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The allowable costs used to determine the credit amount allowed under this subsection for a green whole building may not exceed in the aggregate:<section prefix="(i)">$120 per square foot for that portion of the building that comprises the base building; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">$60 per square foot for that portion of the building that comprises the tenant space.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For the taxable year that is the credit allowance year, an owner may claim a credit in an amount equal to 6% of the allowable costs paid or incurred by the owner for the construction of a green base building or the rehabilitation of a building that is not a green base building to be a green base building.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The allowable costs used to determine the credit amount allowed under this subsection for a green base building may not exceed, in the aggregate, $120 per square foot.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For the taxable year that is the credit allowance year, an owner or tenant may claim a credit in an amount equal to 6% of the allowable costs for tenant improvements paid or incurred by the owner or tenant in the construction or completion of green tenant space or the rehabilitation of tenant space that is not green tenant space to be green tenant space.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The allowable costs used to determine the credit amount allowed under this subsection for green tenant space may not exceed, in the aggregate, $60 per square foot.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If an owner and tenant both incur allowable costs for tenant improvements under this subsection and the costs exceed $60 per square foot in the aggregate, the owner has priority as to costs constituting the basis for the green tenant space credit under this subsection.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The credit under this subsection for green tenant space may not be claimed by an owner of a building that occupies fewer than 10,000 square feet of the building.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The credit under this subsection for green tenant space may not be claimed by a tenant that occupies fewer than 5,000 square feet.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For the taxable year that is the credit allowance year, an owner or tenant may claim a credit in the amount determined under this subsection for the installation of a fuel cell that is a qualifying alternate energy source and is installed to serve a green whole building, green base building, or green tenant space.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The amount of the credit allowed under this subsection is 30% of the sum of the capitalized costs paid or incurred by an owner or tenant with respect to each fuel cell installed, including the cost of the foundation or platform and the labor costs associated with installation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The costs used to determine the credit amount allowed under this subsection for installation of a fuel cell:<section prefix="(i)">may not exceed $1,000 per kilowatt of installed DC rated capacity of the fuel cell; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall be reduced by the amount of any federal, State, or local grant:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For the taxable year that is the credit allowance year, an owner or tenant may claim a credit in the amount determined under this subsection for the installation of photovoltaic modules that constitute a qualifying alternate energy source and are installed to serve a green whole building, green base building, or green tenant space.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The amount of the credit allowed under this subsection is:<section prefix="(i)">20% of the incremental cost paid or incurred by an owner or tenant for building-integrated photovoltaic modules; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">25% of the cost of nonbuilding-integrated photovoltaic modules, including the cost of the foundation or platform and the labor costs associated with installation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The costs used to determine the credit amount allowed under this subsection for installation of photovoltaic modules:<section prefix="(i)">may not exceed the product obtained by multiplying $3 times the number of watts included in the DC rated capacity of the photovoltaic modules; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall be reduced by the amount of any federal, State, or local grant:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For the taxable year that is the credit allowance year, an owner or tenant may claim a credit in the amount determined under paragraph (2) of this subsection for the installation of a wind turbine that is a qualifying alternate energy source and is installed to serve a green whole building, green base building, or green tenant space.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The amount of the credit allowed under this subsection is 25% of the sum of the capitalized costs paid or incurred by an owner or tenant with respect to each wind turbine installed, including the cost of the foundation or platform and the labor costs associated with installation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By regulation, the Administration shall adopt standards for a building to qualify as a green base building eligible for the tax credits under this section that are consistent with the criteria for green base buildings set forth by the United States Green Building Council or other similar criteria.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The regulations adopted under this subsection shall provide that the energy use shall be no more than 65% for new construction of a base building, or 75% in the case of rehabilitation of a base building, of the energy use attributable to a reference building that meets the requirements of applicable energy efficiency standards.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By regulation, the Administration shall adopt standards for tenant space to qualify as green tenant space eligible for the tax credits under this section that are consistent with the criteria for green tenant space set forth by the United States Green Building Council or other similar criteria.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The regulations adopted under this subsection shall provide that the energy use shall be no more than 65% for new construction, or 75% in the case of rehabilitation, of the energy use attributable to a reference building that meets the requirements of applicable energy efficiency standards.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">On application by a taxpayer, the Administration shall issue an initial credit certificate if the taxpayer has made a showing that the taxpayer is likely within a reasonable time to place in service property for which a credit under this section would be allowed.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The initial credit certificate issued under this paragraph:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">To avoid unwarranted hardship, the Administration at its discretion may extend the expiration date stated under an initial credit certificate.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The initial credit certificate shall state the maximum amount of credit allowable in the aggregate for all credits allowed under this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The Administration may not issue initial credit certificates, in the aggregate, for more than $25,000,000 worth of credits.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">Except as provided in subparagraph (vii) of this paragraph, initial credit certificates shall be limited in their applicability, as follows:</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">As of the end of a calendar year, if certificates for credit amounts totaling less than the amount permitted with respect to taxable years beginning in that calendar year have been issued, the maximum amount that may be allowed for taxable years beginning in the subsequent calendar year shall be increased by the amount of the preceding year's shortfall.</section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">The Administration may not issue an initial credit certificate after December 31, 2011.</section>
        <section prefix="(ix)">On January 1, 2004, and each year thereafter, the Administration shall provide to the Comptroller a list of all taxpayers in the prior taxable year that have been issued an initial credit certificate and shall specify for each taxpayer the earliest taxable year for which the credit may be claimed and the maximum amount of the credit allowable in the aggregate for all credits allowed under this section.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">For each taxable year for which a taxpayer claims a credit under this section with respect to a green whole building, green base building, green tenant space, fuel cell, photovoltaic module, or wind turbine, the taxpayer shall obtain an eligibility certificate from an architect or professional engineer licensed to practice in this State.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An eligibility certificate issued under this paragraph shall consist of a certification, under the seal of the architect or engineer, that the property that is the basis for the credit that is claimed is in service and that:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The certification under subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph:</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The taxpayer shall file the eligibility certificate and the associated initial credit certificate with the taxpayer's income tax return and shall file duplicate copies of the eligibility certificate with the Administration.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The eligibility certificate shall include:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the Administration has reason to believe that an architect or professional engineer, in making any certification under this subsection, engaged in professional misconduct, the Administration shall inform the appropriate professional board of the suspected misconduct.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Comptroller and the Administration may adopt regulations necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Regulations adopted under this section shall construe the provisions of this section in such a manner as to encourage the development of green whole buildings, green base buildings, and green tenant space and to maintain high, but commercially reasonable, standards for obtaining tax credits under this section.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">On or before April 1, 2005, the Comptroller and the Administration, jointly and in consultation with the Department of the Environment, shall submit to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly, a written report regarding:<section prefix="(i)">the number of certifications and taxpayers claiming the credit under this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the amount of the credits claimed;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the geographical distribution of the credits claimed; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">any other available information the Administration determines to be meaningful and appropriate.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Comptroller shall ensure that the information is presented and classified in a manner consistent with the confidentiality of tax return information.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">On or before July 1, 2002, the Administration, in consultation with the Department of the Environment and the Department of Natural Resources, shall adopt regulations with respect to the certification of green whole buildings, green base buildings, and green tenant space that are consistent with criteria set forth by the State's Green Buildings Council or other similar criteria for:<section prefix="(1)">energy use;</section><section prefix="(2)">appliance and heating, cooling, and hot water equipment standards;</section><section prefix="(3)">air conditioning equipment, including chillers;</section><section prefix="(4)">building materials, finishes, and furnishings;</section><section prefix="(5)">stormwater runoff for new construction;</section><section prefix="(6)">water conservation and efficiency; and</section><section prefix="(7)">indoor air quality, in consultation with the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
