<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-806" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-10-806</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, each nonresident who has Maryland taxable income and is required to file a federal income tax return shall file an income tax return.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A nonresident dependent who has Maryland taxable income shall file an income tax return if the dependent meets the requirements under &#xA7; 10-805(b) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For county income tax purposes, a nonresident who derives income from salary, wages, or other compensation for personal services for employment in a county shall file an income tax return, unless the Comptroller determines that each locality in which the nonresident resides:<section prefix="(1)">imposes no tax on the income of a Maryland resident derived from wages for employment in that locality;</section><section prefix="(2)">exempts that income from its tax on income; or</section><section prefix="(3)">allows a credit for that income and exempts that income from the withholding requirements for its tax on income.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a nonresident individual who is not otherwise required to file a return shall file a return if the individual:<section prefix="(i)">is not a dependent;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is required to file a federal income tax return; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">has income or losses derived from a business, occupation, profession, or trade carried on in this State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A nonresident individual is not required to file a return if:<section prefix="(i)">the individual's only income in this State is wages, as defined in &#xA7; 10-905(f) of this title, that are earned in this State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Comptroller and the state in which the nonresident resides have agreed in writing to allow a reciprocal exemption from tax and withholding for the wages of residents of each state that are earned in the other state.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
