<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-1-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this article the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Admissions and amusement tax" means the tax imposed under Title 4 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Alcoholic beverage tax" means the tax imposed under Title 5 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Boxing and wrestling tax" means the tax imposed under Title 6 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Comptroller" means the Comptroller of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Comptroller", unless expressly provided otherwise, includes:<section prefix="(i)">an employee of the Comptroller acting within the scope of employment; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">an agent or representative of the Comptroller acting within the scope of the Comptroller's authority.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"County" means a county of the State and, unless expressly provided otherwise, Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Department" means the State Department of Assessments and Taxation.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Financial institution franchise tax" means the tax imposed under Title 8, Subtitle 2 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Income tax" means the tax imposed under Title 10 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Income tax" includes the State income tax and county income tax.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Inheritance tax" means the tax imposed under Title 7, Subtitle 2 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Internal Revenue Code" means Title 26 of the United States Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Maryland estate tax" means the tax imposed under Title 7, Subtitle 3 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Maryland generation-skipping transfer tax" means the tax imposed under Title 7, Subtitle 4 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Motor carrier tax" means the tax imposed under Title 9, Subtitle 2 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Motor fuel tax" means the tax imposed under Title 9, Subtitle 3 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Person" means an individual, receiver, trustee, guardian, personal representative, fiduciary, or representative of any kind and any partnership, firm, association, corporation, or other entity.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Person", unless expressly provided otherwise, does not include a governmental entity or a unit or instrumentality of a governmental entity.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Property" means real property and personal property.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Public service company franchise tax" means the tax imposed under Title 8, Subtitle 4 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Sales and use tax" means the tax imposed under Title 11 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Sales and use tax" includes the tax imposed on the use of certain electricity under &#xA7; 11-1A-01 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Sales and use tax" includes the hotel surcharge imposed under &#xA7; 11-102(b) of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Savings and loan association franchise tax" means the tax imposed under Title 8, Subtitle 3 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">"State" means:<section prefix="(1)">a state, possession, territory, or commonwealth of the United States; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the District of Columbia.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(v)">Repealed.</section>
    <section prefix="(w)">"Tobacco tax" means the tax imposed under Title 12 of this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
