<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-906" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-13-906</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "register" means the register of wills of a county.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a person is required to pay inheritance tax the payment of which would reduce the Maryland estate tax imposed on an estate and would entitle the estate to a Maryland estate tax refund, on the written request of the personal representative of the estate, the Comptroller may pay directly to the register, to be applied against the inheritance tax, any Maryland estate tax refund to which the estate would be entitled as a result of the payment of the inheritance tax.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a person becomes entitled to an inheritance tax refund the payment of which would result in an increase in the Maryland estate tax imposed on an estate, on the written request of the person making a claim for the inheritance tax refund or if a claim for an inheritance tax refund has not been made, the register may pay the inheritance tax refund directly to the Comptroller to be applied against any unpaid Maryland estate tax or additional Maryland estate tax that would become due as a result of the inheritance tax refund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a payment from the Comptroller to the register or from the register to the Comptroller under subsection (b) of this section does not discharge a person's tax liability in its entirety, the person shall pay any remaining unpaid inheritance tax to the register or any remaining unpaid Maryland estate tax to the Comptroller.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Payment by the Comptroller to the register or by the register to the Comptroller under subsection (b) of this section shall satisfy the obligation of the register or Comptroller to pay a refund to the extent of the payment.</section>
  </text>
</law>
