<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-402" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-10-402</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In computing Maryland taxable income, a corporation shall allocate Maryland modified income derived from or reasonably attributable to its trade or business in this State in the following manner:<section prefix="(1)">if a corporation carries on its trade or business wholly within the State, the corporation shall allocate to the State all of the Maryland modified income of the corporation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">if a corporation carries on its trade or business in and out of the State, the corporation shall allocate to the State the part of the corporation's Maryland modified income that is derived from or reasonably attributable to the part of its trade or business carried on in the State, in the manner required in subsection (b), (c), or (d) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (c) or (d) of this section, the part of the corporation's Maryland modified income derived from or reasonably attributable to trade or business carried on in the State may be determined by separate accounting if practicable.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If in any taxable year a corporation is permitted or required to use the separate accounting method in determining all or a portion of its Maryland taxable income, the portion that is separately accounted for to Maryland shall be taxable whether or not the Maryland modified income of the corporation for the taxable year is zero or less.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, if the trade or business is a unitary business, the part of the corporation's Maryland modified income derived from or reasonably attributable to trade or business carried on in the State shall be determined using a 3-factor apportionment fraction:<section prefix="(i)">the numerator of which is the sum of the property factor, the payroll factor, and twice the sales factor; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the denominator of which is 4.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this paragraph:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a manufacturing corporation carries on its trade or business in and out of the State and the trade or business is a unitary business, the part of the corporation's Maryland modified income derived from or reasonably attributable to trade or business carried on in the State shall be determined using a single sales factor apportionment formula, by multiplying its Maryland modified income by 100% of the sales factor.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">In filing its tax return for each year, a manufacturing corporation shall certify that the NAICS Code reported on its Maryland return is consistent with that reported to other government agencies.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">If the Comptroller determines that a corporation has submitted information that incorrectly classifies the corporation as a manufacturing corporation under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the Comptroller shall reclassify the corporation in an appropriate manner.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The Comptroller, in consultation with the Department of Business and Economic Development, shall adopt regulations necessary to carry out the provisions of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">As part of its tax return for a taxable year beginning after December 31, 2005, but before January 1, 2011, each manufacturing corporation that has more than 25 employees and apportions its income under this paragraph shall submit a report, in the form that the Comptroller requires by regulation, that describes for each taxable year as of the last day of the taxable year the following:</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">On or before March 1, 2009, and March 1 of each year thereafter, and notwithstanding any confidentiality requirements, the Comptroller shall prepare and submit to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly, a comprehensive report on the use of single sales factor apportionment by manufacturing corporations that provides, at a minimum:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The property factor under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall include:<section prefix="(i)">rented and owned real property; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">tangible personal property located in the State and used in the trade or business.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">To reflect clearly the income allocable to Maryland, the Comptroller may alter, if circumstances warrant, the methods under subsections (b) and (c) of this section, including:<section prefix="(1)">the use of the separate accounting method;</section><section prefix="(2)">the use of the 3-factor double weighted sales factor formula method or the single sales factor formula method;</section><section prefix="(3)">the weight of any factor in the 3-factor formula;</section><section prefix="(4)">the valuation of rented property included in the property factor; and</section><section prefix="(5)">the determination of the extent to which tangible personal property is located in the State.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
