<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-912" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-10-912</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, "net proceeds" means the total sales price paid to the transferor less:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Net proceeds" does not include adjustments in favor of the transferor that are disclosed on a settlement statement prepared in connection with the sale or exchange of the property.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Nonresident entity" means an entity that:<section prefix="(i)">is not formed under the laws of the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is not qualified by or registered with the Department of Assessments and Taxation to do business in the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Resident entity" means an entity that:<section prefix="(i)">is formed under the laws of the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">is formed under the laws of another state and is qualified by or registered with the Department of Assessments and Taxation to do business in the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Total payment" means the net proceeds of a sale actually paid to a transferor, including the fair market value of any property transferred to the transferor.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Transfer pursuant to a deed in lieu of foreclosure" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a transfer by the owner of the property to:</section><section prefix="(ii)">a transfer by any of the persons described in item (i) of this paragraph to a subsequent purchaser for value.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Transfer pursuant to a foreclosure of a mortgage, deed of trust, or other lien instrument" includes:<section prefix="(i)">with respect to the foreclosure of a mortgage:</section><section prefix="(ii)">with respect to the foreclosure of a deed of trust:</section><section prefix="(iii)">with respect to the foreclosure of any other lien instrument:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For every deed or other instrument of writing that effects a change of ownership on the assessment books under the Tax - Property Article and for which a payment is required under subsection (c) of this section, the total payment shall be described on the form that the Comptroller specifies by regulation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The form required under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be signed under oath by:<section prefix="(i)">the transferor of the property;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an agent of the transferor; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the real property reporting person, as defined under &#xA7; 6045 of the Internal Revenue Code.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, in a sale or exchange of real property and associated tangible personal property owned by a nonresident or nonresident entity, the deed or other instrument of writing that effects a change of ownership on the assessment books under the Tax - Property Article may not be recorded with the clerk of the circuit court for a county or filed with the Department of Assessments and Taxation unless payment is made to the clerk of the circuit court for a county or the Department of Assessments and Taxation in an amount equal to:<section prefix="(1)">the sum of the rate of the tax imposed under &#xA7; 10-106.1 of this title and the top marginal State income tax rate for individuals under &#xA7; 10-105(a) of this title, applied to the total payment to a nonresident; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the rate of the tax for a corporation under &#xA7; 10-105(b) of this title of the total payment to a nonresident entity.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Subsection (c) of this section does not apply when:<section prefix="(1)">a certification under penalties of perjury that the transferor is a resident of the State or is a resident entity is provided by each transferor in:<section prefix="(i)">the recitals or the acknowledgment of the deed or other instrument of writing transferring the property to the transferee; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an affidavit signed by the transferor or by an agent of the transferor that accompanies and is recorded with the deed or other instrument of writing transferring the property;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the transferor presents to the clerk of the circuit court for a county or the Department of Assessments and Taxation a certificate issued by the Comptroller stating that:<section prefix="(i)">no tax is due from that transferor in connection with that sale or exchange of property;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a reduced amount of tax is due from that transferor in connection with that sale or exchange of property and stating the reduced amount that should be collected by the clerk of the circuit court for a county or the Department of Assessments and Taxation before recordation or filing; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the transferor has satisfied the transferor's tax liability described in subsection (c) of this section or has provided adequate security to cover such liability;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">the property transfer is:<section prefix="(i)">a transfer pursuant to a foreclosure of a mortgage, deed of trust, or other lien instrument; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a transfer pursuant to a deed in lieu of foreclosure;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">the property is transferred by the United States, the State, or a unit or political subdivision of the State;</section><section prefix="(5)">a certification under penalties of perjury that the property being transferred is the transferor's principal residence is provided by each transferor in:<section prefix="(i)">the recitals or the acknowledgment of the deed or other instrument of writing transferring the property to the transferee; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an affidavit signed by the transferor or by an agent of the transferor that accompanies and is recorded with the deed or other instrument of writing transferring the property; or</section></section><section prefix="(6)">the property is transferred pursuant to a deed or other instrument of writing that includes a statement of consideration required by &#xA7; 12-104 of the Tax - Property Article indicating that the consideration payable is zero.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in this section, the amounts described in subsection (c) of this section shall be collected by the clerk of the circuit court for a county or the Department of Assessments and Taxation when the deed or other instrument of writing is presented for recordation or filing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 30 business days after the date the amount payable under subsection (c) of this section is paid, the clerk of the circuit court for the county or the Department of Assessments and Taxation shall pay over to the Comptroller the amount collected under subsection (c) of this section as prescribed by the Comptroller.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Amounts collected under subsection (c) of this section and paid over to the Comptroller under subsection (e) of this section shall be deemed to have been paid to the Comptroller on behalf of the transferor from whom the amounts were withheld.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The transferor shall be credited with having paid the amounts for the taxable year in which the transaction that is the subject of the tax occurred.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The transferee, title insurance producer, title insurer, settlement agent, closing attorney, lending institution, and real estate agent or broker in any transaction subject to this section are not liable for any amounts required to be collected and paid over to the Comptroller under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">This section does not:<section prefix="(1)">impose any tax on a transferor or affect any liability of the transferor for any tax; or</section><section prefix="(2)">prohibit the Comptroller from collecting any taxes due from a transferor in any other manner authorized by law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Comptroller shall adopt regulations to administer this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Comptroller's regulations shall establish procedures for the issuance of the certificate referred to in subsection (d)(2) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Comptroller's regulations shall establish a procedure by which a transferor may apply for an early refund of the tax collected under this section if the transferor establishes that no tax will be owed or less tax than collected will be owed.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
