<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-727" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-10-727</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL JUNE 30, 2018 PER CHAPTER 566 OF 2011 //<section prefix="(a)"><section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section><section prefix="(2)">"Administration" means the Maryland Energy Administration.</section><section prefix="(3)">"Bio-heating oil" means a heating oil with a blend of at least 5% biodiesel:<section prefix="(i)">derived from the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency-approved feedstocks; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">accepted under 42 U.S.C. 7545(o) as per the U.S. EPA Renewable Fuel Standard 2 (RFS2) and the accompanying regulations under 40 C.F.R. Part 80 for diesel fuel replacement.</section></section></section><section prefix="(b)">An individual or corporation that receives an initial credit certificate under subsection (d) of this section from the Administration may claim a credit against the State income tax for a taxable year in an amount equal to 3 cents for each gallon of bio-heating oil purchased for space or water heating.</section><section prefix="(c)"><section prefix="(1)">For any taxable year, the credit allowed under this section may not exceed the lesser of:<section prefix="(i)">$500; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the State income tax for that taxable year.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The unused amount of the credit for any taxable year may not be carried over to any other taxable year.</section></section><section prefix="(d)"><section prefix="(1)">On application by a taxpayer, the Maryland Energy Administration shall issue an initial credit certificate for the number of gallons of bio-heating oil purchased by the taxpayer for space or water heating.</section><section prefix="(2)">The initial credit certificate issued under this subsection shall state the maximum amount of credit that may be claimed by the taxpayer.</section><section prefix="(3)">On January 1, 2009, and each year thereafter, the Administration shall provide to the Comptroller a list of all taxpayers in the prior tax year that have been issued an initial credit certificate and shall specify for each taxpayer the maximum amount of credit allowed.</section><section prefix="(4)">The Maryland Energy Administration shall adopt regulations to administer the initial credit certificate required under this subsection.</section></section></text>
</law>
