<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-10-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Applicable tax base" means the portion of the income of an investment conduit or a special exempt entity on which a tax is imposed under:<section prefix="(1)">&#xA7; 11, &#xA7; 527(b), &#xA7; 528(b), &#xA7; 852(b)(1), &#xA7; 857(b)(1) or (4)(a), or &#xA7; 860G(c)(1) of the Internal Revenue Code; or</section><section prefix="(2)">any other section of the Internal Revenue Code that the Comptroller determines by regulation to impose an entity level income tax on an entity that the Comptroller determines to be:<section prefix="(i)">an investment conduit under subsection (h)(2) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a special exempt entity under subsection (m)(2) of this section.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Corporation" includes an association or joint-stock company.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"County income tax" means the county tax on income authorized in &#xA7; 10-103 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Federal adjusted gross income" means:<section prefix="(1)">for an individual other than a fiduciary, the individual's adjusted gross income as determined under the Internal Revenue Code;</section><section prefix="(2)">for a fiduciary other than one described in item (3) of this subsection, the fiduciary's taxable income, as determined under the Internal Revenue Code, increased by the amount allowed to the fiduciary as a deduction for a personal exemption under &#xA7; 642(b) of the Internal Revenue Code; or</section><section prefix="(3)">for a fiduciary exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 408(e)(1) or &#xA7; 501 of the Internal Revenue Code, the fiduciary's unrelated business taxable income as defined under &#xA7; 512 of the Internal Revenue Code.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Fiduciary" means a person holding the legal title to property for the use and benefit of another person.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Fiduciary" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">an agent holding custody or possession of property that the principal of the agent owns; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a guardian, as defined in &#xA7; 13-101 of the Estates and Trusts Article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Individual" means, unless expressly provided otherwise, a natural person or a fiduciary.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Investment conduit" means:<section prefix="(1)">any of the following entities described in the Internal Revenue Code:<section prefix="(i)">a regulated investment company;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a real estate investment trust; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a real estate mortgage investment conduit; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">any other entity that the Comptroller determines by regulation to enjoy a status under the Internal Revenue Code pursuant to which the entity is not generally subject to income tax at the entity level so long as substantially all of its profits are distributed to the holders of equity interests in the entity.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Maryland taxable income" means:<section prefix="(1)">for an individual, Maryland adjusted gross income, less the exemptions and deductions allowed under this title; and</section><section prefix="(2)">for a corporation, Maryland modified income as allocated under this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Nonresident" means an individual who is not a resident.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Resident" means:<section prefix="(i)">an individual, other than a fiduciary, who:</section><section prefix="(ii)">a personal representative of an estate if the decedent was domiciled in this State on the date of the decedent's death; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a fiduciary, other than a personal representative, of a trust if:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Resident" includes, for the part of the taxable year that an individual resides in this State, an individual who:<section prefix="(i)">moves to this State with the intent to be domiciled in this State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">is domiciled in this State and moves outside this State before the last day of the taxable year with the bona fide intention to remain permanently outside of this State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If an individual under paragraph (2)(ii) of this subsection again resides in this State within 6 months after having moved outside this State, there is a rebuttable presumption that the individual did not have a bona fide intention to remain permanently outside this State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"S corporation" means a corporation that elects to be taxed as a small business corporation under Subchapter S of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Special exempt entity" means:<section prefix="(1)">any of the following entities described in the Internal Revenue Code:<section prefix="(i)">a farmers' cooperative;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a political organization; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a homeowners association; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">any other entity not described in &#xA7; 10-104(2) of this subtitle that the Comptroller determines by regulation to be exempt from federal income tax on all or some part of its income.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"State income tax" means the State tax on income imposed under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Taxable year" means:<section prefix="(i)">the period for which Maryland taxable income is computed under this title; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the annual accounting period defined in &#xA7; 441 of the Internal Revenue Code.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Taxable year" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a calendar year ending on December 31, as defined in &#xA7; 441 of the Internal Revenue Code;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a fiscal year ending on the last day of a month other than December, as defined in &#xA7; 441 of the Internal Revenue Code;</section><section prefix="(iii)">if a return is made for a period of less than 1 year, the period for which the return is made; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">if an election is made under &#xA7; 441(f) of the Internal Revenue Code, the period for which a return is made.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
