<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-407" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-11-407</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, on or after July 1, 1993, the Comptroller may not:<section prefix="(i)">grant the authority to make direct payment, to the Comptroller, of sales and use tax due on purchases by a vendor; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">issue permits evidencing such authority.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Comptroller may continue to administer direct payment permits issued to vendors before July 1, 1993.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Comptroller may:<section prefix="(i)">issue the permit subject to reasonable and necessary terms and conditions; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">revoke the direct payment permit at any time for cause.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A vendor who receives evidence that the buyer has a direct payment permit is discharged from:<section prefix="(1)">the duty to collect the sales and use tax; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the liability for the sales and use tax.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Comptroller may enter into an effective rate agreement with a vendor licensed under Subtitle 7 of this title to allow the vendor to compute its sales and use tax liability for purchases made by the vendor for a specific period using a predetermined agreed-upon effective rate, eliminating the need to determine the liability on a transaction-by-transaction basis.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An effective rate agreement:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Comptroller may void an effective rate agreement entered into under this subsection if the vendor's operations significantly change during the term of the agreement.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the Comptroller enters into an effective rate agreement with a vendor under this subsection, the Comptroller may issue a direct payment permit authorizing the vendor to make direct payment, to the Comptroller, of the sales and use tax due on purchases by that vendor that are subject to the effective rate agreement.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A direct payment permit issued under this paragraph remains in effect as long as the effective rate agreement is in effect.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
