<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-210" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-10-210</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The amounts under this section are subtracted from the federal adjusted gross income of a nonresident to determine Maryland adjusted gross income.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To the extent included in federal adjusted gross income, the subtraction under subsection (a) of this section includes all income other than:<section prefix="(1)">income derived from real or tangible personal property located in the State, whether the income is derived directly or from a fiduciary;</section><section prefix="(2)">income derived from:<section prefix="(i)">a business that is wholly carried on in the State and in which the individual is a partner, shareholder of an S corporation, member of a limited liability company as defined under Title 4A of the Corporations and Associations Article, but only to the extent the company is taxable as a partnership under &#xA7; 761 of the Internal Revenue Code, or proprietor; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an occupation, profession, or trade that is wholly carried on in the State;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">the part, allocable to the State under &#xA7; 10-401 of this title, of income derived from:<section prefix="(i)">a business that is carried on both in and out of the State and of which the individual is a partner, shareholder of an S corporation, member of a limited liability company as defined under Title 4A of the Corporations and Associations Article, but only to the extent the company is taxable as a partnership under &#xA7; 761 of the Internal Revenue Code, or proprietor; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an occupation, profession, or trade that is carried on both in and out of the State; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">income from Maryland State Lottery prizes or winnings from any other wagering, as defined in &#xA7; 10-905(e) of this title, in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To the extent not otherwise included under subsection (b) of this section, the subtraction under subsection (a) of this section includes the amounts allowed to be subtracted for residents under &#xA7; 10-207 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Subject to &#xA7; 10-219 of this subtitle, the subtraction under subsection (a) of this section includes the amounts allowed to be subtracted for residents under &#xA7; 10-208 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The subtraction under subsection (a) of this section includes income derived from wages, as defined in &#xA7; 10-905(f) of this title, that are earned in this State if the Comptroller and the state in which the nonresident resides have agreed in writing to allow a reciprocal exemption from tax and withholding for the wages of residents of each state that are earned in the other state.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The subtraction under subsection (a) of this section includes income derived from wages that are earned in the State by a nonresident rendering police, fire, rescue, or emergency services in an area covered under a state of emergency declared by the Governor under &#xA7; 14-107 of the Public Safety Article if the wages are paid by:<section prefix="(1)">a nonprofit organization not registered to do business in the State and not otherwise doing business in the State; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a state, county, or political subdivision of a state, other than the State of Maryland.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
