<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-8-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Company" means an association, corporation, or joint-stock company.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Financial institution" means:<section prefix="(i)">a credit company;</section><section prefix="(ii)">except as provided in paragraph (2)(i) of this subsection, a finance company;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an international banking facility;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a loan company;</section><section prefix="(v)">a mortgage company;</section><section prefix="(vi)">a safe-deposit company; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">a savings and loan association.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Financial institution" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">a finance company that makes loans only to farmers for agricultural purposes;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a company licensed under the federal Small Business Investment Act of 1958;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a corporation that elects to be taxed as a small business corporation under Subchapter S of the Internal Revenue Code;</section><section prefix="(iv)">an entity that is a real estate mortgage investment conduit as defined in the Internal Revenue Code;</section><section prefix="(v)">a limited liability company; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">a commercial bank, savings bank, trust company, or company that substantially competes with national banks in the State.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Savings and loan association" means:<section prefix="(1)">a savings and loan association that:<section prefix="(i)">is organized under the laws of this State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is organized under the laws of another state and is admitted to do business in this State; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">is organized under the laws of the United States and has an office in this State; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">a savings bank chartered by the Federal Home Loan Bank Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Savings bank" means a company or other institution that is organized to receive deposits of money and pay interest on the deposits.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Savings bank" does not include a bank with capital stock.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
