<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-901" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-13-901</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A claim for refund may be filed with the tax collector who collects the tax, fee, or charge by a claimant who:<section prefix="(1)">erroneously pays to the State a greater amount of tax, fee, charge, interest, or penalty than is properly and legally payable;</section><section prefix="(2)">pays to the State a tax, fee, charge, interest, or penalty that is erroneously, illegally, or wrongfully assessed or collected in any manner; or</section><section prefix="(3)">pays a tax qualifying for refund under subsections (b) through (h) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A claim for refund of alcoholic beverage tax may be filed by a claimant who:<section prefix="(1)">buys alcoholic beverages that are exempt under &#xA7; 5-104(b) of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">discontinues an alcoholic beverage business;</section><section prefix="(3)">discontinues the sale and delivery in the State of alcoholic beverages in certain container sizes; or</section><section prefix="(4)">holds alcoholic beverages for sale that:<section prefix="(i)">are condemned by an authorized official; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the claim is $250 or more, are lost, rendered unmarketable, or destroyed in the State due to fire, flood, or other disaster, or due to vandalism or malicious mischief, except loss due to theft.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A claim for refund of income tax may be filed by a claimant whose Maryland taxable income is decreased as a result of a federal contract renegotiation under &#xA7; 1481 of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A claim for refund of income tax under this subsection or subsection (a) of this section may be filed:<section prefix="(i)">by the claimant; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">on behalf of the claimant, by a person allowed to file a return under &#xA7; 10-808 of this article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A claim for refund of Maryland estate tax or Maryland generation-skipping transfer tax may be filed by a claimant required to pay the tax if:<section prefix="(1)">the Maryland estate tax is decreased as a result of:<section prefix="(i)">a decrease in the federal estate tax on the estate; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an inheritance tax payment made after a Maryland estate tax payment; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the Maryland generation-skipping transfer tax is decreased as a result of a decrease in the federal generation-skipping transfer tax on the generation-skipping transfer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A claim for refund of motor carrier tax may be filed by a claimant who has excess motor carrier tax credit, if:<section prefix="(1)">the claimant has provided the security required for a motor carrier under &#xA7; 13-825 of this title; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the Comptroller has audited the records of the claimant.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, a claim for refund of motor fuel tax may be filed by a claimant who pays the tax on:<section prefix="(i)">aviation fuel, as defined in &#xA7; 9-101 of this article, that is:</section><section prefix="(ii)">motor fuel, as defined in &#xA7; 9-101 of this article, that:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A refund based on a claim under paragraph (1)(ii)4 of this subsection may not exceed the following percentages of the motor fuel tax paid:<section prefix="(i)">35% for a concrete mixing vehicle or concrete pump truck;</section><section prefix="(ii)">55% for farm equipment, registered as a vehicle for highway use, that is designed or adapted solely and used exclusively for bulk spreading of agriculture liming materials, chemicals, or fertilizers;</section><section prefix="(iii)">10% for a motor fuel delivery vehicle;</section><section prefix="(iv)">15% for a solid waste compacting vehicle; and</section><section prefix="(v)">80% for a well-drilling vehicle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A person may not make a claim for a refund of motor fuel tax under paragraph (1)(ii)1B of this subsection for motor fuel used to operate a farm truck under the provisions of &#xA7; 8-602(c) of the Transportation Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A claim for refund of sales and use tax may be filed by a claimant who:<section prefix="(1)">pays the tax on a sale exempt under &#xA7; 11-216 of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">refunds the tax to a buyer in a canceled or rescinded sale under &#xA7; 11-403(c) of this article;</section><section prefix="(3)">pays the tax in a canceled or rescinded sale for which the vendor refuses to refund the tax as required under &#xA7; 11-403(c) of this article; or</section><section prefix="(4)">pays the tax under &#xA7; 11-408(c) of this article on a cash sale or sale for use that is not a retail sale.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A claim for refund of tobacco tax may be filed by a claimant who buys tobacco tax stamps that:<section prefix="(1)">are affixed erroneously to anything other than a package of cigarettes;</section><section prefix="(2)">are affixed to a package of unsalable cigarettes;</section><section prefix="(3)">are canceled by the Comptroller;</section><section prefix="(4)">if the claim is $250 or more, are lost or destroyed in the State due to fire, flood, or other disaster, vandalism, or malicious mischief, except loss due to theft; or</section><section prefix="(5)">mutilated or damaged, whether or not affixed to a package of cigarettes.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
