<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-10-720</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>720</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Administration" means the Maryland Energy Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraphs (ii) and (iii) of this paragraph, "qualified energy resources" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 45(c)(1) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Qualified energy resources" includes any nonhazardous waste material that is segregated from other waste materials and is derived from:<section prefix="1.">any of the following forest-related resources, not including old-growth timber:</section><section prefix="2.">waste pallets, crates, and dunnage and landscape or right-of-way trimmings; or</section><section prefix="3.">agricultural sources, including, but not limited to, orchard tree crops, vineyard, grain, legumes, sugar, and other crop by-products or residues.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Qualified energy resources" includes methane gas or other combustible gases resulting from the decomposition of organic materials from an agricultural operation, or from a landfill or wastewater treatment plant using one or a combination of the following processes:<section prefix="1.">anaerobic decomposition; or</section><section prefix="2.">thermal decomposition.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Qualified Maryland facility" means a facility located in the State that:<section prefix="(i)">primarily uses qualified energy resources to produce electricity and is originally placed in service on or after January 1, 2006, but before January 1, 2016; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">produces electricity from a qualified energy resource that is co-fired with coal and initially begins co-firing a qualified energy resource on or after January 1, 2006, but before January 1, 2016, regardless of when the original facility was placed in service.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, an individual or corporation that receives an initial credit certificate from the Administration may claim a credit against the State income tax for a taxable year in an amount equal to 0.85 cents for each kilowatt hour of electricity:<section prefix="(i)">produced by the individual or corporation from qualified energy resources at a qualified Maryland facility during the 5-year period specified in the initial credit certificate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">sold by the individual or corporation to a person other than a related person, within the meaning of &#xA7; 45 of the Internal Revenue Code, during the taxable year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the electricity is produced from a qualified energy resource that is co-fired at a facility that produces electricity from coal, the credit is 0.5 cents for each kilowatt hour of electricity produced from the qualified energy resource instead of 0.85 cents.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The annual tax credit under this subsection may not exceed one-fifth of the maximum amount of credit stated in the initial credit certificate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of this subsection, on application by a taxpayer, the Administration shall issue an initial credit certificate if the taxpayer has demonstrated that the taxpayer will within the next 12 months produce electricity from qualified energy resources at a qualified Maryland facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The initial credit certificate issued under this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">state the maximum amount of credit that may be claimed by the taxpayer for electricity produced over a 5-year period;</section><section prefix="(ii)">state the earliest tax year for which the credit may be claimed; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">state the 5-year period during which electricity produced from qualified energy resources at the qualified Maryland facility qualifies for the credit.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The maximum amount of credit stated in the initial credit certificate shall, for an energy producer, be in an amount equal to the lesser of:<section prefix="(i)">the product of multiplying 5 times the taxpayer's estimated annual tax credit, based on estimated annual energy production, as certified by the Administration; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">$2,500,000.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Administration may not issue initial credit certificates for maximum credit amounts in the aggregate totaling more than $25,000,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Administration shall approve all applications that qualify for an initial credit certificate under this subsection on a first-come, first-served basis.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">If a taxpayer over a 3-year period does not claim on average at least 10% of the maximum credit amount stated in the initial credit certificate, the Administration at its discretion may cancel an amount of the taxpayer's initial credit certificate equal to the product of multiplying:<section prefix="(i)">the amount of the credit on average that was not claimed over the 3-year period; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the remaining number of tax years that the taxpayer is eligible to take the credit.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">An applicant for an initial credit certificate or a taxpayer whose credits have been canceled under paragraph (6) of this subsection, may appeal a decision by the Administration to the Office of Administrative Hearings in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The Administration may not issue an initial credit certificate after December 31, 2015.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">The Administration may not issue initial credit certificates for credit amounts less than $1,000.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the credit allowed under this section in any taxable year exceeds the State income tax otherwise payable by the corporation or individual for that taxable year, the corporation or the individual may claim a refund in the amount of the excess.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On January 1, 2007, and each year thereafter, the Administration shall provide to the Comptroller a list of all taxpayers in the prior tax year that have been issued an initial credit certificate and shall specify for each taxpayer the earliest tax year for which the credit may be claimed and the maximum amount of credit allowed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">On or before October 1, 2007, and each year thereafter, the Comptroller and the Administration jointly shall submit to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly a written report regarding:<section prefix="1.">the number of certifications and taxpayers claiming the credit under this section;</section><section prefix="2.">the name and physical location of each taxpayer issued an initial credit certificate;</section><section prefix="3.">the maximum credit amount approved for each taxpayer;</section><section prefix="4.">the geographical distribution of the credits claimed; and</section><section prefix="5.">any other available information the Administration determines to be meaningful and appropriate.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Comptroller shall ensure that the information is presented and classified in a manner consistent with the confidentiality of tax return information.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
