<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-10-729</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>729</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Administration" means the Maryland Energy Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Qualified electric vehicle recharging equipment" means property used for the recharging of motor vehicles propelled by electricity that meets the definition of "qualified alternative fuel vehicle refueling property" in &#xA7; 30C of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For tax years 2011 through 2013 only, an individual or corporation that receives an initial credit certificate under subsection (d) of this section from the Administration may claim a credit against the State income tax for a taxable year in an amount equal to 20% of the cost of any qualified electric vehicle recharging equipment placed in service by the taxpayer during the taxable year.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For any taxable year, the credit allowed under this section may not exceed the lesser of:<section prefix="(i)">$400 for each individual recharging system; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the State income tax for that taxable year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The unused amount of the credit for any taxable year may not be carried over to any other taxable year.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On application by a taxpayer, the Administration shall issue an initial credit certificate in an amount equal to 20% of the estimated cost of the qualified electric vehicle recharging equipment to be placed in service in the State by the taxpayer during the taxable year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The initial credit certificate issued under this subsection shall state the maximum amount of credit that may be claimed by the taxpayer.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The credit allowed under this section is limited to the acquisition of:<section prefix="(i)">1 recharging system per individual; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">30 recharging systems per business entity.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Administration may issue total credit certificates not to exceed the following amounts:<section prefix="(i)">for tax year 2011, $400,000;</section><section prefix="(ii)">for tax year 2012, $500,000; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">for tax year 2013, $600,000.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">On January 1, 2012, and each year the credit is authorized, the Administration shall provide to the Comptroller a list of all taxpayers in the prior tax year that have been issued an initial credit certificate and shall specify for each taxpayer the maximum amount of credit allowed.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Administration may adopt regulations to administer the initial credit certificate required under this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The regulations adopted by the Administration may include a further limit on the maximum amount of credit that may be claimed by the taxpayer.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
