<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-908" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-10-908</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An employer shall withhold from the wages of an individual the amount indicated in the income tax withholding tables or income tax percentage withholding schedules that the Comptroller prepares.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A payor that is a fiduciary shall withhold from each distribution the amount indicated in the income tax withholding tables or income tax percentage withholding schedules that the Comptroller prepares.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A payor shall withhold the amount from an annuity, sick pay, or retirement distribution that the payee requests.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A payor shall withhold from a payment subject to withholding of winnings derived from wagering:<section prefix="(1)">if the payee is a resident, a rate equal to the sum of 3.0% and the top marginal State income tax rate for individuals under &#xA7; 10-105(a) of this title, applied to the payment; and</section><section prefix="(2)">if the payee is a nonresident, a rate equal to the sum of the rate of the tax imposed under &#xA7; 10-106.1 of this title and the top marginal State income tax rate for individuals under &#xA7; 10-105(a) of this title, applied to the payment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board of Trustees of the State Retirement and Pension System shall withhold from a payment of a death benefit to a resident payee the sum of:<section prefix="(1)">4.75% of the payment; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the county income tax rate applied to the payment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If a payment to a resident payee is a designated distribution that is an eligible rollover distribution within the meaning of &#xA7; 3405(c) of the Internal Revenue Code and the payment is subject to mandatory withholding of federal income tax, the payor shall withhold from the payment an amount equal to 7.75% of the payment.</section>
  </text>
</law>
