<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-911" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-10-911</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each employer or payor required under &#xA7; 10-906 of this subtitle to withhold income tax for an employee or a person who receives a payment subject to withholding shall prepare a statement that shows for the previous calendar year:<section prefix="(1)">the name of the employer or payor;</section><section prefix="(2)">the name of the employee or person who receives the payment subject to withholding;</section><section prefix="(3)">the total amount that the employer paid to the employee as wages or the total amount that the payor has paid to the person;</section><section prefix="(4)">the total amount of tips that the employee reported;</section><section prefix="(5)">the total amount of income tax that has been withheld under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(6)">any amount by which income tax required to be withheld on tips exceeds the other net wages paid to the employee; and</section><section prefix="(7)">any other information that the Comptroller requires by regulation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An employer or payor of a payment subject to withholding shall:<section prefix="(1)">provide 2 copies of the statement required under subsection (a) of this section to the employee or person who receives a payment subject to withholding on or before January 31 of each year; and</section><section prefix="(2)">submit 1 copy of the statement to the Comptroller on or before February 28 of each year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, an employer or payor shall submit statements required under subsection (a) of this section on magnetic media or in other machine-readable or electronic format that the Comptroller requires by regulation, if:<section prefix="(i)">the total number of statements of that statement type that the employer or payor is required to submit equals or exceeds 25; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a lower threshold applies for federal income tax purposes.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Comptroller:<section prefix="(i)">shall adopt regulations to provide a process for an employer or payor that is required to submit statements on magnetic media or in other machine-readable or electronic format under paragraph (1) of this subsection to request a waiver from the requirement; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">may waive the requirement that an employer or payor submit statements on magnetic media or in other machine-readable or electronic format under paragraph (1) of this subsection if the Comptroller determines that the requirement will result in undue hardship to the employer or payor.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
