<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="gtg" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-11-408</section_number>
  <catch_line>If a buyer is required under Subtitle 2 of this title or by regulation to provide a vendor with evid...</catch_line>
  <order_by>408</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If a buyer is required under Subtitle 2 of this title or by regulation to provide a vendor with evidence of an exemption, the vendor may not recognize the exemption unless the buyer, before the sale is consummated, provides the vendor with:<section prefix="(1)">evidence that the buyer has an exemption certificate; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the evidence that the Comptroller requires by regulation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, the duty of a vendor to collect the sales and use tax from a buyer is waived if the buyer provides the vendor with a signed resale certificate that:<section prefix="(i)">is in the form that the Comptroller requires by regulation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">states the name and address of the buyer;</section><section prefix="(iii)"><section prefix="1.">provides the Maryland sales and use tax registration number of the buyer; or</section><section prefix="2.">for the sale of an antique or used collectible, provides a sales and use tax registration number of another state and states that the buyer is an out-of-state vendor who does not engage in the business of an out-of-state vendor, as defined in &#xA7; 11-701 of this title; and</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">contains a statement to the effect that the tangible personal property or taxable service is bought for the purpose of resale.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If a buyer provides a resale certificate with a sales and use tax registration number of another state as provided under paragraph (1)(iii)2 of this subsection, the buyer shall also provide a copy of a sales and use tax registration license issued to the buyer from that state.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a buyer is from a state without a sales and use tax, that buyer shall provide a copy of a trader's license from that state or a comparable type of identification.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A vendor may not accept a resale certificate if the vendor knows or should know that the sale is not for the purpose of resale.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A vendor may not accept a resale certificate for a cash, check, or credit card sale if:<section prefix="1.">the taxable price is less than $200; and</section><section prefix="2.">the tangible personal property or taxable service is not delivered by the vendor directly to the buyer's retail place of business.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A vendor shall obtain a resale certificate from a buyer:<section prefix="(i)">before the sale is consummated; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the vendor receives a notice of the Comptroller's intent to assess sales and use tax for failure to obtain a proper resale certificate, within 60 days after the date on which the notice is mailed.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If the vendor fails to obtain the resale certificate as required, the Comptroller's assessment under paragraph (4)(ii) of this subsection is final.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the taxable price is less than $200 for a cash, check, or credit card sale or sale for use that is not a retail sale and the tangible personal property or taxable service is not delivered by the vendor directly to the buyer's retail place of business:<section prefix="(1)">the sales and use tax shall be paid when the sale is made or when the use becomes taxable; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the buyer who pays the sales and use tax may file a claim for a refund with the Comptroller.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
