<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="gtg" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-9-309</section_number>
  <catch_line>Each person who engages in the business of a dealer, distributor, special fuel seller, special fuel ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>309</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each person who engages in the business of a dealer, distributor, special fuel seller, special fuel user, or turbine fuel seller shall keep for 4 years records of motor fuel that the person:<section prefix="(i)">buys in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">receives in the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">sells in the State;</section><section prefix="(iv)">delivers in the State; or</section><section prefix="(v)">uses in the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The records kept under this subsection shall include:<section prefix="(i)">bills of lading;</section><section prefix="(ii)">invoices; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">any other pertinent record that the Comptroller requires to administer the laws that relate to the motor fuel tax.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person required to keep records under subsection (a) of this section shall make the records available for inspection by the Comptroller at any time during business hours.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Comptroller may charge a person for the reasonable travel and other expenses of inspecting records required to be kept under subsection (a) of this section, if:<section prefix="(i)">the Comptroller decides that the inspection is necessary; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the person does not make the records available in this State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a person does not pay charges assessed against the person under this subsection within 30 days after receipt of a bill for the charges, the Comptroller may:<section prefix="(i)">sue to collect the charges; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">cancel the license, if any, of the person in accordance with &#xA7; 9-330 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
