<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="gtg" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-2-107</section_number>
  <catch_line>Authorized employees of the Field Enforcement Bureau of the Comptroller's Office:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>107</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Authorized employees of the Field Enforcement Bureau of the Comptroller's Office:<section prefix="(1)">shall be individuals who are sworn police officers; and</section><section prefix="(2)">have all the powers, duties, and responsibilities of a peace officer for the purpose of enforcing the laws pertaining to:<section prefix="(i)">alcoholic beverage tax;</section><section prefix="(ii)">tobacco tax;</section><section prefix="(iii)">motor fuel tax;</section><section prefix="(iv)">motor carrier tax;</section><section prefix="(v)">motor fuel and lubricants; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">transient vendors within the meaning of Subtitle 20A of Title 17 of the Business Regulation Article.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department of State Police shall help the Field Enforcement Bureau in enforcing the motor carrier tax, motor fuel tax and motor fuel and lubricants laws.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Comptroller shall pay the salaries and expenses of all Department of State Police staff assigned to the Field Enforcement Bureau.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except for the Sheriff, constables and bailiffs of Baltimore County, each law enforcement officer shall enforce the alcoholic beverage tax and tobacco tax laws.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A State's Attorney or other prosecutor may prosecute alleged violations of the alcoholic beverage tax or tobacco tax laws.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Field Enforcement Bureau:<section prefix="(i)">shall advise a State's Attorney and law enforcement officers about enforcement problems; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">otherwise may work cooperatively with law enforcement officers and prosecutors to carry out the duties of the unit.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This subsection does not restrict the appropriation of money by a political subdivision of the State to aid in the enforcement of the alcoholic beverage tax and tobacco tax laws.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each unit of the State government shall cooperate with the Comptroller's Office by making available, on request, any information in the unit's possession as may be of assistance in the administration and enforcement of the motor carrier tax, motor fuel tax, and motor fuel and lubricants laws.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Field Enforcement Bureau shall cooperate with and help the federal government, other states, and local governments and law enforcement personnel of those jurisdictions to enforce the motor carrier tax, motor fuel tax, and motor fuel and lubricants laws.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
