<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-10-210.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>210.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Depreciation" includes any deduction allowed under &#xA7; 179 of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Heavy duty SUV" means a 4-wheeled vehicle that:<section prefix="(i)">is manufactured primarily for use on public streets, roads, and highways;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is rated at more than 6,000 but not more than 14,000 pounds gross vehicle weight; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">would be a passenger automobile as defined in &#xA7; 280F of the Internal Revenue Code if it were rated at 6,000 pounds gross vehicle weight or less.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to the modifications under &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-204 through 10-210 of this subtitle, to determine Maryland adjusted gross income of an individual:<section prefix="(1)">an amount is added to or subtracted from federal adjusted gross income to reflect the determination of the depreciation deduction provided under &#xA7; 167(a) of the Internal Revenue Code and the adjusted basis of property without regard to the additional allowance under &#xA7; 168(k) of the Internal Revenue Code;</section><section prefix="(2)">an amount is added to or subtracted from federal adjusted gross income to determine the net operating loss deduction allowed under &#xA7; 172 of the Internal Revenue Code without regard to an election under &#xA7; 172(b)(1)(H) of the Internal Revenue Code for a carryback period of up to 5 years;</section><section prefix="(3)">an amount is added to or subtracted from federal adjusted gross income to reflect the determination of the maximum aggregate costs that the taxpayer may treat as an expense under &#xA7; 179 of the Internal Revenue Code for any taxable year without regard to any changes made to that section after December 31, 2002:<section prefix="(i)">increasing above $25,000 the dollar limitation set forth in &#xA7; 179(b)(1) of the Internal Revenue Code; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">increasing above $200,000 the phase-out threshold set forth in &#xA7; 179(b)(2) of the Internal Revenue Code;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">an amount is added to or subtracted from federal adjusted gross income to reflect the recognition of income from discharge of indebtedness and the allowance of any deduction with respect to original issue discount without regard to &#xA7; 108(i) of the Internal Revenue Code; and</section><section prefix="(5)">an amount is added to or subtracted from federal adjusted gross income to reflect the determination of the depreciation deduction with respect to any heavy duty SUV as if the heavy duty SUV were subject to the limitations of &#xA7; 280F of the Internal Revenue Code in the same manner as it would be if the vehicle were rated at 6,000 pounds gross vehicle weight or less.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
