<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-11-206</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>206</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Facility for food consumption" does not include parking spaces for vehicles as the sole accommodation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Food" means food for human consumption.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Food" includes the following foods and their products:<section prefix="1.">beverages, including coffee, coffee substitutes, cocoa, fruit juices, and tea;</section><section prefix="2.">condiments;</section><section prefix="3.">eggs;</section><section prefix="4.">fish, meat, and poultry;</section><section prefix="5.">fruit, grain, and vegetables;</section><section prefix="6.">milk, including ice cream; and</section><section prefix="7.">sugar.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Food" does not include:<section prefix="1.">an alcoholic beverage as defined in &#xA7; 5-101 of this article;</section><section prefix="2.">a soft drink or carbonated beverage; or</section><section prefix="3.">candy or confectionery.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Food for immediate consumption" means:<section prefix="(i)">food obtained from a salad, soup, or dessert bar;</section><section prefix="(ii)">party platters;</section><section prefix="(iii)">heated food;</section><section prefix="(iv)">sandwiches suitable for immediate consumption; or</section><section prefix="(v)">ice cream, frozen yogurt, and other frozen desserts, sold in containers of less than 1 pint.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Premises" includes any building, grounds, parking lot, or other area that:<section prefix="(i)">a food vendor owns or controls; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">another person makes available primarily for the use of the patrons of 1 or more food vendors.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Substantial grocery or market business" means a business at which at least 10% of all sales of food are sales of grocery or market food items, not including food normally consumed on the premises even though it is packaged to carry out.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The sales and use tax does not apply to a sale of food stamp eligible food, as defined in 7 U.S.C. &#xA7; 2012, bought with a food coupon issued in accordance with 7 U.S.C. &#xA7; 2016.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the sales and use tax does not apply to a sale of food for consumption off the premises by a food vendor who operates a substantial grocery or market business at the same location where the food is sold.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The exemption under paragraph (1) of this subsection does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">food that the vendor serves for consumption on the premises of the buyer or of a third party; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">food for immediate consumption.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The sales and use tax does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">a sale of food:<section prefix="(i)">to patients in a hospital when the food charge is included in the regular room rate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">by a church or religious organization;</section><section prefix="(iii)">by a school other than an institution of postsecondary education, including sales at a school by a food concessionaire that is under contract with the school or with its designated contract agent, but not including sales at events that are not sponsored by the school or are not educationally related;</section><section prefix="(iv)">to students at an institution of postsecondary education if the food charge is for a meal plan or is included in the regular charge for room and board; or</section><section prefix="(v)">by a nonprofit food vendor if there are no facilities for food consumption on the premises, unless the food is sold within an enclosure for which a charge is made for admission;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">if the proceeds of the sale are used to support a bona fide nationally organized and recognized organization of veterans of the armed forces of the United States or auxiliary of the organization or 1 of its units, a sale of food or meals for consumption only on the premises, served by the organization or auxiliary;</section><section prefix="(3)">if the proceeds of the sale are used to support a volunteer fire company or department or its auxiliary or a volunteer ambulance company or rescue squad or its auxiliary, a sale of food served by the company, department, squad, or auxiliary; or</section><section prefix="(4)">a sale of food, bottled water, soft drink or carbonated beverage, or candy or confectionery by a nonprofit food vendor at a youth sporting event or 4-H youth event for individuals under the age of 18 years if there are no facilities for food consumption on the premises, unless the sale is within an enclosure for which a charge is made for admission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The sales and use tax does not apply to a sale of food or any beverage in a vehicle that is being operated in the State while in the course of interstate commerce.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The sales and use tax does not apply to a sale for consumption off the premises of:<section prefix="(1)">crabs; or</section><section prefix="(2)">seafood that is not prepared for immediate consumption.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "snack food" means:<section prefix="(i)">potato chips and sticks;</section><section prefix="(ii)">corn chips;</section><section prefix="(iii)">pretzels;</section><section prefix="(iv)">cheese puffs and curls;</section><section prefix="(v)">pork rinds;</section><section prefix="(vi)">extruded pretzels and chips;</section><section prefix="(vii)">popped popcorn;</section><section prefix="(viii)">nuts and edible seeds; or</section><section prefix="(ix)">snack mixtures that contain any one or more of the foods listed in items (i) through (viii) of this paragraph.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The sales and use tax does not apply to the sale of snack food through a vending machine.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The sales and use tax does not apply to the sale through a vending machine of milk, fresh fruit, fresh vegetables, or yogurt.</section>
  </text>
</law>
