<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-9-319</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>319</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To qualify for a Class "A" license, an applicant shall be:<section prefix="(1)">an entity that:<section prefix="(i)">blends or refines gasoline;</section><section prefix="(ii)">owns or controls and dedicates at least 1 million gallons of storage capacity in the State to gasoline, other than aviation gasoline, and to special fuel; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">keeps in the State an inventory of at least 500,000 gallons of that gasoline and special fuel; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">an entity that is wholly owned by one or more entities that would otherwise qualify as a Class "A" licensee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To qualify for a Class "B" license, an applicant shall be an entity that is licensed by the state from which the gasoline is to be exported for importation into this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To qualify for a Class "C" license, an applicant shall be an entity that:<section prefix="(1)">is based in another state;</section><section prefix="(2)">is licensed by the state to which that gasoline is to be exported;</section><section prefix="(3)">has no sales in this State; and</section><section prefix="(4)">does not own, operate or utilize in this State a facility that can store or dispense motor fuel.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">To qualify for a Class "D" license, an applicant shall be an entity that:<section prefix="(1)">is organized under the laws of the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">does not blend or refine gasoline;</section><section prefix="(3)">has, in this State, excluding retail service stations, fixed storage tanks for at least 200,000 gallons of motor fuel other than aviation fuel;</section><section prefix="(4)">keeps an inventory of motor fuel in the State; and</section><section prefix="(5)">annually sells in the State:<section prefix="(i)">at least 1 million gallons of gasoline to persons who are not licensed dealers; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">of the total gallons of motor fuel acquired, at least 50% in gasoline.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">To qualify for a Class "G-Temporary" license, an applicant shall be an entity that:<section prefix="(1)">is not entitled to any other class of license for dealers;</section><section prefix="(2)">has a specific federal contract to supply gasoline to the United States or a unit of the United States that is entitled to an exemption under &#xA7; 9-304 of this subtitle or to a refund under &#xA7; 13-901(f)(1)(ii)2.A of this article; and</section><section prefix="(3)">is licensed by the state from which that gasoline is to be exported, if any part is to be imported into this State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">To qualify for a Class "W" license, an applicant shall be an entity that is not entitled to any other class of license.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">To qualify for an exemption certificate, an applicant:<section prefix="(1)">shall hold a Class "F", "S", or "U" license;</section><section prefix="(2)">shall be an entity that is exempt from the motor fuel tax under this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(3)">may not own or operate on public highways in this State a vehicle that is propelled by special fuel.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">If an applicant is organized under the laws of another state or country, the applicant first shall qualify to do business in this State under the appropriate provisions of the Corporations and Associations Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
