<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="gtg" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-7-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>The inheritance tax does not apply to the receipt of an annuity or other payment under a public or p...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The inheritance tax does not apply to the receipt of an annuity or other payment under a public or private employees' pension or benefit plan if the annuity or other payment is not taxable for federal estate tax purposes.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Child" includes a stepchild or former stepchild.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Parent" includes a stepparent or former stepparent.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">"Surviving spouse" means a surviving spouse who has not remarried.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The inheritance tax does not apply to the receipt of property that passes from a decedent to or for the use of:<section prefix="(i)">a grandparent of the decedent;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a parent of the decedent;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a spouse of the decedent;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a child of the decedent or a lineal descendant of a child of the decedent;</section><section prefix="(v)">a spouse of a child of the decedent or a spouse of a lineal descendant of a child of the decedent;</section><section prefix="(vi)">a surviving spouse of a deceased child of the decedent or of a deceased lineal descendant of a child of the decedent who was married to the child or lineal descendant of the child at the time of the child's or lineal descendant's death;</section><section prefix="(vii)">a brother or sister of the decedent; or</section><section prefix="(viii)">a corporation, partnership, or limited liability company if all of its stockholders, partners, or members consist of individuals specified in items (i) through (vii) of this paragraph.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The inheritance tax does not apply to the receipt of the first $500 of property that passes from a decedent under a will for the perpetual upkeep of graves.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The inheritance tax does not apply to the receipt of the proceeds of a life insurance policy payable to any beneficiary other than the estate of the insured.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The inheritance tax does not apply to the receipt of property that passes from a decedent to or for the use of an organization that is exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code or to which transfers are deductible under &#xA7; 2055 of the Internal Revenue Code if the organization:<section prefix="(1)">is incorporated under the laws of this State;</section><section prefix="(2)">conducts a substantial part of all its activities in this State or in the District of Columbia; or</section><section prefix="(3)">has its principal place of business in a jurisdiction whose law:<section prefix="(i)">does not impose death taxes on the receipt of property that passes from a decedent to a beneficiary of this State that is exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code or to which transfers are deductible under &#xA7; 2055 of the Internal Revenue Code; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">contains a reciprocal exemption from death taxes similar to the exemption allowed in this subsection.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the inheritance tax does not apply to the receipt of personal property that passes from a nonresident decedent if, at the time of death, the decedent is a resident of a state or foreign country whose law, on the date of the decedent's death:<section prefix="(i)">does not impose death taxes on the receipt of similar personal property of a resident of this State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">contains a reciprocal exemption from death taxes similar to the exemption allowed under this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The exemption under paragraph (1) of this subsection does not include the receipt of tangible personal property that has a taxable situs in this State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The inheritance tax does not apply to the receipt of property that passes from a decedent to any 1 person if the total value of the property does not exceed $1,000.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The inheritance tax does not apply to the receipt of property that is distributed from an estate that qualifies under &#xA7; 5-601 of the Estates and Trusts Article for administration as a small estate.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The inheritance tax does not apply to the receipt of property that passes from a decedent to the State, a county, or a municipal corporation of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The inheritance tax does not apply to the receipt of property that is income, including gains and losses, accrued on probate assets after the date of death of the decedent.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Holocaust victim" means an individual who died or lost property as a result of discriminatory laws, policies, or actions targeted against discrete groups of individuals based on race, religion, ethnicity, sexual orientation, or national origin, whether or not the individual was actually a member of any of those groups, or because the individual assisted or allegedly assisted any of those groups, between January 1, 1929 and December 31, 1945, in the country of Nazi Germany, areas occupied by Nazi Germany, those European countries allied with Nazi Germany, areas occupied by those European countries allied with Nazi Germany, or any other neutral European country or area in Europe under the influence or threat of invasion by Nazi Germany or by any European country allied with or occupied by Nazi Germany.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Nazi Germany" means:<section prefix="1.">for the period from 1929 to 1933, the Republic of Germany, commonly referred to as the Weimar Republic; and</section><section prefix="2.">for the period from 1933 through 1945, Deutsche Reich.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The inheritance tax does not apply to the receipt of property that is:<section prefix="(i)">tangible or intangible property or compensation for tangible or intangible property that was seized, misappropriated, or lost as a result of the actions or policies of Nazi Germany toward a Holocaust victim; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">amounts received by a decedent as reparations or restitution for the loss of liberty or damage to the health of the decedent because the decedent was:<section prefix="1.">a Holocaust victim; or</section><section prefix="2.">a spouse or descendant of a Holocaust victim.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The exclusion under paragraph (2) of this subsection includes interest on the proceeds receivable as insurance under policies issued by European insurance companies prior to and during World War II to a Holocaust victim.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The exclusion under paragraph (2) of this subsection does not include:<section prefix="(i)">assets acquired with the assets described in paragraph (2) of this subsection; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">assets acquired with the proceeds from the sale of the assets described in paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The subtraction under paragraph (2)(i) of this subsection shall only apply if the decedent:<section prefix="(i)">was the first recipient of the assets described in paragraph (2)(i) of this subsection after their recovery; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">was:<section prefix="1.">a Holocaust victim; or</section><section prefix="2.">a spouse or descendant of a Holocaust victim.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Domestic partner" means an individual with whom another individual has established a domestic partnership.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Domestic partnership" means a relationship between two individuals that is a domestic partnership within the meaning of &#xA7; 6-101 of the Health - General Article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the domestic partner of a decedent provides evidence of the domestic partnership as described in &#xA7; 6-101(b) of the Health - General Article, the inheritance tax does not apply to the receipt of an interest in a joint primary residence that:<section prefix="(i)">at the time of death was held in joint tenancy by the decedent and the domestic partner; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">passes from the decedent to or for the use of the domestic partner.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
