<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-703" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-10-703</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, a resident may claim a credit only against the State income tax for a taxable year in the amount determined under subsection (c) of this section for State tax on income paid to another state for the year.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A credit under subsection (a) of this section is not allowed to:<section prefix="(1)">a resident other than a fiduciary, if the laws of the other state allow the resident a credit for State income tax paid to this State;</section><section prefix="(2)">a resident fiduciary, if the fiduciary claims, and the other state allows, a credit for State income tax paid to this State;</section><section prefix="(3)">a resident for less than the full taxable year for tax on income that is paid to another state during residency in that state; or</section><section prefix="(4)">a nonresident.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the credit allowed a resident under subsection (a) of this section is the lesser of:<section prefix="(i)">the amount of allowable tax on income that the resident paid to another state; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an amount that does not reduce the State income tax to an amount less than would be payable if the income subjected to tax in the other state were disregarded.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the credit allowed a resident under subsection (a) of this section is based on tax that an S corporation pays to another state, the credit allowable to a shareholder:<section prefix="(i)">may not exceed that shareholder's pro rata share of the tax; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">will be allowed for another state's income taxes or taxes based on income.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
