<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-12-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Cigarette" means any size or shaped roll for smoking that is made of tobacco or tobacco mixed with another ingredient and wrapped in paper or in any other material except tobacco.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Manufacturer" means a person who acts as a manufacturer as defined in &#xA7; 16-201 of the Business Regulation Article or as an other tobacco products manufacturer as defined in &#xA7; 16.5-101 of the Business Regulation Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Other tobacco product" means:<section prefix="(1)">any cigar or roll for smoking, other than a cigarette, made in whole or in part of tobacco; or</section><section prefix="(2)">any other tobacco or product made primarily from tobacco, other than a cigarette, that is intended for consumption by smoking or chewing or as snuff.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Other tobacco products retailer" means a person authorized under &#xA7; 16.5-205(b) of the Business Regulation Article to purchase other tobacco products on which the tobacco tax has not been paid.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Sell" means to exchange or transfer, or to make an agreement to exchange or transfer, title or possession of property, in any manner or by any means, for consideration.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Tax stamp" means a device in the design and denomination that the Comptroller authorizes by regulation for the purpose of being affixed to a package of cigarettes as evidence that the tobacco tax is paid.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Tobacconist" means a person authorized under &#xA7; 16.5-205(e) of the Business Regulation Article to purchase other tobacco products on which the tobacco tax has not been paid.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Unstamped cigarettes" means a package of cigarettes to which tax stamps are not affixed in the amount and manner required in &#xA7; 12-304 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Wholesale price" means the price for which a wholesaler buys other tobacco products, exclusive of any discount, trade allowance, rebate, or other reduction.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Wholesaler" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a person who acts as a wholesaler as defined in &#xA7; 16-201 of the Business Regulation Article or as an other tobacco products wholesaler as defined in &#xA7; 16.5-101 of the Business Regulation Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
