<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="gtg" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-9-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Comptroller may enter into reciprocal agreements on behalf of this State, with the duly authoriz...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Comptroller may enter into reciprocal agreements on behalf of this State, with the duly authorized representatives of any other state, that provide for:<section prefix="(i)">fuel tax registration of vehicles by motor carriers;</section><section prefix="(ii)">establishment of periodic fuel use reporting and fuel use tax payment requirements by motor carriers; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">disbursement of money that is collected by the Comptroller and is due to other states based on:<section prefix="1.">mileage travelled and fuel used in those states; and</section><section prefix="2.">the respective registration fees of those states.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Comptroller may not enter into any reciprocal agreement that would affect:<section prefix="(i)">this State's motor carrier tax rate; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">this State's registration fee for motor carriers.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In exercising the authority granted under subsection (a) of this section, the Comptroller is expressly authorized to:<section prefix="(1)">enter into regional or national fuel use tax agreements;</section><section prefix="(2)">become a member of any regional or national conference, group, compact, or similar organization of motor carrier fuel use tax administrators; and</section><section prefix="(3)">enforce the provisions set forth in any regional or national fuel use tax agreements.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The agreement provisions shall apply to the fuel use taxation, registration, and reporting requirements of motor carriers subject to the provisions of the agreement without reference to or application of any other statutes of this State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
