<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="gtg" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-4-105</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided in this section, the admissions and amusement tax rate is:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>105</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the admissions and amusement tax rate is:<section prefix="(1)">the rate that a county or municipal corporation sets, not exceeding 10% of gross receipts subject to the admissions and amusement tax; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the rate that the Stadium Authority sets, not exceeding 8% of gross receipts subject to the admissions and amusement tax.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(a-1)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, the rate of the State admissions and amusement tax imposed on electronic bingo or electronic tip jars under &#xA7; 4-102(e) of this subtitle is 30% of the net proceeds subject to the tax.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The rate of the State admissions and amusement tax imposed on electronic bingo or electronic tip jars in Calvert County under &#xA7; 4-102(e) of this subtitle is 33% of the net proceeds subject to the tax.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If net proceeds subject to the State admissions and amusement tax imposed on electronic bingo or electronic tip jars under &#xA7; 4-102(e) of this subtitle are also subject to an admissions and amusement tax imposed by a county or a municipal corporation under this subtitle:<section prefix="(i)">the rate of the State tax may not exceed a rate that, when combined with the rate of any county or municipal corporation tax, will exceed 35% of the net proceeds; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the rate of any county or municipal corporation admissions and amusement tax that is applicable to net proceeds derived from electronic bingo or electronic tip jars may not exceed the rate of the admissions and amusement tax imposed by the county or municipal corporation as of January 1, 2009.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If gross receipts subject to the admissions and amusement tax are also subject to the sales and use tax, a county or a municipal corporation may not set a rate so that, when combined with the sales and use tax, the total tax rate will exceed 11% of the gross receipts.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If gross receipts subject to the admissions and amusement tax imposed by the Stadium Authority are also subject to an admissions and amusement tax imposed by a county or municipal corporation, the county or municipal corporation may not set a rate or collect the tax at a rate so that, when combined with the rate of the Stadium Authority, the total tax rate will exceed 10% of the gross receipts.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A municipal corporation may set an admissions and amusement tax rate that differs from the rate set by the county where the municipal corporation is located.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">For purposes of setting admissions and amusement tax rates, a county, a municipal corporation, or the Stadium Authority may:<section prefix="(1)">establish different classes of admissions and amusement charges; and</section><section prefix="(2)">set different rates of tax for those classes.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The admissions and amusement tax that a county, a municipal corporation, or the Stadium Authority may impose on a reduced charge or free admission is:<section prefix="(1)">5 cents, if the charge for any other admission is 50 cents or less;</section><section prefix="(2)">10 cents, if the charge for any other admission is more than 50 cents but does not exceed $1; and</section><section prefix="(3)">15 cents, if the charge for any other admission is more than $1.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If a county, a municipal corporation, or the Stadium Authority changes an admissions and amusement tax rate or changes a class to which a rate applies, the county, municipal corporation, or Stadium Authority shall give the Comptroller notice of the change at least 60 days before the effective date of the change.</section>
  </text>
</law>
