<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="gtg" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-13-912</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this part the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>912</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this part the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Central Collection Unit" means the Central Collection Unit in the Department of Budget and Management.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Debt" means:<section prefix="(i)">a liquidated sum due and owing any State agency that has accrued through contract, subrogation, tort, operation of law, or other cause of action, regardless of whether there is an outstanding judgment for that sum; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a delinquent restitution account on a judgment of restitution referred to the Unit for collection under &#xA7; 11-616 of the Criminal Procedure Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Debt" includes converted funds as defined in &#xA7; 15-122.2 of the Health - General Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Debtor" means:<section prefix="(1)">a person owing a debt to a State agency that has not been adjudged satisfied by court order, set aside by court order, or discharged in bankruptcy; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a defendant or liable parent in arrears of restitution payments whose account has been referred to the Central Collection Unit under &#xA7; 11-616 of the Criminal Procedure Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"State agency" means any agency, association, board, bureau, college, commission, committee, council, foundation, fund, department, institute, institution, public corporation, service, trust, university, the Maryland Higher Education Loan Corporation, or other unit of State government, including any subunit of these agencies.</section>
  </text>
</law>
