<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="gtg" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-5-201</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person who holds a Class E, F, or G alcoholic beverage license shall complete, under oath, and fil...</catch_line>
  <order_by>201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person who holds a Class E, F, or G alcoholic beverage license shall complete, under oath, and file with the Comptroller an alcoholic beverage tax return:<section prefix="(1)">on or before the 25th day of the month that follows the month in which the person sells any alcoholic beverage within the boundaries of the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">if the Comptroller so specifies, by regulation, on other dates for each month in which the licensee does not sell any alcoholic beverages in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each manufacturer and each wholesaler shall complete, under oath, and file with the Comptroller an alcoholic beverage tax return:<section prefix="(1)">on or before the 10th day of the month that follows the month in which:<section prefix="(i)">the manufacturer or wholesaler sells or delivers any alcoholic beverage in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a manufacturer that brews malt beverages, under a Class 6 pub-brewery license, transfers the malt beverages for consumption on the restaurant premises in accordance with federal alcohol tax laws and regulations; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a manufacturer that brews malt beverages, under a Class 7 micro-brewery license, transfers the malt beverages for consumption off the micro-brewery licensed premises in accordance with federal alcohol tax laws and regulations; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">if the Comptroller so specifies, by regulation, on other dates for each month in which the manufacturer or wholesaler does not sell, deliver, or transfer any alcoholic beverage in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A nonresident dealer shall complete, under oath, and file with the Comptroller an alcoholic beverage tax return:<section prefix="(1)">on or before the 15th day of the month that follows the month in which the nonresident dealer delivers beer into the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">if the Comptroller so specifies, by regulation, on other dates for each month in which the nonresident dealer does not deliver beer into the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person who is a direct wine shipper shall file with the Office of the Comptroller a quarterly tax return.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A resident dealer shall complete, under oath, and file with the Comptroller an alcoholic beverage tax return:<section prefix="(1)">on or before the 15th day of the month that follows the month in which the resident dealer delivers beer into the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">if the Comptroller so specifies, by regulation, on other dates for each month in which the resident dealer does not deliver beer into the State.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
