<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-907" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-10-907</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Income tax is not required to be withheld at the time wages are paid to a nonresident:<section prefix="(1)">for State income tax withholding purposes, if the Comptroller and the state in which the nonresident resides have agreed in writing to allow a reciprocal exemption from tax and withholding for the wages of residents of each state that are earned in the other state;</section><section prefix="(2)">for county income tax withholding purposes, if:<section prefix="(i)">the nonresident derives wages from employment in a county; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Comptroller determines that each locality in which the nonresident resides:</section></section><section prefix="(3)">for tips, to the extent that the amount required to be withheld on the tips causes the total withholdings for the period to exceed the available net wages other than tips after deductions are made for:<section prefix="(i)">the federal income and Social Security taxes and income tax required to be withheld on wages other than tips; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the federal income and Social Security taxes required to be withheld on the tips; or</section></section><section prefix="(4)">if the wages are paid to an individual rendering police, fire, rescue, or emergency services in an area covered under a state of emergency declared by the Governor under &#xA7; 14-107 of the Public Safety Article by:<section prefix="(i)">a nonprofit organization not registered to do business in the State and not otherwise doing business in the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a state, county, or political subdivision of a state, other than the State of Maryland.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Unless the payee specifically asks that income tax be withheld from an annuity, sick pay, or retirement distribution, income tax is not required to be withheld from that payment.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Income tax is not required to be withheld on that portion of a death benefit to be excluded from federal adjusted gross income, including amounts to be transferred by the beneficiary or the Board of Trustees of the State Retirement and Pension System to an eligible retirement plan as defined in &#xA7; 402(c)(8)(B) of the Internal Revenue Code in a nontaxable rollover. The State Retirement Agency is authorized to obtain such representation as it deems necessary to determine if the beneficiary will make a nontaxable rollover.</section>
  </text>
</law>
