<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-10-704.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>704.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Cogenerator" means a qualifying cogenerator or qualifying small power producer as determined by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission under the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Electricity supplier" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Public Utilities Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">a cogenerator or electricity supplier that is subject to the public service company franchise tax; or</section><section prefix="(2)">an electricity supplier that, before July 1, 1999, was not an electric company as defined in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Public Utilities Article as in effect on June 30, 1999, unless the electricity supplier is an affiliate of such an electric company.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subject to the limitations in &#xA7; 8-406(b)(2) of this article, a cogenerator or electricity supplier may claim a credit against the State income tax in the amount of $3 for each ton of Maryland-mined coal that the cogenerator or electricity supplier purchased in the taxable year.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A cogenerator or electricity supplier may only apply the credit against the State income tax for the taxable year in which the credit was earned.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The amount of the credit may not exceed the State income tax for that taxable year.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The total amount of credits approved under this section shall be subject to the limitations in &#xA7; 8-406(b)(2)(iv), (v), and (vi) of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A cogenerator or electricity supplier shall submit an application in accordance with &#xA7; 8-406(b)(2)(iii) of this article in order to claim the credit available under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
