<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="gtg" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-5-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>The alcoholic beverage tax does not apply to an alcoholic beverage that is:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The alcoholic beverage tax does not apply to an alcoholic beverage that is:<section prefix="(i)">brought into the State by a person in accordance with:<section prefix="1.">an import-export permit under Article 2B, &#xA7; 2-101(j) of the Code;</section><section prefix="2.">a nonbeverage permit under Article 2B, &#xA7; 2-101(c) of the Code; or</section><section prefix="3.">a nonresident storage permit under Article 2B, &#xA7; 2-101(p) of the Code;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">sold or delivered by a person who holds a Class E, F, or G alcoholic beverage license, while the licensee is operating an aircraft, vessel, or train outside boundaries of the State, including airspace and waterways;</section><section prefix="(iii)">beer or wine that is family-produced and is brought into, possessed, or transported in the State by an individual who is a member of that family if:<section prefix="1.">the individual is at least 21 years of age; and</section><section prefix="2.">the beer or wine is for personal use or for entry in a licensed national family beer and wine exhibition; or</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">brought into the State by a person for storage pending shipment outside of the State, if the alcoholic beverage:<section prefix="1.">is not held for sale, consignment, or delivery in the State;</section><section prefix="2.">is under a customs bond; and</section><section prefix="3.">is stored in a public bonded warehouse.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The exemption under paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection does not apply to an alcoholic beverage sold or delivered by a person who holds a Class E, F, or G alcoholic beverage license while the licensee is operating an aircraft, vessel, or train within the boundaries of the State, including airspace and waterways.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The alcoholic beverage tax does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">an alcoholic beverage bought by a person whom a proper authority of the United States allows to buy alcoholic beverages for sale and use on a federal reservation in the State where the person is assigned;</section><section prefix="(ii)">wine bought and used for sacramental purposes by a religious organization affiliated with and recognized by a generally acknowledged religious faith; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">wine or distilled spirits bought and used for medicinal purposes by a bona fide hospital.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person under paragraph (1) of this subsection who pays the alcoholic beverage tax may obtain the exemption by filing a claim for refund with the Comptroller.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The alcoholic beverage tax does not apply to an alcoholic beverage that a consumer at least 21 years of age brings into the State for personal use:<section prefix="(i)">if the quantity brought from within the continental United States does not exceed:<section prefix="1.">at any one time, one quart;</section><section prefix="2.">in 1 calendar month, two quarts; and</section><section prefix="3.">a total of 1 gallon in the consumer's possession at any one time;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">if the quantity brought from American Samoa, Guam, or the Virgin Islands of the United States does not exceed 1 gallon; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">if the total quantity brought from any other place outside the continental United States does not exceed 1 gallon, the 1st quart of that gallon.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A consumer under paragraph (1)(iii) of this subsection may obtain the exemption for the 1st quart by:<section prefix="(i)">filing an application with the Comptroller on the form the Comptroller requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">paying the alcoholic beverage tax on the quantity of alcoholic beverages that exceeds 1 quart.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
