<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-902" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-10-902</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, each individual, partnership, or corporation required to file quarterly estimated income tax returns shall pay:<section prefix="(1)">at least 25% of the estimated income tax shown on the declaration or amended declaration for a taxable year:<section prefix="(i)">with the declaration or amended declaration that covers that year; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">with each quarterly return for that year; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">any unpaid income tax for the year shown on the income tax return that covers that year, with the return.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If an individual under subsection (a) of this section files a final income tax return on or before January 31 of a taxable year, as allowed under &#xA7; 10-820(b)(3) of this title instead of paying 25% of the estimated income tax shown on the declaration or amended declaration for that year with the estimated tax return on January 15, the individual shall pay in full the unpaid income tax for that year with the final return.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If an individual with estimated income from fishing or farming files the declaration or the return on the dates allowed under &#xA7; 10-820(c) of this title, the individual shall pay in full the income tax shown on the return for that taxable year on or before March 1 of the next year.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An individual who receives income from wagering not subject to withholding under &#xA7; 10-906 of this subtitle shall pay in full the income tax on that income with the estimated tax return that covers the period in which the individual receives that income.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, a fiduciary may use the annualization method as allowed for federal income tax purposes under &#xA7; 6654(d)(2)(B) of the Internal Revenue Code to determine the amount of estimated tax required to be paid.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of this subsection, &#xA7; 6654(d)(2)(B)(i) of the Internal Revenue Code shall be applied by in each instance substituting "ending before the date one month before the due date for the installment" for "ending before the due date for the installment".</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
