<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="gtg" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-11-227</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>227</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Film production activity" means the production or postproduction of film or video projects including feature films, television projects, commercials, corporate films, infomercials, music videos, or other projects for which the producer or production company will be compensated, and which are intended for nationwide commercial distribution.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Film production activity" includes the production or postproduction of digital, animation, and multimedia projects.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Film production activity" does not include:<section prefix="1.">production or postproduction of student films or noncommercial personal videos; or</section><section prefix="2.">any activity not necessary to and undertaken directly and exclusively for the making of a master film, tape, or image.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Tangible personal property or a taxable service used directly in connection with a film production activity" includes:<section prefix="(i)">camera equipment and supplies;</section><section prefix="(ii)">film and tape;</section><section prefix="(iii)">lighting and stage equipment and supplies;</section><section prefix="(iv)">sound equipment and supplies;</section><section prefix="(v)">recording equipment and supplies;</section><section prefix="(vi)">costumes, wardrobes, and materials to construct them;</section><section prefix="(vii)">props, scenery, and materials to construct them;</section><section prefix="(viii)">design supplies and equipment;</section><section prefix="(ix)">drafting supplies and equipment;</section><section prefix="(x)">special effects supplies and equipment;</section><section prefix="(xi)">short-term vehicle rentals; and</section><section prefix="(xii)">fabrication, printing, or production of scripts, storyboards, costumes, wardrobes, props, scenery, or special effects.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The sales and use tax does not apply to a sale of tangible personal property or a taxable service used directly in connection with a film production activity by a film producer or production company certified by the Department of Business and Economic Development under Title 6, Subtitle 2 of the Economic Development Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
