<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-10-207</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>207</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To the extent included in federal adjusted gross income, the amounts under this section are subtracted from the federal adjusted gross income of a resident to determine Maryland adjusted gross income.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The subtraction under subsection (a) of this section includes a distribution, to a beneficiary, of accumulated income on which a fiduciary has paid the income tax.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The subtraction under subsection (a) of this section includes interest or dividends attributable to an obligation of the United States or an authority, commission, instrumentality, possession, or territory of the United States.</section>
    <section prefix="(c-1)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Mutual fund" means a regulated investment company as defined under &#xA7; 851 of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"United States government obligation" means an obligation of the United States or an authority, commission, instrumentality, possession, or territory of the United States.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The subtraction under subsection (a) of this section includes a distribution or dividend by a mutual fund of interest or dividends attributable to a United States government obligation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The subtraction under subsection (a) of this section includes income attributable to an employer-provided official vehicle used in accordance with law by a member of a State, county, or local:<section prefix="(1)">police force; or</section><section prefix="(2)">fire department.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The subtraction under subsection (a) of this section includes a payment from a pension system to an individual for a disability or injury that arose out of and in the course of the individual's employment as a policeman or fire fighter.</section>
    <section prefix="(e-1)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "law enforcement officer" means a law enforcement officer as defined in &#xA7; 3-101 of the Public Safety Article or other sworn law enforcement officer of the United States, a state, or a political subdivision of a state.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The subtraction under subsection (a) of this section includes a payment from a pension system to the surviving spouse or other beneficiary of a law enforcement officer or fire fighter whose death arises out of or in the course of employment as a law enforcement officer or fire fighter.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The subtraction under subsection (a) of this section includes income that:<section prefix="(1)">is received by withdrawing money from a retirement account known as a Keogh Plan and established under Subchapter D of the Internal Revenue Code; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is attributable to:<section prefix="(i)">money contributed by an individual before 1967 for which the individual was not allowed a deduction at the time of contribution to the account; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">interest or dividends paid on the account on which a State tax on income was paid at the time that the interest or dividends accumulated in the account.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The subtraction under subsection (a) of this section includes a payment received under a fire, rescue, or ambulance personnel length of service award program that is funded by any county or municipal corporation of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Repealed.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The subtraction under subsection (a) of this section includes profit realized from the sale or exchange of a bond issued by the State or a political subdivision of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The subtraction under subsection (a) of this section includes a payment received:<section prefix="(1)">under Title II of the Social Security Act; or</section><section prefix="(2)">as a benefit under the Railroad Retirement Act.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The subtraction under subsection (a) of this section includes payment for relocation and assistance under Title 12, Subtitle 2 of the Real Property Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">The subtraction under subsection (a) of this section includes that portion of an annuity received by a retiree of a retirement or pension system:<section prefix="(1)">for which pickup contributions were made under &#xA7; 21-313 of the State Personnel and Pensions Article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">that is included in federal adjusted gross income under &#xA7; 414(h)(2) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">The subtraction under subsection (a) of this section includes a refund of tax on income received from a state or a political subdivision of a state.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">The subtraction under subsection (a) of this section includes any income that federal law or treaty exempts from a state but not federal tax on income.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "remaindermen" includes a person whose remainder interest is vested, contingent, or vested subject to divestment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The subtraction under subsection (a) of this section includes:<section prefix="(i)">income derived from intangible personal property that is held in trust for the benefit of a nonresident or a corporation not doing business in the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">to the extent not included under item (i) of this paragraph, capital gain income derived from the sale or other disposition of intangible personal property that is held in trust, if the proceeds thereof are added to the principal of the trust, and if all the remaindermen in being are:<section prefix="1.">nonresidents during the entire taxable year; or</section><section prefix="2.">corporations not doing business in the State.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The subtraction allowed under paragraph (2)(ii) of this subsection does not apply if there are no remaindermen of the trust in being.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The subtraction under subsection (a) of this section includes the first $15,000 of military pay that is:<section prefix="(i)">received by an individual who is in active service of any branch of the armed forces; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">attributable to military service of the individual outside the United States.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The amount of the subtraction under paragraph (1) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">is reduced dollar for dollar in the amount by which military pay received by the individual exceeds $15,000; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is reduced to zero if the amount of military pay received by the individual exceeds $30,000.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Military service" means:<section prefix="1.">induction into the armed forces of the United States for training and service under the Selective Training and Service Act of 1940 or a subsequent act of a similar nature;</section><section prefix="2.">membership in a reserve component of the armed forces of the United States;</section><section prefix="3.">membership in an active component of the armed forces of the United States;</section><section prefix="4.">membership in the Maryland National Guard; or</section><section prefix="5.">active duty with the commissioned corps of the Public Health Service, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, or the Coast and Geodetic Survey.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Military retirement income" means retirement income received as a result of military service.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The subtraction under subsection (a) of this section includes the first $5,000 of military retirement income received by an individual during the taxable year.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(r)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "modified Maryland adjusted gross income" means Maryland adjusted gross income determined separately for each spouse on a joint return without regard to the subtraction allowed under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For a two-income married couple filing a joint return, the subtraction under subsection (a) of this section includes the lesser of $1,200 or the modified Maryland adjusted gross income of the spouse with the lesser modified Maryland adjusted gross income for the taxable year.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(s)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Qualified beneficiary" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 18-1901 of the Education Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Qualified designated beneficiary" means a qualified designated beneficiary as defined in &#xA7; 18-19A-01 or &#xA7; 18-19B-01 of the Education Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">"Qualified higher education expenses" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 529 of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, the subtraction under subsection (a) of this section includes any amount included in federal adjusted gross income as a result of a distribution to:<section prefix="(i)">a qualified beneficiary pursuant to a prepaid contract under the Maryland Prepaid College Trust;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a qualified designated beneficiary from an investment account under the Maryland College Investment Plan; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a qualified designated beneficiary from an investment account under the Maryland Broker-Dealer College Investment Plan.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The subtraction under paragraph (2) of this subsection does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">a refund under the Maryland Prepaid College Trust; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a distribution that is not used by the qualified beneficiary or qualified designated beneficiary for qualified higher education expenses.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(t)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Holocaust victim" means an individual who died or lost property as a result of discriminatory laws, policies, or actions targeted against discrete groups of individuals based on race, religion, ethnicity, sexual orientation, or national origin, whether or not the individual was actually a member of any of those groups, or because the individual assisted or allegedly assisted any of those groups, between January 1, 1929 and December 31, 1945, in the country of Nazi Germany, areas occupied by Nazi Germany, those European countries allied with Nazi Germany, areas occupied by those European countries allied with Nazi Germany, or any other neutral European country or area in Europe under the influence or threat of invasion by Nazi Germany or by any European country allied with or occupied by Nazi Germany.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Nazi Germany" means:<section prefix="1.">for the period from 1929 to 1933, the Republic of Germany, commonly referred to as the Weimar Republic; and</section><section prefix="2.">for the period from 1933 through 1945, Deutsche Reich.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The subtraction under subsection (a) of this section includes:<section prefix="(i)">income of an individual related to tangible or intangible property that was seized, misappropriated, or lost as a result of the actions or policies of Nazi Germany toward a Holocaust victim; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">amounts received by an individual as reparations or restitution for the loss of liberty or damage to the health of the individual because the individual is:<section prefix="1.">a Holocaust victim; or</section><section prefix="2.">a spouse or descendant of a Holocaust victim.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The subtraction under paragraph (2) of this subsection includes interest on the proceeds receivable as insurance under policies issued to a Holocaust victim by European insurance companies prior to and during World War II.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The subtraction under paragraph (2) of this subsection does not include:<section prefix="(i)">assets acquired with the assets described in paragraph (2) of this subsection; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">assets acquired with the proceeds from the sale of the assets described in paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The subtraction under paragraph (2)(i) of this subsection shall only apply if the individual:<section prefix="(i)">is the first recipient of the assets described in paragraph (2)(i) of this subsection after their recovery; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is:<section prefix="1.">a Holocaust victim; or</section><section prefix="2.">a spouse or descendant of a Holocaust victim.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(u)">Repealed.</section>
    <section prefix="(v)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "artistic work", "arts and entertainment district", and "qualifying residing artist" have the meanings stated in &#xA7; 4-701 of the Economic Development Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The subtraction under subsection (a) of this section includes the amount of income derived within an arts and entertainment district by a qualifying residing artist from the publication, production, or sale of an artistic work that the artist created, wrote, composed, or executed in the arts and entertainment district.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For the purpose of determining whether income is derived within an arts and entertainment district for the purpose of this subsection, a qualifying residing artist shall allocate receipts and expenses as the Comptroller may require.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(w)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">except as provided in item (ii) of this paragraph, "foreign earned income" means foreign earned income within the meaning of &#xA7; 911(b)(1) of the Internal Revenue Code, subject to the limitation under &#xA7; 911(b)(2) of the Internal Revenue Code; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">"foreign earned income" includes amounts paid by the United States or an agency of the United States to an employee of the United States or of an agency of the United States.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to the limitation under paragraph (3) of this subsection, for each taxable year beginning after December 31, 2006, but before January 1, 2010, the subtraction under subsection (a) of this section includes the foreign earned income of an individual earned as an employee of the United States or of an agency of the United States.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The amount subtracted under this section:<section prefix="(i)">does not include any amount subtracted under any other provisions of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">may not exceed $3,500 for any taxable year.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(x)">The subtraction under subsection (a) of this section includes an amount received as a grant under the Solar Energy Grant Program under &#xA7; 9-2007 of the State Government Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(y)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "principal residence" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 121 of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, the subtraction under subsection (a) of this section includes the amount of a gain resulting from a payment from the Maryland Department of Transportation to an individual for the acquisition of a portion of the individual's property on which the individual's principal residence is located.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The amount subtracted under this subsection may not exceed the amount that may be excluded from income on the condemnation of an individual's principal residence under &#xA7; 121 of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
