<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="gtg" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-7-216</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided in this section, the inheritance tax on property that passes from a dec...</catch_line>
  <order_by>216</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the inheritance tax on property that passes from a decedent shall be paid, before it is distributed, by the person who distributes the property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The person who distributes property that passes from a decedent is liable for the inheritance tax on the property distributed until the tax is paid.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Unless a decedent specified a source for paying the inheritance tax and there is sufficient money from that source, the court may order sale of property to pay the inheritance tax on the property.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The inheritance tax on property that passes from a decedent shall be paid by the recipient if:<section prefix="(1)">the person who distributes the property does not pay the tax as required by subsection (a) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the property passes from the decedent to the recipient without distribution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the property that passes from a decedent is a subsequent interest, the inheritance tax on the property shall be paid:<section prefix="(1)">by the person by or for whom a prepayment application is made under &#xA7; 7-219 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">if the inheritance tax is not prepaid on the subsequent interest, by the person in whom the property or subsequent interest ultimately vests.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If property valued or exempt under &#xA7; 7-211 of this subtitle is disqualified for the special valuation or exemption under &#xA7; 7-221 of this subtitle, the person who owns the property when the disqualifying event occurs shall pay any additional inheritance tax determined under &#xA7; 7-221 of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
