<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="gtg" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-13-801</section_number>
  <catch_line>Unpaid tax, interest, and penalties shall be first paid and satisfied from the proceeds of a sale of...</catch_line>
  <order_by>801</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Unpaid tax, interest, and penalties shall be first paid and satisfied from the proceeds of a sale of any property of a person liable for the tax.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, a claim of a tax collector for unpaid tax, interest, and penalties shall be subordinate:<section prefix="(1)">to the claim of any purchaser, holder of a security interest, or mechanic's lienor, as those terms are defined in &#xA7; 6323(h) of the Internal Revenue Code, or to the claim of a judgment creditor whose lien attached before the claim for unpaid tax, interest, and penalties; and</section><section prefix="(2)">to any claim described in &#xA7; 6323(b), (c), or (d) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A judicial officer who makes a sale of property shall determine from a tax collector whether the owner of the property owes any tax, interest, or penalties.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The judicial officer is personally liable and the bond of the officer is liable for any tax, interest, or penalties not paid to the tax collector in violation of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whenever property is taken in execution of an action to collect taxes, the tax collector may bid for and buy the property for the use of the State if the tax collector believes the purchase is necessary and proper for the protection of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A bid under paragraph (1) of this subsection may not exceed the claim of the State for unpaid taxes and the costs and expenses of the sale.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
