<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-102" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-11-102</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, a tax is imposed on:<section prefix="(1)">a retail sale in the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a use, in the State, of tangible personal property or a taxable service.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, in addition to the tax imposed under subsection (a) of this section, a hotel surcharge is imposed in Dorchester County on the sale of a right to occupy a room or lodgings as a transient guest in an establishment that offers at least 380 rooms.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The hotel surcharge imposed under paragraph (1) of this subsection may not be imposed if the Maryland Economic Development Corporation certifies to the Comptroller that the bonds issued by the Maryland Economic Development Corporation secured by the Dorchester County Economic Development Fund established under &#xA7; 10-130 of the Economic Development Article have been paid in full.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A county, municipal corporation, special taxing district, or other political subdivision of the State may not impose any retail sales or use tax except:<section prefix="(i)">a sales tax or use tax that was in effect on January 1, 1971;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a tax on the sale or use of:</section><section prefix="(iii)">a tax imposed by a code county on the sale or use of food and beverages authorized under Article 25B, &#xA7; 13H of the Code.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Paragraph (1) of this subsection may not be construed as conferring authority to impose a sales and use tax.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
