<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="gtg" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-10-906</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in &#xA7; 10-907 of this subtitle, each employer or payor shall:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>906</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 10-907 of this subtitle, each employer or payor shall:<section prefix="(1)">withhold the income tax required to be withheld under &#xA7; 10-908 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">pay to the Comptroller the income tax withheld for a period with the withholding return that covers the period.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Any income tax withheld is deemed to be held in trust for the State by the employer or payor who withholds the tax.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An employer or payor who withholds income tax shall keep a separate ledger account for withholdings that indicates clearly:<section prefix="(1)">the amount of income tax withheld; and</section><section prefix="(2)">that the income tax withheld is the property of the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If an employer or payor negligently fails to withhold or to pay income tax in accordance with subsection (a) of this section, personal liability for that income tax extends:<section prefix="(1)">to the employer or payor;</section><section prefix="(2)">if the employer or payor is a corporation, to:<section prefix="(i)">any officer of the corporation who exercises direct control over its fiscal management; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">any agent of the corporation who is required to withhold and pay the income tax; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">if the employer or payor is a limited liability company as defined under Title 4A of the Corporations and Associations Article or a limited liability partnership as defined under Title 9A of the Corporations and Associations Article, including a limited partnership registered as a limited liability limited partnership, to:<section prefix="(i)">any person who exercises direct control over its fiscal management; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any agent of the limited liability company or limited liability partnership who is required to withhold and pay the income tax.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
