<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="gtg" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-10-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Financial institution" means:<section prefix="1.">a credit company;</section><section prefix="2.">except as provided in subparagraph (ii)1 of this paragraph, a finance company;</section><section prefix="3.">an international banking facility;</section><section prefix="4.">a loan company;</section><section prefix="5.">a mortgage company;</section><section prefix="6.">a safe-deposit company; and</section><section prefix="7.">a savings and loan association.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Financial institution" does not include:<section prefix="1.">a finance company that makes loans only to farmers for agricultural purposes;</section><section prefix="2.">a company licensed under the federal Small Business Investment Act of 1958;</section><section prefix="3.">a corporation that elects to be taxed as a small business corporation under Subchapter S of the Internal Revenue Code;</section><section prefix="4.">an entity that is a real estate mortgage investment conduit as defined in the Internal Revenue Code;</section><section prefix="5.">a limited liability company; or</section><section prefix="6.">a commercial bank, savings bank, trust company, or company that substantially competes with national banks in the State.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Financial institution holding company" means a financial institution whose only activities are:<section prefix="(i)">the maintenance and management of intangible investments; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the collection and distribution of income from intangible investments.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notwithstanding &#xA7; 10-402 of this subtitle, interest received by a financial institution holding company from one of its subsidiary corporations that is a financial institution shall be allocated to this State only to the extent that the interest is derived from the trade or business of the subsidiary corporation within this State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
