<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-4-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Admissions and amusement charge", unless expressly provided otherwise, means a charge for:<section prefix="(i)">admission to a place, including any additional separate charge for admission within an enclosure;</section><section prefix="(ii)">use of a game of entertainment;</section><section prefix="(iii)">use of a recreational or sports facility;</section><section prefix="(iv)">use or rental of recreational or sports equipment; and</section><section prefix="(v)">merchandise, refreshments, or a service sold or served in connection with entertainment at a nightclub or room in a hotel, restaurant, hall, or other place where dancing privileges, music, or other entertainment is provided.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Admissions and amusement charge" does not include a charge for admission to a political fundraising event.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Game of entertainment" includes, in Anne Arundel County or Calvert County, the game of instant bingo permitted under a commercial bingo license.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Person" includes:<section prefix="(1)">this State or a political subdivision, unit, or instrumentality of this State;</section><section prefix="(2)">another state or a political subdivision, unit, or instrumentality of that state; and</section><section prefix="(3)">a unit or instrumentality of a political subdivision of this State or of another state.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Stadium Authority" means the Maryland Stadium Authority created under &#xA7; 10-604 of the Economic Development Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
