<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-721" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-10-721</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL JUNE 30, 2021 PER CHAPTER 20 OF 2010 //<section prefix="(a)"><section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section><section prefix="(2)">"Department" means the Department of Business and Economic Development.</section><section prefix="(3)">"Maryland base amount" means the base amount as defined in &#xA7; 41(c) of the Internal Revenue Code that is attributable to Maryland, determined by:<section prefix="(i)">substituting "Maryland qualified research and development expense" for "qualified research expense";</section><section prefix="(ii)">substituting "Maryland qualified research and development" for "qualified research"; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">using, instead of the "fixed base percentage":</section></section><section prefix="(4)">"Maryland gross receipts" means gross receipts that are reasonably attributable to the conduct of a trade or business in this State, determined under methods prescribed by the Comptroller based on standards similar to the standards under &#xA7; 10-402 of this title.</section><section prefix="(5)">"Maryland qualified research and development" means qualified research as defined in &#xA7; 41(d) of the Internal Revenue Code that is conducted in this State.</section><section prefix="(6)">"Maryland qualified research and development expenses" means qualified research expenses as defined in &#xA7; 41(b) of the Internal Revenue Code incurred for Maryland qualified research and development.</section></section><section prefix="(b)">Subject to the limitations of this section, an individual or a corporation may claim credits against the State income tax in an amount equal to:<section prefix="(1)">3% of the Maryland qualified research and development expenses, not exceeding the Maryland base amount for the individual or corporation, paid or incurred by the individual or corporation during the taxable year; and</section><section prefix="(2)">10% of the amount by which the Maryland qualified research and development expenses paid or incurred by the individual or corporation during the taxable year exceed the Maryland base amount for the individual or corporation.</section></section><section prefix="(c)"><section prefix="(1)">By September 15 of the calendar year following the end of the taxable year in which the Maryland qualified research and development expenses were incurred, an individual or corporation shall submit an application to the Department for the credits allowed under subsection (b)(1) and (2) of this section.</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">Except as provided under paragraph (4) of this subsection, the total amount of credits approved by the Department under subsection (b)(1) of this section may not exceed $3,000,000 for any calendar year.</section><section prefix="(ii)">Subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection, if the total amount of credits applied for by all individuals and corporations under subsection (b)(1) of this section exceeds the maximum specified under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the Department shall approve a credit under subsection (b)(1) of this section for each applicant in an amount equal to the product of multiplying the credit applied for by the applicant times a fraction:</section></section><section prefix="(3)"><section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, the total amount of credits approved by the Department under subsection (b)(2) of this section may not exceed $3,000,000 for any calendar year.</section><section prefix="(ii)">Subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection, if the total amount of credits applied for by all individuals and corporations under subsection (b)(2) of this section exceeds the maximum specified under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the Department shall approve a credit under subsection (b)(2) of this section for each applicant in an amount equal to the product of multiplying the credit applied for by the applicant times a fraction:</section></section><section prefix="(4)"><section prefix="(i)">For any calendar year, if the maximum specified under paragraph (2)(i) of this subsection exceeds the total amount of credits applied for by all individuals and corporations under subsection (b)(1) of this section, the maximum specified under paragraph (3)(i) of this subsection shall be increased for that calendar year by an amount equal to the amount by which the maximum specified under paragraph (2)(i) of this subsection exceeds the total amount of credits applied for by all individuals and corporations under subsection (b)(1) of this section.</section><section prefix="(ii)">For any calendar year, if the maximum specified under paragraph (3)(i) of this subsection exceeds the total amount of credits applied for by all individuals and corporations under subsection (b)(2) of this section, the maximum specified under paragraph (2)(i) of this subsection shall be increased for that calendar year by an amount equal to the amount by which the maximum specified under paragraph (3)(i) of this subsection exceeds the total amount of credits applied for by all individuals and corporations under subsection (b)(2) of this section.</section></section><section prefix="(5)">By December 15 of the calendar year following the end of the taxable year in which the Maryland qualified research and development expenses were incurred, the Department shall certify to the individual or corporation the amount of the research and development tax credits approved by the Department for the individual or corporation under subsection (b)(1) and (2) of this section.</section><section prefix="(6)">To claim the approved credits allowed under this section, an individual or corporation shall:<section prefix="(i)">file an amended income tax return for the taxable year in which the Maryland qualified research and development expense was incurred; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">attach a copy of the Department's certification of the approved credit amount to the amended income tax return.</section></section></section><section prefix="(d)">If the credit allowed under this section in any taxable year exceeds the State income tax for that taxable year, an individual or corporation may apply the excess as a credit against the State income tax for succeeding taxable years until the earlier of:<section prefix="(1)">the full amount of the excess is used; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the expiration of the 7th taxable year after the taxable year in which the Maryland qualified research and development expense was incurred.</section></section><section prefix="(e)"><section prefix="(1)">In determining the amount of the credit under this section:<section prefix="(i)">all members of the same controlled group of corporations, as defined under &#xA7; 41(f) of the Internal Revenue Code, shall be treated as a single taxpayer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the credit allowable by this section to each member shall be its proportionate shares of the qualified research expenses giving rise to the credit.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The Comptroller shall adopt regulations providing for:<section prefix="(i)">determination of the amount of the credit under this section in the case of trades or businesses, whether or not incorporated, that are under common control;</section><section prefix="(ii)">pass-through and allocation of the credit in the case of estates and trusts, partnerships, unincorporated trades or businesses, and S corporations;</section><section prefix="(iii)">adjustments in the case of acquisitions and dispositions described in &#xA7; 41(f)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">determination of the credit in the case of short taxable years.</section></section><section prefix="(3)">The regulations adopted under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be based on principles similar to the principles applicable under &#xA7; 41 of the Internal Revenue Code and regulations adopted thereunder.</section></section><section prefix="(f)"><section prefix="(1)">The Department of Business and Economic Development and the Comptroller jointly shall adopt regulations to prescribe standards for determining when research or development is considered conducted in the State for purposes of determining the credit under this section.</section><section prefix="(2)">In adopting regulations under this subsection, the Department and the Comptroller may consider:<section prefix="(i)">the location where services are performed;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the residence or business location of the person or persons performing services;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the location where supplies used in research and development are consumed; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">any other factors that the Department determines are relevant for the determination.</section></section></section><section prefix="(g)"><section prefix="(1)">On or before January 10 of each year, the Department shall report to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly, on the credits approved under this section.</section><section prefix="(2)">The report required under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall include for each individual or corporation approved to receive a credit under subsection (b)(1) and (2) of this section in the prior calendar year:<section prefix="(i)">the individual's or corporation's name and address; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the amount of the credit approved.</section></section><section prefix="(3)">The report required under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall include the name of the individual or corporation and the aggregate amount of credits approved in all calendar years for each individual or corporation under subsection (b)(1) and (2) of this section.</section><section prefix="(4)">The report required under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall summarize for the credits approved under subsection (b)(1) of this section and for the credits approved under subsection (b)(2) of this section:<section prefix="(i)">the total number of applicants for credits under this section in each calendar year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the number of applications for which a tax credit was approved in each calendar year; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the total credits authorized under this section for all calendar years under this section.</section></section></section><section prefix="(h)">If the provisions of &#xA7; 41 of the Internal Revenue Code governing the federal research and development tax credit are repealed or terminate, the provisions of this section continue to operate as if the provisions of &#xA7; 41 of the Internal Revenue Code remain in effect, and the Maryland research and development tax credit under this section shall continue to be available.</section></text>
</law>
