<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-10-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To the extent excluded from federal adjusted gross income, the amounts under this section are added to the federal adjusted gross income of a resident to determine Maryland adjusted gross income.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The addition under subsection (a) of this section includes interest or dividends, less related expenses, attributable to an obligation or security of:<section prefix="(1)">another state; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a political subdivision or authority of another state.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If exempted by federal law or by treaty from federal but not State tax on income, the addition under subsection (a) of this section includes salary, wages, or other compensation for personal services.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If exempted by federal law or by treaty from federal but not State tax on income, the addition under subsection (a) of this section includes interest or dividends attributable to an obligation of:<section prefix="(i)">the United States or a foreign government; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an authority, commission, instrumentality, possession, or territory of the United States or of a foreign government.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "lump-sum distribution", "minimum distribution allowance", and "total taxable amount" have the meanings stated in &#xA7; 402(e) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The addition under subsection (a) of this section includes the amount by which the total taxable amount of a lump-sum distribution exceeds the sum of:<section prefix="(i)">60% of the capital gains portion of the total taxable amount; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the minimum distribution allowance.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For purposes of this subsection, the capital gains portion of the total taxable amount is determined by multiplying the total taxable amount by a fraction:<section prefix="(i)">the numerator of which is the number of calendar years of active participation by the employee in the plan before January 1, 1974; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the denominator of which is the number of calendar years of active participation by the employee in the plan.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The addition under subsection (a) of this section includes the oil percentage depletion allowance claimed under &#xA7; 613 or &#xA7; 613A of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The addition under subsection (a) of this section includes the amount of pickup contributions of a member of a retirement or pension system:<section prefix="(1)">provided for under &#xA7; 21-313 of the State Personnel and Pensions Article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">excluded from federal adjusted gross income under &#xA7; 414(h)(2) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "remaindermen" includes a person whose remainder interest is vested, contingent, or vested subject to divestment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The addition under subsection (a) of this section includes any capital loss derived from the sale or other disposition of intangible personal property that is held in trust, if the proceeds thereof are added to the principal of the trust, and if all the remaindermen in being are:<section prefix="(i)">nonresidents during the entire taxable year; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">corporations not doing business in the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The addition required under paragraph (2) of this subsection does not apply if there are no remaindermen of the trust in being.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The addition under subsection (a) of this section includes the amount deducted under &#xA7; 222 of the Internal Revenue Code for qualified tuition and related expenses paid during the taxable year.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The addition under subsection (a) of this section includes the amount deducted under &#xA7; 199 of the Internal Revenue Code for the qualified production activities income of the taxpayer for the taxable year.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The addition under subsection (a) of this section includes any amount deducted for costs, as defined under &#xA7; 10-731 of this title, for security clearance administrative expenses and construction and equipment costs incurred to construct or renovate a sensitive compartmented information facility if an amount is included in the application for a credit under &#xA7; 10-731 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">For a taxable year beginning after December 31, 2012, the addition under subsection (a) of this section includes the amount of income of an electing small business trust, as defined under &#xA7; 1361(e)(1) of the Internal Revenue Code, that is subject to the special taxing rules under &#xA7; 641(c) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
  </text>
</law>
