<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-13-508</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>508</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Within 30 days after the date on which a notice of assessment of the admissions and amusement tax, alcoholic beverage tax, boxing and wrestling tax, income tax, motor carrier tax, motor fuel tax, public service company franchise tax, financial institution franchise tax, sales and use tax, or tobacco tax is mailed, a person or governmental unit against which the assessment is made may submit to the tax collector:<section prefix="(1)">an application for revision of the assessment; or</section><section prefix="(2)">except for the public service company franchise tax, if the assessment is paid, a claim for refund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a person or governmental unit fails to submit an application for revision or claim for refund within the time allowed in subsection (a) of this section, the assessment becomes final.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Comptroller or an employee of the Comptroller's office expressly designated by the Comptroller promptly:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">shall hold an informal hearing on a person's or governmental unit's admissions and amusement tax, alcoholic beverage tax, boxing and wrestling tax, income tax, motor carrier tax, motor fuel tax, sales and use tax, or tobacco tax application for revision or claim for refund under subsection (a) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">after the hearing:<section prefix="1.">shall act on the application for revision; and</section><section prefix="2.">may assess any additional tax, penalty, and interest due; and</section></section></section><section prefix="(2)">shall mail to the person or governmental unit a notice of final determination.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department promptly:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">shall act on a person's public service company franchise tax or financial institution franchise tax application for revision under subsection (a) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">shall hold an informal hearing after giving reasonable notice to the person; and</section><section prefix="2.">after the hearing:</section></section></section><section prefix="(2)">shall mail to the person a notice of final determination.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
