<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="gtg" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-10-725</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>725</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Biotechnology company" means a company organized for profit that is primarily engaged in the research, development, or commercialization of innovative and proprietary technology that comprises, interacts with, or analyzes biological material including biomolecules (DNA, RNA, or protein), cells, tissues, or organs.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Company" means any entity of any form duly organized and existing under the laws of any jurisdiction for the purpose of conducting business for profit.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Company" does not include a sole proprietorship.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Department" means the Department of Business and Economic Development.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Investment" means the contribution of money in cash or cash equivalents expressed in United States dollars, at a risk of loss, to a qualified Maryland biotechnology company in exchange for stock, a partnership or membership interest, or other ownership interest in the equity of the qualified Maryland biotechnology company, title to which ownership interest shall vest in the qualified investor.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Investment" does not include debt.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">For purposes of this section, an investment is at risk of loss when its repayment entirely depends upon the success of the business operations of the qualified company.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Qualified investor" means any individual or entity that invests at least $25,000 in a qualified Maryland biotechnology company and that is required to file an income tax return in any jurisdiction.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Qualified investor" does not include a qualified pension plan, individual retirement account, or other qualified retirement plan under the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, as amended, or fiduciaries or custodians under such plans, or similar tax-favored plans or entities under the laws of other countries.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Qualified Maryland biotechnology company" means a biotechnology company that:<section prefix="1.">has its headquarters and base of operations in this State;</section><section prefix="2.">has fewer than 50 full-time employees;</section><section prefix="3.">except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, has been in active business no longer than 10 years;</section><section prefix="4.">does not have its securities publicly traded on any exchange; and</section><section prefix="5.">has been certified as a biotechnology company by the Department.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Qualified Maryland biotechnology company" includes:<section prefix="1.">a company that has been in active business for up to 12 years if the Department determines that the company requires additional time to complete the process of regulatory approval; and</section><section prefix="2.">for fiscal years 2012 and 2013 only, a company that has been in active business for up to 15 years.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Secretary" means the Secretary of Business and Economic Development.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection and subsections (d) and (e) of this section, for the taxable year in which an investment in a qualified Maryland biotechnology company is made, a qualified investor may claim a credit against the State income tax in an amount equal to the amount of tax credit stated in the final credit certificate approved by the Secretary for the investment as provided under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To be eligible for the tax credit described in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the qualified investor shall be:<section prefix="(i)">for a company, duly organized and in good standing in the jurisdiction under the laws under which it is organized;</section><section prefix="(ii)">for a company, in good standing and authorized or registered to do business in the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">current in the payment of all tax obligations to the State or any unit or subdivision of the State; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">not in default under the terms of any contract with, indebtedness to, or grant from the State or any unit or subdivision of the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">To be eligible for the tax credit described in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the qualified investor may not, after making the proposed investment, own or control more than 25% of the equity interests in the qualified Maryland biotechnology company in which the investment is to be made.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 30 days prior to making an investment in a qualified Maryland biotechnology company for which a qualified investor would be eligible for an initial tax credit certificate under subsection (b) of this section, the qualified investor shall submit an application to the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The application shall evidence that the qualified Maryland biotechnology company is:<section prefix="(i)">in good standing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">current in the payment of all tax obligations to the State or any unit or subdivision of the State; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">not in default under the terms of any contract with, indebtedness to, or grant from the State or any unit or subdivision of the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(i)">approve all applications that qualify for credits under this section on a first come first served basis; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">within 30 days of receipt of an application, certify the amount of any approved tax credits to a qualified investor.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">After the date on which the Department issues an initial tax credit certificate under this section, a qualified investor shall have 30 calendar days to make an investment in a qualified Maryland biotechnology company under this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Within 10 calendar days after the date on which a qualified investor makes the investment, the qualified investor shall provide to the Department notice and proof of the making of the investment, including:<section prefix="1.">the date of the investment;</section><section prefix="2.">the amount invested;</section><section prefix="3.">proof of the receipt of the invested funds by the qualified Maryland biotechnology company;</section><section prefix="4.">a complete description of the nature of the ownership interest in the equity of the qualified Maryland biotechnology company acquired in consideration of the investment; and</section><section prefix="5.">any reasonable supporting documentation the Department may require.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If a qualified investor does not provide the notice and proof of the making of the investment required in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph within 40 calendar days after the date on which the Department issues an initial tax credit certificate under this section:<section prefix="1.">the Department shall rescind the initial tax credit certificate; and</section><section prefix="2.">the credit amount allocated to the rescinded certificate shall revert to the Maryland Biotechnology Investment Tax Credit Reserve Fund and shall be available in the applicable fiscal year for allocation by the Department to other initial tax credit certificates in accordance with the provisions of this section.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The tax credit allowed in an initial tax credit certificate issued under this section is 50% of the investment in a qualified Maryland biotechnology company, not to exceed $250,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">During any fiscal year, the Secretary may not certify eligibility for tax credits for investments in a single qualified Maryland biotechnology company that in the aggregate exceed 15% of the total appropriations to the Maryland Biotechnology Investment Tax Credit Reserve Fund for that fiscal year.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the tax credit allowed under this section in any taxable year exceeds the total tax otherwise payable by the qualified investor for that taxable year, the qualified investor may claim a refund in the amount of the excess.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "Reserve Fund" means the Maryland Biotechnology Investment Tax Credit Reserve Fund established under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Biotechnology Investment Tax Credit Reserve Fund which is a special continuing, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The money in the Fund shall be invested and reinvested by the Treasurer, and interest and earnings shall be credited to the General Fund.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to the provisions of this subsection, the Secretary shall issue an initial tax credit certificate for each approved investment in a qualified Maryland biotechnology company eligible for a tax credit.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An initial tax credit certificate issued under this subsection shall state the maximum amount of tax credit for which the qualified investor is eligible.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">
          <section prefix="1.">Except as otherwise provided in this subparagraph, for any fiscal year, the Secretary may not issue initial tax credit certificates for credit amounts in the aggregate totaling more than the amount appropriated to the Reserve Fund for that fiscal year in the State budget as approved by the General Assembly.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">If the aggregate credit amounts under initial tax credit certificates issued in a fiscal year total less than the amount appropriated to the Reserve Fund for that fiscal year, any excess amount shall remain in the Reserve Fund and may be issued under initial tax credit certificates for the next fiscal year.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">For any fiscal year, if funds are transferred from the Reserve Fund under the authority of any provision of law other than under paragraph (4) of this subsection, the maximum credit amounts in the aggregate for which the Secretary may issue initial tax credit certificates shall be reduced by the amount transferred.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">For each fiscal year, the Governor shall include in the budget bill an appropriation to the Reserve Fund.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">Notwithstanding the provisions of &#xA7; 7-213 of the State Finance and Procurement Article, the Governor may not reduce an appropriation to the Reserve Fund in the State budget as approved by the General Assembly.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">Based on the actual amount of an investment made by a qualified investor, the Secretary shall issue a final tax credit certificate to the qualified investor.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in this paragraph, money appropriated to the Reserve Fund shall remain in the Fund.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">Within 15 days after the end of each calendar quarter, the Department shall notify the Comptroller as to each final credit certificate issued during the quarter:</section>
          <section prefix="2.">On notification that an investment has been certified, the Comptroller shall transfer an amount equal to the credit amount stated in the initial tax credit certificate for the investment from the Reserve Fund to the General Fund.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The credit claimed under this section shall be recaptured as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection if within 2 years from the close of the taxable year for which the credit is claimed:<section prefix="(i)">the qualified investor sells, transfers, or otherwise disposes of the ownership interest in the qualified Maryland biotechnology company that gave rise to the credit; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the qualified Maryland biotechnology company that gave rise to the credit ceases operating as an active business with its headquarters and base of operations in the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The amount required to be recaptured under this subsection is the product of multiplying:<section prefix="(i)">the total amount of the credit claimed or, in the case of an event described in paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection, the portion of the credit attributable to the ownership interest disposed of; and</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">100%, if the event requiring recapture of the credit occurs during the taxable year for which the tax credit is claimed;</section><section prefix="2.">67%, if the event requiring recapture of the credit occurs during the first year after the close of the taxable year for which the tax credit is claimed; or</section><section prefix="3.">33%, if the event requiring recapture of the credit occurs more than 1 year but not more than 2 years after the close of the taxable year for which the tax credit is claimed.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The qualified investor that claimed the credit shall pay the amount to be recaptured as determined under paragraph (2) of this subsection as taxes payable to the State for the taxable year in which the event requiring recapture of the credit occurs.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department may revoke its initial or final certification of an approved credit under this section if any representation in connection with the application for the certification is determined by the Department to have been false when made.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The revocation may be in full or in part as the Department may determine and, subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, shall be communicated to the qualified investor and the Comptroller.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The qualified investor shall have an opportunity to appeal any revocation to the Department prior to notification of the Comptroller.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Comptroller may make an assessment against the qualified investor to recapture any amount of tax credit that the qualified investor has already claimed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before January 10 of each year, the Department shall report to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly, on the initial tax credit certificates awarded under this section for the prior calendar year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The report required under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall include for each initial tax credit certificate awarded:<section prefix="(i)">the name of the qualified investor and the amount of credit awarded or allocated to each investor;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the name and address of the qualified Maryland biotechnology company that received the investment giving rise to the credit under this section and the county where the qualified Maryland biotechnology company is located; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the dates of receipt and approval by the Department of all applications for initial tax credit certificates.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The report required under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall summarize for the category of qualified investors:<section prefix="(i)">the total number of applicants for initial tax credit certificates under this section in each calendar year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the number of applications for which initial tax credit certificates were issued in each calendar year; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the total initial tax credit certificates authorized under this section for all calendar years under this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Department and the Comptroller jointly shall adopt regulations to carry out the provisions of this section and to specify criteria and procedures for application for, approval of, and monitoring continuing eligibility for the tax credit under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
