<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-701" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-11-701</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Engage in the business of an out-of-state vendor" means to sell or deliver tangible personal property or a taxable service for use in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Engage in the business of an out-of-state vendor" includes:<section prefix="(i)">permanently or temporarily maintaining, occupying, or using any office, sales or sample room, or distribution, storage, warehouse, or other place for the sale of tangible personal property or a taxable service directly or indirectly through an agent or subsidiary;</section><section prefix="(ii)">having an agent, canvasser, representative, salesman, or solicitor operating in the State for the purpose of delivering, selling, or taking orders for tangible personal property or a taxable service; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">entering the State on a regular basis to provide service or repair for tangible personal property.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Engage in the business of a retail vendor" means to sell or deliver tangible personal property or a taxable service in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Engage in the business of a retail vendor" includes liquidating a business that sells tangible personal property or a taxable service, when the liquidator holds out to the public that the business is conducted by the liquidator.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"License" means a license issued by the Comptroller:<section prefix="(i)">to engage in the business of an out-of-state vendor; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">to engage in the business of a retail vendor.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"License" includes a special license issued under &#xA7; 11-707 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
