<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-2-113</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>113</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Comptroller shall include on the individual income tax return form a checkoff designated as the "Developmental Disabilities Waiting List Equity Fund Contribution".</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The checkoff shall state that:<section prefix="(i)">the individual, or each spouse in the case of a joint return, may contribute to the Waiting List Equity Fund the amount designated by the individual; and</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">the individual shall deduct the amount of the contribution from any refund to which the individual is entitled; or</section><section prefix="2.">if the individual is not entitled to a refund, the individual shall add the amount of the contribution to the income tax to be paid with the return.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Comptroller shall include, with the individual income tax return package, a description of the purposes for which the Waiting List Equity Fund was established and the purposes for which the Fund may be used.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Comptroller shall:<section prefix="(1)">collect the checkoff contributions and account to the State Treasurer for the money collected;</section><section prefix="(2)">from the contributions collected, distribute the amount necessary to administer the checkoff system to an administrative cost account; and</section><section prefix="(3)">after the distribution under item (2) of this subsection, distribute the remainder of the money collected under this subsection to the Waiting List Equity Fund established under &#xA7; 7-205 of the Health - General Article to be used to provide community-based services to individuals who are on the Developmental Disabilities Administration waiting list and are eligible for, but not receiving, services from the Administration.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
