<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-1101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-13-1101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, an assessment of financial institution franchise tax, public service company franchise tax, income tax, or estate tax may not be made after 3 years from the later of:<section prefix="(1)">the date that the return is filed; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the date that the return is due.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An assessment of financial institution franchise tax, public service company franchise tax, income tax, or estate tax may be made at any time if:<section prefix="(1)">a false return is filed with the intent to evade the tax;</section><section prefix="(2)">a willful attempt is made to evade the tax;</section><section prefix="(3)">a return is not filed as required under Title 7, Title 8, or Title 10 of this article;</section><section prefix="(4)">an amended estate tax return is not filed as required under Title 7 of this article;</section><section prefix="(5)">an incomplete return is filed; or</section><section prefix="(6)">a report of federal adjustment is not filed within the period required under &#xA7; 13-409 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a report of federal adjustment is filed within the time required under &#xA7; 13-409 of this title, the tax collector shall assess the financial institution franchise tax, public service company franchise tax, income tax, or estate tax within 1 year after the date on which the tax collector receives the report.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, an assessment of income tax or estate tax arising out of an amended return shall be made within 3 years after the date that the amended return is filed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An assessment of income tax under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be related to changes made by the amended items in the return.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
