<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-910" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-10-910</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">At the time of employment, an employee shall sign and file with the employer an exemption certificate that states the number of exemptions to which the employee is entitled under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, an employer shall base withholding for an employee:<section prefix="(i)">on the number of exemptions stated in the exemption certificate that the employee files; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the employee fails to file an exemption certificate or files an invalid certificate under subsection (c) of this section, on 1 exemption.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Comptroller notifies an employer that an employee has an unpaid tax liability, that the employee failed to file a required Maryland income tax return, or that an employee is subject to a tax refund interception request, the employer shall base withholding for the employee:<section prefix="(i)">on a number of exemptions not exceeding the actual number of exemptions allowed on the employee's prior year's income tax return, as specified by the Comptroller; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the employee failed to file a required Maryland income tax return, on 1 exemption.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An exemption certificate is invalid if it:<section prefix="(i)">does not contain the information required; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">contains false or fraudulent information.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An exemption certificate is not invalid if it states:<section prefix="(i)">a number of exemptions that is less than the number of exemptions to which the individual is entitled under &#xA7; 10-211 of this title; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a number of additional exemptions less than or equal to the fraction, rounded down to the nearest whole number:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person who is entitled to receive a payment subject to withholding of winnings derived from wagering shall complete, under oath, and give to the payor a withholding certificate that contains the name, address, state of residence, and taxpayer identification number of:<section prefix="(1)">the person who is to receive the payment; and</section><section prefix="(2)">each person entitled to any portion of the payment.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
