<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-731" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-10-731</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL JUNE 30, 2016 PER CHAPTER 3 OF 2012 //<section prefix="(a)"><section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section><section prefix="(2)">"Department" means the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene.</section><section prefix="(3)">"Fund" means the Health Enterprise Zone Reserve Fund established under &#xA7; 20-1406 of the Health - General Article.</section><section prefix="(4)">"Health Enterprise Zone" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 20-1401 of the Health - General Article.</section><section prefix="(5)">"Health Enterprise Zone practitioner" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 20-1401 of the Health - General Article.</section><section prefix="(6)">"Qualified employee" means a Health Enterprise Zone practitioner, community health worker, or interpreter who:<section prefix="(i)">provides direct support to a Health Enterprise Zone practitioner; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">expands access to services in a Health Enterprise Zone.</section></section><section prefix="(7)"><section prefix="(i)">"Qualified position" means a qualified employee position that:</section><section prefix="(ii)">"Qualified position" does not include a position that is filled for a period of less than 12 months.</section></section></section><section prefix="(b)">A Health Enterprise Zone practitioner who practices health care in a Health Enterprise Zone may be eligible for a tax credit against the State income tax in accordance with a proposal approved by the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene, if the individual:<section prefix="(1)">demonstrates competency in cultural, linguistic, and health literacy in a manner determined by the Department;</section><section prefix="(2)">accepts and provides care for patients enrolled in the Maryland Medical Assistance Program and for uninsured patients; and</section><section prefix="(3)">meets any other criteria established by the Department.</section></section><section prefix="(c)"><section prefix="(1)">A nonprofit community-based organization or a local government agency that submits a proposal to the Department and the Community Health Resources Commission under Title 20, Subtitle 14 of the Health - General Article may also submit to the Department a request for certification of eligibility for certain income tax credits on behalf of a Health Enterprise Zone practitioner practicing or seeking to practice in a Health Enterprise Zone.</section><section prefix="(2)">The proposal shall meet the requirements specified under Title 20, Subtitle 14 of the Health - General Article.</section></section><section prefix="(d)"><section prefix="(1)">If the Department approves a request for certification submitted under this section, a Health Enterprise Zone practitioner may claim a credit against the State income tax in an amount equal to 100% of the amount of the State income tax expected to be due from the Health Enterprise Zone practitioner from income to be derived from practice in the Health Enterprise Zone, as certified by the Department for the taxable year.</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">In addition to the State income tax credit provided under paragraph (1) of this subsection, a Health Enterprise Zone practitioner may claim a refundable credit of $10,000 against the State income tax for hiring for a qualified position in the Health Enterprise Zone, as certified by the Department for the taxable year.</section><section prefix="(ii)">To be eligible for the credit provided under this paragraph, a Health Enterprise Zone practitioner may create one or more qualified positions during any 24-month period.</section><section prefix="(iii)">The credit earned under this paragraph shall be taken over a 24-month period, with one-half for the credit amount allowed each year beginning with the first taxable year in which the credit is certified.</section><section prefix="(iv)">If the qualified position is filled for a period of less than 24 months, the tax credit shall be recaptured as follows:</section></section><section prefix="(3)"><section prefix="(i)">To be certified as eligible for the credits provided under this section, a Health Enterprise Zone practitioner may apply for certification through the nonprofit community-based organization or local government that submits an approved proposal under Title 20, Subtitle 14 of the Health - General Article.</section><section prefix="(ii)"/></section></section><section prefix="(e)">The Department shall certify to the Comptroller the applicability of the credit provided under this section for each Health Enterprise Zone practitioner and the amount of each credit assigned to a Health Enterprise Zone practitioner, for each taxable year.</section><section prefix="(f)">The credits allowed under this section for a fiscal year may not exceed the amount provided for in the State budget for that fiscal year.</section><section prefix="(g)">The Department, in consultation with the Comptroller, shall adopt regulations to implement the tax credit under this section.</section></text>
</law>
