<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-10-717</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>717</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An individual who is a classroom teacher or a teacher at a State or local correctional facility or a juvenile facility listed in &#xA7; 9-226 of the Human Services Article and who holds a standard professional certificate or an advanced professional certificate may claim a credit against the State income tax for up to $1,500 of tuition paid by the individual during the taxable year for graduate level courses required to maintain certification if the individual:<section prefix="(1)">successfully completes the courses with a grade of B or better;</section><section prefix="(2)">is employed by a county board of educationa State or local correctional facility, or a juvenile facility listed in &#xA7; 9-226 of the Human Services Article;</section><section prefix="(3)">teaches in a public schoola State or local correctional facility, or a juvenile facility listed in &#xA7; 9-226 of the Human Services Article and receives a satisfactory performance evaluation for that teaching; and</section><section prefix="(4)">has not been reimbursed by the State or a county for the tuition paid.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a countythe State or local correctional facility, or a juvenile facility listed in &#xA7; 9-226 of the Human Services Article partially reimburses an individual for tuition paid, the individual may claim a tax credit allowed under this section for the balance of the tuition not paid by the county or the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The credit allowed under this section may not exceed the State income tax for that taxable year, calculated before the application of the credits allowed under this section and &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-701 and 10-701.1 of this subtitle but after the application of the other credits allowable under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The unused amount of the credit for any taxable year may not be carried over to any other taxable year.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
