<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-11-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the sales and use tax rate is:<section prefix="(1)">for a taxable price of less than $1:<section prefix="(i)">1 cent if the taxable price is 20 cents;</section><section prefix="(ii)">2 cents if the taxable price is at least 21 cents but less than 34 cents;</section><section prefix="(iii)">3 cents if the taxable price is at least 34 cents but less than 51 cents;</section><section prefix="(iv)">4 cents if the taxable price is at least 51 cents but less than 67 cents;</section><section prefix="(v)">5 cents if the taxable price is at least 67 cents but less than 84 cents; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">6 cents if the taxable price is at least 84 cents; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">for a taxable price of $1 or more:<section prefix="(i)">6 cents for each exact dollar; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">for that part of a dollar in excess of an exact dollar:<section prefix="1.">1 cent if the excess over an exact dollar is at least 1 cent but less than 17 cents;</section><section prefix="2.">2 cents if the excess over an exact dollar is at least 17 cents but less than 34 cents;</section><section prefix="3.">3 cents if the excess over an exact dollar is at least 34 cents but less than 51 cents;</section><section prefix="4.">4 cents if the excess over an exact dollar is at least 51 cents but less than 67 cents;</section><section prefix="5.">5 cents if the excess over an exact dollar is at least 67 cents but less than 84 cents; and</section><section prefix="6.">6 cents if the excess over an exact dollar is at least 84 cents.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a retail sale of tangible personal property or a taxable service is made through a vending or other self-service machine, the sales and use tax rate is 6%, applied to 94.5% of the gross receipts from the vending machine sales.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">"short-term vehicle rental" means a rental of a passenger car, as defined in &#xA7; 11-144.1 of the Transportation Article, or a vehicle that may be registered as a Class E, F, G, or M vehicle under Title 13, Subtitle 9 of the Transportation Article, for a period of 180 days or less under the following terms:<section prefix="1.">the vendor does not provide a driver for the vehicle as a part of the rental; and</section><section prefix="2.">if the vehicle is a passenger car, as defined in &#xA7; 11-144.1 of the Transportation Article, or a multipurpose passenger vehicle, the vehicle is not to be used to transport individuals or property for hire; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">"short-term vehicle rental" does not include a rental of:<section prefix="1.">a dump truck, as described in &#xA7; 13-919 of the Transportation Article;</section><section prefix="2.">a tow truck, as described in &#xA7; 13-920 of the Transportation Article; or</section><section prefix="3.">a farm vehicle exempt from the sales and use tax under &#xA7; 11-201(a) of this title.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The sales and use tax rate for a short-term vehicle rental for a taxable price of $2 or more is:<section prefix="(i)">if the vehicle is a passenger car or a multipurpose passenger vehicle:<section prefix="1.">23 cents for each exact multiple of $2; and</section><section prefix="2.">for that part of $2 in excess of an exact multiple of $2:</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">if the vehicle is a vehicle that may be registered as a Class E, F, or G vehicle under Title 13, Subtitle 9 of the Transportation Article:<section prefix="1.">8 cents for each exact dollar; and</section><section prefix="2.">2 cents for each 25 cents or part of 25 cents in excess of an exact dollar.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The sales and use tax rate for the first retail sale of a manufactured home, as defined in &#xA7; 12-301(g) of the Public Safety Article, is the rate imposed under subsection (a) of this section applied to 60% of the taxable price.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The rate of the hotel surcharge imposed under &#xA7; 11-102(b) of this subtitle is 2.5% of the taxable price.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "modular building" includes single-family or multifamily houses, apartment units, or commercial buildings, and permanent additions to single-family or multifamily houses, apartment units, or commercial buildings, comprised of one or more sections that are:<section prefix="(i)">intended to become real property;</section><section prefix="(ii)">primarily constructed at a location other than the permanent site at which they are to be assembled;</section><section prefix="(iii)">built to comply with the standards for industrialized buildings under Title 12, Subtitle 3 of the Public Safety Article; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">shipped with most permanent components in place.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The sales and use tax rate for the sale of a modular building is the rate imposed under subsection (a) of this section applied to 60% of the taxable price.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The sales and use tax rate for the sale of an alcoholic beverage, as defined in &#xA7; 5-101 of this article, is:<section prefix="(1)">9% of the charge for the alcoholic beverage; and</section><section prefix="(2)">6% of a charge that is made in connection with the sale of an alcoholic beverage and is stated as a separate item of the consideration and made known to the buyer at the time of sale for:<section prefix="(i)">any labor or service rendered;</section><section prefix="(ii)">any material used; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">any property sold.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Dyed diesel fuel" means diesel fuel that is dyed under U.S. Environmental Protection Agency rules for high sulfur diesel fuel or is dyed under Internal Revenue Service rules for nontaxable use.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Marina" means a person who maintains a place of business where motor fuel is sold primarily to vessels.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a retail sale of dyed diesel fuel is made by a marina, the sales and use tax rate is 6%, applied to 94.5% of the gross receipts from the dyed diesel fuel sales.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The sales and use tax rate for a mandatory gratuity or service charge in the nature of a tip for serving food or any type of beverage to a group of more than 10 individuals is 6%.</section>
  </text>
</law>
