<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-221" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-7-221</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If within 15 years after the date of a decedent's death, property valued under &#xA7; 7-211 of this subtitle is disqualified for the special valuation, additional inheritance tax is due in the amount of the difference between the inheritance tax paid and the inheritance tax that would have been paid if the election under &#xA7; 7-211 of this subtitle had not been made.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Property is disqualified for the special valuation under &#xA7; 7-211 of this subtitle, if:<section prefix="(i)">the property qualified for valuation as National Register property and is removed from the National Register of Historic Places; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the property qualified for valuation as farmland or woodland and ceases to qualify for farmland or woodland assessment under &#xA7; 8-209 or &#xA7; 8-211 of the Tax - Property Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department or the Maryland Historical Trust shall report to the Comptroller and the register any event that causes property to be disqualified for special valuation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The property owner may submit to the appropriate register an application for a certificate that a disqualifying event has not occurred before a date that is stated in the certificate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The application shall:<section prefix="(i)">be made on the form and in the manner that the Comptroller requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">include appropriate certifications of the property owner.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After receiving the application, the register shall inquire about the property with:<section prefix="(i)">the Department, for farmland or woodland property; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Maryland Historical Trust, for property listed on the National Register of Historic Places.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department or Maryland Historical Trust shall report to the register about the property.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If, based on the certifications of the property owner and the report under subsection (c)(2) of this section, the register determines that a disqualifying event has not occurred, the register shall issue a certificate of nondisqualification, on the form and in the manner that the Comptroller determines.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The date stated in a certificate of nondisqualification shall be:<section prefix="(1)">on or after the application date; and</section><section prefix="(2)">as close as possible to the date on which the certificate is issued.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A grantee of the property and the successors or assigns of the grantee may rely conclusively on the certificate issued under subsection (d) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
