<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-9-322</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>322</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A Class "A" license authorizes the licensee to:<section prefix="(1)">import into this State gasoline on which the motor fuel tax has not been paid;</section><section prefix="(2)">export from this State gasoline on which the motor fuel tax has not been paid; and</section><section prefix="(3)">acquire in this State from another holder of a Class "A" license gasoline on which the motor fuel tax has not been paid.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A Class "B" license authorizes the licensee to import into this State gasoline on which the motor fuel tax has not been paid, for personal use or for redistribution.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A holder of a Class "B" license may not acquire in this State gasoline on which the motor fuel tax has not been paid.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A Class "C" license authorizes the licensee to:<section prefix="(i)">acquire, in this State, from a supplier whom the Comptroller specifically approves, gasoline on which the motor fuel tax has not been paid; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">export that gasoline.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A holder of a Class "C" license may not import into this State gasoline on which the motor fuel tax has not been paid.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A Class "D" license authorizes the licensee to acquire, in this State, gasoline on which the motor fuel tax has not been paid from:<section prefix="(i)">a holder of a Class "A" license; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">another holder of a Class "D" license.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless authorized by the Comptroller, a holder of a Class "D" license may not import into this State gasoline on which the motor fuel tax has not been paid.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A Class "F" license authorizes the licensee to engage, in this State, in the business of a turbine fuel seller.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A Class "G-Temporary" license authorizes the licensee during the term of the federal contract for which the license is issued to:<section prefix="(i)">acquire, in this State, gasoline on which the motor fuel tax has not been paid, in the amount that the contract specifies and from a supplier whom the Comptroller specifically approves; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">deliver that amount to the location that the contract specifies.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A Class "G-Temporary" license may be extended if:<section prefix="(i)">the original federal contract is extended; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">during the term of the license, another contract is awarded to the licensee.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A Class "S" license authorizes a licensee to engage, in this State, in the business of a special fuel seller.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A Class "U" license authorizes a licensee to engage, in this State, in the business of a special fuel user.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A Class "W" license authorizes a licensee to engage, in this State, in the business of a distributor.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">A dealer who holds any class of license because the dealer was licensed before July 1, 1985 has the privileges authorized for that class until the dealer is required to apply for a new license, in accordance with regulations of the Comptroller in effect as of July 1, 1985.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">As indicated on an exemption certificate, the certificate authorizes the holder to acquire, in bulk and without paying the motor fuel tax:<section prefix="(1)">special fuel other than turbine fuel; or</section><section prefix="(2)">turbine fuel.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
