<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-204" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-8-204</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A financial institution shall compute its net earnings:<section prefix="(1)">based on the accounting period used as its fiscal year; and</section><section prefix="(2)">subject to the modifications required under this section, in the manner that a corporation computes, for purposes of the income tax, the Maryland modified income.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A financial institution shall add to its net earnings computed under subsection (a) of this section the amounts that, even if otherwise allowed to be subtracted under &#xA7; 10-307(b) and (g)(1) and (4) of this article, equal:<section prefix="(1)">profit realized from the sale or exchange of bonds issued by this State or a political subdivision of this State;</section><section prefix="(2)">dividends received from foreign corporations and included in federal gross income under &#xA7; 78 of the Internal Revenue Code;</section><section prefix="(3)">interest derived from a United States obligation;</section><section prefix="(4)">State tax-exempt interest received from a mutual fund and allowed to be subtracted under &#xA7; 10-307(g)(4) of this article; and</section><section prefix="(5)">interest excluded from federal gross income under &#xA7; 103 of the Internal Revenue Code and derived from a bond:<section prefix="(i)">issued by a state or a public corporation, special district, political subdivision of a state or their instrumentalities; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">under &#xA7; 150 of the Internal Revenue Code, treated as a bond issued by a state or a public corporation, special district, or political subdivision of a state or their instrumentalities.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A financial institution shall subtract from its net earnings computed under subsection (a) of this section interest expense incurred to purchase or carry a bond as defined in subsection (b)(5) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
