<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-13-834</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>834</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this Part VI of this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Contraband alcoholic beverage" means an alcoholic beverage, as defined in &#xA7; 5-101 of this article:<section prefix="(1)">on which alcoholic beverage tax is not paid; and</section><section prefix="(2)">that is delivered, possessed, sold, or transported in the State in a manner not authorized under Title 5 of this article or Article 2B of the Code.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Contraband tobacco products" means cigarettes or other tobacco products, as defined in &#xA7; 12-101 of this article:<section prefix="(1)">on which tobacco tax is not paid; and</section><section prefix="(2)">that are delivered, possessed, sold, or transported in the State in a manner not authorized under Title 12 of this article or Title 16 of the Business Regulation Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Contraband motor fuel" means motor fuel, as defined in &#xA7; 9-101 of this article:<section prefix="(1)">on which motor fuel tax is not paid; and</section><section prefix="(2)">that is delivered, possessed, sold, or transferred in the State in a manner not authorized under Title 9 of this article or Title 10 of the Business Regulation Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Conveyance" means:<section prefix="(1)">an aircraft, vehicle, or vessel used to transport alcoholic beverages, cigarettes, or other tobacco products; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a tank car, vehicle, or vessel that is used to transport motor fuel and that, exclusive of any tank used for its own propulsion, has a capacity exceeding 50 gallons.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
