<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-10-209</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>209</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section:<section prefix="(1)">"employee retirement system" means a plan:<section prefix="(i)">established and maintained by an employer for the benefit of its employees; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">qualified under &#xA7; 401(a), &#xA7; 403, or &#xA7; 457(b) of the Internal Revenue Code; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">"employee retirement system" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">an individual retirement account or annuity under &#xA7; 408 of the Internal Revenue Code;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a Roth individual retirement account under &#xA7; 408A of the Internal Revenue Code;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a rollover individual retirement account;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a simplified employee pension under Internal Revenue Code &#xA7; 408(k); or</section><section prefix="(v)">an ineligible deferred compensation plan under &#xA7; 457(f) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to subsection (d) of this section, to determine Maryland adjusted gross income, if, on the last day of the taxable year, a resident is at least 65 years old or is totally disabled or the resident's spouse is totally disabled, an amount is subtracted from federal adjusted gross income equal to the lesser of:<section prefix="(1)">the cumulative or total annuity, pension, or endowment income from an employee retirement system included in federal adjusted gross income; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the maximum annual benefit under the Social Security Act computed under subsection (c) of this section, less any payment received as old age, survivors, or disability benefits under the Social Security Act, the Railroad Retirement Act, or both.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For purposes of subsection (b)(2) of this section, the Comptroller:<section prefix="(1)">shall determine the maximum annual benefit under the Social Security Act allowed for an individual who retired at age 65 for the prior calendar year; and</section><section prefix="(2)">may allow the subtraction to the nearest $100.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Military retirement income that is included in the subtraction under &#xA7; 10-207(q) of this subtitle may not be taken into account for purposes of the subtraction under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
