<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-110" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-10-110</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Maryland Business Tax Reform Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall review and evaluate the State's current business tax structure and make specific recommendations for changes to the State's business tax structure to provide for fair and equitable taxation for all corporations and other business entities doing business in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission's recommendations may include, without limitation, changes such as tax rate changes, tax base broadening measures, measures to address tax avoidance strategies, and elimination of ineffective or inefficient tax policies intended as economic development incentives.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission's study shall include, at a minimum, a review and evaluation of the following options for business tax reform:<section prefix="(i)">the imposition of combined reporting using the "water's edge method" under the corporate income tax for unitary groups of affiliated corporations;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the imposition of other types of business taxes, in lieu of or in addition to the current taxes imposed, including gross receipts taxes, value added taxes, and alternative minimum taxes; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">improved methods for evaluation of the effectiveness and efficiency of tax policies intended as economic development incentives.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission shall be composed of 19 members, as follows:<section prefix="(1)">a chair, appointed by the Governor;</section><section prefix="(2)">three members of the Senate Budget and Taxation Committee, appointed by the President of the Senate;</section><section prefix="(3)">three members of the House Committee on Ways and Means, appointed by the Speaker of the House;</section><section prefix="(4)">the Comptroller of the Treasury, or the Comptroller's designee;</section><section prefix="(5)">the Secretary of Business and Economic Development, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(6)">the Secretary of Budget and Management, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(7)">the Director of the State Department of Assessments and Taxation, or the Director's designee;</section><section prefix="(8)">a representative of the Maryland Association of Counties;</section><section prefix="(9)">a representative of the Maryland Municipal League;</section><section prefix="(10)">a representative of the Maryland Chamber of Commerce;</section><section prefix="(11)">a representative of the Greater Baltimore Committee;</section><section prefix="(12)">a representative of an organization that represents Maryland manufacturers, appointed by the Governor; and</section><section prefix="(13)">three members of the public, each of whom shall be an attorney at law or an accountant knowledgeable about the State's business tax structure, appointed by the Governor.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Comptroller and the Department of Budget and Management shall provide staff support to the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A member of the Commission:<section prefix="(1)">may not receive compensation; but</section><section prefix="(2)">is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">On or before December 15, 2010, the Commission shall submit a final report of its findings and recommendations to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly.</section>
  </text>
</law>
