<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="gtg" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-7-211</section_number>
  <catch_line>The person responsible for paying the inheritance tax may elect to value real property, for purposes...</catch_line>
  <order_by>211</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The person responsible for paying the inheritance tax may elect to value real property, for purposes of the inheritance tax:<section prefix="(1)">at its most recent real property assessment plus any inflation allowance if, for the 5 years immediately before the date of the death of the decedent, the real property qualifies under &#xA7; 8-209 or &#xA7; 8-211 of the Tax - Property Article as farmland or woodland; or</section><section prefix="(2)">based on its actual use on the date of the decedent's death if the real property qualifies as National Register property by a listing in the National Register of Historic Places, whether as a separate property or as a part of a listed district.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To elect a valuation under subsection (a) of this section, the person responsible for paying the inheritance tax shall file with the register a statement that:<section prefix="(i)">contains a written election of a valuation under subsection (a) of this section, in the form and manner that the Comptroller requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">describes the qualifying real property in reasonable detail, including its fair market value.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The statement shall be filed:<section prefix="(i)">with the administration account that affects the distribution of the qualifying real property; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the qualifying real property is not subject to formal administration, with the report or inventory required under &#xA7; 7-224 or &#xA7; 7-225(c) or (d) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
