<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtg" order_by="gtg" level="1">Tax - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-12-304</section_number>
  <catch_line>A manufacturer that pays the tobacco tax shall indicate prominently on each package of cigarettes th...</catch_line>
  <order_by>304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A manufacturer that pays the tobacco tax shall indicate prominently on each package of cigarettes that:<section prefix="(1)">the package contains sample cigarettes that are not for sale; and</section><section prefix="(2)">all applicable tobacco taxes on those cigarettes have been paid.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, within 72 hours after receiving cigarettes in the State and before selling or attempting to sell the cigarettes, a licensed wholesaler who first possesses the cigarettes shall affix, to the smallest cigarette package, tax stamps:<section prefix="(i)">in a total amount that at least equals the tobacco tax due on the number of cigarettes in the package; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">in the manner that the Comptroller requires, including placing the tax stamps on the cigarette package so that the stamps are visible to a buyer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a tax stamp has been affixed to a package of cigarettes, a person may not affix the same tax stamp to another package of cigarettes.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A licensed wholesaler is not required to affix tax stamps to:<section prefix="(1)">sample cigarettes if the cigarette package is marked in accordance with subsection (a) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(2)">cigarettes that are segregated or marked to indicate that the cigarettes:<section prefix="(i)">were received within the immediately preceding 72 hours; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">are being held for a sale or use that is exempt under this title.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (c)(2) of this section, a rebuttable presumption exists that any unstamped cigarettes in the possession of a licensed wholesaler are possessed in violation of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The licensed wholesaler who possesses unstamped cigarettes has the burden of proving that the cigarettes are not possessed in violation of this title.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
