<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-1104" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtg-13-1104</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, a claim for refund under this article may not be filed after 3 years from the date the tax, interest, or penalty was paid.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A claim for refund of alcoholic beverage tax may not be filed after:<section prefix="(1)">90 days from the date of purchase or invoice of exempt alcoholic beverages used by a hospital or religious organization; and</section><section prefix="(2)">6 months from the date on which alcoholic beverages are condemned, lost, or rendered unmarketable.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a claim for refund or credit of overpayment of financial institution franchise tax or income tax may not be filed after the periods of limitations for filing claims for refund or credit of overpayment set forth in &#xA7; 6511 of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A claim for refund or credit of overpayment may not be filed later than 1 year from the date of:<section prefix="(i)">a final adjustment report of the Internal Revenue Service; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a final decision of the highest court of the United States to which an appeal of a final decision of the Internal Revenue Service is taken.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, a refund or credit of overpayment allowed upon a claim filed under this subsection may not exceed the amount of the Maryland tax resulting from the application of the limits set forth in &#xA7; 6511 of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A refund or credit of overpayment allowed upon a claim filed under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be limited to the amount of the reduction in Maryland tax resulting from the federal income tax adjustment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A claim for refund of Maryland estate tax, inheritance tax, or Maryland generation-skipping transfer tax may not be filed after 3 years from the date of the event that caused the refund.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A claim for refund of excess motor carrier tax credit may not be filed after 24 months following the end of the period in which the excess credit was developed.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 13-508 of this title or for a claim under &#xA7; 13-901(a)(1) or (2) of this title, a claim for refund of motor fuel tax may not be filed:<section prefix="(1)">after 1 year from the date of purchase;</section><section prefix="(2)">after October 1, if the claimant elects to file an annual claim for the 12-month period ending June 30; or</section><section prefix="(3)">for a period of less than 1 year, after 3 months following the end of the period for which the claim is filed.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 13-508 of this title, a claim for refund of sales and use tax may not be filed after 4 years from the date the tax was paid.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Except for a claim under &#xA7; 13-901(a)(1) or (2) of this title, a claim for refund of tobacco tax may not be filed after 1 year from the date of the event that caused the refund.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A claim for refund or credit for overpayment of income tax attributable to a credit claimed under &#xA7; 10-703 of this article for the payment of a state tax on income paid to another state may not be filed after the later of:<section prefix="(1)">the end of the limitation period otherwise prescribed under this section; or</section><section prefix="(2)">1 year after the date the taxpayer received notification that the other state's income tax was due.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">Notwithstanding subsection (c) of this section, a claim for refund or credit for overpayment of income tax attributable to a right to a reduction in a person's Maryland income tax that is established by a decision of an administrative board or by an appeal of a decision of an administrative board may be filed within 1 year after the date of a final decision of the administrative board or a final decision of the highest court to which an appeal of a final decision of the administrative board is taken.</section>
  </text>
</law>
