<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-14-911</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>911</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A refund claim shall be approved or denied:<section prefix="(1)">under &#xA7; 14-904 of this subtitle, by the Comptroller;</section><section prefix="(2)">under &#xA7; 14-905 of this subtitle, by the appropriate collector; or</section><section prefix="(3)">except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, under &#xA7; 14-907 or &#xA7; 14-908 of this subtitle, by the Department, clerk, or the Director of Finance that collected the tax.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a refund claim made under &#xA7; 14-907 or &#xA7; 14-908 of this subtitle is not allowed and is not denied on or before 6 months from the date the refund claim is submitted, the person submitting the claim may treat the claim as denied.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a refund claim is made under &#xA7; 14-907 or &#xA7; 14-908 of this subtitle, the Department, clerk, or Director of Finance considering the refund claim shall:<section prefix="(1)">investigate the claim;</section><section prefix="(2)">notify the claimant of an opportunity for a hearing on the claim; and</section><section prefix="(3)">if the claimant requests a hearing on the claim, conduct a hearing.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a claim is determined to be eligible for refund, the agency considering the claim shall request authorization of payment for a claim under:<section prefix="(1)">&#xA7; 14-904 of this subtitle, from the Comptroller;</section><section prefix="(2)">&#xA7; 14-905(a) of this subtitle, from the appropriate county or municipal corporation official; or</section><section prefix="(3)">&#xA7; 14-907 or &#xA7; 14-908 of this subtitle, from the Comptroller or the chief fiscal officer of the county.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The agency determining a claim made under &#xA7; 14-907 or &#xA7; 14-908 of this subtitle shall give written notice to the claimant of:<section prefix="(1)">a denial of the claim by that agency;</section><section prefix="(2)">a denial of payment authorization under subsection (d)(3) of this section by the Comptroller or chief fiscal officer of the county; or</section><section prefix="(3)">a delay in paying an approved claim.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
