<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-7-506.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>506.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "service facilities" includes nondwelling commercial and community facilities, community rooms, dining halls, infirmaries, child and adult day care facilities, and drug rehabilitation facilities.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except in Baltimore City, real property may be exempt from county and municipal corporation property tax if:<section prefix="(i)">the real property is owned by a person engaged in constructing or operating housing structures or projects;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the real property is used for a housing structure or project that is constructed or substantially rehabilitated under a federal, State, or local government program that:<section prefix="1.">funds construction or insures its financing in whole or in part; or</section><section prefix="2.">provides interest subsidy, rent subsidy, or rent supplements;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">the owner and the governing body of the county and, where applicable, the municipal corporation where the real property is located agree that the owner shall pay a negotiated amount in lieu of the applicable county or municipal corporation property tax; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the owner of the real property:<section prefix="1."/><section prefix="2.">enters into an agreement with the governing body of the county or municipal corporation to allow the entire property or the portion of the property which was maintained for lower income persons to remain as housing for lower income persons for a term of at least 5 years.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the structure and facilities of the real property are used predominantly for residential purposes, the real property may contain service facilities to serve its occupants and the surrounding neighborhood.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Real property described in subsection (a) of this section is exempt when the requirements of subsection (a) of this section are met.</section>
  </text>
</law>
