<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="gtp" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-8-224</section_number>
  <catch_line>If a part of any land that meets the requirements of &#xA7; 8-221 of this subtitle is subdivided by a re...</catch_line>
  <order_by>224</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a part of any land that meets the requirements of &#xA7; 8-221 of this subtitle is subdivided by a recorded plat or is improved by the construction of permanent buildings, the assessment of that part under &#xA7; 8-222 of this subtitle shall be terminated, and the part shall be assessed as provided under &#xA7; 8-104 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The remaining part of the land described under paragraph (1) of this subsection may continue to be assessed under &#xA7; 8-222 of this subtitle if the remainder meets all of the requirements of &#xA7; 8-221 of this subtitle other than the 500-acre requirement.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a part of any land that meets the requirements of &#xA7; 8-221 of this subtitle is rezoned at the request of the owner to a zoning classification that does not meet the requirements of &#xA7; 8-221 of this subtitle, the assessment of that part under &#xA7; 8-222 of this subtitle shall be terminated and the part shall be assessed at the greater value determined under &#xA7; 8-223 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When a property is assessed under paragraph (1) of this subsection, a deferred property tax is due for the amount of the difference, if any, between the assessment of the land under &#xA7; 8-222 of this subtitle and the assessment under &#xA7; 8-223 of this subtitle for each year in which the assessment was determined under &#xA7; 8-222 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The total of the deferred property tax due may not exceed 4% of the assessment under &#xA7; 8-223 of this subtitle in effect at the time of rezoning under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The proceeds of the deferred property tax are collected and distributed as provided by Title 13 of this article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
