<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-109" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-109</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Mayor and the City Council of Baltimore City and the governing body of each county and of each municipal corporation shall grant a property tax credit under this section against the county or municipal corporation property tax imposed on real property if:<section prefix="(1)">the homeowner is otherwise eligible for the credit allowed under &#xA7; 9-105 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">the dwelling is:</section><section prefix="(ii)">the dwelling is revalued after the dwelling is repaired or reconstructed; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">as a result of the revaluation, the assessment of the dwelling exceeds the last assessment of the dwelling; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">the homeowner claiming the credit had a legal interest in the dwelling at the time the dwelling was damaged or destroyed as described under item (2) of this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The amount of the property tax credit allowed under this section shall equal 100% of the property tax attributable to an increase in the assessment of the dwelling upon revaluation under &#xA7; 8-104(c)(1)(iii) of this article, including improvements, over the last assessment of the dwelling before the natural disaster, less the amount of any assessment on which a property tax credit under &#xA7; 9-105 of this subtitle has been authorized.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A credit under this section may not be granted for more than 5 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the governing body of a county or municipal corporation shall:<section prefix="(1)">establish procedures or requirements for the application, review, and approval of tax credits under this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">notify the Department of any credits that have been granted under this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The credit under this section may not be claimed for a dwelling for which repair or reconstruction is completed before September 18, 2003.</section>
  </text>
</law>
