<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-309" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-309</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The governing body of Cecil County and of a municipal corporation in Cecil County shall grant a property tax credit under this section against the county and municipal corporation property tax imposed on:<section prefix="(1)">property that is owned by the Society for the Preservation of Maryland Antiquities, Incorporated; and</section><section prefix="(2)">property that is owned by the Friends of the Library of Cecil County, Maryland, Incorporated.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The governing body of Cecil County or of a municipal corporation in Cecil County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county or municipal corporation property tax imposed on:<section prefix="(1)">property that is owned by the Upper Chesapeake Watershed Association and is used:<section prefix="(i)">to assist in the preservation of a wild nature area;</section><section prefix="(ii)">to establish a nature reserve or other protected area; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">generally to promote conservation;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">property that is owned by an incorporated, nonprofit fire company or rescue squad, if the property:<section prefix="(i)">is leased for more than 60 days during any 12-month period under a contractual agreement for the operation of the fire company's fire hall; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">would qualify for the exemption under &#xA7; 7-209 of this article if leased for not more than 60 days during any 12-month period; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">property that:<section prefix="(i)">is owned by:</section><section prefix="(ii)">is actually used exclusively for the purposes of a little league organization of Cecil County.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of a municipal corporation in Cecil County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the municipal corporation property tax imposed on residential real property that is:<section prefix="(i)">owned by an individual serving as a member of a volunteer fire company as defined under &#xA7; 3-1101 of the Courts and Judicial Proceedings Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">occupied as the principal residence of an individual serving as a member of a volunteer fire company as defined under &#xA7; 3-1101 of the Courts and Judicial Proceedings Article; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">located within the jurisdiction of the municipal corporation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The municipal corporation may provide, by law, for:<section prefix="(i)">the amount of a property tax credit under this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the duration of a property tax credit under this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">any other provision necessary to carry out this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
