<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The governing body of Anne Arundel County and of a municipal corporation in Anne Arundel County shall grant a property tax credit under this section against the county and municipal corporation property tax imposed on:<section prefix="(1)">property that is:<section prefix="(i)">owned by the United States Naval Academy Alumni Association, Incorporated;</section><section prefix="(ii)">located at the corner of College Avenue and King George Street in Annapolis, Maryland; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">known as Ogle Hall;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">property that is:<section prefix="(i)">owned by the Naval Academy Athletic Association; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">used for athletic events and purposes;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">real property that is owned by the Three Rivers Sportsmen, Incorporated; and</section><section prefix="(4)">property that is owned by the Maryland Ornithological Society, Incorporated.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Anne Arundel County or of a municipal corporation in Anne Arundel County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county or municipal corporation tax imposed on real property that is:<section prefix="(i)">owned by a nonprofit community civic association or corporation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">dedicated by plat or deed restriction to the use of the lot owners in the community, if the use is not contingent on the payment of:<section prefix="1.">dues to the association or corporation, unless the dues are used only to improve or maintain the property of the community; or</section><section prefix="2.">compensation for admission to or use of the property, unless the compensation is used only to improve or maintain the property of the community.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body of Anne Arundel County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county tax imposed on real property that is:<section prefix="(i)">owned by the Village Commons Community Center, Incorporated; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">leased by Anne Arundel Community College at Arundel Mills.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The governing body of Anne Arundel County or of a municipal corporation in Anne Arundel County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county or municipal corporation tax imposed on real property that is owned by Arundel Habitat for Humanity, Inc., and is located at 8101 Fort Smallwood Road, Baltimore, Maryland or 8104 Parkway Drive, Baltimore, Maryland.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The governing body of Anne Arundel County or of a municipal corporation in Anne Arundel County may provide, by law, for:<section prefix="1.">the amount, terms, scope, and duration of the credit granted under this paragraph; and</section><section prefix="2.">any other provision necessary to administer the credit granted under this paragraph.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The governing body of Anne Arundel County or of a municipal corporation in Anne Arundel County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county or municipal corporation property tax imposed on real property that is:<section prefix="1.">leased to a public charter school, as defined in &#xA7; 9-102 of the Education Article; and</section><section prefix="2.">used exclusively for primary or secondary educational purposes.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The governing body of Anne Arundel County or of a municipal corporation in Anne Arundel County may provide, by law, for:<section prefix="1.">the amount and duration of the tax credit under this paragraph;</section><section prefix="2.">additional eligibility criteria for the tax credit under this paragraph, including a requirement that the tax credit benefit the public charter school;</section><section prefix="3.">regulations and procedures for the application and uniform processing of requests for the tax credit; and</section><section prefix="4.">any other provision necessary to carry out the credit under this paragraph.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The governing body of Anne Arundel County shall grant a property tax credit under this section against county property tax imposed on real property that is owned by the Davidsonville Ruritan Foundation, Incorporated.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The governing body of Anne Arundel County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county tax imposed on real property that is subject to the State's or county's agricultural land preservation program.</section>
  </text>
</law>
