<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-220</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>220</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Conservation land" means real property that is:<section prefix="(i)">subject to a perpetual conservation easement donated to a land trust, the Department of Natural Resources, or the Maryland Environmental Trust on or after July 1, 1991;</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">acquired by a land trust on or after July 1, 1991; and</section><section prefix="2.">owned in fee by that land trust;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">owned by the Potomac Conservancy; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">owned by the Western Shore Conservancy.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Land trust" means a qualified conservation organization as defined in &#xA7; 3-2A-01 of the Natural Resources Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the governing body of a county or municipal corporation may grant, by law, a property tax credit against the county or municipal corporation property tax imposed on conservation land or property owned by a land trust that qualifies under subsection (d) of this section, that is used:<section prefix="(1)">to assist in the preservation of a natural area;</section><section prefix="(2)">for the environmental education of the public;</section><section prefix="(3)">generally to promote conservation;</section><section prefix="(4)">for the maintenance of:<section prefix="(i)">a natural area for public use; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a sanctuary for wildlife; or</section></section><section prefix="(5)">to conserve agricultural land and to promote continued agricultural use of the land.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the governing body of a county or municipal corporation may provide, by law, for:<section prefix="(1)">the amount and duration of the property tax credit under this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">any other provision necessary to carry out the property tax credit under this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">To qualify for a property tax credit under this section, a land trust shall:<section prefix="(1)">be certified by the Maryland Environmental Trust to be a land trust in good standing and to have a cooperative agreement in effect; and</section><section prefix="(2)">obtain a written certification every 5 years beginning July 1, 1998, or as scheduled by the Maryland Environmental Trust.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
