<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="gtp" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-322</section_number>
  <catch_line>The governing body of Talbot County and the governing body of a municipal corporation in Talbot Coun...</catch_line>
  <order_by>322</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The governing body of Talbot County and the governing body of a municipal corporation in Talbot County shall grant a property tax credit under this section against the county and municipal corporation property tax imposed on:<section prefix="(1)">property that:<section prefix="(i)">is owned by the Academy of the Arts, Easton, Maryland, Incorporated;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is used primarily for the purpose of the organization; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">is not used primarily for revenue or income-producing purposes;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">property that is:<section prefix="(i)">owned by the Bailey's Neck Park Association; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">used for charitable purposes;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">property that is owned by the Maryland Ornithological Society, Incorporated, or any of its chapters; and</section><section prefix="(4)">property that is owned by the Tuckahoe Steam and Gas Association, Incorporated.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The governing body of Talbot County or of a municipal corporation in Talbot County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county or municipal corporation property tax imposed on:<section prefix="(1)">property that is owned by the Chesapeake Audubon Society, Inc. and is used solely for:<section prefix="(i)">the environmental education of the public; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the maintenance of:<section prefix="1.">a natural area for public use; or</section><section prefix="2.">a sanctuary for wildlife; and</section></section></section><section prefix="(2)">personal property that is:<section prefix="(i)">owned by Chesapeake Wildlife Heritage, Incorporated;</section><section prefix="(ii)">used primarily for the purpose of the organization; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">not used primarily for revenue or income-producing purposes.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Talbot County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county property tax imposed on real property that is:<section prefix="(i)">owned or occupied by a commercial or industrial business that is currently or will be doing business in Talbot County; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">new construction or a substantial improvement to the real property.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body of Talbot County may:<section prefix="(i)">set, by law, the amount, terms, scope, and duration of a credit granted under paragraph (1) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">adopt any provision necessary to administer a credit granted under paragraph (1) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">provide for any other restriction or condition considered desirable on the granting of a credit under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Talbot County or of a municipal corporation in Talbot County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county or municipal corporation property tax imposed on personal property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body of Talbot County or of a municipal corporation in Talbot County may, by law:<section prefix="(i)">set the amount, terms, scope, and duration of a credit granted under paragraph (1) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">designate subclasses of personal property under &#xA7; 8-101(c) of this article to which a credit granted under paragraph (1) of this subsection applies;</section><section prefix="(iii)">provide for any restriction or condition considered desirable on the granting of a credit under paragraph (1) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">adopt any other provisions necessary to administer a credit granted under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Talbot County or of a municipal corporation in Talbot County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county or municipal corporation property tax that is imposed on real property that is:<section prefix="(i)">owned by Habitat for Humanity of Talbot &amp; Dorchester Counties, Inc. with the intention of relinquishing ownership in the immediate future;</section><section prefix="(ii)">used exclusively for the purpose of rehabilitation and transfer to a private owner; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">not occupied by administrative or warehouse buildings owned by Habitat for Humanity.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Habitat for Humanity of Talbot &amp; Dorchester Counties, Inc. shall submit an annual written report to the governing body of Talbot County documenting:<section prefix="(i)">all of Habitat for Humanity of Talbot &amp; Dorchester Counties, Inc.'s real property holdings in Talbot County; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">all transactions involving Habitat for Humanity of Talbot &amp; Dorchester Counties, Inc.'s real property holdings in Talbot County.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The governing body of Talbot County or of a municipal corporation in Talbot County may, by law:<section prefix="(i)">set the amount, terms, scope, and duration of a credit granted under paragraph (1) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">adopt any provision necessary to administer a credit granted under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
