<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-103" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-3-103</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, each board consists of 3 regular members and 1 alternate member.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In Anne Arundel County, Baltimore City, Baltimore County, Montgomery County, and Prince George's County, each board consists of 3 regular members and 3 alternate members.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Governor shall appoint the members from a list of names submitted as follows:<section prefix="(i)">for Baltimore City, by the Mayor of Baltimore City; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">for a county other than Baltimore City, by:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The number of names on each list shall be 3 times the number of vacancies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Each list shall be submitted at least 3 months before the end of a term.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Before taking office, each appointee to the board shall take the oath required by Article I, &#xA7; 9 of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 5 years. The term ends on June 1 of the appropriate year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the board on July 1, 1985.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">An alternate member fills a vacancy of a regular member until the vacancy is permanently filled. However, if an alternate member is appointed by the Governor as the regular member, the Governor shall appoint a new alternate member.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The board chairman or the Administrator may ask an alternate member to serve on the board during the temporary absence of a regular member. However, an alternate may not serve on the board when the 3 regular members are present.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor may remove a member only for incompetence, malfeasance, conduct unbecoming a board member, or inability or failure to perform the duties of the office on a regular basis.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After giving a member notice and an opportunity for a hearing, the Mayor of Baltimore City, the county commissioners or the county council of the county, or if the county charter provides for a county executive, the county executive with the approval of the county council, may recommend the removal of the member by the Governor for the grounds listed in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
