<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-312" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-312</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Frederick County and of a municipal corporation in Frederick County shall grant a property tax credit under this section against the county and municipal corporation property tax imposed on property that:<section prefix="(i)">is owned by the Frederick Optimist Boy's Foundation, Incorporated; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is not under a lease or rented commercially.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In paragraph (1) of this subsection, commercial renting does not include the operation of a parking lot.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Frederick County shall grant a property tax credit under this section against the county tax imposed on:<section prefix="(i)">real property that is owned by the Emmitsburg Civic Association, Incorporated; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">real property on which an improvement is made to an existing structure that is located in a historic district.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A property tax credit granted under paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection shall be:<section prefix="(i)">the following percentage of the increase that is due to the improvement:</section><section prefix="(ii)">ended after the 5th taxable year that the improved structure is subject to county property tax.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Frederick County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county property tax imposed on:<section prefix="(i)">real property that is owned by Ruritan National;</section><section prefix="(ii)">real property that is owned by any Ruritan club that is affiliated with Ruritan National;</section><section prefix="(iii)">real property that is owned by a nonprofit community or civic association or corporation and is used only for:</section><section prefix="(iv)">real property owned by the Audubon Society of Central Maryland, Inc. and appurtenant to the premises of the Audubon Society of Central Maryland, Inc., if the property is used only for:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless the compensation is used only to improve or maintain the real property, the use of the real property under paragraph (1)(iii) of this subsection may not be contingent on the payment of compensation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Unless the compensation is used only to improve or maintain the real property, the real property under paragraph (1)(iii) of this subsection may not be granted a property tax credit if failure to pay compensation is a reason to deny admission to or use of the property.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The governing body of Frederick County and of a municipal corporation in Frederick County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county or municipal corporation property tax imposed on real property that is:<section prefix="(1)">leased to the Frederick County Board of County Commissioners or to the Frederick County Board of Education; and</section><section prefix="(2)">used exclusively for public school educational purposes.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The governing body of Frederick County and of a municipal corporation in Frederick County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county or municipal corporation property tax imposed on real property that is:<section prefix="(1)">leased to a nonprofit school; and</section><section prefix="(2)">used exclusively for primary or secondary educational purposes.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A taxpayer may apply for a property tax credit under this section on or before October 1 of the taxable year.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "agricultural preservation land" means:<section prefix="(i)">real property subject to an easement or other interest that is permanently conveyed or assigned to preserve the agricultural use of the real property; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">real property that the governing body of Frederick County has designated as being within an agricultural preservation district.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body of Frederick County may grant, by law, a property tax credit of up to 100% of any county property tax imposed on agricultural preservation land.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The governing body of Frederick County may provide, by law, for any procedural or enforcement provisions necessary to carry out this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Valuation and assessment of agricultural preservation land shall be made in the same manner as any other real property in the county.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Frederick County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county property tax imposed on a building that is:<section prefix="(i)">located on land that qualifies for an agricultural use assessment; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">used in connection with an activity that is recognized by the Department as an approved agricultural activity.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body of Frederick County:<section prefix="(i)">shall develop criteria necessary to implement the credit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall designate an agency to administer the credit; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">may specify:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Affiliate" means a person:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Business entity" means a person conducting a trade or business in the State that is subject to the State individual or corporate income tax or insurance premiums tax.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">"Full-time position" means a position requiring at least 840 hours of an individual's time during at least 24 weeks in a 6-month period.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">"New or expanded premises" means commercial or industrial real property, including a building or part of a building that has not been previously occupied, where a business entity or its affiliates locate to conduct business.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)"/>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body of Frederick County may grant, by law, a property tax credit against the county property tax imposed on real property owned or leased by a business entity that meets the requirements specified for the tax credit under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">To qualify for a property tax credit under this subsection, before a business entity obtains the new or expanded premises or hires employees to fill the new permanent full-time positions at the new or expanded premises, the business entity shall provide written notification to the governing body of Frederick County stating:<section prefix="(i)">that the business entity intends to claim the property tax credit; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">when the business entity expects to obtain the new or expanded premises and hire the required number of employees in the new permanent full-time positions.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">To qualify for a property tax credit under this subsection, an existing business entity in the county shall:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">To qualify for the property tax credit under this subsection, a new business entity locating in the county shall:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If an existing business entity in the county meets the requirements of paragraph (4)(i) of this subsection, the property tax credit granted under this subsection shall equal a percentage of the amount of property tax imposed on the assessment of the new or expanded premises, as follows:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a new business entity locating in the county meets the requirements of paragraph (4)(ii) of this subsection, the property tax credit granted under this subsection shall equal a percentage of the amount of property tax imposed on the assessment of the new or expanded premises, as follows:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The lessor of real property granted a property tax credit under this subsection shall reduce the amount of taxes for which a business entity is contractually liable under the lease agreement by the amount of any credit granted under this subsection for improvements made by the business entity.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The governing body of Frederick County shall provide, by law, for:<section prefix="(i)">the specific requirements for eligibility for a property tax credit authorized under this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">any additional limitations on eligibility for the credit; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">any other provision appropriate to implement the credit.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided under paragraph (2) of this subsection, a property tax credit granted under this section shall continue until the property is conveyed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A property tax credit granted under subsection (d), (e), or (g) of this section shall continue as long as the property is in compliance with the terms of that subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
