<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-511" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-14-511</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For a hearing before a property tax assessment appeal board, the person making the appeal may submit a written request to the supervisor, at least 15 days before the hearing, for a list of other properties that will be used as comparables by the supervisor at the scheduled hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The supervisor shall supply the list:<section prefix="(i)">at least 30 days before the date that the hearing has been scheduled for a written request made at least 35 days before the hearing; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">within 5 days from the request for a request made between 35 days and 15 days before the hearing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The list shall identify the location and owner of each property.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the supervisor will use the information in the appeal, the list shall also include for each property on the list:<section prefix="(i)">the sale price and date of sale;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the assessment and the year or years to which the assessment applied; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the construction costs and the date of construction.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Department may charge a reasonable fee for copies of the information sent under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A property tax assessment appeal board shall include in any order or notice of assessment that it issues:<section prefix="(1)">a statement of its action or assessment;</section><section prefix="(2)">a summary of the basis of its decision; and</section><section prefix="(3)">a statement that:<section prefix="(i)">advises the person making the appeal of the right to appeal to the Maryland Tax Court as provided by &#xA7; 14-512 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">includes the address of the Maryland Tax Court.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
