<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-242</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>242</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, in this section, "high performance building" means a building that:<section prefix="(i)">achieves at least a silver rating according to the U.S. Green Building Council's LEED (Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design) green building rating system as adopted by the Maryland Green Building Council;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is a residential building that achieves at least a silver rating according to the International Code Council's 700 National Green Building Standards;</section><section prefix="(iii)">achieves at least a comparable rating according to any other appropriate rating system; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">meets comparable green building guidelines or standards approved by the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of paragraph (1) of this subsection, under LEED Credit MR7 or a similar criterion in a comparable rating system, credit may be awarded for the use of wood-based materials derived from all credible sources, including the Sustainable Forestry Initiative Program, the Canadian Standards Association, the American Tree Farm System, and other credible certified sources programs.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the governing body of a county or of a municipal corporation may grant, by law, a tax credit against the county or municipal corporation property tax imposed on a high performance building.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A county or municipal corporation may provide, by law, for:<section prefix="(1)">the amount of a property tax credit under this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">the duration of a property tax credit under this section;</section><section prefix="(3)">the criteria and qualifications necessary to receive the credit; and</section><section prefix="(4)">any other provision necessary to carry out this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
