<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-14-509</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>509</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For property assessed by a supervisor, on or before 30 days from the date of the notice, any taxpayer, a county, a municipal corporation, or the Attorney General may appeal a value or classification in the notice of assessment under &#xA7; 8-407 of this article to the property tax assessment appeal board where the property is located.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The property tax assessment appeal board may waive the 30-day requirement under paragraph (1) of this subsection for a taxpayer on good cause shown because of the physical inability of the taxpayer to meet the 30-day requirement.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For property assessed by a supervisor, on or before 30 days from the date of determination by a supervisor, on a petition for review by a supervisor, the owner may appeal the value or classification in the determination to the property tax assessment appeal board where the property is located.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">On or before 30 days from the date of the final determination, any taxpayer may appeal a final determination of a property tax credit or relief under &#xA7;&#xA7; 9-101, 9-102, and 9-104 of this article, to the property tax assessment appeal board where the property is located.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The landowner or the Maryland Agricultural Land Preservation Foundation may appeal the value of an easement determined under &#xA7; 2-511 of the Agriculture Article to the property tax assessment appeal board where the property is located.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before 30 days from the date of a supervisor's denial of a hearing based on failure to meet the 45-day requirement under &#xA7; 14-502(a)(1) of this subtitle, the taxpayer may appeal the denial to the property tax assessment appeal board where the property is located.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On an appeal under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the property tax assessment appeal board may waive the 45-day requirement under &#xA7; 14-502(a)(1) of this subtitle for a taxpayer on good cause shown because of the physical inability of the taxpayer to meet the 45-day requirement.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If the requirements of subsections (a), (b), (c), (d), or (e) of this section are met, the property tax assessment appeal board shall hold a hearing, as provided under &#xA7; 14-510(b) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">For any appeal under this section in which the value of property is at issue, at least 10 days before a hearing on the appeal, the Department and the taxpayer shall exchange any written appraisals to be used for the purpose of placing a value on the property.</section>
  </text>
</law>
