<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="gtp" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-14-828</section_number>
  <catch_line>If the property is redeemed, the person redeeming shall pay the collector:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>828</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If the property is redeemed, the person redeeming shall pay the collector:<section prefix="(1)">the total lien amount paid at the tax sale for the property together with interest;</section><section prefix="(2)">any taxes, interest, and penalties paid by any holder of the certificate of sale;</section><section prefix="(3)">any taxes, interest, and penalties accruing after the date of the tax sale;</section><section prefix="(4)">in the manner and by the terms required by the collector, any expenses or fees for which the plaintiff or the holder of a certificate of sale is entitled to reimbursement under &#xA7; 14-843 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(5)">for vacant and abandoned property sold under &#xA7; 14-817 of this subtitle for a sum less than the amount due, the difference between the price paid and the unpaid taxes, interest, penalties, and expenses.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The rate of interest on redemption under subsection (a) of this section shall be set under &#xA7; 14-820 of this subtitle computed from the date of the tax sale to the date of the redemption payment.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">On receipt of the proper amount, the collector shall notify the holder of the certificate of sale that the property has been redeemed and that on surrender of the certificate of sale all redemption money excluding taxes received by the collector will be paid to the holder. For the purposes of this section, the collector is authorized to conclusively presume that the original purchaser at the tax sale is the holder of the certificate of sale, unless the collector receives a written notice of an assignment of the certificate of sale that gives the collector the name and address of the assignee. Upon request, the collector shall execute and deliver to the person redeeming the property a certificate of redemption which may be recorded among the land records of the county in which the land is located, and when recorded shall have the same effect as a release of a mortgage.</section>
  </text>
</law>
