<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-14-818</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>818</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The payment of the purchase price and the high-bid premium, if any, shall be on the terms required by the collector. Except as provided in subparagraphs (ii) and (iii) of this paragraph and &#xA7; 14-826 of this subtitle, the collector shall require the purchaser to pay, not later than the day after the sale, the full amount of taxes due on the property sold, whether the taxes are in arrears or not, together with interest and penalties on the taxes, expenses incurred in making the sale, and the high-bid premium, if any. The residue of the purchase price remains on credit.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In Washington County, the collector shall require the purchaser to pay on the day of the sale the full amount of taxes due on the property sold, whether the taxes are in arrears or not, together with interest and penalties on the taxes, and expenses incurred in making the sale.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">In Baltimore City, when abandoned property is sold for less than the full amount of taxes due on the property, the collector shall require the purchaser to pay, not later than the day after the sale:<section prefix="1.">the full amount bid; and</section><section prefix="2.">the expenses incurred in making the sale.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After the final decree has been passed foreclosing the right of redemption in any property, the collector may not execute or deliver a deed to any purchaser other than the governing body of a county until the balance of the purchase price has been paid in full, together with all taxes and interest and penalties on the taxes accruing after the date of sale.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On receiving the balance and after accrued taxes and interest and penalties on the taxes, the collector shall execute and deliver a proper deed to the purchaser.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Any balance over the amount required for the payment of taxes, interest, penalties, and costs of sale shall be paid by the collector to:<section prefix="(i)">the person entitled to the balance; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">when there is a dispute regarding payment of the balance, a court of competent jurisdiction pending a court order to determine the proper distribution of the balance.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In Washington County, any money held by the collector under subsection (a) of this section may be deposited in an interest-bearing account in a commercial bank. Any interest accrued is paid to the general fund of Washington County.</section>
  </text>
</law>
