<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="gtp" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-204.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "eligible improvements" means significant improvements to, or restoration or rehabi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "eligible improvements" means significant improvements to, or restoration or rehabilitation of, historic or heritage properties.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The General Assembly declares that it is in the general public interest to foster and encourage historic preservation and heritage tourism activities through improvement, restoration, and rehabilitation of, historic or heritage property so as to:<section prefix="(1)">preserve and protect the heritage of the State as represented by its remaining historic buildings and structures;</section><section prefix="(2)">stimulate the positive aspects of historic or heritage preservation, such as economic development and employment opportunities; and</section><section prefix="(3)">implement and effect local government planning activities aimed at preserving historic structures, sites, districts, and heritage areas.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">It is the intent of the General Assembly that:<section prefix="(1)">the taxation of significant improvements to, and restoration or rehabilitation of, historic or heritage properties be maintained, for a period of up to 10 years, at taxation levels not greater than those in place before the eligible improvements if approved as part of a local government plan for historic or heritage preservation;</section><section prefix="(2)">the methods and procedures to implement a program for the purposes of this section be determined by the applicable local government; and</section><section prefix="(3)">State financial assistance to a local government not be conditioned upon the local government implementing a program under this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore, the governing body of each county, and the governing body of each municipal corporation may:<section prefix="(1)">implement, by law, a program that provides for a property tax credit not to exceed the difference between:<section prefix="(i)">the property tax that, but for the tax credit, would be payable after the completion of eligible improvements; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the property tax that would be payable if the eligible improvements were not made; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">adopt any requirements and procedures that are necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A property tax credit provided for under this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">be subject to eligibility requirements no less stringent than those applicable to credits authorized under &#xA7; 9-204 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">be for a period that does not exceed 10 years for each property;</section><section prefix="(3)">apply to eligible improvements which are:<section prefix="(i)">located within the boundaries of:<section prefix="1.">a property listed individually on the National Register of Historic Places, or a national register historic or landmark district;</section><section prefix="2.">a property or district designated as a historic property or district under local law; or</section><section prefix="3.">a property included within the boundaries of a certified heritage area under &#xA7; 13-1111 of the Financial Institutions Article; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">for a property or district under paragraph (3)(i)1 or 2 of this subsection, determined by the local historic district commission to be compatible with local historic preservation standards.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
