<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-7-505</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>505</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "service facilities" includes nondwelling commercial and community facilities, community rooms, dining halls, and infirmaries.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except in Baltimore City, real property is exempt from county and municipal corporation property tax if:<section prefix="(i)">the real property is owned by a person engaged in constructing or operating housing structures or projects;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the real property is used for a housing structure or project that:<section prefix="1.">is constructed or substantially rehabilitated under a federal, State, or local government program that:</section><section prefix="2.">is substantially completed after July 1, 1978;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">the structures and facilities of the real property are governmentally controlled as to rents, charges, rates of return, and methods of operation so that the real property operates on a nonprofit or limited distribution basis; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the owner and the governing body of the county and, where applicable, municipal corporation where the real property is located agree that the owner shall pay a negotiated amount in lieu of the applicable county and municipal corporation property tax.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the structure and facilities of the real property are used predominantly for residential purposes, the real property may contain service facilities to serve its occupants and the surrounding neighborhood.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Real property described in subsection (a) of this section is exempt when the requirements of subsection (a) of this section are met.</section>
  </text>
</law>
