<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="gtp" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-401</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "dwelling":...</catch_line>
  <order_by>401</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "dwelling":<section prefix="(1)">means a newly constructed or substantially rehabilitated dwelling in Baltimore City, that is unsold, unrented, and unoccupied; and</section><section prefix="(2)">does not include land.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A property tax credit granted under this section applies only to the county property tax.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The governing body of Baltimore City may grant a property tax credit not exceeding 100% against the county tax imposed on the dwelling.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A property tax credit under this section may not be granted:<section prefix="(i)">for any dwelling that is used as an office or sample home by the builder or the owner; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">for more than 3 dwellings of an owner each year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not change the regular assessment procedures that are applicable in Baltimore City.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The governing body of Baltimore City may provide for procedures necessary to apply for a property tax credit under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">When the owner of a dwelling applies to the governing body of Baltimore City for a property tax credit under this section, the owner shall certify that the dwelling is unsold, unrented, and unoccupied.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A recipient of a property tax credit under this section shall send immediately to the governing body of Baltimore City a notice that the dwelling has been sold, rented, or occupied.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A property tax credit granted under this section is available:<section prefix="(1)">as long as the dwelling remains unsold, unrented, and unoccupied; and</section><section prefix="(2)">over a continuous period of time not exceeding 1 year for any dwelling.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">If a recipient of a property tax credit under this section fails to comply with the provisions of this section, the property tax credit under this section is forfeited immediately.</section>
  </text>
</law>
