<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="gtp" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>To qualify under this section, a structure shall:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To qualify under this section, a structure shall:<section prefix="(1)">have historic value;</section><section prefix="(2)">have architectural value; or</section><section prefix="(3)">be designated under Title 8, &#xA7; 10-204, or &#xA7; 22-108 of the Land Use Article, Article 25A, &#xA7; 5(X) or (BB) of the Code, or the charter powers of Baltimore City, as:<section prefix="(i)">an architecturally compatible new structure that is located in a historic district; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a landmark.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A property tax credit of up to 10% of the properly documented expenses of a private owner taxpayer for the restoration and preservation of a structure that the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the governing body of a county or of a municipal corporation determines has historic or architectural value may be granted, by law, by the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the governing body against the county or municipal corporation property tax imposed.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A property tax credit of up to 5% of the properly documented expenses of a private owner taxpayer for the construction of an architecturally compatible new structure in a historic district may be granted, by law, by the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the governing body of a county or of a municipal corporation against the county or municipal corporation property tax imposed.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a historic district commission is established by the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the governing body of a county or of a municipal corporation, only the historic district commission shall designate each structure in the county or municipal corporation that is eligible for a property tax credit under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A property tax credit granted in 1 year under this section may be applied to any property tax on the structure for up to 5 subsequent tax years.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the governing body of a county or of a municipal corporation may provide for any procedure or condition necessary to carry out this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The county or a municipal corporation may require the owner of a structure granted a tax credit under this section to periodically exhibit the structure for public education.</section>
  </text>
</law>
