<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-306" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-306</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The governing body of Calvert County and of a municipal corporation in Calvert County shall grant a tax credit under this section against the county and municipal corporation property tax imposed on:<section prefix="(1)">real property that is owned by the Calvert Arundel Medical Facility, Incorporated; and</section><section prefix="(2)">agricultural land, not including any improvements, that is located in an agricultural preservation district.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The governing body of Calvert County shall grant a property tax credit under this section against the county tax imposed on:<section prefix="(1)">real property that is:<section prefix="(i)">owned by a nonprofit community or civic improvement association or corporation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">used only for a community, civic, educational, or library purpose, if:</section></section><section prefix="(2)">real property that is owned by the Calvert County Sportsmen's Club, Incorporated; and</section><section prefix="(3)">real property that is:<section prefix="(i)">located in the 2nd election district of Calvert County;</section><section prefix="(ii)">actually used for the Calvert County Fair; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">known as the Calvert County Fairgrounds.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The governing body of Calvert County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county property tax imposed on a building that is:<section prefix="(1)">located on land that qualifies for an agricultural use assessment; and</section><section prefix="(2)">used in connection with an activity that is recognized by the Department as an approved agricultural activity.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The governing body of Calvert County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county property tax imposed on real property that is:<section prefix="(1)">owned by the Huntingtown Volunteer Fire Department and Rescue Squad, Incorporated; and</section><section prefix="(2)">leased to the United States Postal Service for use as a post office.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The governing body of Calvert County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county property tax imposed on real property that is owned by the Calvert Post No. 85, the American Legion Department of Maryland, Incorporated.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Calvert County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county property tax imposed on real property that is owned by members of volunteer fire and rescue companies.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body of Calvert County may provide, by law, for:<section prefix="(i)">the amount and duration of the tax credit under this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the criteria for qualifying for the tax credit under this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the governing body of Calvert County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county property tax imposed on real property owned by an expanding or new business that:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the expanding or new business is engaged in the generation of electricity, the credit under this section may be granted against the county property tax imposed on personal property and real property owned by the expanding or new business.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The tax credit under this section shall be granted to:<section prefix="(i)">a business that owns the land and building it occupies within the county; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">any party responsible for paying the real property taxes on all or part of the land or building.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The amount of the credit may not exceed 50% of the amount of property tax due in any taxable year.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The governing body of Calvert County may define, fix, or limit the amount, terms, scope, and duration of any credit provided for or affirmed under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
