<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Assets" include:<section prefix="1.">real property;</section><section prefix="2.">cash;</section><section prefix="3.">savings accounts;</section><section prefix="4.">stocks;</section><section prefix="5.">bonds; and</section><section prefix="6.">any other investment.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Assets" do not include:<section prefix="1.">the dwelling for which a property tax credit is sought under this section;</section><section prefix="2.">the cash value of the life insurance policies on the life of the homeowner;</section><section prefix="3.">the cash value of any qualified retirement savings plans or individual retirement accounts; or</section><section prefix="4.">tangible personal property.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Combined income" means the combined gross income of all individuals who actually reside in a dwelling except an individual who:<section prefix="(i)">is a dependent of the homeowner under &#xA7; 152 of the Internal Revenue Code; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">pays a reasonable amount for rent or room and board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Current market value" means:<section prefix="(i)">for residential property, the value as determined by the Department; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">for farmland, marshland, and woodland, the value under Title 8, Subtitle 2 of this article as determined by the Department.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Disabled veteran" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 7-208(a) of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Dwelling" means:<section prefix="(i)">for a homeowner who is not a home purchaser, a house that is:<section prefix="1.">used as the principal residence of a homeowner and the lot or curtilage on which the house is erected;</section><section prefix="2.">occupied by not more than 2 families; and</section><section prefix="3.">actually occupied or expected to be actually occupied by the homeowner for more than 6 months of a 12-month period, which actual or expected occupancy period shall include July 1 of the taxable year for which the property tax credit under this section is sought; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">for a homeowner who is a home purchaser, a house that is:<section prefix="1.">used as the principal residence of a homeowner and the lot or curtilage on which the house is erected;</section><section prefix="2.">occupied by not more than 2 families; and</section><section prefix="3.">actually occupied or expected to be actually occupied by the home purchaser for the remainder of the taxable year for which the property tax credit under this section is sought.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Final tax liability" means the tax liability for any property tax on the real property of a dwelling less any property tax credit provided under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Gross income" means the total income from all sources for the calendar year that immediately precedes the taxable year, whether or not the income is included in the definition of gross income for federal or State tax purposes.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Gross income" includes:<section prefix="1.">any benefit under the Social Security Act or the Railroad Retirement Act;</section><section prefix="2.">the aggregate of gifts over $300;</section><section prefix="3.">alimony;</section><section prefix="4.">support money;</section><section prefix="5.">any nontaxable strike benefit;</section><section prefix="6.">public assistance received in a cash grant;</section><section prefix="7.">a pension;</section><section prefix="8.">an annuity;</section><section prefix="9.">any unemployment insurance benefit;</section><section prefix="10.">any workers' compensation benefit;</section><section prefix="11.">the net income received from a business, rental, or other endeavor;</section><section prefix="12.">any withdrawal, payment, or distribution from an individual retirement account;</section><section prefix="13.">any withdrawal, payment, or distribution from any qualified retirement savings plan; and</section><section prefix="14.">any rent on the dwelling, including the rent from a room or apartment.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Gross income" does not include:<section prefix="1.">any income tax refund received from the State or federal government; or</section><section prefix="2.">any loss from business, rental, or other endeavor.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(9)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Homeowner" means an individual who:<section prefix="1.">on July 1 of the taxable year for which the tax credit is to be allowed:</section><section prefix="2."/></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Homeowner" includes a beneficiary of a trust described in 42 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1396p(d)(4), or a trust established for the benefit of an individual with a disability by an individual other than the beneficiary and that is funded with assets that were never owned or controlled by the beneficiary, if, on July 1 of the taxable year for which the tax credit is to be allowed, the beneficiary of the trust is an individual who actually resides in the dwelling.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(10)">"Home purchaser" means an individual who purchases a dwelling in the taxable year for which the tax credit under this section is sought.</section>
      <section prefix="(11)">"Legal interest" includes an interest in a dwelling:<section prefix="(i)">as sole owner;</section><section prefix="(ii)">as a joint tenant;</section><section prefix="(iii)">as a tenant in common;</section><section prefix="(iv)">as a tenant by the entireties;</section><section prefix="(v)">through membership in a cooperative;</section><section prefix="(vi)">under a land installment contract, as defined in &#xA7; 10-101 of the Real Property Article;</section><section prefix="(vii)">as a holder of a life estate; or</section><section prefix="(viii)">under a continuing care contract for an independent living unit at a continuing care facility for the aged, which means a nontransferable agreement between a continuing care facility for the aged as defined in &#xA7; 7-206 of this article and an occupant of an independent living unit, which agreement provides that the occupant may reside in the unit until termination under the terms of the contract.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(12)">"Net worth" means the sum of the current market value of all assets, less any outstanding liability.</section>
      <section prefix="(13)">"Total real property tax" means the product of the sum of all property tax rates on real property, including special district tax rates, for the taxable year on a dwelling, multiplied by the lesser of:<section prefix="(i)">$300,000; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the assessed value of the dwelling reduced by the amount of any assessment on which a property tax credit is granted under &#xA7; 9-105 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The homeowners' tax credit under this section is a State-funded program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">It is the intent of the General Assembly that:<section prefix="(i)">the State shall appropriate sufficient funds to reimburse the full amount of tax credits granted under this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the State, and not the local governments, shall bear the burden of any insufficiency of funds to fully reimburse the counties for property tax credits under this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For any fiscal year, if State appropriations for reimbursement of tax credits under this section do not provide sufficient funds to fully reimburse the counties for tax credits granted under this section, the Governor shall include in the budget bill for the next fiscal year a deficiency appropriation to provide the additional funds to fully reimburse the counties.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department shall adopt regulations to carry out this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (f) of this section, the Department is responsible for the administrative duties that relate to the application and determination of eligibility for a property tax credit under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department may:<section prefix="(i)">make an agreement with a county collector for limited assistance with a part of the administrative duties; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">reimburse the county for the reasonable cost of the assistance provided.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">When an applicant for the property tax credit under this section resides in an independent living unit at a continuing care facility for the aged, the Department shall determine for the independent living unit:<section prefix="(i)">the lot size;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the assessed value of land and building; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the total real property tax.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">When an assessment notice is sent to a homeowner, the Department shall give notice of the possible property tax credit under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Comptroller shall include, in each package of income tax forms and instructions, notice of the availability of a property tax credit under this section. Notice shall include any information needed to convey:<section prefix="(i)">eligibility;</section><section prefix="(ii)">filing deadlines;</section><section prefix="(iii)">applicable limitations; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">contact information for application forms.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notice in the package of income tax forms and instructions shall be:<section prefix="(i)">prominently placed;</section><section prefix="(ii)">printed in an open typeface, such as Helvetica, no smaller than 10 points; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">positioned and colored to distinguish it from income tax material.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For income verification, the Comptroller shall:<section prefix="(i)">cooperate with the Department in adopting a procedure to audit the application forms; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">notwithstanding &#xA7; 13-202 of the Tax - General Article, supply the Department with additional information.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Comptroller shall assist the Department in a postaudit of each application.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A homeowner who meets the requirements of this section shall be granted the property tax credit under this section against the property tax imposed on the real property of the dwelling.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (i) of this section, the property tax credit under this section is the total real property tax of a dwelling, less the percentage of the combined income of the homeowner that is described in paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The percentage is:<section prefix="(i)">0% of the 1st $8,000 of combined income;</section><section prefix="(ii)">4% of the next $4,000 of combined income;</section><section prefix="(iii)">6.5% of the next $4,000 of combined income; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">9% of the combined income over $16,000.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">For home purchasers, the property tax credit is the amount of the credit as calculated under subsection (h) of this section multiplied by a fraction, where:<section prefix="(1)">the numerator of the fraction is the number of days in the fiscal year that the home purchaser actually occupies or expects to actually occupy a dwelling in which the home purchaser has a legal interest; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the denominator is 365 days.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">If a surviving spouse of a homeowner has not remarried and meets the qualifications except for age or disability, the property tax credit under this section is available to the unmarried surviving spouse.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A property tax credit under this section may not be granted to a homeowner whose combined net worth exceeds $200,000 as of December 31 of the calendar year that precedes the year in which the homeowner applies for the property tax credit or whose combined gross income exceeds $60,000 in that same calendar year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a property tax credit under this section is less than $1 in any taxable year, the credit may not be granted.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A homeowner may claim a property tax credit under this section for only 1 dwelling.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Except as provided in subsection (v) of this section, if a property tax credit is issued under this section, the credit or a voucher for a credit may be used only in the taxable year in which it was issued or the next succeeding taxable year. However, a homeowner whose dwelling is sold for taxes may receive the credit until the final decree under &#xA7; 14-844 of this article is entered.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">A homeowner may qualify for a property tax credit under this section if the homeowner does not actually reside in the dwelling for the required time period because of illness or need of special care even if the homeowner:<section prefix="(1)">rents the dwelling for less than 1 year; or</section><section prefix="(2)">rents the dwelling for more than 1 year to a member of the homeowner's immediate family.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsections (n) and (v) of this section, on or before September 1 of the taxable year in which the property tax credit under this section is sought, a homeowner may apply to the Department for a property tax credit under this section. The application shall be made on the form that the Department provides.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">For good cause, the Department may accept an application after September 1 but on or before October 31 of the taxable year.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Department shall notify the homeowner in writing of its acceptance or rejection of a late application.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The homeowner shall state under oath that the facts in the application are true.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">To substantiate the application, the applicant may be required to provide a copy of an income tax return, or other evidence detailing gross income or net worth.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A home purchaser may apply to the Department for a property tax credit under this section after the execution of a contract of sale on the dwelling or settlement on the dwelling by filing an application on the form that the Department provides.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The home purchaser shall state under oath that the facts in the application are true.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">To substantiate the application, the Department may require the applicant to provide a copy of an income tax return, or other evidence detailing gross income or net worth.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the home purchaser files an application for a credit under this section prior to settlement, the purchaser must file this application within 7 working days after the execution of a contract of sale.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Upon receipt of an application prior to settlement, the Department:<section prefix="(i)">may further require the applicant to provide a copy of the executed sale agreement;</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall determine the amount, if any, of the credit for which the home purchaser is eligible under this section; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">shall notify the home purchaser in writing of its decision within 5 working days from receipt of the application.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Department shall adopt regulations governing the application for and granting of a credit before settlement as provided under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">On certification by the Department, the Comptroller shall pay to the home purchaser the property tax credit due under this section unless the credit was used to adjust the home purchaser's final tax liability paid at settlement under subsection (s) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">The Department shall notify an applicant in writing if the applicant is not eligible for the property tax credit under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For any eligible application received before the May 1 that precedes the taxable year in which the property tax credit under this section is sought, the Department shall request the appropriate county collector to prepare a tax bill that reflects the final tax liability.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a homeowner presents the revised tax bill or a tax voucher with the tax bill to the county collector, the homeowner may make a single payment for the final tax liability.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in subsection (v) of this section, if a credit is granted for an eligible application received after May 1, property tax is not due on the property until 30 days after the revised tax bill is sent to the homeowner.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If a municipal corporation or a special taxing district issues a tax bill separate from the county tax bill, the county may require the homeowner to submit:<section prefix="(i)">the separate tax bill; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">proof of payment of the separate tax bill.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(q)">If a municipal corporation or a special taxing district issues a tax bill to a homeowner, the Department shall include the property tax rate of the municipal corporation or the special taxing district in calculating the property tax credit under this section and final tax liability.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for transfers between spouses, including a conveyance to a surviving spouse from the personal representative of a deceased spouse, if a homeowner transfers a dwelling that is subject to a property tax credit under this section, the property tax credit ends on the date that the property is transferred. The credit is not ended if the transfer is between spouses.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The total amount of the property tax credit under this section is included in determining the amount of property tax that is:<section prefix="(i)">paid by the homeowner; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">adjusted at the time of settlement between the homeowner and the buyer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The homeowner is credited for the part of the property tax credit under this section that the homeowner's period of ownership during the taxable year in which the transfer occurs bears to the entire taxable year. The buyer shall pay the remaining part of the property tax credit under this section to the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Any property tax credit under this section that is collected by a county from a buyer under this subsection shall be credited to the State less any cost incurred by any county or a municipal corporation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(s)">The final tax liability of a home purchaser due at settlement shall be adjusted to reflect any credit certified by the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each month or more frequently, if appropriate, each county collector shall submit a request to the Department for reimbursement for an amount equal to the property tax credits under this section and redeemed property tax credit vouchers paid under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The request may not include the property tax credits for which the county or municipal corporation is responsible under &#xA7; 9-101(g) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Within 5 working days after receipt of the request the Department shall certify to the Comptroller the amount of reimbursement due to each county.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Within 5 working days:<section prefix="(i)">the Comptroller shall make the reimbursement to each county; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the appropriate county collector may withhold an amount of State taxes sufficient to reimburse the county.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(u)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An eligible homeowner who has a continuing care contract for an independent living unit at a continuing care facility for the aged shall receive payment for the amount of the property tax credit under this section from the Comptroller upon certification by the Department. A credit granted to the homeowner under this subsection may not be assigned to the continuing care facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (h) of this section, if a homeowner under this subsection is a disabled veteran, the homeowner may receive a credit for the total real property tax attributable to the independent living unit, up to the maximum credit authorized under this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A disabled veteran may apply for the credit under this subsection by providing the Department with the information required under subsection (m) of this section and &#xA7; 7-208(d) of this article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The surviving spouse of a disabled veteran may, upon application, continue to receive the credit provided under this subsection until the surviving spouse remarries.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(v)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Under the conditions set forth in this subsection, the Department may accept an application from a homeowner within 3 years after April 15 of the taxable year for which a credit is sought, if the homeowner:<section prefix="(i)">is at least 70 years old as of the taxable year for which a credit is sought; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">was eligible for the credit under this section for the taxable year for which the credit is sought.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A homeowner may apply to the Department for a property tax credit under this section by filing an application on the form that the Department provides.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The homeowner shall state under oath that the facts in the application are true.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">To substantiate the application, the Department may require the homeowner to provide a copy of an income tax return, or other evidence detailing gross income or net worth.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">On certification by the Department, the Comptroller shall pay to the homeowner the property tax credit due under this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
