<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-324" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-324</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The governing body of Wicomico County and the governing body of a municipal corporation in Wicomico County may grant a property tax credit under this section against the county and municipal corporation property tax imposed on property that is owned by the East Side Men's Club, Inc.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Wicomico County may grant, by law, a property tax credit against the county property tax imposed on agricultural land and agricultural easements, not including any improvements, that are located in an agricultural preservation district.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In establishing a tax credit under this subsection, the governing body of Wicomico County shall specify:<section prefix="(i)">the amount and duration of the credit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the qualification and application procedures for the credit;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the circumstances under which the credit shall terminate;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the liability of the property owner in the event of termination of the credit; and</section><section prefix="(v)">any other requirement or procedure related to the credit and considered necessary.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Wicomico County or the governing body of a municipal corporation in Wicomico County may grant, by law, a property tax credit against the county or municipal corporation property tax imposed on property that is owned by the Salisbury Area Chamber of Commerce, Inc.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body of Wicomico County or of a municipal corporation in Wicomico County may provide, by law, for:<section prefix="(i)">the amount and duration of a property tax credit under this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any other provision necessary to carry out this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
