<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-323</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>323</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Washington County or of a municipal corporation in Washington County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county or municipal corporation property tax imposed on:<section prefix="(i)">new construction or on an improvement to existing property;</section><section prefix="(ii)">property that is:<section prefix="1.">owned by a nonprofit civic association;</section><section prefix="2.">used only for a community, civic, educational, or library purpose; and</section><section prefix="3.">unless the compensation is used only to improve or maintain the property, use of the property is not contingent on the payment of compensation for admission to or use of the property and failure to pay compensation is not a reason to deny admission to or use of the property;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">real property that is owned by the Women's Club of Hagerstown, Inc.;</section><section prefix="(iv)">property that is owned by the Rohrersville Cornet Band of Washington County;</section><section prefix="(v)">real property that is owned and occupied as the principal residence of an individual serving as:<section prefix="1.">a volunteer firefighter;</section><section prefix="2.">a member of the fire police; or</section><section prefix="3.">an emergency medical technician; or</section></section><section prefix="(vi)">real property that is owned by the Hagerstown Soccer Club, Inc.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The law adopted under paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection shall specify:<section prefix="(i)">the qualifications for the tax credit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the amount of the property tax credit, based on a percentage of the cost of any new construction or of any improvement to existing property, and not based on the increase in the assessment; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the duration of the tax credit.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In authorizing a credit under paragraph (1)(v) of this subsection, the governing body of the county or municipal corporation may provide, by law, for:<section prefix="(i)">the amount of the credit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the duration of the credit; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">any other provision necessary to administer the credit.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Washington County shall grant a property tax credit under this section against the county property tax imposed on:<section prefix="(i)">property that is owned by the District 15 Civic Association, Incorporated, of Big Pool, Maryland; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">real property on which an improvement is made to an existing structure that is located in a historic district.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A property tax credit granted under paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection shall be:<section prefix="(i)">the following percentage of the increase that is due to the improvement:<section prefix="1.">100% of the increase in the assessment of the real property in the 1st and 2nd taxable years that the improved structure is subject to the county property tax;</section><section prefix="2.">80% of the increase in the assessment of the real property in the 3rd taxable year that the improved structure is subject to the county property tax;</section><section prefix="3.">60% of the increase in the assessment of the real property in the 4th taxable year that the improved structure is subject to the county property tax;</section><section prefix="4.">40% of the increase in the assessment of the real property in the 5th taxable year that the improved structure is subject to the county property tax; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">ended after the 5th taxable year that the improved structure is subject to county property tax.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The governing body of Washington County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county property tax imposed on:<section prefix="(1)">personal property that is owned by Mid-East Milk Lab Services, Incorporated; and</section><section prefix="(2)">real property that is subject to the county's agricultural land preservation program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "qualifying business" means an industrial or commercial business that is or will be doing business in Washington County, employing five or more full-time employees on a regular basis, and that is initially building or making substantial improvements or otherwise undertaking new construction work.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding &#xA7; 9-301(b) of this subtitle and subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection, the governing body of Washington County may grant to a qualifying business a property tax credit against all or part of the county property tax levied on real or personal property of the qualifying business for a period not exceeding 5 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A property tax credit granted under this subsection may phase in the payment of county property taxes over the period of the credit.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The governing body of Washington County may grant a property tax credit under this subsection only at a public meeting. The decision of the governing body shall be included in its minutes.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Washington County may grant a property tax credit against the county property tax imposed on renovated or rehabilitated business real property located in a priority funding area as designated in Title 5, Subtitle 7B of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the governing body of the county may provide, by law, for:<section prefix="(i)">the amount of the credit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the duration of the credit; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">any other provision necessary to administer the credit.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A tax credit under this subsection may not exceed the amount of additional property tax assessed as a result of the renovation or rehabilitation.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A tax credit under this subsection is available to a qualified property for no more than 5 years.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Affiliate" means a person:<section prefix="1.">that directly or indirectly owns at least 80% of a business entity; or</section><section prefix="2.">at least 80% of which is owned, directly or indirectly, by a business entity.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Business entity" means a person conducting a trade or business in the State that is subject to the State individual or corporate income tax or insurance premiums tax.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">"Full-time position" means a position requiring at least 840 hours of an individual's time during at least 24 weeks in a 6-month period.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">"New or expanded premises" means commercial or industrial real property, including a building or part of a building that has not been previously occupied, where a business entity or its affiliates locate to conduct business.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">
          <section prefix="1.">"New permanent full-time position" means a position that is:</section>
          <section prefix="2.">"New permanent full-time position" does not include a position that is:</section>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body of Washington County may grant, by law, a property tax credit against the county property tax imposed on real property owned or leased by a business entity that meets the requirements specified for the tax credit under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">To qualify for a property tax credit under this subsection, before a business entity obtains the new or expanded premises or hires employees to fill the new permanent full-time positions at the new or expanded premises, the business entity shall provide written notification to the governing body of Washington County stating:<section prefix="(i)">that the business entity intends to claim the property tax credit; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">when the business entity expects to obtain the new or expanded premises and hire the required number of employees in the new permanent full-time positions.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">To qualify for a property tax credit under this subsection, an existing business entity in the county shall:<section prefix="1.">obtain at least an additional 1,500 square feet of new or expanded premises by purchasing newly constructed premises, constructing new premises, causing new premises to be constructed, or leasing previously unoccupied premises; and</section><section prefix="2.">employ at least one individual in a new permanent full-time position during a 12-month period, during which period the business entity also must obtain and occupy the new or expanded premises.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">To qualify for the property tax credit under this subsection, a new business entity locating in the county shall:<section prefix="1.">obtain at least 2,500 square feet of new or expanded premises by purchasing newly constructed premises, constructing new premises, causing new premises to be constructed, or leasing previously unoccupied premises; and</section><section prefix="2.">employ at least five individuals in new permanent full-time positions during a 24-month period, during which period the business entity also must obtain and occupy the new or expanded premises.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If an existing business entity in the county meets the requirements of paragraph (4)(i) of this subsection, the property tax credit granted under this subsection shall equal a percentage of the amount of property tax imposed on the assessment of the new or expanded premises, as follows:<section prefix="1.">52% in the first and second taxable years;</section><section prefix="2.">39% in the third and fourth taxable years; and</section><section prefix="3.">26% in the fifth and sixth taxable years.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a new business entity locating in the county meets the requirements of paragraph (4)(ii) of this subsection, the property tax credit granted under this subsection shall equal a percentage of the amount of property tax imposed on the assessment of the new or expanded premises, as follows:<section prefix="1.">30% in the first and second taxable years;</section><section prefix="2.">20% in the third and fourth taxable years; and</section><section prefix="3.">10% in the fifth and sixth taxable years.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The lessor of real property granted a property tax credit under this subsection shall reduce the amount of taxes for which a business entity is contractually liable under the lease agreement by the amount of any credit granted under this subsection for improvements made by the business entity.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The governing body of Washington County shall provide, by law, for:<section prefix="(i)">the specific requirements for eligibility for a property tax credit authorized under this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">any additional limitations on eligibility for the credit; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">any other provision appropriate to implement the credit.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
