<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-7-206</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>206</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "facility" means a continuing care facility for the aged that:<section prefix="(1)">provides continuing care as defined in &#xA7; 10-401 of the Human Services Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">is licensed as a related institution under Title 19, Subtitle 3 of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="(3)">is certified by the Department of Aging; and</section><section prefix="(4)">is exempt from federal income tax under &#xA7; 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Property that is not otherwise exempt from taxation under this section or &#xA7; 7-202 of this subtitle is not subject to property tax if the property:<section prefix="(1)">is owned by a facility; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is used:<section prefix="(i)">exclusively for religious worship;</section><section prefix="(ii)">exclusively for administration or for providing nonprofit services and activities to residents, including that part of land reasonably allocable to providing the administration, activities, or services, but may not include independent living units; however, nothing in this paragraph affects those independent living units qualifying for exemption under &#xA7; 7-202 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">to provide nursing care, domiciliary care, or comprehensive care including:<section prefix="1.">the part of any central administrative or service facility that is reasonably allocable to the licensed health care part of the facility; or</section><section prefix="2.">the part of any land that is reasonably allocable to the licensed health care part of the facility.</section></section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
