<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-103" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-12-103</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The recordation tax rates under this section are applied to each $500 or fraction of $500 of consideration payable or of the principal amount of the debt secured for an instrument of writing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The consideration:<section prefix="(i)">includes the amount of any mortgage or deed of trust assumed by the grantee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">subject to item (i) of this paragraph, includes only the amount paid or delivered in return for the sale of the property and does not include the amount of any debt forgiven or no longer secured by a mortgage or deed of trust on the property.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the governing body of a county may set, by law, the recordation tax rate in the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the governing body of a county may provide for an exemption from the tax of a specified amount of the consideration payable on the conveyance of owner-occupied residential property if the buyer intends to use the property as the buyer's principal residence by actually occupying the residence for at least 7 months of a 12-month period.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The governing body of a county or Baltimore City may provide for an exemption from the recordation tax for an instrument of writing for residentially improved owner-occupied real property if the instrument of writing is accompanied by a statement under oath signed by each grantee that:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)"/></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The recordation tax rate is 55 cents for an instrument of writing for property that:<section prefix="(1)">is located in 2 or more counties; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is security for a corporate bond of a public service company as defined in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Public Utilities Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For articles of transfer, articles of merger, or articles of consolidation filed with the Department under &#xA7; 3-107 of the Corporations and Associations Article, or other document filed with the Department which evidences a merger or consolidation of foreign corporations, foreign limited liability companies, foreign partnerships, or foreign limited partnerships, the recordation tax rate is $1.65. The Department shall collect the recordation tax when the articles of transfer, articles of merger, articles of consolidation, or other document which evidences a merger or consolidation of foreign corporations, foreign limited liability companies, foreign partnerships, or foreign limited partnerships are filed.</section>
  </text>
</law>
