<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="gtp" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-8-209</section_number>
  <catch_line>The General Assembly declares that it is in the general public interest of the State to foster and e...</catch_line>
  <order_by>209</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The General Assembly declares that it is in the general public interest of the State to foster and encourage farming activities to:<section prefix="(1)">maintain a readily available source of food and dairy products close to the metropolitan areas of the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">encourage the preservation of open space as an amenity necessary for human welfare and happiness; and</section><section prefix="(3)">prevent the forced conversion of open space land to more intensive uses because of the economic pressures caused by the assessment of the land at rates or levels incompatible with its practical use for farming.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">It is the intention of the General Assembly that the assessment of farmland:<section prefix="(1)">be maintained at levels compatible with the continued use of the land for farming; and</section><section prefix="(2)">not be affected adversely by neighboring land uses of a more intensive nature.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Land that is actively used for farm or agricultural use shall be valued on the basis of that use and may not be valued as if subdivided.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Land that is valued under subsection (c) of this section shall be assessed on the basis of its use value.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall establish in regulations criteria to determine if land that appears to be actively used for farm or agricultural purposes:<section prefix="(i)">is actually used for farm or agricultural purposes; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">qualifies for assessment under this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The criteria shall include:<section prefix="(i)">the zoning of the land;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the present and past use of the land including land under the Soil Bank Program of the United States;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the productivity of the land, including timberlands and reforested lands; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the gross income that is derived from the agricultural activity.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In administering this section, periodically, the Director shall consult with:<section prefix="(1)">the Secretary of Agriculture;</section><section prefix="(2)">officials of the State who are knowledgeable in agriculture;</section><section prefix="(3)">representatives of the agricultural community;</section><section prefix="(4)">officials of counties and municipal corporations; and</section><section prefix="(5)">other persons as determined by the Director.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated:<section prefix="(i)">"actively used" means land that is actually and primarily used for a continuing farm or agricultural use;</section><section prefix="(ii)">"agricultural land unit" means the combination of not more than 3 parcels of land when the parcels are:<section prefix="1.">located in the same county; and</section><section prefix="2.">under the same ownership;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">"average gross income" means the average of the 2 highest years of gross income during a 3-year period;</section><section prefix="(iv)">"family farm unit" means not more than 1 parcel of land of less than 20 acres for each immediate family member for land that is:<section prefix="1.">contiguous to land receiving the farm or agricultural use assessment; and</section><section prefix="2.">owned by a member or members of the immediate family of the owner of the farm or agricultural use land; and</section></section><section prefix="(v)">"gross income" means the actual income that is received in a calendar year that results directly from the farm or agricultural use of the land.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In determining if a parcel of land of less than 20 acres, or not zoned for agricultural use, is actively used, the Department may require the owner of the land to affirm, under oath, on a standard form provided by the Department that the farm or agricultural use of the land results in an average gross income of at least $2,500 from the parcel or the agricultural land unit.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department may require an owner who submits an affirmation under paragraph (2) of this subsection to verify the gross income from the land by providing:<section prefix="(i)">copies of sales receipts or invoices;</section><section prefix="(ii)">lease agreements; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">other documents required by the Department.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An affirmation under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be filed before July 1 of the taxable year.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If land that appears to be actively used does not yield an average gross income of $2,500, the Director shall waive the gross income requirement on finding that:<section prefix="(i)">the land is leased and the nature of the farm or agricultural use of the land when related to the amount of the land in farm or agricultural use reasonably would be expected to yield an average gross income of at least $2,500;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the nature of the farm or agricultural use of the land and the amount of the land in farm or agricultural use reasonably would be expected to yield an average gross income of at least $2,500 from the agricultural products, if sold, that are derived from the use of the land;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a drought or other natural cause has adversely affected the income-producing capability of the land during a 3-year period; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">for a newly established farm or agricultural use, the nature of the use and the amount of the land in farm or agricultural use reasonably would be expected to yield an average gross income of at least $2,500 if the use had existed for a 3-year period.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Director may grant only the following additional waivers:<section prefix="(i)">under paragraph (5)(iii) of this subsection, for 1 additional consecutive 3-year period; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">under paragraph (5)(iv) of this subsection, for 1 additional consecutive 3-year period.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The gross income requirement of paragraph (2) of this subsection does not apply if the land is actively used as a family farm unit.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">For purposes of qualifying for the agricultural use assessment under this section, the following real property is deemed to be a single contiguous parcel:<section prefix="(i)">parcels that are created or separated by roads, easements, or other rights-of-way; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">land relating to a right-of-way that reverts back to its owner's use for purposes of farming.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the following land does not qualify to be assessed under this section:<section prefix="(i)">land rezoned to a more intensive use than the use that immediately preceded the rezoning, if a person with an ownership interest in the land has applied for or requested the rezoning;</section><section prefix="(ii)">land used as a homesite, which means the area of land that is reasonably related to a dwelling;</section><section prefix="(iii)">parcels of land of less than 3 acres that are under the same ownership excluding the homesite unless:<section prefix="1.">the land is owned by an owner of adjoining land that is receiving the farm or agricultural use assessment and is actively used;</section><section prefix="2.">the owner receives at least 51% of the owner's gross income from the active use; or</section><section prefix="3.">the parcels are part of a family farm unit;</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">if part of a subdivision plat, parcels of land of less than 10 acres that are owned by an owner of 5 other parcels of land of less than 10 acres each that are located in the same county and that are receiving the farm or agricultural use assessment;</section><section prefix="(v)">parcels of woodland of less than 5 acres excluding the homesite; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">land that fails to meet the gross income requirement of subsection (g) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">No more than 2 parcels of less than 3 acres under the same ownership may qualify for the agricultural use assessment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Surviving spouse" means the surviving spouse of the property owner who applied for the waiver under this subsection if the surviving spouse has not remarried and had a legal interest in the property at the time of the application for the waiver.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"3-year cycle" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 8-103 of this title.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Director may grant a waiver from the requirements of subsection (e) or (g) of this section if:<section prefix="(i)">the property owner is at least 70 years of age;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the property owner applies to the Department for a waiver of the requirements of either subsection (e) or (g) of this section;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the land has not changed ownership during the two previous 3-year cycles; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the land has been assessed for at least the two previous 3-year cycles on the basis of farm or agricultural use under the law or regulations of the Department that were in effect as of the date of the application.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Director may grant a waiver from the requirements of subsection (e) or (g) of this section if:<section prefix="(i)">the property owner becomes disabled and is unable to continue the farm or agricultural use of the land;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the property owner applies to the Department for a waiver of the requirements of either subsection (e) or (g) of this section;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the property owner engaged in farm or agricultural use activities on the land prior to the disability; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the land has been assessed for at least the two previous 3-year cycles on the basis of farm or agricultural use under the law or regulations of the Department that were in effect as of the date of the application.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Any waiver granted under this subsection shall be in effect until:<section prefix="(i)">the transfer of the property; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the later of the death of the property owner who received the waiver or the death of the surviving spouse.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Department may adopt regulations to carry out the provisions of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
