<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="gtp" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-6-305</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "tax setoff" means:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>305</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "tax setoff" means:<section prefix="(1)">the difference between the general county property tax rate and the property tax rate that is set for assessments of property in a municipal corporation; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a payment to a municipal corporation to aid the municipal corporation in funding services or programs that are similar to county services or programs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only in:<section prefix="(1)">Allegany County;</section><section prefix="(2)">Anne Arundel County;</section><section prefix="(3)">Baltimore County;</section><section prefix="(4)">Frederick County;</section><section prefix="(5)">Garrett County;</section><section prefix="(6)">Harford County;</section><section prefix="(7)">Howard County;</section><section prefix="(8)">Montgomery County; and</section><section prefix="(9)">Prince George's County.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The governing body of the county shall meet and discuss with the governing body of any municipal corporation in the county the county property tax rate to be set for assessments of property in the municipal corporation as provided in this section. After the meeting if it can be demonstrated that a municipal corporation performs services or programs instead of similar county services or programs, the governing body of the county shall grant a tax setoff to the municipal corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as provided in subsection (k) of this section, in determining the county property tax rate to be set for assessments of property in a municipal corporation, the governing body of the county shall consider:<section prefix="(1)">the services and programs that are performed by the municipal corporation instead of similar county services and programs; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the extent that the similar services and programs are funded by property tax revenues.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The county property tax rate for assessments of property located in a municipal corporation is not required to be:<section prefix="(1)">the same as the rate for property located in other municipal corporations in the county; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the same as the rate set in a prior year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 180 days before the date that the annual county budget is required to be approved, any municipal corporation in the county that desires that a tax setoff be provided shall submit to the county a proposal that states the desired level of property tax setoff for the next fiscal year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A request submitted under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be accompanied by:<section prefix="1.">a description of the scope and nature of the services or programs provided by the municipal corporation instead of similar services or programs provided by the county; and</section><section prefix="2.">financial records and other documentation regarding municipal revenues and expenditures.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The materials submitted under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph shall provide sufficient detail for an assessment of the similar services or programs.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">After receiving a proposal from a municipal corporation requesting a tax setoff under this subsection, the governing body of the county shall promptly submit to the municipal corporation financial records and other documentation regarding county revenues and expenditures.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 90 days before the date that the annual county budget is required to be approved, the county and any municipal corporation submitting a tax setoff request under subsection (f) of this section shall designate appropriate policy and fiscal officers or representatives to meet and discuss the nature of the tax setoff request, relevant financial information of the county and municipal corporation, and the scope and nature of services provided by both entities.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A meeting held under paragraph (1) of this subsection may be held by the county representatives jointly with representatives from more than one municipal corporation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The county officers or representatives may request from the municipal corporation officers or representatives additional information that may reasonably be needed to assess the tax setoff.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The municipal corporation officers or representatives shall provide the additional information expeditiously.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At or before the time the proposed county budget is released to the public, the county commissioners, the county executive of a charter county, or the county council of a charter county without a county executive shall submit a statement of intent to each municipal corporation that has requested a tax setoff.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The statement of intent shall contain:<section prefix="(i)">an explanation of the level of the proposed tax setoff;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a description of the information or process used to determine the level of the proposed tax setoff; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">an indication that, before the budget is enacted, appropriate officials or representatives of the municipal corporation are entitled to appear before the county governing body to discuss or contest the level of the proposed tax setoff.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Representatives of each municipal corporation in the county requesting a tax setoff shall be afforded an opportunity to testify before the county governing body during normally scheduled hearings on the county's proposed budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsections (d), (f), and (g) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">a county and one or more municipal corporations may enter into an agreement setting different terms or timing for negotiations, calculations, or approval of a tax setoff; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a county may grant a tax setoff to a municipal corporation that does not make a request in the fashion described in this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">In Frederick County, for the taxable years that begin July 1, 2011, and July 1, 2012, the governing body of Frederick County shall grant a tax setoff to a municipal corporation in an amount that:<section prefix="(1)">is no less than the tax setoff granted to that municipal corporation for the preceding taxable year; and</section><section prefix="(2)">increases by the same percentage by which the county property tax rate exceeds the constant yield tax rate.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
