<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-302</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>302</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The governing body of Allegany County and of a municipal corporation in Allegany County shall grant a property tax credit under this section against the county and municipal corporation property tax imposed on:<section prefix="(1)">personal property that is owned by a nonprofit television broadcast translator station that is supported principally by public subscription; and</section><section prefix="(2)">property that is:<section prefix="(i)">owned by the South Cumberland Business and Civic Association, Incorporated; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">known as the South Cumberland Civic Center.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The governing body of Allegany County or of a municipal corporation in Allegany County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county or municipal corporation property tax imposed on:<section prefix="(1)">property that is owned by the Upper Potomac Jaycees, Incorporated;</section><section prefix="(2)">property that is owned by the Allegany Beagle Club, Incorporated;</section><section prefix="(3)">property that is:<section prefix="(i)">leased by Frostburg Community Hospital, Inc.; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">used for hospital purposes;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">property that is owned by the Western Maryland Scenic Railroad;</section><section prefix="(5)">property that is owned by the Frostburg Lions Club;</section><section prefix="(6)">property that is owned by the Cumberland/Allegany County Industrial Foundation, Inc.;</section><section prefix="(7)">property that is owned by the La Vale Lions Club Foundation, Inc.;</section><section prefix="(8)">property that is owned by the Carver Community Center, Inc.;</section><section prefix="(9)">property that is owned by the Cumberland Cultural Foundation and is known as the Gilchrist Museum;</section><section prefix="(10)">property that is owned by the Allegany County Agricultural Expo, Inc.; and</section><section prefix="(11)">property that is owned by the Allegany County Building Trades Education Foundation, Inc.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Allegany County shall grant a property tax credit under this section against the county property tax imposed on:<section prefix="(i)">property that is:<section prefix="1.">owned directly or indirectly by a bona fide labor union or a corporation whose capital stock is owned only by a bona fide labor union;</section><section prefix="2.">used only for the mutual benefit of the members of the bona fide labor union; and</section><section prefix="3.">except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, not used for profit;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">real property that is:<section prefix="1.">owned by a religious organization;</section><section prefix="2.">leased to the La Vale Athletic Association;</section><section prefix="3.">located in La Vale; and</section><section prefix="4.">used only to conduct athletic and recreational programs for youth; and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">real property on which improvements are made to a structure that the governing body of Allegany County has certified to be historically or architecturally significant.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any property under paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection that is commercially rented is taxable to the extent of the commercial use of the property.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A property tax credit granted under paragraph (1)(iii) of this subsection shall be:<section prefix="(i)">the following percentage of the increase that is due to the improvement:<section prefix="1.">100% of the increase in the assessment of the real property in the 1st and 2nd taxable years that the improved structure is subject to the county property tax;</section><section prefix="2.">80% of the increase in the assessment of the real property in the 3rd taxable year that the improved structure is subject to the county property tax;</section><section prefix="3.">60% of the increase in the assessment of the real property in the 4th taxable year that the improved structure is subject to the county property tax; and</section><section prefix="4.">40% of the increase in the assessment of the real property in the 5th taxable year that the improved structure is subject to the county property tax; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">ended after the 5th taxable year that the improved structure is subject to county property tax.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The governing body of Allegany County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county property tax imposed on real property that is:<section prefix="(1)">owned by the Greater Cumberland Chamber of Commerce;</section><section prefix="(2)">known as the Bell Tower Building; and</section><section prefix="(3)">located in Cumberland, Maryland.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The governing body of Allegany County shall grant a property tax credit under this section against the county and special district property tax imposed on:<section prefix="(1)">property that is owned by the Cresaptown Civic Improvement Association, Incorporated; and</section><section prefix="(2)">property that is owned by the Potomac Park Citizens Committee, Incorporated.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The governing body of Allegany County or of the City of Cumberland may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county and municipal corporation tax imposed on property that is owned by the Cumberland Outdoor Club, Incorporated.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Allegany County or of the City of Cumberland may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county and municipal corporation tax imposed on:<section prefix="(i)">property that is rehabilitated under regulations adopted by the governing body; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">property that is new construction under regulations adopted by the governing body.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A property tax credit granted under paragraph (1) of this subsection may not extend beyond the first 10 years after the rehabilitation or new construction is completed.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The amount of a tax credit granted under paragraph (1) of this subsection may not exceed the amount of the initial valuation of the rehabilitation to the property or the new construction and the resulting phase-in of the valuation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The governing body of Allegany County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county and special district property tax imposed on property that is owned by the Western Maryland Street Rod Association, Incorporated.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Allegany County may grant a county property tax credit or exemption for machinery and equipment used in manufacturing, assembling, processing, or refining products for sale or in the generation of electricity and may define, fix, or limit the amount, terms, scope, and duration of any credit or exemption provided for or affirmed under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To the extent that a tax credit or exemption is granted under this subsection for machinery and equipment used in manufacturing, assembling, processing, or refining products for sale, the property may not be treated as taxable personal property for the purpose of computing any payments of State aid to education under &#xA7; 5-202 of the Education Article or other payments of State aid to counties or municipal corporations that by law are based on the assessment of property.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">To the extent that a tax credit or exemption is granted under this subsection for machinery and equipment that is used in the generation of electricity for a facility that started generating electricity prior to June 1, 2000, the property may not be treated as taxable personal property for the purpose of computing any payments of State aid to education under &#xA7; 5-202 of the Education Article or other payments of State aid to counties or municipal corporations that by law are based on the assessment of property.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection do not apply to any personal property unless Allegany County submits to the Department, on or before October 31 of the taxable year for which the tax credit or exemption for the property is granted, the information required under &#xA7; 9-201(b) of this title regarding the tax credit or exemption.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To encourage the location and development of business operations and expansion of the employment base in Allegany County, the governing body of Allegany County and of a municipal corporation in Allegany County may grant, by law, a property tax credit against the county and municipal corporation property tax imposed on any property within:<section prefix="(i)">the area known as the Riverside Industrial Park;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a commercial or industrial park owned, managed, or operated by the Allegany County Commissioners; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a public industrial park owned, managed, or operated by an organization described in &#xA7; 501(c)(6) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In authorizing a credit under paragraph (1)(ii) or (iii) of this subsection, the governing body of the county or municipal corporation may provide, by law, for:<section prefix="(i)">the amount of the credit; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any other provision necessary to administer the credit.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A tax credit granted under this subsection may not be granted for more than 10 years.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the governing body of Allegany County or of a municipal corporation in Allegany County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county or municipal corporation property tax imposed on property that is subdivided into five or more lots for purposes of future residential development.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A property tax credit granted under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall equal 100% of the tax imposed on the increase in the assessment of the real property when the property is first revalued following the subdivision of the property.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A property tax credit granted under paragraph (1) of this subsection does not apply to a subdivided lot that has been transferred to a new owner after the property was subdivided.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Allegany County or of a municipal corporation in Allegany County may grant, by law, a property tax credit against the county or municipal corporation property tax imposed on any property that:<section prefix="(i)">is owned by Western Maryland Health System Corporation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">was formerly designated and operated as Western Maryland Health System Braddock Hospital; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">is vacant as a result of hospital consolidation and relocation approved by the Maryland Health Care Commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To encourage the location and development of business operations and expansion of the employment base in Allegany County, the governing body of Allegany County or of a municipal corporation in Allegany County may grant, by law, a property tax credit against the county or municipal corporation property tax imposed on any property that:<section prefix="(i)">was formerly owned by Western Maryland Health System Corporation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">was formerly designated and operated as Western Maryland Health System Braddock Hospital;</section><section prefix="(iii)">was formerly vacant as a result of hospital consolidation and relocation approved by the Maryland Health Care Commission; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">is owned, managed, or operated by an organization described in &#xA7; 501(c)(3) or &#xA7; 501(c)(6) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In authorizing a credit under paragraph (1) or (2) of this subsection, the governing body of the county or municipal corporation may provide, by law, for:<section prefix="(i)">the amount of the credit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">eligibility criteria for the credit;</section><section prefix="(iii)">regulations and procedures for the application and uniform processing of requests for the credit; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">any other provision necessary to administer the credit.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A tax credit granted under this subsection may not be granted for more than 10 years.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To encourage the location and development of business operations and expansion of the employment base in Allegany County, the governing body of Allegany County or of a municipal corporation in Allegany County may grant, by law, a property tax credit against the county or municipal corporation property tax imposed on any property within the area known as the Memorial Hilltop Centre.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In authorizing a credit under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the governing body of the county or municipal corporation may provide, by law, for:<section prefix="(i)">the amount of the credit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">eligibility criteria for the credit;</section><section prefix="(iii)">regulations and procedures for the application and uniform processing of requests for the credit; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">any other provision necessary to administer the credit.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A tax credit granted under this subsection may not be granted for more than 10 years.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
