<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-304" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-10-304</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">As used in this section, "damaged property" means:<section prefix="(1)">real property that is partially damaged or totally destroyed; or</section><section prefix="(2)">personal property that is totally destroyed.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">As to damaged property that should be removed from the assessment roll:<section prefix="(1)">if the damage occurred during the 6-month period from the date of finality to the June 30 following, property tax is not due for the taxable year beginning on the following July 1;</section><section prefix="(2)">if the damage occurred during the first month of the taxable year, 8% of the property tax is due;</section><section prefix="(3)">if the damage occurred during the second month of the taxable year, 17% of the property tax is due;</section><section prefix="(4)">if the damage occurred during the third month of the taxable year, 25% of the property tax is due;</section><section prefix="(5)">if the damage occurred during the fourth month of the taxable year, 33% of the property tax is due;</section><section prefix="(6)">if the damage occurred during the fifth month of the taxable year, 42% of the property tax is due;</section><section prefix="(7)">if the damage occurred during the sixth month of the taxable year, 50% of the property tax is due;</section><section prefix="(8)">if the damage occurred during the seventh month of the taxable year, 58% of the property tax is due;</section><section prefix="(9)">if the damage occurred during the eighth month of the taxable year, 67% of the property tax is due;</section><section prefix="(10)">if the damage occurred during the ninth month of the taxable year, 75% of the property tax is due;</section><section prefix="(11)">if the damage occurred during the tenth month of the taxable year, 83% of the property tax is due;</section><section prefix="(12)">if the damage occurred during the eleventh month of the taxable year, 91% of the property tax is due; and</section><section prefix="(13)">if the damage occurred during the twelfth month of the taxable year, the full amount of property tax is due.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If property tax is paid on property that qualifies for a property tax abatement under this section, the property tax shall be refunded as provided by Title 14, Subtitle 9 of this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
