<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-215" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-8-215</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person claiming to be aggrieved by discrimination prohibited by &#xA7; 8-214 of this subtitle may file a sworn, written complaint with the Attorney General.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Attorney General or the Attorney General's designee shall investigate all written complaints.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Attorney General may initiate an investigation of a suspected violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If there is reasonable cause for believing that a country club or golf course has practiced or is practicing discrimination in violation of &#xA7; 8-214 of this subtitle, the Attorney General or the Attorney General's designee shall hold a hearing to determine the existence of the alleged violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Attorney General or the Attorney General's designee may:<section prefix="(i)">administer oaths; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">issue subpoenas to compel the attendance and testimony of witnesses or the production of books, papers, records, and documents.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the Attorney General finds evidence of a pattern or practice of discrimination, the Attorney General shall make a consent agreement with the country club or golf course to end the discrimination.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a country club or golf course refuses to make a consent agreement, or breaches or violates a consent agreement, the Attorney General shall issue an order to the country club or golf course to end the discrimination.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a country club or golf course fails to comply with an order issued under subsection (c) of this section, the country club or golf course may not be assessed as a country club or golf course under &#xA7; 8-213 of this subtitle until the Attorney General determines that the country club or golf course complies with the order.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A country club or golf course that has failed to comply with an order issued under subsection (c) of this section shall be assessed as if there were no agreement under &#xA7; 8-213 of this subtitle. However, the country club or golf course is not liable for the unpaid taxes described in &#xA7; 8-216 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A country club or golf course may appeal any action taken under this section as provided by &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-222 and 10-223 of the State Government Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a country club or golf course fails to provide information requested by the Attorney General to investigate a charge of discrimination, the Attorney General may request that the circuit court for the county in which the country club or golf course is located issue a subpoena for the information.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the circuit court finds that the information sought relates to proof of discrimination by a country club or golf course, the court shall issue a subpoena for the information.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After a complaint has been filed, the Attorney General may bring an action to obtain a temporary injunction.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The action shall be brought in the circuit court for the county where the country club or golf course which is the subject of the alleged discrimination is located.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
