<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-304" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-304</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City shall grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county property tax imposed on real property that:<section prefix="(i)">is subject to a perpetual conservation easement donated to the Maryland Environmental Trust on or before June 30, 1986; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is not eligible for a credit under &#xA7; 9-107 of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City shall provide, by law, for:<section prefix="(i)">the amount and duration of the property tax credit under this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any other provisions necessary to carry out the property tax credit under this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county property tax imposed on:<section prefix="(1)">real property that is leased, occupied, and used only by the Baltimore Association for Retarded Citizens, Incorporated;</section><section prefix="(2)">personal property that is owned by the Northwest Family Sport Center, Inc.; and</section><section prefix="(3)">property that is:<section prefix="(i)">owned by the South Baltimore Little League;</section><section prefix="(ii)">located at 1101 E. Fort Avenue, Baltimore, Maryland; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">used for amateur sports.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "vacant dwelling" means residential real property that:<section prefix="(i)">contains no more than four dwelling units; and</section><section prefix="(ii)"/></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this subsection against the county property tax imposed on real property that is owned by qualifying owners of vacant dwellings.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A property tax credit granted under this subsection may not exceed the amount of county property tax imposed on the increased value of the residential real property that is due to the improvements made to the property immediately before the occupancy permit was issued, multiplied by:<section prefix="(i)">100% for the first taxable year in which the property qualifies for the tax credit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">80% for the second taxable year in which the property qualifies for the tax credit;</section><section prefix="(iii)">60% for the third taxable year in which the property qualifies for the tax credit;</section><section prefix="(iv)">40% for the fourth taxable year in which the property qualifies for the tax credit;</section><section prefix="(v)">20% for the fifth taxable year in which the property qualifies for the tax credit; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">0% for each taxable year thereafter.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Owners of vacant dwellings may qualify for the tax credit authorized by this subsection by:<section prefix="(i)">substantially rehabilitating the vacant dwelling in compliance with the code and laws applied to dwellings;</section><section prefix="(ii)">occupying the dwelling after rehabilitation as their principal residence; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">satisfying other requirements as may be provided by the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City may provide for procedures necessary and appropriate for the submission of an application for and the granting of a property tax credit under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Owner" means "homeowner" as defined in &#xA7; 9-105 of this title.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this subsection against the county property tax imposed on newly constructed dwellings that are owned by qualifying owners.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A property tax credit granted under this subsection may not exceed the amount of county property tax imposed on the real property, less the amount of any other credit applicable in that year, multiplied by:<section prefix="(i)">50% for the first taxable year in which the property qualifies for the tax credit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">40% for the second taxable year in which the property qualifies for the tax credit;</section><section prefix="(iii)">30% for the third taxable year in which the property qualifies for the tax credit;</section><section prefix="(iv)">20% for the fourth taxable year in which the property qualifies for the tax credit;</section><section prefix="(v)">10% for the fifth taxable year in which the property qualifies for the tax credit; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">0% for each taxable year thereafter.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Notwithstanding the credit amount calculated under paragraph (3) of this subsection, the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City may establish, by law, maximum limits on the cumulative property tax credit allowed under this subsection or on the amount of the credit allowed for any year.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Owners of newly constructed dwellings may qualify for the tax credit authorized by this subsection by:<section prefix="(i)">purchasing a newly constructed dwelling;</section><section prefix="(ii)">occupying the newly constructed dwelling as their principal residence;</section><section prefix="(iii)">filing a State income tax return during the period of the tax credit as a resident of Baltimore City; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">satisfying other requirements as may be provided by the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City may provide, by law, for two application periods during which owners can apply for the property tax credit under this subsection, one that is based on the purchase date of the dwelling and one that is based on the date of the assessment notice.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City shall provide for any procedures necessary and appropriate for implementing the application and amnesty periods.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City may provide for additional procedures necessary and appropriate for the submission of an application for and the granting of a property tax credit under this subsection, including procedures for granting partial credits for eligibility for less than a full taxable year.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The estimated amount of all tax credits received by owners under this subsection in any fiscal year shall be reported by the Director of Finance of Baltimore City as a "tax expenditure" for that fiscal year and shall be included in the publication of the City's budget for any subsequent fiscal year with the estimated or actual City property tax revenue for the applicable fiscal year.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">
        <section prefix="(i)">After June 30, 2014, additional owners of newly constructed dwellings may not be granted a credit under this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">This paragraph does not apply to an owner's continuing receipt of a credit as allowed in paragraph (3) of this subsection, with respect to a property for which a tax credit under this subsection was received for a taxable year ending on or before June 30, 2014.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Dwelling" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 9-105(a)(2) of this title.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Homeowner" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 9-105(a)(3) of this title.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City may grant, by law, a property tax credit against the county property tax imposed on a dwelling that:<section prefix="(i)">is owned by a homeowner;</section><section prefix="(ii)">has been substantially improved since the last reassessment; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">is reassessed at a higher value.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection, a tax credit under this section shall equal the amount of county property tax imposed on the increased value of the dwelling that is due to the improvements made to the property, multiplied by:<section prefix="(i)">100% for the first taxable year following the first reassessment after the improvements are made;</section><section prefix="(ii)">80% for the second taxable year following the first reassessment after the improvements are made;</section><section prefix="(iii)">60% for the third taxable year following the first reassessment after the improvements are made;</section><section prefix="(iv)">40% for the fourth taxable year following the first reassessment after the improvements are made;</section><section prefix="(v)">20% for the fifth taxable year following the first reassessment after the improvements are made; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">0% for each taxable year thereafter.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">To continue eligibility for a tax credit under this subsection, a dwelling must remain in compliance with the local housing code.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a dwelling owned by a person who has received a tax credit under this subsection is found to be in violation of the local housing code, the property owner is not eligible for any further tax credit under this subsection until the dwelling is determined again to be in compliance with the local housing code.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A dwelling that is again brought into compliance is eligible for a tax credit at the rate it would have been eligible before the violation of the local housing code.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If a dwelling that is eligible for a tax credit under this subsection is transferred, the grantee is eligible for the balance of the property tax credits under this subsection in the same manner and under the same conditions as the grantor of the property.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The property tax credit may not apply to the value of the improvements to the dwelling that exceed $100,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">To receive the tax credit under this subsection, the homeowner shall have the burden of showing that the increase in assessment is due to the value of the improvements to the dwelling that were made since the last assessment of the dwelling.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Market-rate rental housing project" means a multifamily dwelling containing five or more units in which none of the units are subject to government restrictions on the amount of rent charged or the income level of the tenant.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Newly constructed" means that an occupancy permit is issued on or after October 1, 1995.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this subsection against the county property tax imposed on newly constructed market-rate rental housing projects.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A property tax credit granted under this subsection may not exceed the amount of county property tax imposed on the real property, less the amount of any other credit applicable in that year, multiplied by:<section prefix="(i)">50% for the first taxable year in which the property qualifies for the tax credit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">40% for the second taxable year in which the property qualifies for the tax credit;</section><section prefix="(iii)">30% for the third taxable year in which the property qualifies for the tax credit;</section><section prefix="(iv)">20% for the fourth taxable year in which the property qualifies for the tax credit;</section><section prefix="(v)">10% for the fifth taxable year in which the property qualifies for the tax credit; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">0% for each taxable year thereafter.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City may provide additional eligibility requirements.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City may provide for procedures for the submission of an application for a property tax credit under this subsection and the granting of the credit, including procedures for the granting of a partial credit for property qualifying for the credit for less than a full taxable year.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A newly constructed market-rate rental housing project may not qualify for the first taxable year of a tax credit under this subsection after June 30, 2001.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">An ordinance of the Mayor and City Council authorizing tax credits in accordance with this subsection shall require:<section prefix="(i)">the development of a method, to be approved by the Board of Estimates, for analysis of the public costs and benefits of the tax credits; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">an annual report to the Board of Estimates and to the Mayor and City Council of the results and findings of that analysis.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
