<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-308</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>308</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Carroll County shall grant a property tax credit under this section against the county tax imposed on:<section prefix="(i)">real property that is:<section prefix="1.">owned by a nonprofit community or civic improvement association or corporation; and</section><section prefix="2.">used only for a community, civic, educational, or library purpose, if:</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">real property on which an improvement is made to an existing structure that is located in a historic district.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A property tax credit granted under paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection shall be:<section prefix="(i)">the following percentage of the increase that is due to the improvement:<section prefix="1.">100% of the increase in the assessment of the real property in the 1st and 2nd taxable years that the improved structure is subject to the county property tax;</section><section prefix="2.">80% of the increase in the assessment of the real property in the 3rd taxable year that the improved structure is subject to the county property tax;</section><section prefix="3.">60% of the increase in the assessment of the real property in the 4th taxable year that the improved structure is subject to the county property tax; and</section><section prefix="4.">40% of the increase in the assessment of the real property in the 5th taxable year that the improved structure is subject to the county property tax; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">ended after the 5th taxable year that the improved structure is subject to county property tax.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Carroll County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county property tax imposed on:<section prefix="(i)">real property that is:<section prefix="1.">owned by the Maryland Jaycees Foundation, Incorporated, of Carroll County; and</section><section prefix="2.">located at 602 Johahn Drive in Westminster, Maryland; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">real property that is:<section prefix="1.">leased by the Sykesville Little League, Incorporated;</section><section prefix="2.">located east of Obrecht Road in the 5th election district of Carroll County; and</section><section prefix="3.">used only by the Sykesville Little League, Incorporated.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A property tax credit granted under paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection shall continue in effect until the property is conveyed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Carroll County may grant, by law, a property tax credit against the county property tax imposed on real property used as a principal residence and owned by certain classes of individuals, as specified by the governing body of Carroll County, who are at least 65 years old and who are of limited income.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body of Carroll County may provide, by law, for:<section prefix="(i)">eligibility criteria for the credit under this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the amount and duration of the tax credit under this subsection;</section><section prefix="(iii)">regulations and procedures for the application and uniform processing of requests for the tax credit; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">any other provision necessary to carry out the credit under this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Carroll County may grant, by law, a property tax credit against the county property tax imposed on real property that is:<section prefix="(i)">located in designated geographic regions of the county;</section><section prefix="(ii)">owned by specified classes of persons; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">renovated, upgraded, or rehabilitated in accordance with eligibility criteria established by the county.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body of Carroll County, by law, may:<section prefix="(i)">specify the geographic areas of the county, classes of owners, and types of improvements to property eligible for the tax credit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">establish the amount and duration of the tax credit;</section><section prefix="(iii)">establish eligibility criteria for the tax credit; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">provide for any other provision necessary to carry out the tax credit under this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Carroll County may grant, by law, a property tax credit against the county property tax imposed on property on which a person installs environmentally friendly or "green" technologies, including conserving water, incorporating recycled or recyclable materials, and incorporating renewable and energy efficient power generation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body, by law, may:<section prefix="(i)">set the amount of the tax credit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">establish eligibility criteria for the tax credit;</section><section prefix="(iii)">establish the type of work that shall qualify for the tax credit;</section><section prefix="(iv)">establish the type of environmental technologies that will qualify for the tax credit; and</section><section prefix="(v)">set forth regulations and procedures for the application and uniform processing of requests for the tax credit.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "independent living retirement community" means a community or facility for the aged that:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">provides continuing care as defined in &#xA7; 10-401 of the Human Services Article;</section><section prefix="2.">is licensed as a related institution under Title 19, Subtitle 3 of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="3.">is certified by the Department of Aging; and</section><section prefix="4.">is exempt from federal income tax under &#xA7; 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code or is owned or operated by a person that is exempt from federal income tax under &#xA7; 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">offers an age-restricted life occupancy agreement and requires payment of an entrance fee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body of Carroll County or of a municipal corporation in Carroll County may grant, by law, a tax credit against the county or municipal corporation property tax imposed on that portion of the real property owned by an independent living retirement community that is used as housing units.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The governing body of Carroll County or of a municipal corporation in Carroll County may provide, by law, for:<section prefix="(i)">the amount and duration of the tax credit under this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">additional eligibility criteria for the tax credit under this subsection;</section><section prefix="(iii)">regulations and procedures for the application and uniform processing of requests for the tax credit under this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">any other provision necessary to carry out the tax credit under this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the governing body of Carroll County or of a municipal corporation in Carroll County authorizes a tax credit under this subsection, the full benefit of the tax credit shall be assigned to residents of the independent living retirement community.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
