<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="gtp" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-7-502</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subsection, "essential service facilities" includes dining halls, community rooms, and infir...</catch_line>
  <order_by>502</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "essential service facilities" includes dining halls, community rooms, and infirmaries.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Real property that meets the requirements of subsection (b) of this section is not subject to property tax if:<section prefix="(i)">the owner of the real property is:<section prefix="1.">a person who meets the ownership requirements of &#xA7; 7-202 of this title; or</section><section prefix="2.">a nonprofit corporation that is exempt from income tax under &#xA7; 10-104 of the Tax - General Article; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">the owner of the real property is engaged solely in constructing, operating, or managing multifamily rental housing and other related essential service facilities that:<section prefix="1.">are newly constructed on and after September 24, 1959;</section><section prefix="2.">are financed for at least 95% of the cost from loan funds provided under the National Housing Act of 1959 for senior citizen housing programs; and</section><section prefix="3.">are operated on a nonprofit basis with the revenues from the operation of the housing and facilities controlled by the loan program in order not to produce any net income.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The real property described in subsection (a) of this section may be exempt from property tax only if:<section prefix="(1)">the governing body of the subdivision where the real property is located approves an agreement between the subdivision and the owner; and</section><section prefix="(2)">under the agreement the owner pays the subdivision a negotiated amount in lieu of property tax.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An agreement under subsection (b) of this section may provide for abating or reducing property tax previously imposed on the real property.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Any payment negotiated under this section in lieu of the property tax shall be divided between the State and the subdivision, in the ratio that the tax rate of the State and the subdivision each bears to the total of the tax rates of the State and the subdivision.</section>
  </text>
</law>
