<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-7-514</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>514</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section shall be applicable to all taxable years beginning after June 30, 2008.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding &#xA7; 7-237 of this title, and subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, for a taxable year beginning before July 1, 2011, the governing body of a county may increase to not more than 65%, by law, the percent of the assessment of any personal property described in &#xA7; 7-237 of this title that is subject to county property tax.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body of a county may not increase the percent of assessment of personal property described in &#xA7; 7-237 of this title that is subject to county personal property tax to more than:<section prefix="(i)">65% for the taxable year beginning July 1, 2008;</section><section prefix="(ii)">60% for the taxable year beginning July 1, 2009; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">55% for the taxable year beginning July 1, 2010.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A county that increases the percent of assessment of taxable personal property under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall submit a copy of the law to the Department.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the Department receives a copy of the law on or before May 1, the change shall be effective for the taxable year following the date the law is enacted.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of a county may enter into an agreement with the owner of a facility for the generation of electricity that is located or locates in the county for a negotiated payment by the owner in lieu of taxes on the facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An agreement for a negotiated payment in lieu of taxes under this section shall provide that, for the term specified in the agreement:<section prefix="(i)">the owner shall pay to the county a specified amount each year in lieu of the payment of county real and personal property tax; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">all or a specified part of the real and personal property at the facility shall be exempt from county property tax for the term of the agreement.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">As specified in the agreement for a negotiated payment in lieu of taxes under this section, for the term specified in the agreement, the real and personal property at a facility for the generation of electricity that is located or locates in the county is exempt from county property tax.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">For each taxable year, Washington County shall distribute to the Town of Williamsport an amount equal to 35% of:<section prefix="(1)">any county property tax revenue attributable to increasing the percent of assessment of any personal property described in &#xA7; 7-237 of this title that is subject to county property tax, as authorized under subsection (b) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(2)">any amount received by the county under a negotiated payment in lieu of taxes under this section from an owner of an electricity generation facility that is located or locates in the Town of Williamsport.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
