<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-202.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-10-202.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "revitalization district" means a district designated by resolution adopted by the Prince George's County Council and approved by the County Executive or designated by the governing body of a municipal corporation in Prince George's County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">It is found and declared that there exists within Prince George's County:<section prefix="(i)">a number of economically depressed areas in need of revitalization; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">deteriorating communities.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Older commercial centers are decaying. A need exists to provide an incentive to property owners to revive the older communities. New business in these areas would bring about new housing and new jobs. The establishment of revitalization districts with the provision of a tax deferral will give property owners an incentive to renovate deteriorating properties.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the governing body of Prince George's County or any municipal corporation within Prince George's County may by resolution establish revitalization districts for the purpose of encouraging revitalization.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body of Prince George's County may not establish a revitalization district within the boundaries of a municipal corporation without the approval of the governing body of the municipal corporation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The governing body of Prince George's County or the governing body of a municipal corporation in Prince George's County may authorize, by law, the deferral of increased property taxes imposed by that governing body on real property located within a revitalization district that:<section prefix="(1)">is substantially renovated after the creation of the revitalization district;</section><section prefix="(2)">is reassessed as the result of the renovation and is assessed at a higher value than would otherwise have been assessed; and</section><section prefix="(3)">is eligible for the tax deferral as provided by local law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The governing body authorizing the tax deferral may authorize, by law, procedures for the determination of eligibility of property for the tax deferral by:<section prefix="(1)">establishing criteria for the extent of renovation;</section><section prefix="(2)">requiring approval of the renovation plan; and</section><section prefix="(3)">requiring the owner of the property to make application for the deferral.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The deferral authorized under this section:<section prefix="(1)">may apply only to the tax liability increase directly attributable to the value added by the renovation of the property;</section><section prefix="(2)">may not be granted for a period exceeding 5 years; and</section><section prefix="(3)">shall constitute a lien on the property until paid in full.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Upon expiration of the deferral, the governing body may provide for payment of the deferred taxes in 1 payment or in annual payments of not more than 5 payments.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Upon transfer of ownership of the property, the governing body may provide for immediate payment of the deferred taxes in 1 payment.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
