<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="gtp" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-6-308</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "taxing authority" means:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>308</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "taxing authority" means:<section prefix="(1)">the county council or board of county commissioners;</section><section prefix="(2)">the City Council of Baltimore City; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the governing body of a municipal corporation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless the requirements of this section are met, a taxing authority may not set a county or municipal corporation real property tax rate that exceeds the constant yield tax rate in any taxable year excluding revenue from real property appearing for the 1st time on the assessment roll.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A taxing authority does not meet the requirements of this section until it provides to the Department:<section prefix="(i)">on or before 15 days after the date of the advertisement required by this section a copy of the entire newspaper page that carried the meeting notice required by this section; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the evidence that the Department requires of the mailing of the notices described in subsection (c) of this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a taxing authority intends to set a county or municipal corporation real property tax rate that exceeds the constant yield tax rate, it shall advertise to the public by:<section prefix="(1)">placing an advertisement that satisfies the Department and meets the requirements of this section in a newspaper of general circulation in the jurisdiction of the taxing authority; or</section><section prefix="(2)">mailing a notice that meets the requirements of this section to each property taxpayer who resides in the jurisdiction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The advertisement shall be at least 1/4 of a page in size for counties and 1/8 of a page in size for municipal corporations.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The type that is used in the advertisement shall be:<section prefix="(i)">at least 18 point for counties; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">at least 12 point for municipal corporations.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The advertisement may not be placed with legal notices or classified advertisements.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The headline for the advertisement shall be in bold print, with all letters capitalized.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The text of the advertisement, other than the headline, shall be in upper and lower case letters.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The notice or advertisement shall be in the following form:</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The meeting on the proposed county or municipal corporation real property tax rate increase shall be held:<section prefix="(i)">on or after the 7th day and on or before the 21st day after the notice is published as required by subsection (c) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">on or before June 17th before the date required by law for imposition of the real property tax.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The meeting may coincide with the meeting on the proposed budget of the taxing authority.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In computing periods of time under this subsection all calendar days shall be counted including Saturdays, Sundays, and holidays.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">After the meeting, the taxing authority may adopt by law an increase in the county or municipal corporation real property tax rate that exceeds the constant yield tax rate:<section prefix="(1)">on the day of the meeting; or</section><section prefix="(2)">on a later day, if the day, time, and location to consider the increase are announced at that meeting.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The requirements of this section do not apply if a taxing authority:<section prefix="(1)">increases the county or municipal corporation real property tax rate above the constant yield tax rate solely because of the reduction in the taxing authority's real property assessable base due to the final determination of assessment appeals; or</section><section prefix="(2)">sets a county or municipal corporation real property tax rate that does not exceed the constant yield tax rate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Annually, a county shall include on the face of a real property tax bill:<section prefix="(i)">the county real property tax rate and the constant yield tax rate for the taxable year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the amount, if any, by which the county real property tax rate exceeds the constant yield tax rate; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">a designation that the property is either the owner's "principal residence" or "not a principal residence".</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A county shall also mail with the real property tax bill the information described below in substantially the following form:</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">A taxing authority that in good faith has made all reasonable efforts to comply with the requirements of subsections (b) through (g) of this section and provides satisfactory evidence to the Department that any lack of compliance with the requirements was for reasons beyond the taxing authority's control:<section prefix="(1)">is deemed to have complied with the requirements; and</section><section prefix="(2)">may set a real property tax rate that exceeds the constant yield tax rate.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
