<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="gtp" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-14-833</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in subsections (a-1), (e), (f), and (g) of this section, at any time after 6 mont...</catch_line>
  <order_by>833</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsections (a-1), (e), (f), and (g) of this section, at any time after 6 months from the date of sale a holder of any certificate of sale may file a complaint to foreclose all rights of redemption of the property to which the certificate relates.</section>
    <section prefix="(a-1)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The holder of a certificate of sale may not file a complaint to foreclose the right of redemption until at least 2 months after sending the first notice and at least 30 days after sending the second notice required under this subsection to:<section prefix="(i)">the person who last appears as owner of the property on the collector's tax roll; and</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">the current mortgagee of the property, assignee of a mortgagee of record, or servicer of the current mortgage; or</section><section prefix="2.">the current holder of a beneficial interest in a deed of trust recorded against the property.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The holder of a certificate of sale is not required to provide the notices under this subsection if subsection (e), (f), or (g) of this section applies to the property.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The notices required under this subsection shall include at least the following:<section prefix="(i)">a statement of the fact of the issuance of a certificate of sale;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a copy of the certificate of sale, if the holder of the certificate of sale received the certificate of sale before the notice was sent under this paragraph;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a statement that the owner, a mortgage holder, or any other person that has an estate or interest in the property may redeem the property at any time until the right of redemption has been finally foreclosed under the provisions of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a statement that the holder of the certificate of sale may file an action to foreclose the right of redemption at any time after 2 months from the date of the first notice;</section><section prefix="(v)">a statement that if the property is redeemed before an action to foreclose the right of redemption is filed, the amount that shall be paid to redeem the property is:<section prefix="1.">the total lien amount on the property at the time of sale, with interest;</section><section prefix="2.">any taxes, interest, and penalties paid by the holder of the certificate of sale;</section><section prefix="3.">any taxes, interest, and penalties accruing after the date of the tax sale; and</section><section prefix="4.">the following expenses incurred by the holder of the certificate of sale:</section></section><section prefix="(vi)">a statement that if the property is redeemed after an action to foreclose the right of redemption has been filed, the amount that shall be paid to redeem the property is the sum of:<section prefix="1.">the total lien amount on the property at the time of sale, with interest;</section><section prefix="2.">any taxes, interest, and penalties paid by the holder of the certificate of sale;</section><section prefix="3.">any taxes, interest, and penalties accruing after the date of the tax sale; and</section><section prefix="4.">attorney's fees and expenses to which the holder of the certificate of sale may be entitled under &#xA7; 14-843(a)(4) and (5) of this subtitle;</section></section><section prefix="(vii)">the provisions of &#xA7; 14-843(a) of this subtitle, reproduced as they appear in the Code;</section><section prefix="(viii)">a statement that, in Baltimore City only, the holder of the certificate of sale is entitled to taxes, interest, and penalties paid in accordance with &#xA7; 14-843(c) of this subtitle and interest at the rate of redemption under &#xA7; 14-820 of this subtitle from the date of payment to the date of redemption; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">the name, address, and telephone number of:<section prefix="1.">the holder of the certificate of sale, or the holder's agent or attorney; and</section><section prefix="2.">the collector who made the sale.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The first of the two notices required under this subsection may not be sent until 4 months after the date of sale.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The second of the two notices required under this section shall be sent:<section prefix="1.">to the persons listed in paragraph (1) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="2.">no earlier than 1 week after the first notice required under this subsection is sent.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If a certificate of sale is assigned after the first notice required under this subsection is sent and before an action to foreclose the right of redemption is filed, the assignee:<section prefix="(i)">at any time after the assignment, shall send one additional notice under this subsection reflecting the new holder of the certificate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">may not file a complaint to foreclose the right of redemption until at least 2 months after the additional notice has been sent.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The first of the two notices required under this subsection shall be sent:<section prefix="1.">by first-class certified mail, postage prepaid, return receipt requested, bearing a postmark from the United States Postal Service; and</section><section prefix="2.">in an envelope prominently marked on the outside with the following phrase "Notice of Delinquent Property Tax".</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The second of the two notices required under this subsection shall be sent:<section prefix="1.">by first-class certified mail, postage prepaid, return receipt requested, bearing a postmark from the United States Postal Service; and</section><section prefix="2.">in an envelope prominently marked on the outside with the following phrase "Notice of Delinquent Property Tax".</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The notice required under this subsection shall be sent to each person at the person's last address known to the holder of the certificate of sale, as obtained from:<section prefix="(i)">the last deed or mortgage relating to the property recorded among the land records in the county in which the property is located;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the tax rolls of the collector who made the sale, as to the property described in the certificate of sale; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">with respect to the address of the resident agent and the principal office of the current mortgagee of record, the Department of Assessments and Taxation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(8)">In a proceeding to foreclose the right of redemption, if the holder of a certificate of sale, the holder's agent, or the attorney of the holder of a certificate of sale, files an affidavit, before the court enters a final judgment foreclosing the right of redemption, attesting to the fact that the affiant has complied with the notice provisions of this subsection and provides evidence that the second of the two notices required under this subsection was sent by certified mail as required under paragraph (6)(ii) of this subsection, then:<section prefix="(i)">the notice provisions of this subsection shall be deemed satisfied; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the failure of the owner, mortgagee, or beneficiary of a deed of trust to receive the required notice does not invalidate the proceeding to foreclose the right of redemption or the final judgment of the court.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The right to redeem shall continue until finally barred by decree of the circuit court in which the foreclosure proceeding is filed.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The certificate is void unless a proceeding to foreclose the right of redemption is filed within 2 years of the date of the certificate of sale.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Baltimore City a certificate for abandoned property sold under &#xA7; 14-817(c) of this subtitle with a minimum bid less than the lien amount reverts to the Mayor and City Council and is void as to the private purchaser at tax sale unless:<section prefix="(i)">a proceeding to foreclose the right of redemption is filed within 3 months of the date of the certificate of sale; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">unless the holder is granted an extension by the court due to a showing of extraordinary circumstances beyond the certificate holder's control, the holder secures a decree from the circuit court in which the foreclosure proceeding was filed within 18 months from the date of the filing of the foreclosure proceeding.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a certificate is void under subsection (c) of this section, then any right, title, and interest of the holder of the certificate of sale, in the property sold shall cease and all money received by the collector on account of the sale shall be deemed forfeited, and shall be applied by the collector on the taxes in arrears on the property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a certificate for abandoned property reverts to the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City under this section, the Mayor and City Council may:<section prefix="(i)">file a foreclosure proceeding in its own name; or</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">resell the certificate; and</section><section prefix="2.">apply all money received on account of the sale to any outstanding balance remaining after the sale on the tax debt owed by the previous owner of the abandoned property.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If any building or structure is sold and purchased under this subtitle, and the appropriate government agency certifies that the particular building or structure involved requires, or within 6 months shall require, substantial repairs to comply with the applicable building code:<section prefix="(1)">the holder of any certificate of sale may at any time after 60 days from the date of sale file a complaint to foreclose all rights of redemption of the property to which the certificate relates; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the certificate of the appropriate government agency shall be a part of the complaint to foreclose the rights of redemption.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The holder of a certificate of sale for abandoned property in Baltimore City sold under &#xA7; 14-817(c) of this subtitle with a minimum bid less than the lien amount may file a complaint to foreclose all rights of redemption in the property at any time after the date of sale.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">When the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City becomes the holder of a certificate of sale purchased in accordance with &#xA7; 14-824 of this subtitle, the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City may file a complaint, at any time after the date of sale, to foreclose all rights of redemption in abandoned property consisting of:<section prefix="(1)">a vacant lot; or</section><section prefix="(2)">improved property cited as vacant and unfit for habitation on a housing or building violation notice.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
