<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-12-110</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>110</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsections (c) and (d) of this section, in any county except Prince George's, the recordation tax collected by the collector or the clerk of the circuit court shall be paid to the governing body of the county in which the recordation tax was collected.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Prince George's County the recordation tax is both paid to and collected by the Director of Finance of Prince George's County.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who offers for recordation an instrument of writing for property located in 2 or more counties shall submit to the collector or the clerk of the circuit court for each county a certificate showing the apportionment of the total value of the property between each of the counties.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For an instrument of writing recorded under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the recordation tax in each county in which the property is located is:<section prefix="(i)">payable at the rate of tax that applies in the county; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">based on the ratio that the value of the property in that county bears to the value of the property in all counties.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Recordation tax collected under &#xA7; 12-103(c) of this title shall be paid to the Comptroller for deposit in the General Fund of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall deduct the cost of administering the recordation tax from the taxes collected under this title and credit those revenues to the fund established under &#xA7; 1-203.3 of the Corporations and Associations Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After deducting the revenues required under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the recordation tax collected under &#xA7;&#xA7; 12-103(d) and 12-117 of this title shall be paid to the Comptroller. The Comptroller shall distribute the revenue to the counties in the ratio that the recordation tax collected in the prior fiscal year in each county bears to the total recordation tax collected in all counties in that year.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
