<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-317" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-317</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The governing body of Montgomery County and of a municipal corporation in Montgomery County shall grant a property tax credit under this section against the county and municipal corporation property tax imposed on:<section prefix="(1)">personal property that is owned by a nonprofit, nonstock cooperative housing corporation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">real property that is:<section prefix="(i)">leased, if the payment to the lessor under the lease is limited to:</section><section prefix="(ii)">used only as a theater that contains at least 175 seats; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">used by a nonprofit community theatrical organization that, except for any clerical or maintenance employee, does not have any paid officer, director, or employee. The organization may be required by the governing body to pay an annual charge for any actual public service rendered.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Montgomery County or of a municipal corporation in Montgomery County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county or municipal corporation property tax imposed on:<section prefix="(i)">real property that is:</section><section prefix="(ii)">personal property that is used to improve, replace, or maintain a road, common area, or common facility that is:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The amount of a property tax credit granted under paragraph (1)(i)4 of this subsection may not exceed 25% of the county property tax or the municipal corporation property tax due on the property.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The governing body of Montgomery County or of the municipal corporation shall specify the qualifications for eligibility and conditions of certification for the tax credit under paragraph (1)(i)4 of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On application of the governing body of a municipal corporation and approval by the governing body of Montgomery County, the property eligible for a credit against the municipal corporation property tax, under this subsection, shall also receive a credit against the county property tax.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Montgomery County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county property tax imposed on:<section prefix="(i)">real property on which an improvement is made to an existing structure in a neighborhood improvement plan area that the governing body of Montgomery County determines to be a special target area for residential, business, and community redevelopment because of blight or deterioration;</section><section prefix="(ii)">real property that is:</section><section prefix="(iii)">real property for which the county has determined there are development impact tax credits that exceed the amount that can be used under county law.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A property tax credit granted under paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection shall be:<section prefix="(i)">a percentage of the actual cost of the improvements as the governing body of Montgomery County determines for the 1st 4 taxable years that the improved property is subject to county property tax; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">not allowed after the 1st 4 taxable years that the improved property is subject to property tax.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The governing body of Montgomery County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county property tax imposed on the portion of real property that is owned by the American Association of Blood Banks, Incorporated or leased by the American Association of Blood Banks, Incorporated under a lease of 50 years or more and that is necessary for and actually used exclusively for the charitable or educational purposes of that organization.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "dwelling unit" means a building or portion of a building providing complete living facilities for not more than one family, including, at a minimum, facilities for cooking, sanitation, and sleeping.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body of Montgomery County may grant, by law, to a total of 1,500 dwelling units, a property tax credit against the county property tax imposed on owner-occupied, residential real property that is purchased from July 1, 2000 through June 30, 2002, in specific geographic areas of Montgomery County that:<section prefix="(i)">contain not fewer than 50 dwelling units; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">are designated by the County Executive of Montgomery County for participation in a demonstration project for neighborhood preservation and stabilization.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In order to qualify for the credit under this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">for the 12-month period immediately prior to purchasing the property, the individual's principal residence may not have been located in the geographic areas designated under this subsection, unless the individual was not an owner of the property that was the individual's principal residence; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the residential real property must have been purchased in conformance with regulations adopted by the County Executive that are approved by the County Council.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The property tax credit shall equal:<section prefix="(i)">40% of the county property tax for each of the first 5 taxable years after the purchase of the real property;</section><section prefix="(ii)">35% of the county property tax for the 6th taxable year after the purchase of the real property;</section><section prefix="(iii)">30% of the county property tax for the 7th taxable year after the purchase of the real property;</section><section prefix="(iv)">25% of the county property tax for the 8th taxable year after the purchase of the real property;</section><section prefix="(v)">20% of the county property tax for the 9th taxable year after the purchase of the real property;</section><section prefix="(vi)">15% of the county property tax for the 10th taxable year after the purchase of the real property; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">0% of the county property tax for each taxable year thereafter.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The property tax credit shall first apply to the taxable year beginning after the date of the purchase of the eligible real property.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The governing body of Montgomery County may provide, by law, for any other provision necessary to carry out the property tax credit under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The County Executive of Montgomery County shall hold a public hearing prior to the final designation of the geographic areas under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Designation of geographic areas shall be made by regulation adopted by the County Executive and approved by the County Council.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A geographic area may be designated within a municipality only with the approval of the municipality's governing body.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The Montgomery County Department of Finance shall provide, on an annual basis to those individuals qualifying for the property tax credit under this subsection, a statement certifying qualification for the property tax credit and the amount of the property tax credit being granted. The statement may be provided on or with the annual property tax bill or in another manner as chosen by the local government.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">In order to be eligible for a property tax credit under this subsection, an individual shall apply for the credit within 6 months after the title to the residential property has been transferred to the individual.</section>
      <section prefix="(10)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The property tax credit granted under this subsection terminates on the sale of the residential real property granted the credit.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A property owner who purchases residential real property for which the property tax credit has been terminated under this paragraph may apply for, and may be granted, a separate property tax credit if the property owner and the residential real property otherwise meet the conditions of this subsection.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Eligible business entity" means a person who operates or conducts a trade or business on qualified enterprise zone property but does not own the qualified enterprise zone property.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Qualified enterprise zone property" means real property that:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to paragraphs (4) and (5) of this subsection, the governing body of Montgomery County or of a municipal corporation in Montgomery County may grant, by law, a property tax credit against the county or municipal corporation property tax imposed on:<section prefix="(i)">improvements made by an eligible business entity to qualified enterprise zone property; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">personal property owned by an eligible business entity located on qualified enterprise zone property.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The governing body of Montgomery County or of a municipal corporation in Montgomery County may provide, by law, for:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The governing body of Montgomery County or of a municipal corporation in Montgomery County shall define, by law, the improvements eligible for a credit under this subsection.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The lessor of real property granted a credit under paragraph (2)(i) of this subsection shall reduce the amount of taxes for which an eligible business entity is contractually liable under the lease agreement by the amount of any credit granted under paragraph (2)(i) of this subsection for improvements made by the eligible business entity.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The lessor of real property that receives a credit under &#xA7; 9-103 of this title may not be granted a credit under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Benefit corporation" means a Maryland corporation that elects to be a benefit corporation and complies with Title 5, Subtitle 6C of the Corporations and Associations Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Benefit limited liability company" means a Maryland limited liability company that elects to be a benefit limited liability company and complies with Title 4A, Subtitle 11 of the Corporations and Associations Article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body of Montgomery County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this subsection against the county property tax imposed on real or personal property that is:<section prefix="(i)">owned or leased by a benefit corporation or benefit limited liability company;</section><section prefix="(ii)">not used for residential purposes; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">used in a trade or business by a benefit corporation or benefit limited liability company.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The governing body of Montgomery County may provide, by law, for:<section prefix="(i)">criteria for eligibility and certification for the tax credit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the amount of the tax credit;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the duration of the tax credit, for a period not to exceed 10 years;</section><section prefix="(iv)">regulations and procedures for the application, certification, and uniform processing of requests for the tax credit;</section><section prefix="(v)">limited aggregate amounts of tax credits granted under this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">any other provision necessary to carry out the tax credit under this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
