<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-209</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>209</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">As provided in subsection (c) of this section, the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the governing body of a county or of a municipal corporation may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county or municipal corporation property tax imposed on the operating property of a railroad company that is subject to assessment under &#xA7; 8-108 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The property tax credit under this section shall be 100% of the county or municipal corporation property tax against the property described in subsection (a) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A property tax credit may be granted for any fiscal year that the railroad company provides freight service in the county or municipal corporation under a contract between the railroad company or its trustees and:<section prefix="(i)">the county or municipal corporation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an industrial development corporation; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a private shippers' association.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Under a formula that reduces the obligation because of the property tax credit provided under this section, a contract under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall include a provision that obligates the county or municipal corporation, the industrial development corporation, or the private shippers' association:<section prefix="(i)">to supplement the revenues of the railroad company; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">to contribute to the restoration or maintenance of the operating property.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A property tax credit granted under this section may be effective for the 3 fiscal years immediately before the fiscal year for which the tax credit is sought.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In Frederick County a property tax credit granted under this section shall continue from year to year until the property is conveyed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the appropriate governing body may adopt regulations necessary to carry out this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or each governing body shall designate the administrative unit or official to administer the property tax credit granted under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">When a tax bill is sent to a taxpayer who is entitled to a property tax credit under this section, the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the appropriate governing body shall give notice of the property tax credit under this section to the taxpayer.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except in Frederick County, if a taxpayer fails to apply for a property tax credit under this section on or before October 1 of each taxable year, the property tax credit may not be granted.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Frederick County, a taxpayer may apply for a property tax credit under this section on or before October 1 of the taxable year.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A taxpayer shall state under oath that the facts in the application are true.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
