<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="gtp" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-314</section_number>
  <catch_line>The governing body of Harford County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section aga...</catch_line>
  <order_by>314</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Harford County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county property tax imposed on:<section prefix="(i)">real property that is:<section prefix="1.">owned by any incorporated community association:</section><section prefix="2.">used as a public park, playground, or picnic area;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">property that is:<section prefix="1.">owned by the Habonim Camp Association Company, Incorporated;</section><section prefix="2.">used only for the purposes of the Habonim Camp Association Company; and</section><section prefix="3.">in excess of the property exempted under &#xA7; 7-202 of this article;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">property that is owned by the Maryland Ornithological Society, Incorporated;</section><section prefix="(iv)">real property that is:<section prefix="1.">owned by the North Harford Game and Fish Association, Incorporated;</section><section prefix="2.">located on Wheeler School Road; and</section><section prefix="3.">used only for the purposes of the association;</section></section><section prefix="(v)">real property that is:<section prefix="1.">owned by the trustees of the Ladew Topiary Gardens;</section><section prefix="2.">located on Jarrettsville Pike;</section><section prefix="3.">used only for the purposes of the Ladew Topiary Gardens; and</section><section prefix="4.">in excess of the property exempted under &#xA7; 7-202 of this article;</section></section><section prefix="(vi)">real property that:<section prefix="1.">is used primarily for an agricultural purpose; and</section><section prefix="2.">does not have an agricultural use assessment;</section></section><section prefix="(vii)">real property that is:<section prefix="1.">used primarily for amateur sports events; and</section><section prefix="2.">owned by the Havre de Grace Little League, Incorporated;</section></section><section prefix="(viii)">real property, only after July 1, 1988, that:<section prefix="1.">is located in an agricultural district under an original or renewed agreement to be located within an agricultural district; or</section><section prefix="2.">becomes subject to an agricultural preservation easement that has been conveyed to the Maryland Agricultural Land Preservation Foundation;</section></section><section prefix="(ix)">real property that is:<section prefix="1.">owned by a Harford County volunteer fire or ambulance company;</section><section prefix="2.">held for the future use as a station or substation site, as approved by the Harford County Volunteer Fire and Ambulance Association in their 5-year plan; and</section><section prefix="3.">not exempt under &#xA7; 7-209 of this article;</section></section><section prefix="(x)">subject to the condition established under paragraph (4) of this subsection, owner-occupied residential real property:<section prefix="1."/><section prefix="2.">that is determined by the governing body of Harford County to have been adversely impacted by its proximity to the refuse disposal system;</section></section><section prefix="(xi)">real property, only after July 1, 1993, that:<section prefix="1.">is located in the Harford County Agricultural District in accordance with the Harford County Agricultural Land Preservation Program under Chapter 60 of the Harford County Code; or</section><section prefix="2.">becomes subject to an agricultural preservation easement that has been conveyed to Harford County in accordance with the Harford County Agricultural Land Preservation Program, under Chapter 60 of the Harford County Code;</section></section><section prefix="(xii)">subject to paragraph (6) of this subsection, real property that is new construction or a substantial improvement to the real property of a commercial or industrial business that:<section prefix="1.">is or will be doing business in Harford County; and</section><section prefix="2.">will employ at least 12 additional full-time local employees by the second year the credit is allowed;</section></section><section prefix="(xiii)">subject to paragraph (7) of this subsection, real property:<section prefix="1.">that is located in a Rural Legacy Area as defined in &#xA7; 5-9A-02 of the Natural Resources Article; and</section><section prefix="2.">for which the property owner has sold the development rights under the Rural Legacy Program established under Title 5, Subtitle 9A of the Natural Resources Article; and</section></section><section prefix="(xiv)">real property:<section prefix="1.">that is adjacent to property that is:</section><section prefix="2.">that was subdivided from the adjacent property, withdrawn from the agricultural district or agricultural easement, and conveyed to a child of the owner of the adjacent property under a child lot exclusion to build a home on the property; and</section><section prefix="3.">the owner of which:</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body of Harford County shall adopt procedures that govern the amount of and the conditions of eligibility and method of application for the property tax credit granted under paragraph (1)(vi) of this subsection. The amount of the property tax credit may not be more than the amount of property tax on real property that is associated with the difference between the actual assessment of the land and the maximum allowable agricultural use assessment that the Department establishes.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A property owner is not eligible for a tax credit for real property under paragraph (1)(viii) of this subsection, and any such tax credit granted shall terminate, if the property owner terminates the agricultural district agreement or the agricultural preservation easement.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A property owner who has been granted a property tax credit for real property under paragraph (1)(viii) of this subsection, and who subsequently terminates the agricultural preservation district agreement or the agricultural preservation easement shall be liable for all property taxes that the owner would have been liable for if a property tax credit had not been granted under this section for a period not exceeding 3 years from the date that the agricultural district agreement was recorded.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this paragraph, "environmental surcharges" means tipping fees that:<section prefix="1.">are paid to the county by the user of a refuse disposal system; and</section><section prefix="2.">have been set at a specific amount per ton of refuse that is deposited at the site of the disposal system.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A property tax credit may not be granted under paragraph (1)(x) of this subsection unless the governing body of Harford County approves the use of environmental surcharges to offset the total amount of the property tax credits granted.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A property owner is not eligible for a tax credit for real property under paragraph (1)(xi) of this subsection and any such tax credit granted shall terminate if the property owner withdraws the property from the Harford County Agricultural District.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A property owner who has been granted a property tax credit for real property under paragraph (1)(xi) of this subsection, and who subsequently withdraws the property from the Agricultural Preservation District shall be liable for all property taxes that the owner would have been liable for if a property tax credit had not been granted.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Except as otherwise provided in this paragraph, the governing body of Harford County may:<section prefix="(i)">provide for the amount of and the conditions of eligibility and method of application for the property tax credit authorized under paragraph (1)(xii) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">review compliance with the conditions of the property tax credit annually; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">eliminate the credit for any taxpayer if the terms and conditions of the credit are not met.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The governing body of Harford County may provide for the conditions of eligibility and method of application for and the amount of the property tax credit authorized under paragraph (1)(xiii) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Harford County or of a municipal corporation in Harford County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county or municipal corporation property tax imposed on real property that is:<section prefix="(i)">owned by any person who:<section prefix="1.">constructs a housing structure; or</section><section prefix="2.">operates a housing project;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">used for a housing structure or project which may contain a community service facility;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a structure constructed or substantially rehabilitated under &#xA7; 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 primarily for occupancy by elderly individuals;</section><section prefix="(iv)">receiving rent subsidy; and</section><section prefix="(v)">operated on a nonprofit or limited distribution basis.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body of Harford County and of a municipal corporation in Harford County, where applicable, shall make an agreement with the owner of property for which a property tax credit is granted under paragraph (1) of this subsection to pay negotiated amounts instead of all county or municipal corporation property taxes. Where applicable, the amount paid shall be apportioned between Harford County and the municipal corporation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of a municipal corporation in Harford County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the municipal corporation property tax imposed on real property located within the jurisdiction of the municipal corporation that is owned and occupied as the principal residence of an individual serving as a member of a:<section prefix="(i)">volunteer fire company;</section><section prefix="(ii)">volunteer ambulance company; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">ladies' auxiliary of a volunteer fire company or volunteer ambulance company.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The municipal corporation may provide, by law, for:<section prefix="(i)">the amount of a property tax credit under this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the duration of a property tax credit under this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">any other provision necessary to carry out this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "facility" means a continuing care facility for the aged that:<section prefix="(i)">provides continuing care as defined in &#xA7; 10-401 of the Human Services Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is licensed as a related institution under Title 19, Subtitle 3 of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">is certified by the Department of Aging; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">is exempt from federal income tax under &#xA7; 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code or is owned or operated by a person that is exempt from federal income tax under &#xA7; 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body of Harford County or of a municipal corporation in Harford County may grant, by law, a tax credit against the county or municipal corporation property tax imposed on property that is:<section prefix="(i)">owned or operated by a facility or by a person that is exempt from federal income tax under &#xA7; 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">available for use in connection with a facility.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The governing body of Harford County or of a municipal corporation in Harford County may provide, by law, for:<section prefix="(i)">the amount and duration of the tax credit under this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">additional eligibility criteria for the tax credit under this subsection;</section><section prefix="(iii)">regulations and procedures for the application and uniform processing of requests for the tax credit; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">any other provision necessary to carry out the credit under this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
