<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="gtp" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-319</section_number>
  <catch_line>The governing body of Queen Anne's County and the governing body of a municipal corporation in Queen...</catch_line>
  <order_by>319</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The governing body of Queen Anne's County and the governing body of a municipal corporation in Queen Anne's County shall grant a property tax credit under this section against the county and municipal corporation property tax imposed on property that is not used for a commercial purpose and is owned by:<section prefix="(1)">the Ingleside Community Group;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Lions Club of Kent Island, Maryland, Inc.;</section><section prefix="(3)">the Price Community Club, Incorporated;</section><section prefix="(4)">the Ruthsburg Community Club, Incorporated;</section><section prefix="(5)">the Sudlersville Community Betterment Club, Incorporated;</section><section prefix="(6)">the Templeville Community Association, Incorporated;</section><section prefix="(7)">the William T. Roe Memorial Range; or</section><section prefix="(8)">the Kent Island Volunteer Fire Department, Incorporated.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The governing body of Queen Anne's County shall grant a property tax credit under this section against the county property tax imposed on real property that is:<section prefix="(1)">owned by the Maryland Jaycees, Incorporated; and</section><section prefix="(2)">used as the principal office of the organization.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The governing body of Queen Anne's County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county property tax imposed on real property that is:<section prefix="(1)">owned by the Wildfowl Trust of North America, Inc.; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is used solely for:<section prefix="(i)">the maintenance of a natural area for public use;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a sanctuary for wildlife;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the environmental education of the public;</section><section prefix="(iv)">scientific research in ornithology; or</section><section prefix="(v)">the general management of wildlife.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Queen Anne's County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the  county property tax imposed on real property owned by a business that:<section prefix="(i)">makes significant real property improvements in the county, including construction, reconstruction, rehabilitation, or expansion of a nonresidential structure; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">employs at least 25 new additional full-time employees.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In each year following the year in which the nonresidential real property improvements are completed and assessed, a tax credit granted under this subsection may not exceed:<section prefix="(i)">80% of the amount of the county property tax imposed on the increased assessment in the first taxable year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">60% of the amount of the county property tax imposed on the increased assessment in the second taxable year;</section><section prefix="(iii)">40% of the amount of the county property tax imposed on the increased assessment in the third taxable year;</section><section prefix="(iv)">20% of the amount of the county property tax imposed on the increased assessment in the fourth taxable year; and</section><section prefix="(v)">0% of the amount of the county property tax imposed on the increased assessment in the fifth taxable year and all taxable years after the fifth taxable year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The governing body of Queen Anne's County may further define, fix, or limit the amount, terms, scope, and duration of any credit authorized under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Queen Anne's County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this subsection against the county property tax imposed on real property that is owned by a foster parent of a child.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body of Queen Anne's County may provide, by law, for:<section prefix="(i)">eligibility criteria for the tax credit under this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the amount and duration of the tax credit under this subsection;</section><section prefix="(iii)">regulations and procedures for the application and uniform processing of requests for the tax credit; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">any other provision necessary to carry out the credit under this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
