<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-8-211</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>211</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Agreement" means an agreement made under subsection (c) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Program" means the forest conservation and management program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department of Natural Resources shall establish the program to:<section prefix="(1)">encourage the preservation or development of land for productive woodland purposes;</section><section prefix="(2)">increase the income of persons in the State from the sale of timber;</section><section prefix="(3)">prevent flooding of land and the loss of the State's soil;</section><section prefix="(4)">provide wooded areas for the use and enjoyment of all individuals in the State; and</section><section prefix="(5)">promote the welfare and assets of the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The owner of at least 5 contiguous acres of land may make an agreement with the Department of Natural Resources to place the land in the program.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A memorandum of the agreement shall be recorded in each county where the land is located under &#xA7;&#xA7; 3-102 and 3-103 of the Real Property Article. The woodland owner shall pay for recording the memorandum.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The owner of land that is subject to an agreement shall promptly notify:<section prefix="(i)">the supervisor of the county where the land is located that the land is subject to an agreement;</section><section prefix="(ii)">before a sale or transfer, a prospective buyer or transferee that the land is subject to an agreement; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">within 30 days of a sale or transfer, the Department of Natural Resources.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The requirements applicable to an owner under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall apply to:<section prefix="(i)">a successor, heir, or assign of the owner; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">as applicable, the personal representative of the owner's estate.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for an agreement made on or before July 1, 1984, an agreement shall be for at least 15 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Consecutive agreements shall be deemed a single agreement from the date of the original agreement.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">An agreement may be assigned and transferred to a buyer of all or part of the land that is subject to the agreement, if:<section prefix="(1)">the buyer assumes the obligation of the agreement;</section><section prefix="(2)">the agreement is transferred to the buyer by the landowner or the landowner's successors, heirs, or assigns; and</section><section prefix="(3)">property tax on an assessment under subsection (i) of this section is not due.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Except as provided in subsection (i) of this section, the value of woodland for assessment purposes in effect at the beginning of an agreement may not be increased for the period covered by the agreement.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Woodland shall be reassessed when:<section prefix="(i)">an agreement ends and is not renewed as provided in subsection (f)(2) of this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">timber is harvested, unless harvested according to the plan approved by the Department of Natural Resources;</section><section prefix="(iii)">land subject to an agreement is conveyed to a new owner except as provided in subsection (g) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">an agreement is ended by the Department of Natural Resources at the request of the owner or because the owner has not complied with the agreement.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If only part of the land subject to an agreement is conveyed or only part of the timber is harvested, the reassessment shall be only for the part of land conveyed or the part of land on which the timber is harvested.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">If the assessment under subsection (i)(1)(ii) through (iv) of this section is greater than the value used to determine the assessment under subsection (h) of this section, the difference between the 2 valuations is computed in approximately equal annual steps that cover the number of taxable years between the 2 valuations, and the agreement holder owes property tax for each taxable year payable at the property tax rates applicable for each taxable year.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of this subsection and any pertinent local laws, a woodland owner who has 50 or more contiguous acres subject to an agreement may subdivide the property and transfer to a child of the owner a building lot for the purposes of constructing a dwelling unit on the lot without liability for prior taxable years under subsection (j) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A building lot transferred under this subsection may not exceed:<section prefix="(i)">1 acre; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if local law or regulations adopted by the Department of the Environment require that the minimum size of a building lot exceed 1 acre, the minimum size required under local law or regulations adopted by the Department of the Environment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A woodland owner may not transfer under this subsection more than one building lot for every 10 acres subject to the agreement or more than one building lot to each child of the owner.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A woodland owner shall apply to the Department of Natural Resources for a modification of an agreement under this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">On approval by the Department of Natural Resources, the woodland owner shall notify the supervisor of the county where the land is located.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The supervisor shall reassess that portion of the property removed from the program and establish the property as a separate account in the assessment records of the county.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A modification of an agreement under this subsection shall be recorded in each county where the building lot is located under &#xA7;&#xA7; 3-102 and 3-103 of the Real Property Article. The woodland owner shall pay for recording the modification.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A modification of an agreement under this subsection is not subject to a penalty under subsection (l) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">An agreement holder shall pay the Department of Natural Resources a penalty of $100 if an agreement is terminated as a result of noncompliance or at the request of the owner.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Land that is removed from an agreement by eminent domain or other involuntary proceeding is not subject to:<section prefix="(i)">reassessment under subsection (i) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">penalty under subsection (l) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If only part of the land subject to an agreement is removed by eminent domain or other involuntary procedure the supervisor shall:<section prefix="(i)">apportion the assessment and enter the removed part as a separate assessment on the tax roll; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">adjust the assessment of the land that remains under the agreement to reflect the change.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">This section does not affect any benefit charge or other special charge that applies to woodland.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">This section does not apply to the valuation or assessment of improvements or agricultural, mineral, or other nonforest values on land that is subject to an agreement.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">The Department of Natural Resources may set reasonable fees for the development of management plans, original agreements, and conducting inspections. The fees shall be designed to cover the administrative costs of conducting the program.</section>
  </text>
</law>
