<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="gtp" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-7-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section:<section prefix="(1)">"fraternal organization" means any organization that:<section prefix="(i)">is conducted solely for the benefit of its members and its beneficiaries;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is operated on a lodge system with a ritualistic activity; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">has a representative form of government;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">"fraternal organization" includes a sororal organization; and</section><section prefix="(3)">"fraternal organization" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">any college or high school fraternity or sorority; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">any other fraternal or sororal organization the membership of which is restricted wholly or largely to students or graduates of an educational institution or a professional school.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, property is not subject to property tax if the property:<section prefix="(i)">is necessary for and actually used exclusively for a charitable or educational purpose to promote the general welfare of the people of the State, including an activity or an athletic program of an educational institution; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is owned by:<section prefix="1.">a nonprofit hospital;</section><section prefix="2.">a nonprofit charitable, fraternal, educational, or literary organization including:</section><section prefix="3.">a corporation, limited liability company, or trustee that holds the property for the sole benefit of an organization that qualifies for an exemption under this section; or</section><section prefix="4.">a nonprofit housing corporation.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The exemption under paragraph (1)(ii)1 of this subsection includes any personal property initially leased by a nonprofit hospital for more than 1 year under a lease that is noncancellable except for cause.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for a nonprofit hospital, not more than 100 acres of real property owned by an exempt organization and appurtenant to the premises of the exempt organization is exempt from property tax, if the property is located outside of a municipal corporation or Baltimore City.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Not more than 100 acres of real property of a nonprofit hospital that is appurtenant to the hospital is exempt from property tax.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding &#xA7; 7-104 of this title and after filing the application provided by &#xA7; 7-103 of this title, property tax on any property that is transferred to a nonprofit charitable organization is abated from the date during the taxable year when the instrument transferring title to the organization is recorded if:<section prefix="(i)">the property is transferred to a nonprofit charitable organization qualified under &#xA7; 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the property becomes exempt under this section;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the property has a value less than $300,000 as listed in the records of the Department on the date when the instrument transferring title to the organization is recorded; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the nonprofit charitable organization provides the Department evidence of the property tax it actually paid or reimbursed at the property settlement.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The amount of property tax abated under this subsection may not exceed the amount of property tax actually paid or reimbursed by an eligible organization at the property settlement.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
