<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="gtp" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-243</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to subsection (b) of this section, the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the gover...</catch_line>
  <order_by>243</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to subsection (b) of this section, the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the governing body of a county or of a municipal corporation may grant a tax credit under this section against the county or municipal corporation property tax imposed on real property if:<section prefix="(1)">the homeowner is otherwise eligible for the credit allowed under &#xA7; 9-105 of this title;</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">the dwelling is:<section prefix="1.">damaged or destroyed due to a natural disaster; and</section><section prefix="2.">subsequently repaired or reconstructed;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">the dwelling is revalued after the dwelling is repaired or reconstructed; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">as a result of the revaluation, the assessment of the dwelling exceeds the last assessment of the dwelling; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">the homeowner claiming the credit had a legal interest in the dwelling at the time the dwelling was damaged or destroyed as described under item (2) of this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A homeowner may receive a tax credit under this section only if the homeowner qualified and received a tax credit under &#xA7; 9-109 of this title and is no longer receiving a tax credit under &#xA7; 9-109 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The amount of the property tax credit allowed under this section shall equal 50% of the property tax attributable to an increase in the assessment of the dwelling on revaluation under &#xA7; 8-104(c)(1)(iii) of this article, including improvements, over the last assessment of the dwelling before the natural disaster, less the amount of any assessment on which a property tax credit under &#xA7; 9-105 of this title has been authorized.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A credit under this section may not be granted for more than 3 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the governing body of a county or municipal corporation may:<section prefix="(1)">establish procedures or requirements for the application, review, and approval of tax credits under this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">establish additional eligibility criteria such as age, income level, or assessment value; and</section><section prefix="(3)">notify the Department of any credits that have been granted under this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The credit under this section may not be claimed for a dwelling for which repair or reconstruction is completed before September 18, 2003.</section>
  </text>
</law>
