<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="gtp" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-12-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this title the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Articles of consolidation" means a document filed with the Department under &#xA7; 3-107 of the Corporations and Associations Article which evidences a consolidation of at least one Maryland corporation with another corporation to form a new Maryland corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Articles of merger" means a document filed with the Department under &#xA7; 3-107, &#xA7; 4A-703, &#xA7; 9A-903, or &#xA7; 10-208 of the Corporations and Associations Article which evidences a merger involving at least one Maryland corporation, Maryland limited liability company, Maryland partnership, or Maryland limited partnership.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Articles of transfer" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 1-101(c) of the Corporations and Associations Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Documents which evidence the merger or consolidation of foreign corporations, foreign partnerships, foreign limited liability companies, or foreign limited partnerships" means those documents that are filed or recorded with:<section prefix="(1)">the Department under &#xA7; 3-117, &#xA7; 4A-1012, &#xA7; 9A-910, or &#xA7; 10-912 of the Corporations and Associations Article; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the clerk of the circuit court of a county evidencing that title to real property has been conveyed through a merger or consolidation of 2 or more foreign corporations, foreign limited liability companies, foreign partnerships, or foreign limited partnerships.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e-1)">"Domestic partner" means an individual with whom another individual has established a domestic partnership.</section>
    <section prefix="(e-2)">"Domestic partnership" means a relationship between two individuals who:<section prefix="(1)">are at least 18 years old;</section><section prefix="(2)">are not related to the other by blood or marriage within four degrees of consanguinity under the civil law rule;</section><section prefix="(3)">are not married or a member of a civil union or domestic partnership with another individual;</section><section prefix="(4)">agree to be in a relationship of mutual interdependence in which each domestic partner contributes to the maintenance and support of the other domestic partner and the relationship, even if both domestic partners are not required to contribute equally to the relationship; and</section><section prefix="(5)">share a common residence where both domestic partners live, even if:<section prefix="(i)">only one of the domestic partners has the right to legal possession of the common residence; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">one of the domestic partners has an additional residence.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e-3)">"Evidence of a domestic partnership" means:<section prefix="(1)">an affidavit signed under penalty of perjury by two individuals stating that they have established a domestic partnership; and</section><section prefix="(2)">evidence of any two of the following:<section prefix="(i)">joint liability of the individuals for a mortgage or other loan or for a lease;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the designation of one of the individuals as the primary beneficiary under a life insurance policy on the life of the other individual or under a retirement plan of the other individual;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the designation of one of the individuals as the primary beneficiary of the will of the other individual;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a durable power of attorney for health care or financial management granted by one of the individuals to the other individual;</section><section prefix="(v)">joint ownership or lease by the individuals of a motor vehicle;</section><section prefix="(vi)">a joint checking account, joint investments, or a joint credit account;</section><section prefix="(vii)">a joint renter's or homeowner's insurance policy;</section><section prefix="(viii)">coverage of one of the individuals under a health insurance policy of the other individual;</section><section prefix="(ix)">joint responsibility for childcare, such as school documents or guardianship documents; or</section><section prefix="(x)">a relationship or cohabitation contract.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e-4)">"Evidence of dissolution of a domestic partnership" means:<section prefix="(1)">a death certificate; or</section><section prefix="(2)">an affidavit signed under penalty of perjury by two individuals who formerly established a domestic partnership stating that the domestic partnership has been dissolved.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e-5)">"Former domestic partner" means an individual with whom another individual had established a domestic partnership that has subsequently been dissolved.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Instrument of writing" means a written instrument that:<section prefix="(i)">conveys title to or creates or gives notice of a security interest in real property; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">creates or gives notice of a security interest in personal property.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Instrument of writing" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a deed or contract;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a mortgage, deed of trust, or other contract that creates an encumbrance on real property;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a lease of real property;</section><section prefix="(iv)">an assignment of a lessee's interest in real property;</section><section prefix="(v)">articles of transfer;</section><section prefix="(vi)">a security agreement;</section><section prefix="(vii)">articles of merger or other document which evidences a merger of foreign corporations, foreign partnerships, foreign limited liability companies, or foreign limited partnerships; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">articles of consolidation or other document which evidences a consolidation of foreign corporations.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Recordation tax" means the tax imposed under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Security agreement" means an agreement that creates or provides for a security interest.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Security agreement" includes a financing statement filed under the Maryland Uniform Commercial Code to perfect a security interest.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Security interest" means an interest in real property or personal property that secures payment or performance of an obligation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Security interest" includes a lien or encumbrance on real property or personal property.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Subsidiary corporation" includes any corporation that is a subsidiary of either a parent corporation or any other subsidiary corporation of the parent corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Successor" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 1-101(y) of the Corporations and Associations Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Supplemental instrument of writing" means an instrument of writing that confirms, corrects, modifies, or supplements a previously recorded instrument of writing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Supplemental instrument of writing" includes an instrument of writing that secures a debt and grants a security interest in property in addition to or in substitution for property described in the previously recorded instrument of writing.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
