<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="gtp" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-8-419</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subsection, "appropriate official" means:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>419</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "appropriate official" means:<section prefix="(i)">except as otherwise provided in this paragraph, the Department or supervisor and the county or municipal corporation treasurer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">in Baltimore City, the Department or supervisor and the city solicitor;</section><section prefix="(iii)">in Montgomery County, the Department or supervisor and the director of finance; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">for municipal corporations in Caroline County, the Department or supervisor and the appropriate town board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding failure to file a protest of an assessment and after the date of finality for an assessment, the appropriate official may issue an order decreasing or abating an assessment:<section prefix="(i)">to correct an erroneous assessment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">to correct an improper assessment; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">to prevent injustice.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The order shall state clearly the reasons for decreasing or abating the assessment.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department may audit any personal property assessment after the assessment is made.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If, as a result of the audit, the Department determines that the assessment is:<section prefix="(i)">greater than the assessment previously made, the Department shall make an assessment of the difference; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">less than the assessment previously made, the Department shall abate the difference.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If action is taken under paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Department shall mail a notice of assessment to the owner. The notice may be appealed as provided by Title 14, Subtitle 5 of this article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
