<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="gtp" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-325</section_number>
  <catch_line>The governing body of Worcester County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section a...</catch_line>
  <order_by>325</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Worcester County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county property tax imposed on:<section prefix="(i)">property that is:<section prefix="1.">owned by the Berlin Community Improvement Association, Incorporated, of Worcester County; and</section><section prefix="2.">used only for the nonprofit activities of the organization;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">property that is:<section prefix="1.">owned by the Marlin Park Association, Incorporated; and</section><section prefix="2.">used for nonprofit purposes;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">property that is owned or leased by the Greater Ocean City Health Service Corporation; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">property that is owned by the Ocean City, Maryland Chamber of Commerce.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body of Worcester County may provide, by law, for:<section prefix="(i)">the amount and duration of a property tax credit under this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any other provision necessary to carry out this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Worcester County or the governing body of a municipal corporation in Worcester County may grant, by law, a property tax credit against the county or municipal corporation property tax imposed on:<section prefix="(i)">property that is owned by the Pocomoke City Chamber of Commerce;</section><section prefix="(ii)">real property that is:<section prefix="1.">owned by the Mayor and City Council of Ocean City;</section><section prefix="2.">leased to the Sinepuxent Pier and Improvement Company, Incorporated; and</section><section prefix="3.">known as the Ocean City Amusement and Fishing Pier; and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">real property that:<section prefix="1.">is located in Ocean City on or west of Route 528;</section><section prefix="2.">consists of at least 30 acres; and</section><section prefix="3.">is actually used exclusively for the operation of an amusement park.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body of Worcester County or of a municipal corporation in Worcester County may provide, by law, for:<section prefix="(i)">the amount and duration of a property tax credit under this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">additional eligibility criteria for a property tax credit under this subsection;</section><section prefix="(iii)">regulations and procedures for the application and uniform processing of requests for the tax credit; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">any other provision necessary to carry out this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "historically operated amusement park" means real property that is used for mechanical amusement rides, games, and concessions that:<section prefix="(i)">have been continuously owned by members of the same family or by entities of which members of the same family own a controlling interest;</section><section prefix="(ii)">have been operated at the same general location for a period of more than 100 years and continue to be operated at the same general location; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">have created a tourist destination at a boardwalk.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body of Worcester County or of a municipal corporation in Worcester County may grant, by law, a property tax credit against the county or municipal corporation property tax imposed on real property that is actually used as a historically operated amusement park.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The governing body of Worcester County or of a municipal corporation in Worcester County may provide, by law, for:<section prefix="(i)">the amount and duration of the property tax credit under this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">additional eligibility criteria for the tax credit under this subsection;</section><section prefix="(iii)">regulations and procedures for the application and uniform processing of requests for the tax credit; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">any other provision necessary to carry out the credit under this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
