<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="gtp" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-102</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>102</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Assets" include:<section prefix="1.">real property;</section><section prefix="2.">cash;</section><section prefix="3.">savings accounts;</section><section prefix="4.">stocks;</section><section prefix="5.">bonds; and</section><section prefix="6.">any other investment.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Assets" do not include:<section prefix="1.">the cash value of the life insurance policies on the life of the renter; or</section><section prefix="2.">tangible personal property.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Assumed real property tax" means:<section prefix="(i)">15% of the occupancy rent paid by a renter during the calendar year; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">15% of the occupancy rent paid by a renter during the calendar year plus any tax paid under Article 24, &#xA7; 9-401 of the Code.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Combined income" means the combined gross income of all individuals who actually reside in a dwelling except an individual who:<section prefix="(i)">is a dependent of the renter under &#xA7; 152 of the Internal Revenue Code; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">pays a reasonable amount for rent or room and board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Dwelling" means a rental unit that is the principal residence of a renter.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Dwelling" includes a mobile home pad on which the principal residence of the renter rests.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Gross income" means the total income from all sources for the calendar year that immediately precedes the taxable year, whether or not the income is included in the definition of gross income for federal or State tax purposes.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Gross income" includes:<section prefix="1.">any benefit under the Social Security Act or the Railroad Retirement Act;</section><section prefix="2.">the aggregate of gifts over $300;</section><section prefix="3.">alimony;</section><section prefix="4.">support money;</section><section prefix="5.">any nontaxable strike benefit;</section><section prefix="6.">public assistance received in a cash grant;</section><section prefix="7.">a pension;</section><section prefix="8.">an annuity;</section><section prefix="9.">any unemployment insurance benefit;</section><section prefix="10.">any workers' compensation benefit; and</section><section prefix="11.">the net income received from a business, rental, or other endeavor.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Gross income" does not include:<section prefix="1.">any income tax refund received from the State or federal government, including any refundable portion of the federal earned income tax credit; or</section><section prefix="2.">any loss from business, rental, or other endeavor.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Net worth" means the sum of the current market value of all assets, less any outstanding liability.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Occupancy rent" means the rent paid for the right to occupy a dwelling less the reasonable value of the utilities or furnishings or both if the utilities or the use of the furnishings or both are included in the rent.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">"Renter" means an individual, who during the calendar year for which the property tax relief under this section is sought, actually occupies a dwelling in which the individual has a leasehold interest and who:<section prefix="(i)">is at least 60 years old;</section><section prefix="(ii)">has been found permanently and totally disabled and has qualified for benefits under:<section prefix="1.">the Social Security Act;</section><section prefix="2.">the Railroad Retirement Act;</section><section prefix="3.">any federal act for members of the United States armed forces; or</section><section prefix="4.">any federal retirement system;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">has been found permanently and totally disabled by a county health officer or the Baltimore City Commissioner of Health; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">is under the age of 60 years and:<section prefix="1.">has gross income below the poverty threshold that is established by the U.S. Department of Commerce, Bureau of the Census in August of the previous calendar year;</section><section prefix="2.">has 1 or more dependent children under 18 years old living with the renter; and</section><section prefix="3.">does not receive federal or State housing subsidies or reside in public housing.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a property tax relief program for any renter.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department shall adopt regulations necessary to carry out this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall give to each renter notice of possible property tax relief under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Comptroller shall provide in each package of income tax forms and instructions notice of the availability of a property tax credit under this section. Such notice shall be similar in every way to that provided homeowners in &#xA7; 9-104(f) of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a dwelling is not actually occupied or expected to be occupied by the renter for 6 months or more of the calendar year, the dwelling is not a principal residence.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before September 1 of the year following the calendar year for which property tax relief under this section is sought, a renter may apply to the Department for the property tax relief. The application shall be made on the form that the Department provides.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For good cause, the Department may accept an application from a renter after September 1 but on or before October 31 of the year following the calendar year for which property tax relief under this section is sought.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The renter shall state under oath that the statements in the application are true.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">To substantiate the application, the applicant may be required to provide a copy of an income tax return, or other evidence detailing gross income or net worth.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Notwithstanding &#xA7; 13-202 of the Tax - General Article, to verify the income stated in an application, the Comptroller shall give the Department the information required.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The property tax relief that a renter may receive under this section is the assumed property tax on real property less a percentage of the combined income of the renter.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The percentage is:<section prefix="(i)">0% of the 1st $4,000 of combined income;</section><section prefix="(ii)">2.5% of the 2nd $4,000 of combined income;</section><section prefix="(iii)">5.5% of the 3rd $4,000 of combined income;</section><section prefix="(iv)">7.5% of the 4th $4,000 of combined income; and</section><section prefix="(v)">9% of the combined income over $16,000.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The property tax relief under this section may not be:<section prefix="(1)">more than $750;</section><section prefix="(2)">granted to any renter whose combined net worth exceeds $200,000 as of December 31 of the calendar year for which the property tax relief is sought;</section><section prefix="(3)">granted to any renter whose dwelling is exempt from property tax; and</section><section prefix="(4)">granted if the credit under this section is less than $1 in any year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(i)">process applications upon receipt;</section><section prefix="(ii)">certify to the Comptroller the property tax relief under this section due each renter; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">make the certifications required under item (ii) of this paragraph no less frequently than each month.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Comptroller shall pay the amount to the renter upon receipt of the certification from the Department.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
