<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-310</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>310</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The governing body of Charles County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county tax imposed on:<section prefix="(1)">real property that is:<section prefix="(i)">owned by a nonprofit community or civic improvement association or corporation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">used only for a community, civic, educational, recreational, or library purpose, if:<section prefix="1.">unless the compensation is used only to improve or maintain the property, the use is not contingent on the payment of compensation for admission; and</section><section prefix="2.">unless the compensation is used only to improve or maintain the property, failure to pay compensation is not a reason to deny admission to or use of the property;</section></section></section><section prefix="(2)">real property that is owned by the Greater Waldorf Jaycees, Incorporated;</section><section prefix="(3)">real property that is owned by the Southern Maryland Youth Organization, Incorporated;</section><section prefix="(4)">agricultural land, including any farm improvement, that is located in an agricultural preservation district;</section><section prefix="(5)">a building other than a tobacco barn that is:<section prefix="(i)">located on land that qualifies for an agricultural use assessment; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">used in connection with an activity that is recognized by the Department as an approved agricultural activity;</section></section><section prefix="(6)">real property that is owned by Habitat for Humanity or any charitable organization holding that property with the intention of relinquishing ownership in the immediate future for charitable purposes;</section><section prefix="(7)">subject to subsection (b) of this section, real property:<section prefix="(i)">that is located in a rural legacy area as defined in &#xA7; 5-9A-02 of the Natural Resources Article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">for which the property owner has sold the development rights under the Rural Legacy Program established under Title 5, Subtitle 9A of the Natural Resources Article; and</section></section><section prefix="(8)">subject to subsection (c) of this section, residential real property that is located in a designated targeted area and has been converted from a rental dwelling to an owner-occupied dwelling.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The governing body of Charles County may provide for the conditions of eligibility and method of application for and the amount of the property tax credit authorized under subsection (a)(7) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Charles County may, by law after a public hearing, designate as eligible for the tax credit under subsection (a)(8) of this section and the recordation tax exemption authorized under &#xA7; 12-114 of this article geographically defined targeted areas of the county that the governing body determines are in transition from predominantly owner-occupied homes to predominantly rental dwellings.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body of Charles County may provide by law for:<section prefix="(i)">any criteria for eligibility, conditions, or restrictions for a credit authorized under subsection (a)(8) of this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">provisions to define, fix, or limit the amount, terms, scope, and duration of a credit authorized under subsection (a)(8) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">any other provision appropriate to implement the credit authorized under subsection (a)(8) of this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The governing body of Charles County may grant to new businesses locating in the county a county property tax credit for machinery and equipment used in manufacturing, assembling, processing, or refining products for sale or for new facilities in the generation of electricity and may define, fix, or limit the amount, terms, scope, and duration of any credit provided for or affirmed under this subsection.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To encourage the location and development of business operations and expansion of the employment base in Charles County, the governing body of Charles County and of a municipal corporation in Charles County may grant, by law, a property tax credit against the county and municipal corporation property tax imposed on any property owned by a new or expanding business that creates 10 or more full-time jobs in an industry targeted for expansion by the Charles County Economic Development Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A tax credit granted under this subsection may not be granted for more than 10 years.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Charles County may grant a property tax credit against the county property tax imposed on real property that was formerly used solely as a tobacco barn if the real property:<section prefix="(i)">is located on land that is subject to a tobacco buyout agreement; or</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">is located on land that qualifies for an agricultural use assessment; and</section><section prefix="2.">is used in connection with an activity that is recognized by the Department as an approved agricultural activity.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In authorizing a credit under this subsection, the governing body of the county may provide, by law, for:<section prefix="(i)">the amount of the credit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the duration of the credit; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">any other provision necessary to administer the credit.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Charles County may grant a property tax credit against the county property tax imposed on renovated or rehabilitated business real property located in a priority funding area as designated in Title 5, Subtitle 7B of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the governing body of the county may provide, by law, for:<section prefix="(i)">the amount of the credit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the duration of the credit; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">any other provision necessary to administer the credit.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A tax credit under this subsection shall not exceed the amount of additional property tax assessed as a result of the renovation or rehabilitation.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A tax credit under this subsection is available to a qualified property for no more than 5 years.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Charles County may grant, by law, a property tax credit against the county property tax imposed on real property that:<section prefix="(i)">is owner-occupied;</section><section prefix="(ii)">was formerly owned by Habitat for Humanity of Charles County with the intention of relinquishing ownership;</section><section prefix="(iii)">was used by Habitat for Humanity of Charles County exclusively for the purpose of rehabilitation and transfer to a private owner; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">was transferred to a private owner who meets the criteria established by Habitat for Humanity of Charles County.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The property tax credit shall equal:<section prefix="(i)">100% of the county property tax for the first taxable year after the transfer of ownership;</section><section prefix="(ii)">75% of the county property tax for the second taxable year after the transfer of ownership;</section><section prefix="(iii)">50% of the county property tax for the third taxable year after the transfer of ownership;</section><section prefix="(iv)">25% of the county property tax for the fourth taxable year after the transfer of ownership; and</section><section prefix="(v)">0% of the county property tax for the fifth taxable year after the transfer of ownership and each taxable year thereafter.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The governing body of Charles County may provide, by law, for any other provision necessary to carry out the property tax credit under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Charles County may grant, by law, a property tax credit against the county property tax imposed on real property that is subject to a perpetual conservation easement donated to the Conservancy for Charles County, Inc., or another qualified entity approved by the governing body.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The property tax credit granted under this section shall:<section prefix="(i)">benefit the original grantor of the perpetual conservation easement;</section><section prefix="(ii)">be granted for the duration that the original grantor of the perpetual conservation easement continues to reside on the property subject to the easement;</section><section prefix="(iii)">terminate on transfer of the property subject to the conservation easement by the grantor; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">be applicable to preexisting conservation easements.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The governing body of Charles County may provide, by law, for:<section prefix="(i)">the amount and duration of the property tax credit under this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any other provision necessary to carry out the property tax credit under this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
