<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Base year" means the taxable year immediately before the taxable year in which a property tax credit under this section is to be granted.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Base year value" means the value of the property used to determine the assessment on which the property tax on real property was imposed for the base year.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Base year value" does not include any new real property that was first assessed in the base year.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Business entity" means a person who operates or conducts a trade or business.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Business entity" includes a person who owns, operates, develops, constructs, or rehabilitates real property, if the real property:<section prefix="1.">is intended for use primarily as single or multifamily residential property located in the enterprise zone; and</section><section prefix="2.">is partially devoted to a nonresidential use.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Eligible assessment" means the difference between the base year value and the actual value as determined by the Department for the applicable taxable year in which the tax credit under this section is to be granted.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For a business entity that is located on land or within improvements owned by the federal, State, county, or municipal government, "eligible assessment" means the difference between the base year value and the actual value reduced by the value of any property entitled to an exemption under Title 7 of this article as determined by the Department for the applicable taxable year in which the tax credit under this section is to be granted.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Qualified property" means real property that is:<section prefix="1.">not used for residential purposes;</section><section prefix="2.">used in a trade or business by a business entity that meets the requirements of &#xA7; 5-707 of the Economic Development Article; and</section><section prefix="3.">located in an enterprise zone that is designated under Title 5, Subtitle 7 of the Economic Development Article.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Qualified property" includes personal property on real property that is located in a focus area as defined in &#xA7; 5-701 of the Economic Development Article.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of a county or of a municipal corporation shall grant a tax credit under this section against the property tax imposed on the eligible assessment of qualified property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Montgomery County the lessor of real property eligible for a credit under this section shall reduce the amount of taxes for which a tenant is contractually liable under the lease agreement by the amount of any credit allowed under this section that is attributable to improvements made by the tenant.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Unless the county in which a municipal corporation is located agrees to the designation of an enterprise zone in the municipal corporation, qualified property in the municipal corporation may not receive a tax credit against county property tax.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The appropriate governing body shall calculate the amount of the tax credit under this section equal to a percentage of the amount of property tax imposed on the eligible assessment of the qualified property, as follows:<section prefix="(i)">80% in each of the 1st 5 taxable years following the calendar year in which the property initially becomes a qualified property;</section><section prefix="(ii)">70% in the 6th taxable year;</section><section prefix="(iii)">60% in the 7th taxable year;</section><section prefix="(iv)">50% in the 8th taxable year;</section><section prefix="(v)">40% in the 9th taxable year; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">30% in the 10th taxable year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall allocate the eligible assessment to the nonresidential part of the qualified property at the same percentage as the square footage of the nonresidential part is to the total square footage of the building.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For purposes of calculating the amount of the credit allowed under this section, the amount of property tax imposed on the eligible assessment shall be calculated without reduction for any credits allowed under this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">For qualified property located in a focus area, the appropriate governing body shall calculate the amount of the tax credit under this section equal to 80% of the amount of property tax imposed on the eligible assessment of the qualified property for each of the 10 taxable years following the calendar year in which the property initially becomes a qualified property.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A tax credit under this section is available to a qualified property for no more than 10 consecutive years beginning with the taxable year following the calendar year in which the real property initially becomes a qualified property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Even if the designation of an enterprise zone expires, the tax credit under this section continues to be available to a qualified property.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding &#xA7; 5-707(d) of the Economic Development Article but subject to &#xA7; 5-707(b) and (c) of the Economic Development Article, a business entity operating in an enterprise zone when the designation of the enterprise zone expires may claim the credits allowed under this section for real property that:<section prefix="(i)">the business owns, operates, develops, constructs, or rehabilitates within 5 years after the date the designation of the enterprise zone expired; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">otherwise qualifies for the credits allowed under this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">State property tax imposed on real property is not affected by this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">When an enterprise zone is designated by the Secretary of the Department of Business and Economic Development, the appropriate governing body shall certify to the Department of Assessments and Taxation:<section prefix="(1)">the real properties in the enterprise zone that are qualified properties for each taxable year for which the property tax credit under this section is to be granted; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the date that the real properties became qualified properties.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Before property tax bills are sent, the Department of Assessments and Taxation shall submit to the appropriate governing body a list of:<section prefix="(1)">each qualified property;</section><section prefix="(2)">the amount of the base year value for each qualified property; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the amount of the eligible assessment for each qualified property.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">As provided in the State budget, the State shall remit to each county or municipal corporation an amount equal to one-half of the funds that would have been collected if the property tax credit under this section had not been granted.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Quarterly or more frequently, the county or municipal corporation shall submit a request to the Department of Assessments and Taxation for the amount required by subsection (h) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 5 working days after the Department of Assessments and Taxation receives the request from the county or municipal corporation, the Department shall certify to the Comptroller the reimbursement due to each county or municipal corporation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Within 5 working days after the Comptroller receives the certification from the Department, the Comptroller shall reimburse each county or municipal corporation.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
