<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-215.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-215.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The governing body of a municipal corporation may grant, by law, a local supplement to the Homeowners Property Tax Credit Program provided under &#xA7; 9-104 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The municipal corporation may not obtain reimbursement under &#xA7; 9-104(t) of this title for the amount of the local supplement authorized under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The municipal corporation shall notify the Department of the enactment of the local supplement and any change in the local supplement in accordance with any guidelines specified by the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The municipal corporation is responsible for the administrative duties that relate to the application, determination of eligibility, and payment of a property tax credit under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The amount of the local supplement authorized in accordance with subsection (a) of this section shall not exceed the net property tax liability due after providing for any State property tax credit authorized under &#xA7; 9-104 of this title and any local supplement to the homeowners property tax credit authorized under &#xA7; 9-215 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the local supplement authorized in accordance with subsection (a) of this section shall be subject to the provisions of the State Homeowners Property Tax Credit Program provided under &#xA7; 9-104 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body of a municipal corporation:<section prefix="(i)">may alter, by law, the following provisions for purposes of a local supplement granted under this section:</section><section prefix="(ii)">may provide, by law, for limitations on eligibility for a local supplement granted under this section in addition to the requirements for eligibility under &#xA7; 9-104 of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The additional eligibility criteria provided under paragraph (2)(ii) of this subsection may include:<section prefix="(i)">criteria limiting eligibility for a local supplement granted under this section to homeowners:</section><section prefix="(ii)">any combination of the criteria specified in item (i) of this paragraph; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">any additional criteria for eligibility that the governing body of a municipal corporation determines to be necessary or appropriate.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
