<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-14-603</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>603</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section and for estimated personal property tax in &#xA7; 14-604 of this subtitle, the rate of interest for full year county or municipal corporation property tax or taxing district property tax is two-thirds of 1% for each month or fraction of a month that the county or municipal corporation property tax or taxing district property tax is overdue.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For the following counties and municipal corporations the rate of interest for each month or fraction of a month that county or municipal corporation property tax or taxing district property tax is overdue is:<section prefix="(1)">1% for Garrett County;</section><section prefix="(2)">1% for the City of Salisbury;</section><section prefix="(3)">1% for Washington County;</section><section prefix="(4)">1% for Somerset County; and</section><section prefix="(5)">the rate set by law by:<section prefix="(i)">the governing body of a county that has adopted a charter form of government under Article XI-A of the Maryland Constitution;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the governing body of:<section prefix="1.">Allegany County;</section><section prefix="2.">the City of Annapolis;</section><section prefix="3.">Berlin, not exceeding 1.5%;</section><section prefix="4.">Caroline County, not exceeding 1%;</section><section prefix="5.">Cecil County, or any municipal corporation in Cecil County, not exceeding 1%;</section><section prefix="6.">Dorchester County;</section><section prefix="7.">the City of Frederick, not exceeding 1%, that is set on or before the date of finality;</section><section prefix="8.">Frederick County, not exceeding 1%, that is set on or before the date of finality;</section><section prefix="9.">Ocean City, not exceeding 1.5%;</section><section prefix="10.">Pocomoke City, not exceeding 1.5%;</section><section prefix="11.">the Town of Princess Anne, not exceeding 1.5%;</section><section prefix="12.">Kent County or any municipal corporation in Kent County;</section><section prefix="13.">Queen Anne's County or any municipal corporation in Queen Anne's County;</section><section prefix="14.">Snow Hill, not exceeding 1.5%;</section><section prefix="15.">Worcester County, not exceeding 1.5%;</section><section prefix="16.">Calvert County;</section><section prefix="17.">St. Mary's County;</section><section prefix="18.">the City of Taneytown;</section><section prefix="19.">the City of Cambridge; or</section><section prefix="20.">Mardela Springs, not exceeding 1%; or</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City for Baltimore City, if the rate is set on or before June 30 for the following taxable year.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The governing body of Calvert County or of St. Mary's County may set, by law:<section prefix="(1)">an interest rate for overdue tax on commercial property; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a separate interest rate for overdue tax on noncommercial property.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
