<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-14-830</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>830</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The owner of any property sold under the provisions of this subtitle shall have the right, during the period of redemption, to continue in possession of, and to exercise all rights of ownership over the property until the right of redemption has been finally foreclosed under the provisions of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The holder of any certificate of sale may apply to the circuit court for the county in which the property is located for the appointment of a receiver of the property covered by the certificate, in accordance with the usual provisions of the laws and of rules and practice of the circuit courts that relate to receivers.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If any certificate of sale is held by the governing body of the county or any other taxing agency, the governing body or taxing agency may make application by complaint, to the circuit court for the county for the appointment of a receiver of the property covered by the certificate of sale.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The defendant, in the action brought by the governing body of the county or any other taxing agency under subsection (c) of this section for the appointment of a receiver shall be the owner of the property whose name last appears as the owner on the collector's tax roll.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">However, except as to property actually occupied by the owner if a certificate of sale is held by the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the governing body of a county, then the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the governing body of the county has the right of immediate possession of the property represented by the certificate of sale and to the rents accruing from the property from the date of sale, without the necessity of receivership proceedings.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the governing body of the county shall make a strict accounting of any and all rents collected to the owner on redemption of the property, and on the redemption, shall remit the rents, less all expenses required for the property maintenance and upkeep of the property.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Any reasonable sums caused to be expended to conserve or stabilize the property shall become part of the redemption amount, provided the sums expended and the necessity for making the repairs are approved by the court.</section>
  </text>
</law>
