<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-12-108</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>108</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, an instrument of writing is not subject to recordation tax, if the instrument of writing transfers property to or grants a security interest to:<section prefix="(i)">the United States;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an agency of the State; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">a political subdivision in the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the governing body of a county may impose, by law, the recordation tax uniformly on all instruments of writing that secure repayment of debt created by the sale of bonds authorized under Title 12, Subtitle 1 of the Economic Development Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A security agreement is not subject to recordation tax, if the security agreement is:<section prefix="(1)">on a vehicle and is perfected by filing with the Motor Vehicle Administration; or</section><section prefix="(2)">on a vessel and is perfected by filing with the Department of Natural Resources.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When property is transferred subject to a mortgage or deed of trust, the recordation tax does not apply to the principal amount of debt assumed by the transferee, if the instrument of writing transfers the property from the transferor to a:<section prefix="(i)">spouse or former spouse;</section><section prefix="(ii)">son, daughter, stepson, or stepdaughter;</section><section prefix="(iii)">parent or stepparent;</section><section prefix="(iv)">son-in-law, daughter-in-law, stepson-in-law, or stepdaughter-in-law;</section><section prefix="(v)">parent-in-law or stepparent-in-law;</section><section prefix="(vi)">brother, sister, stepbrother, or stepsister;</section><section prefix="(vii)">grandchild or stepgrandchild;</section><section prefix="(viii)">grandparent or stepgrandparent; or</section><section prefix="(ix)">domestic partner or former domestic partner.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">To qualify as a domestic partner under this subsection, an individual shall submit evidence of a domestic partnership.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">To qualify as a former domestic partner under this subsection, an individual shall submit evidence of dissolution of a domestic partnership.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The exemption under paragraph (1) of this subsection for transfers to a domestic partner or former domestic partner of the transferor applies only to an instrument of writing for residential property.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An instrument of writing that transfers property between the following individuals is not subject to recordation tax:<section prefix="(i)">spouses or former spouses; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">domestic partners or former domestic partners.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">To qualify as a domestic partner under this subsection, an individual shall submit evidence of a domestic partnership.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">To qualify as a former domestic partner under this subsection, an individual shall submit evidence of dissolution of a domestic partnership.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The exemption under paragraph (1) of this subsection for transfers between domestic partners or former domestic partners applies only to an instrument of writing for residential property.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A supplemental instrument of writing is not subject to recordation tax except to the extent that:<section prefix="(1)">actual consideration is payable on the supplemental instrument of writing; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the amount of debt is increased by the supplemental instrument of writing.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An instrument of writing previously recorded is not subject to recordation tax when the instrument or a counterpart is recorded in another county or in the same county.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "original mortgagor" includes:<section prefix="(i)">an individual who assumed a debt secured by real property that the individual purchased as a principal residence and who paid the recordation tax on the consideration paid for the property; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the trustee of an inter vivos trust if:<section prefix="1.">the mortgaged property is used as a principal residence of the settlor of the trust; and</section><section prefix="2.">the trustee or the settlor of the trust originally assumed or incurred the debt secured by the mortgage or deed of trust.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A mortgage or deed of trust is not subject to recordation tax to the extent that it secures the refinancing of an amount not greater than the unpaid principal amount secured by an existing mortgage or deed of trust at the time of refinancing if the mortgage or deed of trust secures the refinancing of real property that is:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">used as a principal residence by the original mortgagor; and</section><section prefix="2.">being refinanced by the original mortgagor or by the original mortgagor and the spouse of the original mortgagor; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">used as a principal residence by the settlor of an inter vivos trust if the mortgage or deed of trust is given by a trustee of the trust.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">To qualify for an exemption under paragraph (2) of this subsection an original mortgagor or agent of the original mortgagor shall include a statement in the recitals or in the acknowledgment of the mortgage or deed of trust, or submit with the mortgage or deed of trust, an affidavit under oath, signed by the original mortgagor or agent of the original mortgagor, stating:<section prefix="(i)">that the individual is the original mortgagor or agent of the original mortgagor;</section><section prefix="(ii)">that the mortgaged property is the principal residence of the original mortgagor or of the settlor of an inter vivos trust if the mortgage or deed of trust is given by a trustee of the trust; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the amount of unpaid principal of the original mortgage or deed of trust that is being refinanced.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A statement under paragraph (3) of this subsection by an agent of the original mortgagor shall state that the statement:<section prefix="(i)">is based on a diligent inquiry made by the agent with respect to the facts set forth in the statement; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is true to the best of the knowledge, information, and belief of the agent.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">An instrument of writing of a mechanic's lien or crop lien that relates to farm products or equipment used in farming operations is not subject to recordation tax.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "purchase money mortgage" or "purchase money deed of trust" means a mortgage or deed of trust that:<section prefix="(i)">is given by the transferee of real property with respect to the property purchased;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is delivered as part of the same transaction as the instrument of writing that transfers the property purchased and that is subject to the recordation tax;</section><section prefix="(iii)">recites on its face that it secures, in whole or in part, the purchase money for the property or otherwise recites on its face that it is a purchase money mortgage or purchase money deed of trust;</section><section prefix="(iv)">is fully executed within 30 days of the date that the instrument of writing transferring the property is fully executed; and</section><section prefix="(v)">is recorded no later than 30 days after the date that the instrument of writing transferring the property is duly recorded.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For the purpose of this subsection, the date that an instrument is fully executed is the later of:<section prefix="(i)">the date of the last acknowledgment; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the date on the instrument of writing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A purchase money mortgage or a purchase money deed of trust is not subject to recordation tax.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">An assignment of a mortgage or deed of trust is not subject to recordation tax.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">A security agreement filed or recorded under the Maryland Uniform Commercial Code is not subject to recordation tax:<section prefix="(1)">if it is filed or recorded:<section prefix="(i)">to perfect a security interest in inventory;</section><section prefix="(ii)">to perfect a security interest in contract rights, general intangibles, or accounts;</section><section prefix="(iii)">to perfect a security interest in farm products or in equipment used in farming operations;</section><section prefix="(iv)">to perfect a security interest taken or retained by a seller of collateral to secure all or part of its price; or</section><section prefix="(v)">to publicize a lease of goods or fixtures, provided that the security agreement states on its face that it does not create a security interest; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">if it is filed or recorded with the Department under &#xA7; 9-501(a)(2) of the Commercial Law Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">A judgment of a court is not subject to recordation tax.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">A release is not subject to recordation tax.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">An order of satisfaction is not subject to recordation tax.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">A participation agreement that shows an interest of a person in a note, mortgage, or deed of trust that is based on a previously recorded loan to the mortgagor or grantor under a deed of trust is not subject to recordation tax.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">An instrument of writing is not subject to recordation tax if the instrument of writing is:<section prefix="(1)">a transfer of title to real property between a parent corporation and its subsidiary corporation or between 2 or more subsidiary corporations wholly owned by the same parent corporation, if the parent corporation is an original stockholder of the subsidiary corporation, or subsidiary corporations, or became a stockholder through gift or bequest from an original stockholder of the subsidiary corporation, or subsidiary corporations, for:<section prefix="(i)">no consideration;</section><section prefix="(ii)">nominal consideration; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">consideration that comprises only the issuance, cancellation, or surrender of stock of a subsidiary corporation;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">an instrument of writing made pursuant to reorganizations described in &#xA7; 368(a) of the Internal Revenue Code; or</section><section prefix="(3)">a transfer of title to real property from a subsidiary corporation to its parent corporation for no consideration, nominal consideration or consideration that comprises only the issuance, cancellation, or surrender of a subsidiary's stock, where the parent corporation:<section prefix="(i)">previously owned the real property;</section><section prefix="(ii)">owns the stock of the subsidiary and has owned that stock for a period greater than 18 months; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">acquires the stock of a subsidiary corporation which has been in existence and has owned the real property for a period of 2 years.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(q)">An instrument of writing that transfers real property from a corporation, limited liability company, or partnership on its liquidation, dissolution, or termination is not subject to recordation tax, if the transferee is:<section prefix="(1)">an original stockholder of the corporation, an original member of the limited liability company, or an original partner of the partnership;</section><section prefix="(2)">a direct descendant or relative within 2 degrees of an original stockholder of the corporation, an original member of the limited liability company, or an original partner of the partnership counting by the civil law method; or</section><section prefix="(3)">a stockholder, member, or partner who became a stockholder, member, or partner through gift or bequest from an original stockholder of the corporation, an original member of the limited liability company, or an original partner of the partnership.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(r)">A land installment contract described in &#xA7; 10-101(c) of the Real Property Article is not subject to recordation tax.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">An option agreement for the purchase of real property is not subject to recordation tax.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">A deed conveying title to real property is not subject to recordation tax if recordation tax was paid on a prior contract of sale between the same parties for the real property.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">A lease of 7 years or less, which is not required to be recorded under &#xA7; 3-101 of the Real Property Article, is not subject to recordation tax.</section>
    <section prefix="(v)">Articles of merger or other document which evidences a merger of foreign corporations are not subject to recordation tax if there is a transfer of real property:<section prefix="(1)">from a parent corporation to its subsidiary corporation;</section><section prefix="(2)">from a subsidiary corporation to its parent corporation where the parent corporation:<section prefix="(i)">previously owned the real property;</section><section prefix="(ii)">owns the stock of the subsidiary and has owned that stock for a period greater than 18 months; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">acquires the stock of a subsidiary corporation which has been in existence and has owned the real property for a period of 2 years; or</section></section><section prefix="(3)">from a corporation merging out of existence to its successor corporation where recordation tax and, if then required to have been paid, transfer tax were paid when the corporation merging out of existence acquired title to the real property.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(w)">Articles of consolidation or other documents that evidence a consolidation of foreign corporations are not subject to recordation tax if recordation tax and, if then required to have been paid, transfer tax were paid when the corporation consolidating to form a new corporation acquired title to the real property.</section>
    <section prefix="(x)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in this subsection, an instrument of writing that transfers real property from a cooperative housing corporation on its termination to an owner of a cooperative interest in the cooperative housing corporation is not subject to recordation tax if the cooperative housing corporation consists of single residential units and was established on or before January 1, 1970.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The exemption under paragraph (1) of this subsection does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">the conversion of a cooperative housing corporation to a condominium regime; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the transfer of property to a person who:<section prefix="1.">does not occupy the property transferred; or</section><section prefix="2.">has received the credit allowed under this section for another property transferred as part of the same corporate termination.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The exemption under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall apply only in a county that:<section prefix="(i)">does not levy a county property transfer tax; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">has, by law, adopted an exemption from any local transfer tax for property as described in this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(y)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Foreign general partnership", "foreign limited partnership", "foreign limited liability partnership", "foreign limited liability limited partnership", and "foreign joint venture" mean, respectively, a partnership, limited partnership, limited liability partnership, limited liability limited partnership, or joint venture organized or formed under the laws of the United States, another state of the United States, or a territory, possession, or district of the United States.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Predecessor entity" includes a:<section prefix="1.">Maryland general partnership or foreign general partnership;</section><section prefix="2.">Maryland limited partnership or foreign limited partnership;</section><section prefix="3.">Maryland limited liability partnership or foreign limited liability partnership;</section><section prefix="4.">Maryland limited liability limited partnership or foreign limited liability limited partnership; and</section><section prefix="5.">Maryland joint venture or foreign joint venture.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An instrument of writing that transfers title to real property from a predecessor entity or a trustee or nominee of a predecessor entity to a limited liability company is not subject to recordation tax if:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">the members of the limited liability company are identical to the partners of the converting general partnership, limited partnership, limited liability partnership, or limited liability limited partnership; or</section><section prefix="2.">the members of the limited liability company are identical to the joint venturers of the converting joint venture;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">each member's allocation of the profits and losses of the limited liability company is identical to that member's allocation of the profits and losses of the converting predecessor entity; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the instrument of writing that transfers title to real property represents the dissolution of the predecessor entity for purposes of conversion to a limited liability company.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(z)">Expired.</section>
    <section prefix="(aa)">An instrument of writing pursuant to which the Maryland Stadium Authority transfers title to, or creates a leasehold interest in, real property is not subject to recordation tax if the transferee or lessee is an Authority affiliate as defined in &#xA7; 10-601 of the Economic Development Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(bb)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "real estate enterprise" means a business conducted by one or more individuals who own real property, including a sole proprietorship or a tenancy by the entirety, and are principally involved in buying, selling, leasing, or managing real property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An instrument of writing that transfers title to real property from the individual or individuals conducting a real estate enterprise to a limited liability company is not subject to recordation tax if:<section prefix="(i)">the transfer is for no consideration other than the issuance of membership interests in the limited liability company;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the members of the limited liability company are identical to the partners of the conveying real estate enterprise;</section><section prefix="(iii)">each member's allocation of the profits and losses of the limited liability company is identical to that member's allocation of the profits and losses of the conveying real estate enterprise;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the transfer is part of a discontinuation of the real estate enterprise; and</section><section prefix="(v)">all real property owned by the individuals and used in the conduct of any real estate enterprise is being conveyed to a single limited liability company.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An individual's other business interests unrelated to the real estate enterprise and unaffected by the title transfer to a limited liability company may not affect the individual's ability to claim the exemption from the recordation tax described in this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(cc)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Land trust" means a qualified conservation organization that:<section prefix="1.">is a qualified organization under &#xA7; 170(h)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code and regulations adopted under that section; and</section><section prefix="2.">has executed a cooperative agreement with the Maryland Environmental Trust.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Conservation easement" means a restriction prohibiting or limiting the use of water or land areas, or any improvement or appurtenance thereto, described in &#xA7; 2-118 of the Real Property Article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An instrument of writing conveying or assigning a conservation easement to a land trust is not subject to recordation tax.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An instrument of writing conveying fee simple title to a land trust is not subject to recordation tax if the land trust files a declaration of intent that the land will be used:<section prefix="(i)">to assist in the preservation of a natural area;</section><section prefix="(ii)">for the environmental education of the public;</section><section prefix="(iii)">to conserve agricultural land and to promote continued agricultural use of the land;</section><section prefix="(iv)">generally to promote conservation; or</section><section prefix="(v)">for the maintenance of a natural area for public use or a sanctuary for wildlife.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(dd)">An instrument of writing that transfers real property or an interest in real property from an estate is not subject to recordation tax as provided in &#xA7; 9-105(c) of the Estates and Trusts Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(ee)">An instrument of writing that transfers real property or an interest in real property to a trust or from a trust to one or more beneficiaries under the circumstances specified in &#xA7; 14-114 of the Estates and Trusts Article is not subject to recordation tax.</section>
  </text>
</law>
