<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-7-208</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>208</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Disabled veteran" means an individual who:<section prefix="1.">is honorably discharged or released under honorable circumstances from active military, naval, or air service as defined in 38 U.S.C. &#xA7; 101; and</section><section prefix="2.">has been declared by the Veterans' Administration to have a permanent 100% service connected disability that results from blindness or other disabling cause that:</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Disabled veteran" includes an individual who qualifies posthumously for a 100% service connected disability.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Dwelling house":<section prefix="(i)">means real property that is:<section prefix="1.">the legal residence of a disabled veteran or a surviving spouse; and</section><section prefix="2.">occupied by not more than 2 families; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">includes the lot or curtilage and structures necessary to use the real property as a residence.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Surviving spouse" means a surviving spouse, who has not remarried:<section prefix="(i)">of a disabled veteran;</section><section prefix="(ii)">of an individual who died in the line of duty; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">who receives Dependency and Indemnity Compensation from the United States Department of Veterans Affairs.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Individual who died in the line of duty" means an individual who died while in the active military, naval, or air service of the United States as a result of an injury or disease that is deemed under 38 U.S.C. &#xA7; 105 to have been incurred in the line of duty.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, a dwelling house is exempt from property tax if:<section prefix="(1)">the dwelling house is owned by:<section prefix="(i)">a disabled veteran;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a surviving spouse of an individual who died in the line of duty, if:<section prefix="1.">the dwelling house was owned by the individual at the time of the individual's death;</section><section prefix="2.">the dwelling house was acquired by the surviving spouse within 2 years of the individual's death, if the individual or the surviving spouse was domiciled in the State as of the date of the individual's death; or</section><section prefix="3.">the dwelling house was acquired after the surviving spouse qualified for exemption for a former dwelling house under item 1 or 2 of this item, to the extent of the previous exemption; or</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">a surviving spouse of a disabled veteran who meets the requirements of subsection (c) of this section; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the application requirements of subsection (d) of this section are met.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as provided in subsections (d) and (e) of this section, after a disabled veteran dies, the surviving spouse of the disabled veteran shall receive a disabled veteran's property tax exemption:<section prefix="(1)">for the dwelling house that was formerly owned by the disabled veteran:<section prefix="(i)">if the dwelling house received an exemption under this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the surviving spouse owns and resides in the dwelling house;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">for the dwelling house that was formerly occupied by the disabled veteran:<section prefix="(i)">if the dwelling house did not receive an exemption under this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the disabled veteran was domiciled in the State at death; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">if the surviving spouse owns and resides in the dwelling house; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">for a dwelling house subsequently acquired by the surviving spouse, equal to the exemption for the former dwelling house when the dwelling house owned by the surviving spouse was transferred by the surviving spouse:<section prefix="(i)">if the surviving spouse owns and resides in the subsequently acquired dwelling house; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the surviving spouse has qualified under item (1) or (2) of this subsection.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A disabled veteran or a surviving spouse of a disabled veteran shall apply for an exemption under this section by providing to the supervisor:<section prefix="(i)">a copy of the disabled veteran's discharge certificate from active military, naval, or air service; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">on the form provided by the Department, a certification of the disabled veteran's disability from the Veterans' Administration.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The disabled veteran's certificate of disability may not be inspected by individuals other than:<section prefix="(i)">the disabled veteran; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">appropriate employees of the State, a county, or a municipal corporation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A surviving spouse of an individual who died in the line of duty shall apply for an exemption under this section by providing to the supervisor certification that the individual died while in active service as a result of an injury or disease incurred in the line of duty.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, an exemption under this section shall be granted in addition to any other exemption authorized by law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual may receive an exemption under this section or under &#xA7; 7-207 of this subtitle but not under both.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An exemption under this section is prorated by the supervisor for any part of a taxable year that remains after the date in the year when the disabled veteran or the surviving spouse applies for the exemption.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this article, if a dwelling is transferred to a disabled veteran or a surviving spouse who qualifies for an exemption under this section, the exemption applies and the property tax is abated from the date of settlement for the purchase of the property, if the transferee applies for the exemption within 30 days after the settlement for the purchase of the property.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department shall adopt regulations to administer the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In the taxable years in which an exemption under this section was authorized but not granted, the governing body of a county or a municipal corporation may authorize, by law, a refund to an individual described below who receives an exemption under this section:<section prefix="(i)">to a disabled veteran or a surviving spouse for any county property tax paid; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">to a disabled veteran for any municipal corporation property tax paid.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A surviving spouse may apply for a refund of county property tax paid on the dwelling house while the exemption was available, only if the surviving spouse applies for the exemption during the 3-year period beginning with the calendar year in which the surviving spouse initially became eligible for an exemption under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For the purposes of subsections (f) and (g) of this section, a county or municipal corporation shall pay to a disabled veteran or surviving spouse interest on the amount of a refund if:<section prefix="(i)">the governing body has authorized the refund;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the disabled veteran or surviving spouse is eligible and has applied for the refund; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the county or municipal corporation fails to make the refund within 60 days after the eligible disabled veteran or surviving spouse has applied for the refund.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If interest is payable under this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">the county or municipal corporation shall pay interest at the rate the county or municipal corporation charges on overdue taxes; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">interest shall accrue from the date the application is filed with the county or municipal corporation.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Each county shall include information on the property tax bill about the availability of the property tax exemption for disabled veterans and surviving spouses authorized under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
