<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="gtp" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-8-213</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "agreement" means an agreement made under subsection (b) of this section....</catch_line>
  <order_by>213</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "agreement" means an agreement made under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department may make agreements with country clubs and golf courses that specify the manner of assessing the land of a country club or golf course. All agreements shall contain uniform provisions.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the land of a country club or golf course that is actively used as a country club or golf course that meets the requirements of &#xA7; 8-212 of this subtitle shall be valued at rates equivalent to land assessed under &#xA7; 8-219 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the land of a country club or golf course that meets the requirements of &#xA7; 8-212 of this subtitle has a greater market value than its value when used as a country club or golf course, the land shall also be assessed on the basis of the greater value.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as provided under &#xA7; 8-216 of this subtitle, the property tax payable by a country club or golf course under this section is based on the assessment of the land under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If an assessment is made on the greater value under paragraph (2) of this subsection, the assessment records for the country club or golf course shall record the assessment under paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Any assessment of the land of a country club or golf course under this section is effective on the date of finality next following the date of an agreement.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An agreement shall be for at least 10 consecutive years or for a longer period as determined by the country club or golf course and the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An agreement may be extended, but only in increments of at least 5 years.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
