<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-311</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>311</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The governing body of Dorchester County and of a municipal corporation in Dorchester County shall grant a property tax credit under this section against the county and municipal corporation property tax imposed on:<section prefix="(1)">property that on July 1, 1969 was owned by the Women's Auxiliary of the Dorchester Memorial Hospital; and</section><section prefix="(2)">property that is owned by the Cambridge Little League, Incorporated.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The governing body of Dorchester County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county property tax imposed on:<section prefix="(1)">property that is owned by the Cedar Meadows Rod and Gun Club, Incorporated; and</section><section prefix="(2)">property that is owned by the Cambridge Skeet and Gun Club, Incorporated.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To encourage the location of warehouse plant facilities or the expansion of existing warehouse plant facilities, the governing body of Dorchester County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county property tax imposed on the real property of commercial warehouse plant facilities if:<section prefix="(i)">the property is used in connection with warehouse activities; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the facilities have a minimum of 80,000 square feet of enclosed commercial warehouse space under a roof and within a building or buildings.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A tax credit granted under this subsection may not be granted for more than 20 years.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Dorchester County or of a municipal corporation in Dorchester County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county or municipal corporation property tax that is imposed on real property that is:<section prefix="(i)">owned by Habitat for Humanity of Talbot &amp; Dorchester Counties, Inc. with the intention of relinquishing ownership in the immediate future;</section><section prefix="(ii)">used exclusively for the purpose of rehabilitation and transfer to a private owner; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">not occupied by administrative or warehouse buildings owned by Habitat for Humanity.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Habitat for Humanity of Talbot &amp; Dorchester Counties, Inc. shall submit an annual written report to the governing body of Dorchester County documenting:<section prefix="(i)">all of Habitat for Humanity of Talbot &amp; Dorchester Counties, Inc.'s real property holdings in Dorchester County; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">all transactions involving Habitat for Humanity of Talbot &amp; Dorchester Counties, Inc.'s real property holdings in Dorchester County.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The governing body of Dorchester County or of a municipal corporation in Dorchester County may, by law:<section prefix="(i)">set the amount, terms, scope, and duration of a credit granted under paragraph (1) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">adopt any provision necessary to administer a credit granted under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The governing body of Dorchester County or of a municipal corporation in Dorchester County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against county or municipal corporation property tax imposed on property that:<section prefix="(1)">is owned by the Chesapeake Audubon Society, Inc.; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is used solely for:<section prefix="(i)">the environmental education of the public; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the maintenance of:<section prefix="1.">a natural area for public use; or</section><section prefix="2.">a sanctuary for wildlife.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Dorchester County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county property tax imposed on:<section prefix="(i)">agricultural land that is subject to a nutrient management plan or that is developing a nutrient management plan for implementation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">agricultural land that:<section prefix="1.">is located in an agricultural preservation district; or</section><section prefix="2.">is subject to an agricultural land preservation easement or similar easement; or</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">forest land that is subject to a forest management plan or similar agreement.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In establishing a tax credit under this subsection, the governing body of Dorchester County:<section prefix="(i)">shall develop criteria necessary to implement the credit; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">may specify the amount and duration of the credit, the qualification and application procedures for the credit, and any other requirement or procedure that the governing body considers appropriate.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
