<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-2-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "taxing authority" means:<section prefix="(1)">the county council or board of county commissioners of a county;</section><section prefix="(2)">the City Council of Baltimore City; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the governing body of a municipal corporation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before February 14 of each year, the Department shall send each taxing authority:<section prefix="(i)">an estimate of the total assessment of all real property in the county or municipal corporation for the next taxable year; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">an estimate of the total assessment:<section prefix="1.">of all new construction and improvements in the county or municipal corporation not assessed since the last date of finality; and</section><section prefix="2.">of all real property in the county or municipal corporation that may be deleted from the assessment records.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall notify each taxing authority of any change in the estimated assessment of all real property in the county or the municipal corporation that results from actions of a property tax assessment appeal board or the Maryland Tax Court.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall notify each taxing authority of the constant yield tax rate that will provide the same property tax revenue that is provided by the real property tax rate that is in effect for the current taxable year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In calculating a constant yield tax rate for a taxable year, the Department shall use an estimate of the total assessment of all real property for the next taxable year exclusive of real property that appears for the 1st time on the assessment records.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On or before May 15 of each year, the Department may amend a constant yield tax rate but only:<section prefix="(i)">when directed to make a change by an enactment of the General Assembly;</section><section prefix="(ii)">to correct an error in the calculation of the constant yield tax rate; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">to reflect a significant loss of taxable base, as determined by the Director.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Director shall exempt a municipal corporation from the constant yield tax rate provisions of &#xA7; 6-308 of this article if a difference of less than $25,000 exists between:<section prefix="(1)">the property tax revenue that is provided by applying the municipal corporation real property tax rate for the preceding taxable year to the estimated assessment of all real property in the municipal corporation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the property tax revenue that is provided by applying the constant yield tax rate for the next taxable year to the estimated assessment of all real property in the municipal corporation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Director shall report to the Attorney General any taxing authority that appears to have violated the requirements of &#xA7; 6-308 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Attorney General shall investigate the report forwarded by the Director. If the Attorney General finds that a taxing authority violated the requirements of &#xA7; 6-308 of this article, the Attorney General shall institute appropriate legal action to effect compliance with the requirements of &#xA7; 6-308 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a court finds that a taxing authority violated &#xA7; 6-308 of this article, the real property tax rate of that taxing authority shall be the constant yield tax rate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A taxing authority that does not exceed the constant yield tax rate shall notify the Department within the time set by the Director.</section>
  </text>
</law>
