<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="gtp" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-13-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this title the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Articles of consolidation" means a document filed with the Department under &#xA7; 3-107 of the Corporations and Associations Article which evidences a consolidation of at least one Maryland corporation with another corporation to form a new Maryland corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Articles of merger" means a document filed with the Department under &#xA7; 3-107, &#xA7; 4A-703, &#xA7; 9A-903, or &#xA7; 10-208 of the Corporations and Associations Article which evidences a merger involving at least one Maryland corporation, Maryland limited liability company, Maryland partnership, or Maryland limited partnership.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Articles of transfer" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 1-101(c) of the Corporations and Associations Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Documents which evidence the merger or consolidation of foreign corporations, foreign partnerships, foreign limited liability companies, or foreign limited partnerships" means those documents that are filed or recorded with:<section prefix="(1)">the Department under &#xA7; 3-117, &#xA7; 4A-1012, &#xA7; 9A-910, or &#xA7; 10-912 of the Corporations and Associations Article; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the clerk of the circuit court of a county evidencing that title to real property has been conveyed through a merger or consolidation of 2 or more foreign corporations, foreign partnerships, foreign limited liability companies, or foreign limited partnerships.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Instrument of writing" means a written instrument that conveys title to, or a leasehold interest in, real property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Instrument of writing" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a deed or contract;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a lease;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an assignment of a lessee's interest;</section><section prefix="(iv)">articles of transfer;</section><section prefix="(v)">articles of merger or other document which evidences a merger of foreign corporations, foreign limited liability companies, foreign partnerships, or foreign limited partnerships; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">articles of consolidation or other document which evidences a consolidation of foreign corporations.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Instrument of writing" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">a mortgage, deed of trust, or other contract that creates an encumbrance on real property; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a security agreement, as defined in &#xA7; 12-101(h) of this article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Subsidiary corporation" includes any corporation that is a subsidiary of either a parent corporation or any other subsidiary corporation of the parent corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Successor" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 1-101(y) of the Corporations and Associations Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
