<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="gtp" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-251</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>251</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section:<section prefix="(1)">"marine trade waterfront property" means real property that:<section prefix="(i)">is adjacent to the tidal waters of the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is used primarily for an activity or business that requires direct access to, or location in, marine waters due to the nature of the activity or business; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">for the most recent 3-year period, has produced an average annual gross income of at least $1,000; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">"marine trade waterfront property" includes:<section prefix="(i)">marinas, boat ramps, boat hauling and repair facilities, fishing facilities, and any other boating facilities; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">land that is adjacent to or under improvements used primarily for an activity or business that requires access to, or location in, marine waters due to the nature of the activity or business.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the governing body of a county or of a municipal corporation may grant, by law, a tax credit against the county or municipal corporation property tax imposed on marine trade waterfront property.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the governing body of a county or of a municipal corporation may provide, by law, for:<section prefix="(1)">the amount and duration of the tax credit under this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">additional eligibility criteria for the tax credit under this section;</section><section prefix="(3)">regulations and procedures for the application and uniform processing of requests for the tax credit; and</section><section prefix="(4)">any other provision necessary to carry out the credit under this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
