<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-512" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-14-512</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Any taxpayer, the governing body of a county, a municipal corporation, or the Attorney General may appeal a final action by the Department on an appeal under &#xA7; 14-504 of this subtitle to the Maryland Tax Court. The appeal shall be made on or before 30 days from:<section prefix="(1)">the date of the final action of the Department; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the earlier of the date of delivery or mailing of the notice of the final action to the address specified under &#xA7; 14-507 of this subtitle, if a request is made under &#xA7; 14-507 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The person against whom final action has been taken by the Department under &#xA7; 14-506 of this subtitle may appeal the action to the Maryland Tax Court on or before 30 days after the earlier of the delivery or mailing of a notice of final action by the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, the person who submitted a property tax refund claim under Subtitle 9 of this title, the Department, a county, or a municipal corporation may appeal a final determination of a property tax refund claim by a refunding authority to the Maryland Tax Court on or before 30 days from the date that the refunding authority mails the notice of its determination.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The person who submitted a tax refund claim under &#xA7; 14-907 or &#xA7; 14-908 of this title may appeal any final action taken under &#xA7; 14-911 of this title to the Maryland Tax Court on or before 30 days from the date that the notice of disallowance is received by the person. However, if a refund claim under &#xA7; 14-911 of this title is not allowed or disallowed on or before 6 months from the date of filing the claim, the person who filed the claim may:<section prefix="(1)">deem the claim to be finally disallowed; and</section><section prefix="(2)">submit an appeal to the Maryland Tax Court.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">On or before 30 days from the date of the determination, any taxpayer, the State, a county, or a municipal corporation may appeal a determination of a property tax credit or relief under &#xA7; 14-509(c) of this subtitle by a property tax assessment appeal board to the Maryland Tax Court.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any taxpayer, a municipal corporation, the Attorney General, the Department, or the governing body of a county may appeal a determination made by a property tax assessment appeal board under &#xA7; 14-509(a) or (b) of this subtitle to the Maryland Tax Court.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The appeal shall be made:<section prefix="(i)">on or before 30 days after the determination under &#xA7; 14-509(a) or (b) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">on or before 30 days from the date of mailing a notice of the determination to the address requested under &#xA7; 14-507 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">if the appellant is the Department, on or before 30 days from the date the board sends written notice of its determination, by mail or otherwise, to the Department.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Unless a taxpayer previously appealed as required by &#xA7; 14-502 or &#xA7; 14-503 of this subtitle to a property tax assessment appeal board, the taxpayer may not appeal to the Maryland Tax Court under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An appeal under this subsection shall state:<section prefix="(i)">that the value or classification is erroneous because of overvaluation or undervaluation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">that the assessment is unequal because it is made at a higher proportion of value than other property of the same class; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">any other errors that may exist for which an appeal is allowed and because of which the petitioner claims to be injured.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Unless extended by the court at the request of a party, the Maryland Tax Court shall hear and determine all appeals under this subsection on or before:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Any party to an appeal may request the court to extend the 120 or 90 day requirement.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The court may grant an extension if it deems the request to be valid.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">For any appeal under this subsection to the Maryland Tax Court, the Department and the taxpayer shall, at least 10 days before a hearing on the appeal, exchange any written appraisals to be used for the purpose of placing a value on the property.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">An appeal to the Maryland Tax Court under this section shall be deemed to be filed within the time allowed for the appeal if a written petition is mailed to the Maryland Tax Court with a postmark date within the time allowed for the appeal.</section>
  </text>
</law>
