<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="1-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-1-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this article the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Assess" means:<section prefix="(1)">for real property, to determine the phased-in full cash value or use value to which the property tax rate may be applied; and</section><section prefix="(2)">for personal property, to determine the value to which the property tax rate may be applied.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Assessment" means:<section prefix="(1)">for real property, the phased-in full cash value or use value to which the property tax rate may be applied; and</section><section prefix="(2)">for personal property, the value to which the property tax rate may be applied.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Assessment roll" means the official listing of assessments of property required under &#xA7; 2-202(3) of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Collector" includes an officer of a county or municipal corporation who has a duty to collect or remit taxes.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Corporation" includes an association or joint-stock company.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Corporation" does not include a common trust fund as defined in &#xA7; 3-501(b) of the Financial Institutions Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"County" means a county of the State and, unless expressly provided otherwise, Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"County property tax" means the tax on property that is authorized under &#xA7;&#xA7; 6-202 and 10-102 through 10-105 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"County property tax" does not include a tax imposed on property specifically benefited by local improvements.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Date of finality" means January 1, when assessments become final for the taxable year next following.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Department" means the State Department of Assessments and Taxation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Department" includes, unless the context requires otherwise, a supervisor.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Director" means the Director of the State Department of Assessments and Taxation.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Domestic corporation" means a corporation organized under the laws of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Foreign corporation" means a corporation organized under the laws of the United States, a foreign country, or another state.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Governing body" means:<section prefix="(1)">for Baltimore City, unless otherwise provided, the Board of Estimates;</section><section prefix="(2)">for charter counties, as provided by local law, the county council or the county executive and the county council;</section><section prefix="(3)">for code counties, the county commissioners or county council;</section><section prefix="(4)">for county commissioner counties, the county commissioners; and</section><section prefix="(5)">for municipal corporations, the body provided by municipal charter.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Includes" or "including" means includes or including by way of illustration and not by way of limitation.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Internal Revenue Code" means Title 26 of the United States Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Law" includes any enactment, order, resolution, or ordinance of a county or municipal corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Manufacturing" means the process of substantially transforming, or a substantial step in the process of substantially transforming, tangible personal property into a new and different article of tangible personal property by use of labor or machinery.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Manufacturing" includes:<section prefix="(i)">the operation of sawmills, grain mills, or feed mills;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the operation of machinery and equipment used to extract and process minerals, metals, or earthen materials or by-products that result from the extracting or processing;</section><section prefix="(iii)">research and development activities, whether or not the company has a product for sale;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the identification, design, or genetic engineering of biological materials for research or manufacture; and</section><section prefix="(v)">the design, development, or creation of computer software for sale, lease, or license.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Manufacturing" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">activities that are primarily a service;</section><section prefix="(ii)">activities that are intellectual, artistic, or clerical in nature;</section><section prefix="(iii)">public utility services, including telephone, gas, electric, water, and steam production services; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">any other activity that would not commonly be considered as manufacturing.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Municipal corporation" means an entity that is subject to Article XI-E of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Municipal corporation property tax" means the tax on property authorized under &#xA7;&#xA7; 6-203 and 10-102 through 10-105 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Municipal corporation property tax" does not include a tax imposed on property specifically benefited by local improvements.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(u)">"Operating land" means any land used to operate a railroad or public utility.</section>
    <section prefix="(v)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Operating personal property" includes any property, other than real property, used to operate a railroad or public utility.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For a public utility, "operating personal property" includes cables, lines, poles, and towers.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(w)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Operating property" means any property used to operate a railroad or public utility.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Operating property" includes operating real property and operating personal property.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(x)">"Operating real property" includes any real property used to operate a railroad or public utility.</section>
    <section prefix="(y)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Operating unit" means, as determined by the Department, all of the operating property of a railroad or a public utility.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Operating unit" includes operating property that is located outside of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Operating unit" does not include more than 1 railroad or public utility for which separate accounts are kept, unless the Department finds that:<section prefix="(i)">the accounts are under the same or commonly controlled management; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the inclusion is necessary to determine the value of the operating property.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(z)">"Person" means an individual, receiver, trustee, guardian, personal representative, fiduciary, or representative of any kind and any partnership, firm, corporation, or other entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(aa)">"Principal office of a domestic corporation" means:<section prefix="(1)">the office in the State where the business of the corporation is directed and managed;</section><section prefix="(2)">if there is no office in the State where the business is directed and managed, the place in the State where the principal business of the corporation in the State is transacted; or</section><section prefix="(3)">if there is no office or place that meets the requirements of item (1) or (2) of this subsection, the principal office named in the corporation charter or reported to the Department.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(bb)">"Principal office of a foreign corporation in the State" means the place in the State where the principal business or operation of the corporation in the State is carried on.</section>
    <section prefix="(cc)">"Property" means real property and personal property.</section>
    <section prefix="(dd)">"Property tax" means the property tax imposed by:<section prefix="(1)">the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">a county; or</section><section prefix="(3)">a municipal corporation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(ee)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Public utility" means a company classified by the Department as a public utility under &#xA7; 8-109 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Public utility" includes:<section prefix="(i)">an electric company;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a gas company;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a pipeline company;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a sewage disposal company;</section><section prefix="(v)">a steam heating company;</section><section prefix="(vi)">a telephone company; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">a water company.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Public utility" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">a cable television company;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a cellular telephone company;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a cogenerator;</section><section prefix="(iv)">an exempt wholesale generator;</section><section prefix="(v)">an independent power producer;</section><section prefix="(vi)">a small power producer; or</section><section prefix="(vii)">a utility owned by a county or municipal corporation.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(ff)">"Quarterly date of finality" means the April 1 or October 1 when assessments may be made for real property that becomes assessable up to that time and after the last date of finality or semiannual date of finality.</section>
    <section prefix="(gg)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Real property" means any land or improvements to land.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Real property" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a leasehold or other limited interest in real property; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">an easement.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(hh)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Research and development" means:<section prefix="(i)">basic and applied research in the sciences and engineering; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the design, development, and governmentally required premarket testing of prototypes, products, and processes.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Research and development" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">market research;</section><section prefix="(ii)">research in the social sciences, psychology, or other nontechnical activities;</section><section prefix="(iii)">routine product testing;</section><section prefix="(iv)">sales services;</section><section prefix="(v)">technical and nontechnical services; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">research and development of a public utility.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(ii)">"Resident of the State" includes a domestic corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(jj)">"Semiannual date of finality" means July 1, when assessments may be made for real property that becomes assessable after the immediately preceding date of finality or quarterly date of finality.</section>
    <section prefix="(kk)">"State" means:<section prefix="(1)">a state, possession, or territory of the United States;</section><section prefix="(2)">the District of Columbia; or</section><section prefix="(3)">the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(ll)">"State property tax" means the tax imposed on property under &#xA7; 6-201 of this article and authorized under &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-102 and 10-103 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(mm)">"Supervisor" means the supervisor of assessments for a county.</section>
    <section prefix="(nn)">"Tax roll" means the assessment roll to which the property tax rate has been applied and on which the property tax on each property is shown.</section>
    <section prefix="(oo)">"Taxable year" means July 1 to June 30, both inclusive, for which the State, each county, municipal corporation, and taxing district of the State computes, imposes, and collects property tax.</section>
    <section prefix="(pp)">"Valuation" means the process of determining the value of property.</section>
    <section prefix="(qq)">"Value" means the full cash value of property.</section>
  </text>
</law>
