<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-14-839</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>839</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The plaintiff shall show in the title of the complaint the last address known to the plaintiff or to the attorney filing the complaint of each defendant, as obtained from:<section prefix="(i)">any records examined as part of the title examination;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the tax rolls of the collector who made the sale, as to the property described in the complaint; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">any other address that is known to the plaintiff or the attorney filing the complaint.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Paragraph (1) of this subsection does not require the plaintiff or the attorney for the plaintiff to make any investigations or to search any other records or sources of information other than those stated.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On the filing of the complaint, the court shall issue a summons to procure the answer and appearance of all the defendants as in other civil actions.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">This paragraph does not apply if a last known address for a defendant is not obtained as provided under paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection. The plaintiff shall cause a copy of the order of publication to be mailed by first class mail or certified mail, postage prepaid, to each defendant at the defendant's address as determined by the provisions of paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection. As to any defendant not served by summons or as provided by paragraph (5) of this subsection, the plaintiff shall file an affidavit in the proceedings, which affidavit:<section prefix="(i)">shall certify that this provision has been complied with; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall be accompanied by:<section prefix="1.">the receipt obtained from the post office for the mailing; or</section><section prefix="2.">the certified mail receipt.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Notice to a defendant may be made in any other manner that results in actual notice of the pendency of the action to the defendant. When notice is made under this paragraph it shall be certified to by an affidavit that fairly describes the method and time of service.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A final judgment may not be entered before the last of:<section prefix="(i)">where actual service is made on the defendant, the passage of the time specified in the summons issued by the court;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the actual time specified in the order of publication; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">33 days after the date of mailing the copy of the order of publication under paragraph (4) of this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The provisions of this section as to notice to persons who may have an interest in property sold for nonpayment of taxes, coupled with the order of publication and the other publicity and notices as ordinarily accompanies the sale of such property, as well as the knowledge of the taxes and the consequences for nonpayment of the taxes is declared:<section prefix="(1)">to be reasonable and sufficient under all of the circumstances involved, and necessary in light of the compelling need for the prompt collection of taxes; and</section><section prefix="(2)">to supersede any other requirement in other cases or civil causes generally.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notice of the institution of a proceeding to foreclose the right of redemption also shall be given to the collector where the property is located.</section>
  </text>
</law>
