<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="gtp" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-14-201</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided in this section, an officer, former officer, employee, or former employ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, an officer, former officer, employee, or former employee of the State, a county, a municipal corporation, or a taxing district may not open for public inspection valuation records, including:<section prefix="(1)">assessor notes and medical-related adjustments on residential worksheets or cards;</section><section prefix="(2)">commercial assessment worksheets or cards; and</section><section prefix="(3)">correspondence containing information concerning private appraisals, building costs, rental data, or business volume.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall permit a valuation record to be inspected by:<section prefix="(i)">the person whose property is the subject of the valuation record; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an officer of the State or a county or municipal corporation affected by the valuation record.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Valuation records, including rental data or business volume, may be submitted to the Maryland Tax Court as evidence in an appeal under Subtitle 5 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Residential assessment worksheets that list the property description with assigned cost rates and depreciation factors shall be available for inspection as they appear on the Department's website.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department shall provide a copy of assessment worksheets and cards that relate to a real property valuation:<section prefix="(1)">to the person whose property is the subject of the valuation if:<section prefix="(i)">the value or classification of the property is to be changed for property tax purposes; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the person requests the worksheets and cards; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">except for income and expense statements, to any person who pays property tax, if the person:<section prefix="(i)">seeks the worksheets and cards for other comparable property;</section><section prefix="(ii)">has a timely filed and pending appeal under Subtitle 5 of this title regarding the assessment of the person's property;</section><section prefix="(iii)">identifies the comparable property by address; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">pays the reasonable fee that the Department requires for the copy.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department may adopt regulations establishing reasonable conditions for release of information contained in valuation records that directly relate to descriptions of physical characteristics of and improvements to the land.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, a fee may be imposed for providing the information under this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A fee may not be imposed for providing to the property owner on the Department's website information concerning the calculation of the assessment and description of the property that is the subject of the assessment as required under subsection (c)(1) of this section.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
