<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-210</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>210</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Disabled law enforcement officer or rescue worker" means an individual who:<section prefix="(i)">has been found to be permanently and totally disabled by an administrative body or court of competent jurisdiction authorized to make such a determination; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">became disabled:<section prefix="1.">as a result of or in the course of employment as a law enforcement officer or a correctional officer; or</section><section prefix="2.">while in the active service of a fire, rescue, or emergency medical service, unless the disability was the result of the individual's own willful misconduct or abuse of alcohol or drugs.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Dwelling" means real property that:<section prefix="1.">is the legal residence of a disabled law enforcement officer or rescue worker or a surviving spouse; and</section><section prefix="2.">is occupied by not more than two families.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Dwelling" includes the lot or curtilage and structures necessary to use the real property as a residence.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Fallen law enforcement officer or rescue worker" means an individual who dies:<section prefix="(i)">as a result of or in the course of employment as a law enforcement officer or a correctional officer; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">while in the active service of a fire, rescue, or emergency medical service, unless the death was the result of the individual's own willful misconduct or abuse of alcohol or drugs.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Surviving spouse" means a surviving spouse, who has not remarried, of a fallen law enforcement officer or rescue worker.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the governing body of a county or municipal corporation may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county or municipal corporation property tax imposed on a dwelling that is owned by a disabled law enforcement officer or rescue worker or a surviving spouse of a fallen law enforcement officer or rescue worker:<section prefix="(1)">if the dwelling was owned by the disabled law enforcement officer or rescue worker at the time the law enforcement officer or rescue worker was adjudged to be permanently and totally disabled or by the fallen law enforcement officer or rescue worker at the time of the fallen law enforcement officer's or rescue worker's death;</section><section prefix="(2)">if the disabled law enforcement officer or rescue worker was domiciled in the State as of the date the disabled law enforcement officer or rescue worker was adjudged to be permanently and totally disabled or the fallen law enforcement officer or rescue worker or the surviving spouse was domiciled in the State as of the date of the fallen law enforcement officer's or rescue worker's death and the dwelling was acquired by the disabled law enforcement officer or rescue worker within 2 years of the date the disabled law enforcement officer or rescue worker was adjudged to be permanently and totally disabled or by the surviving spouse within 2 years of the fallen law enforcement officer's or rescue worker's death; or</section><section prefix="(3)">if the dwelling was acquired after the disabled law enforcement officer or rescue worker or the surviving spouse qualified for a credit for a former dwelling under item (1) or (2) of this subsection, to the extent of the previous credit.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A county or municipal corporation may provide, by law, for:<section prefix="(1)">the amount and duration of a property tax credit allowed under this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">any other provision necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
