<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="gtp" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-239</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>239</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Existing electricity generation facility" means an electricity generation facility that:<section prefix="(i)">exists in a county before June 1, 2001; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">receives approval for a modification under &#xA7; 7-205 of the Public Utilities Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Machinery and equipment of a new electricity generation facility" means machinery and equipment used in the generation of electricity at a new electricity generation facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Machinery and equipment of an existing electricity generation facility" means machinery and equipment used in the generation of electricity and added as part of an expansion of an existing electricity generation facility for the purpose of increasing electricity production at the existing electricity generation facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"New electricity generation facility" means an electricity generation facility that:<section prefix="(i)">locates in a county on or after June 1, 2001; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">receives a certificate of public convenience and necessity under &#xA7; 7-207 of the Public Utilities Article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, to the extent that a county grants a personal property tax credit for the machinery and equipment of a new electricity generation facility or the machinery and equipment of an existing electricity generation facility, the machinery and equipment may not be treated as taxable personal property for the purpose of computing any payments of State aid to education under &#xA7; 5-202 of the Education Article or other payments of State aid to counties or municipal corporations that by law are based on the assessment of property.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subsection (b) of this section does not apply to any personal property unless the county submits to the Department, on or before October 31 of the taxable year for which the tax credit for the property is granted, the information required under &#xA7; 9-201(b) of this subtitle regarding the tax credit.</section>
  </text>
</law>
