<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="gtp" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-208</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "open space" or "open area" means:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>208</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "open space" or "open area" means:<section prefix="(1)">real property, exclusive of any improvement, determined to be an "open space" or "open area" as defined in &#xA7; 5-1201 of the Natural Resources Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">real property that is determined by law of the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the governing body of the county where the real property is located to be an "open space" or an "open area" on the recommendation of:<section prefix="(i)">the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Department of Natural Resources; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">real property subject to an easement of interest in the property that:<section prefix="(i)">except as provided in subsection (i) of this section, limits the use of the property in a manner to preserve in perpetuity the natural open character of the property; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is permanently conveyed or assigned to:<section prefix="1.">the federal, the State, or local government; or</section><section prefix="2.">the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsections (c) and (d) of this section, the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the governing body of a county or of a municipal corporation may grant, by law, a property tax credit not exceeding 75% of the county, municipal corporation, or special district property tax imposed on any category of "open space" or "open area".</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A property tax credit not exceeding 100% of the county, municipal corporation, or special district property tax imposed on real property by the governing body of a county or of a municipal corporation on any category of "open space" or "open area" may be granted in:<section prefix="(1)">Anne Arundel County.</section><section prefix="(2)">Calvert County.</section><section prefix="(3)">Charles County.</section><section prefix="(4)">Frederick County.</section><section prefix="(5)">Harford County.</section><section prefix="(6)">Howard County.</section><section prefix="(7)">Montgomery County.</section><section prefix="(8)">Prince George's County.</section><section prefix="(9)">St. Mary's County.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the governing body of a county or of a municipal corporation may grant a property tax credit not exceeding 100% of the county, municipal corporation, or special district property tax imposed on an "open space" or "open area" if:<section prefix="(1)">the owner of the "open space" or "open area" agrees to sell or convey the "open space" or "open area" in an option agreement to:<section prefix="(i)">the federal, the State, or local government; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the option agreement:<section prefix="(i)">provides that the conveyance is in fee simple;</section><section prefix="(ii)">provides that the conveyance is made within a fixed period not exceeding 20 years;</section><section prefix="(iii)">provides that the price of the conveyance does not exceed the fair market value of the real property when the option is executed; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">contains provisions as the grantee deems necessary to preserve the real property as an "open space" or "open area".</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the governing body of a county or of a municipal corporation may provide, by law, for:<section prefix="(1)">any procedural or enforcement provision necessary to carry out this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">any condition that is uniformly applied in the granting of a property tax credit under this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the governing body of a county or of a municipal corporation may designate a functional or geographical category of "open space" or "open area" on which a property tax credit under this section may be granted.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A functional category may include:<section prefix="(i)">a country club;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a woodland;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a commercial golf course; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">a golf driving range.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A geographical category may include:<section prefix="(i)">a river basin real property;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a conservation area; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">a stream valley.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Any property tax credit granted and any standard used in granting a property tax credit shall be applied uniformly to all real property in each category.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Valuation and assessment of "open space" or "open area" shall be made in the same manner as any other real property in the county or municipal corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Montgomery County and Prince George's County, an easement or interest conveyed under this section may be in perpetuity or for a period of not less than 5 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An easement or interest previously conveyed may be extended for any period of time.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A property tax credit granted under this section is effective as long as the federal, the State, or local government or the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission holds the easement or interest.</section>
  </text>
</law>
