<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-318</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>318</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The governing body of Prince George's County shall grant a property tax credit under this section against the county property tax imposed on:<section prefix="(1)">real property:<section prefix="(i)">owned by the Maryland Jaycees, Incorporated; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">used in the operation of a charitable nonprofit educational or rehabilitation institution of the kind that is exempted under &#xA7; 7-202 of this article; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">real property owned by the Prince George's County Chamber of Commerce Foundation, Inc., if the real property:<section prefix="(i)">is acquired on or after November 24, 1973; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is not used for a commercial purpose.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Prince George's County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against county property tax imposed on:<section prefix="(i)">real property that is:<section prefix="1.">owned by a nonprofit community civic association or corporation;</section><section prefix="2.">dedicated by plat or deed restriction to the use of the lot owners in the community, if the use is not contingent on the payment of:</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">real property that is owned by the Piscataway Hills Citizens Association;</section><section prefix="(iii)">real property that is improved to promote housing, community redevelopment, and business revitalization;</section><section prefix="(iv)">real property used by the property owner to provide child care for the children of at least 25 employees;</section><section prefix="(v)">real property that is:<section prefix="1.">owned by the American Center for Physics, Inc.;</section><section prefix="2.">leased by the American Center for Physics, Inc. to affiliated societies; and</section><section prefix="3.">used only for nonprofit activities relating to the advancement and diffusion of the knowledge of physics and its application to human welfare;</section></section><section prefix="(vi)">subject to the condition established under paragraph (6) of this subsection, residential real property that is located within an area that the governing body determines is adversely impacted by its proximity to a refuse disposal system for which a permit has been issued under &#xA7; 9-204 of the Environment Article;</section><section prefix="(vii)">real property that is owned by the Kettering-Largo-Mitchellville Boys and Girls Club; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">agricultural land, including any farm improvement used in connection with an activity that is recognized by the Department as an approved agricultural activity, that is subject to State or county agricultural land preservation programs.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The amount of a property tax credit granted under paragraph (1)(iii) of this subsection is a percentage of the actual cost of the improvements as the governing body of Prince George's County determines after reassessment by the supervisor. The property tax credit may not be more than the increased tax that results from the improvements as the supervisor determines.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A property tax credit granted under paragraph (1)(iii) of this subsection may not be granted for more than 5 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The governing body of Prince George's County shall define the improvements that are eligible for a tax credit under paragraph (1)(iii) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">For purposes of the property tax credit granted under paragraph (1)(iv) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">at least 50% of the employees whose children receive child care shall be employed by the property owner;</section><section prefix="(ii)">in order to qualify for the tax credit, the property owner shall provide the child care in an area of the property that is set aside and dedicated by the property owner exclusively for the child care; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the amount of the tax credit may not exceed $1,000 or the amount of the county property tax attributable to the area of the property used for child care due in a taxable year, whichever is less.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this paragraph, "environmental surcharges" means tipping fees that:<section prefix="1.">are paid to the county by the user of a refuse disposal system; and</section><section prefix="2.">have been set at a specific amount per ton of refuse that is deposited at the site of the disposal system.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A property tax credit may not be granted under paragraph (1)(vi) of this subsection unless the governing body of Prince George's County approves the use of environmental surcharges to offset the total amount of the property tax credits granted.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The governing body of Prince George's County may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county property tax or special district tax imposed on:<section prefix="(1)">property that is owned by the Chapel Hill Citizens' Association;</section><section prefix="(2)">property that is:<section prefix="(i)">owned by the Clinton Boys and Girls Club; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">used only for nonprofit athletic recreation;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">property that is owned by the East Pines Citizens' Association;</section><section prefix="(4)">property that is owned by the Lions Club of Bowie;</section><section prefix="(5)">property that is owned by the Prince George's Jaycees, Incorporated;</section><section prefix="(6)">property that is owned by the Suitland Civic Association, Incorporated;</section><section prefix="(7)">real property that is:<section prefix="(i)">owned by the Prince George's County Parks and Recreation Foundation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">not used for a commercial purpose;</section></section><section prefix="(8)">property that is:<section prefix="(i)">owned by the Freestate Riding Club, Inc.; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">used only for nonprofit athletic recreation;</section></section><section prefix="(9)">property that is owned by a boys and girls club in Prince George's County that is chartered by the Prince George's County Boys and Girls Club, Incorporated;</section><section prefix="(10)">property that is owned by the Lake Arbor Foundation, Incorporated;</section><section prefix="(11)">property that is:<section prefix="(i)">owned by the George A. and Carmel D. Aman Memorial Trust; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">known as the George Washington House;</section></section><section prefix="(12)">property that:<section prefix="(i)">is owned by Crescent Cities Charities, Incorporated; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is not exempt from taxation under Title 7 of this article; and</section></section><section prefix="(13)">property that is:<section prefix="(i)">owned by a nonprofit, tax-exempt community development corporation qualified under &#xA7; 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code;</section><section prefix="(ii)">not used for a commercial purpose; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">located in Prince George's County on Maryland Route 202 at the intersection with St. Joseph's Drive.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of Prince George's County may grant, by law, a property tax credit against the county property tax imposed on owner-occupied, residential real property that is purchased from July 1, 2000 through June 30, 2002, specific to two geographic areas of Prince George's County that:<section prefix="(i)">contain up to 2,500 single-family dwellings in the aggregate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">are designated by the County Executive of Prince George's County for participation in a demonstration project for neighborhood preservation and stabilization.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In order to qualify for the credit under this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">for the 12-month period immediately prior to purchasing the property, the individual's principal residence may not have been located in the geographic areas designated under this subsection, unless the individual was not an owner of the property that was the individual's principal residence;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the designated geographic areas shall be located within two of the following areas:<section prefix="1.">a priority funding area, as defined in &#xA7; 5-7B-02 of the State Finance and Procurement Article;</section><section prefix="2.">a revitalization tax credit district, as defined in &#xA7; 10-235.02 established under the Prince George's County Code; or</section><section prefix="3.">an enterprise zone, as defined in &#xA7; 5-701 of the Economic Development Article; and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">the residential real property must have been purchased in conformance with a resolution adopted by the County Executive that is approved by the County Council.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The property tax credit shall equal:<section prefix="(i)">40% of the county property tax for each of the first 5 taxable years after the purchase of the real property;</section><section prefix="(ii)">35% of the county property tax for the 6th taxable year after the purchase of the real property;</section><section prefix="(iii)">30% of the county property tax for the 7th taxable year after the purchase of the real property;</section><section prefix="(iv)">25% of the county property tax for the 8th taxable year after the purchase of the real property;</section><section prefix="(v)">20% of the county property tax for the 9th taxable year after the purchase of the real property;</section><section prefix="(vi)">15% of the county property tax for the 10th taxable year after the purchase of the real property; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">0% of the county property tax for each taxable year thereafter.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The property tax credit shall first apply to the taxable year beginning after the date of the purchase of the eligible real property.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The governing body of Prince George's County may provide, by law, for any other provision necessary to carry out the property tax credit under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The County Executive of Prince George's County shall hold a public hearing prior to the final designation of the geographic areas under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Designation of geographic areas shall be made by a resolution adopted by the County Executive and approved by the County Council.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The Prince George's County Department of Finance shall provide, on an annual basis to those individuals qualifying for the property tax credit under this subsection, a statement certifying qualification for the property tax credit and the amount of the property tax credit being granted. The statement may be provided on or with the annual property tax bill or in another manner as chosen by the local government.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">In order to be eligible for a property tax credit under this subsection, an individual shall apply for the credit at least 6 months after the title to the residential property has been transferred to the individual.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">The property tax credit granted under this subsection terminates on the sale of the property.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A property owner who has been granted a property tax credit for agricultural land under subsection (b)(1)(viii) of this section and subsequently withdraws the property from a State or county agricultural land preservation program shall be liable for:<section prefix="(i)">all property taxes for which the property owner would have been liable if a property tax credit for agricultural land had not been granted under subsection (b)(1)(viii) of this section for a period not exceeding 10 years from the date that the property was subject to a State or county agricultural land preservation program;</section><section prefix="(ii)">interest on the total tax liability as required under &#xA7; 14-605 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">a penalty as required under &#xA7; 14-703 of this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body of Prince George's County may provide, by law, any procedural or enforcement provision necessary to carry out this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Green business" means a business that is certified by Prince George's County and:<section prefix="1.">primarily distributes, manufactures, markets, or sells green products;</section><section prefix="2.">primarily provides services relating to green products; or</section><section prefix="3.">primarily provides research and development relating to green products.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Green product" means a product that:<section prefix="1.">is energy or water efficient;</section><section prefix="2.">uses healthy, nontoxic materials;</section><section prefix="3.">is made from recycled or renewable resources; or</section><section prefix="4.">makes current products more energy efficient.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body of Prince George's County may grant, by law, a property tax credit against the county property tax imposed on real or personal property that is owned or leased by a certified green business.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The governing body of Prince George's County may provide, by law, for:<section prefix="(i)">criteria for eligibility and certification for the tax credit under this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the amount and duration of the tax credit under this subsection;</section><section prefix="(iii)">regulations and procedures for the application, certification, and uniform processing of requests for the tax credit; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">any other provision necessary to carry out the tax credit.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The County Council and County Executive of Prince George's County shall jointly appoint an advisory board to provide advice to the governing body of Prince George's County regarding the implementation of paragraph (3) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A majority of the members of the advisory board shall be affiliated with a nonprofit environmental organization in the State.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of a municipal corporation in Prince George's County may, by resolution, establish revitalization districts for the purpose of encouraging redevelopment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body of a municipal corporation in Prince George's County may grant, by law, a property tax credit against the municipal corporation property tax imposed on real property located within a revitalization district established under this subsection that is:<section prefix="(i)">constructed or substantially redeveloped in conformance with adopted eligibility criteria; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">reassessed as a result of the construction or redevelopment at a higher value than that assessed prior to the construction or redevelopment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The governing body of a municipal corporation in Prince George's County may provide by law:<section prefix="(i)">criteria for the designation of a revitalization district;</section><section prefix="(ii)">criteria for eligibility for the property tax credit under this subsection;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the amount and duration of the tax credit;</section><section prefix="(iv)">regulations and procedures for the application and uniform processing of requests for the tax credit; and</section><section prefix="(v)">any other provision necessary to carry out the tax credit under this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
