<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="gtp" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-14-847</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the judgment of the court shall direct the c...</catch_line>
  <order_by>847</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the judgment of the court shall direct the collector to execute a deed to the holder of the certificate of sale in fee simple or in leasehold, as appropriate, on payment to the collector of the balance of the purchase price, due on account of the purchase price of the property, together with all taxes and interest and penalties on the property that accrue after the date of sale. The judgment shall direct the supervisor to enroll the holder of the certificate of sale in fee simple or in leasehold, as appropriate, as the owner of the property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Frederick County, if the collector is absent, the deed may be executed by a deputy collector designated by the collector.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The deed shall be prepared by the holder of the certificate of sale or the attorney for the holder of the certificate of sale and all expenses incident to the preparation and execution of the deed shall be paid by the holder of the certificate of sale.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The clerk of the court in which the suit is instituted shall issue a certified copy of the judgment of the court to the collector and supervisor and the collector is not obligated to execute the deed provided for in this section until that certified copy of the judgment is delivered to the collector.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the holder of the certificate of sale does not comply with the terms of the final judgment of the court within 90 days as to payments to the collector of the balance of the purchase price due on account of the purchase price of the property and of all taxes, interest, and penalties that accrue after the date of sale, that judgment may be stricken by the court on the motion of an interested party for good cause shown.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Baltimore City, a certificate holder who has been enrolled as the owner of the property under subsection (a) of this section is not an interested party within the meaning of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
