<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-252</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>252</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the governing body of a county or municipal corporation may grant, by law, a property tax credit under this section against the county or municipal corporation property tax that is imposed on real property that is:<section prefix="(1)">owned by Habitat for Humanity with the intention of relinquishing ownership in the near future;</section><section prefix="(2)">used for the purposes of development, rehabilitation, and transfer to a private owner; and</section><section prefix="(3)">not occupied by administrative or warehouse buildings owned by Habitat for Humanity.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the governing body of a county or municipal corporation grants a property tax credit under this section, Habitat for Humanity shall submit an annual written report to the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the governing body of a county or municipal corporation granting the tax credit documenting:<section prefix="(1)">all of Habitat for Humanity's real property holdings in the jurisdiction granting the tax credit; and</section><section prefix="(2)">all transactions involving Habitat for Humanity's real property holdings in the jurisdiction granting the tax credit.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City or the governing body of a county or municipal corporation may, by law:<section prefix="(1)">set the amount, terms, scope, and duration of a credit granted under subsection (a) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">adopt any other provision necessary to administer a credit granted under subsection (a) of this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
