<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtp" order_by="gtp" level="1">Tax - Property</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtp-9-105</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>105</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Active member" means:<section prefix="(i)">a shareholder in a family corporation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a partner in a general partnership; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a member of a limited liability company or partner in a limited liability partnership who has or shares the authority to manage, control, and operate the limited liability company or limited liability partnership and who shares the assets and earnings of the limited liability company or limited liability partnership under an operating agreement under &#xA7; 4A-402 of the Corporations and Associations Article or under a partnership agreement.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Agricultural ownership entity" means a family corporation, general partnership, limited liability company, or limited liability partnership that:<section prefix="(i)">owns real property that:<section prefix="1.">includes land receiving an agricultural use assessment under &#xA7; 8-209 of this article; and</section><section prefix="2.">includes land used as a homesite that is part of or contiguous to a parcel described in item 1 of this item;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">owns personal property used to operate the agricultural land; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">owns no other property.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Bicounty commission" means:<section prefix="(i)">the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Washington Suburban Transit Commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Dwelling" means:<section prefix="1.">a house that is:</section><section prefix="2.">the lot or curtilage on which the house is erected.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Dwelling" includes:<section prefix="1.">a condominium unit that is occupied by an individual who has a legal interest in the condominium;</section><section prefix="2.">an apartment in a cooperative apartment corporation that is occupied by an individual who has a legal interest in the apartment; and</section><section prefix="3.">a part of real property used other than primarily for residential purposes, if the real property is used as a principal residence by an individual who has a legal interest in the real property.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Family corporation" means a corporation that does not have any stockholders other than the homeowner and the following members of the homeowner's family:<section prefix="(i)">a spouse or former spouse;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a child or stepchild;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a parent or stepparent;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a brother or sister;</section><section prefix="(v)">a son-in-law, daughter-in-law, stepson-in-law, or stepdaughter-in-law;</section><section prefix="(vi)">a grandchild or stepgrandchild; or</section><section prefix="(vii)">a grandparent or stepgrandparent.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Homeowner" means an individual who has a legal interest in a dwelling or who is an active member of an agricultural ownership entity that has a legal interest in a dwelling.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Legal interest" means an interest in a dwelling:<section prefix="(i)">as a sole owner;</section><section prefix="(ii)">as a joint tenant;</section><section prefix="(iii)">as a tenant in common;</section><section prefix="(iv)">as a tenant by the entireties;</section><section prefix="(v)">through membership in a cooperative;</section><section prefix="(vi)">under a land installment contract, as defined in &#xA7; 10-101 of the Real Property Article; or</section><section prefix="(vii)">as a holder of a life estate.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(9)">"Taxable assessment" means the assessment on which the property tax rate was imposed in the preceding taxable year, adjusted by the phased-in assessment increase resulting from a revaluation under &#xA7; 8-104(c)(1)(iii) of this article, less the amount of any assessment on which a property tax credit under this section is authorized.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If there is an increase in property assessment as calculated under this section, the State and the governing body of each county and of each municipal corporation shall grant a property tax credit under this section against the State, county, and municipal corporation property tax imposed on real property by the State, county, or municipal corporation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A property tax credit granted under this section shall be applicable to any State, county, or municipal corporation property tax and any property tax imposed for a bicounty commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a dwelling is not used primarily for residential purposes, the Department shall apportion the total property assessment between the part of the dwelling that is used for residential purposes and the part of the dwelling that is not used for residential purposes.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a homeowner does not actually reside in a dwelling for the required time period because of illness or need of special care and is otherwise eligible for a property tax credit under this section, the homeowner may qualify for the property tax credit under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a homeowner otherwise eligible for a credit under this section does not actually reside in a dwelling for the required time period because the dwelling is damaged due to an accident or natural disaster, the homeowner may continue to qualify for a credit under this section for the current taxable year and 2 succeeding taxable years even if the dwelling has been removed from the assessment roll in accordance with &#xA7; 10-304 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">For a homeowner who is an active member of an agricultural ownership entity to qualify for the property tax credit under this section:<section prefix="1.">the dwelling must have been owned and occupied by the active member:</section><section prefix="2.">the agricultural ownership entity and the active member who occupies the dwelling must file an application with the Department establishing initial eligibility for the credit on or before June 30 for the following taxable year and, at the request of the Department, must file an application in any future year to verify continued eligibility.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Failure to file a timely application may result in disqualification from the Homestead Tax Credit Program for the following taxable year.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The credit may only be granted to one dwelling owned by the agricultural ownership entity.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Participation in the credit program as the active member of an agricultural ownership entity disqualifies any other dwellings owned by the active member for the credit.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies only if the homeowner owned and occupied a dwelling on the subject property as the homeowner's principal residence for at least the 3 tax years immediately preceding the razing of the dwelling or the commencement of substantial improvements on the property.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a homeowner otherwise eligible for a credit under this section does not actually reside in a dwelling on the subject property for the required period of time under subsection (a)(2) or (d)(2) of this section because the dwelling was razed by the homeowner for the purpose of replacing it with a new dwelling or was vacated by the homeowner for the purpose of making substantial improvements to the property, the homeowner may continue to qualify for a credit under this section for the tax year in which the razing or the substantial improvements were commenced and 1 succeeding tax year even if the dwelling has been removed from the assessment roll.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If a homeowner qualifies for a credit under this paragraph, the full benefit of the credit existing at the commencement of the tax year in which the razing or vacating of the dwelling occurred may not be diminished during that tax year except that neither the calculation of the abatement nor the assessment under this paragraph shall include an assessment less than zero.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">If a homeowner qualifies for a credit under this paragraph, the calculation of the credit associated with the initial taxable assessment of the substantially completed new improvements, which is effective on or before the second July 1 after the razing or vacating of the dwelling, shall include the revaluation under &#xA7; 8-104(c)(1)(iii) of this article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies if:<section prefix="1.">the credit under this section has been denied for a dwelling for any taxable year because of the homeowner's failure to occupy the dwelling for the required time period; and</section><section prefix="2.">the homeowner's failure to occupy the dwelling for the required time period was the result of the homeowner's being an employee of the United States government stationed outside the State for a period not exceeding 6 consecutive years.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subject to subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph, a homeowner otherwise eligible for a credit under this section may qualify for the credit for a dwelling to which this paragraph applies for the next taxable year following the homeowner's resumption of residency in the dwelling.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The credit allowed under this paragraph shall be calculated based on the prior year's taxable assessment of the dwelling determined as if the credit had not been lost for the intervening taxable years when the homeowner was an employee of the United States government stationed outside the State.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (6) of this subsection, the Department shall authorize and the State, a county, or a municipal corporation shall grant a property tax credit under this section for a taxable year unless during the previous taxable year:<section prefix="(i)">the dwelling was transferred for consideration to new ownership;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the value of the dwelling was increased due to a change in the zoning classification of the dwelling initiated or requested by the homeowner or anyone having an interest in the property;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the use of the dwelling was changed substantially; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">the assessment of the dwelling was clearly erroneous due to an error in calculation or measurement of improvements on the real property.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A homeowner must actually reside in the dwelling by July 1 of the taxable year for which the property tax credit under this section is to be allowed.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A homeowner may claim a property tax credit under this section for only 1 dwelling.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If a property tax credit under this section is less than $1 in any taxable year, the tax credit may not be granted.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the dwelling was transferred for consideration in a deed dated on or after January 1 but before the beginning of the next taxable year and the deed was recorded with the clerk of the circuit court or the Department on or after July 1 but before September 1 of the next taxable year, the new owner may submit a written application to the Department on or before September 1 requesting that the date of the deed be accepted by the Department as the date of transfer under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">The applicant shall submit with the written application a copy of the executed deed evidencing the date of the transfer.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">If the applicant fails to submit a copy of the executed deed as required under subsubparagraph 1 of this subparagraph, the Department shall deny the application.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The date of the transfer under this paragraph is the effective date of the deed as described under &#xA7; 3-201 of the Real Property Article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">To qualify for the credit under this section, a homeowner shall submit an application for the credit to the Department as provided in this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The application shall:<section prefix="1.">be made on the form that the Department provides;</section><section prefix="2.">provide the information required by the form;</section><section prefix="3.">include a statement by the homeowner under oath that the facts stated in the application are true, correct, and complete; and</section><section prefix="4.">be filed on or before July 1 of the first taxable year for which the property tax credit under this section is to be allowed.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">For a dwelling that was last transferred for consideration to new ownership on or before December 31, 2007, the Department may not authorize and the State, county, and municipal corporation may not grant the property tax credit under this section after December 31, 2012, unless an application is filed with the Department as required under this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">If a dwelling previously received a credit under this section and failed to qualify for 1 taxable year because of a failure to file the application required under this paragraph, the Department:<section prefix="1.">shall grant the credit for the dwelling for the next following taxable year on the timely filing of the application by the same homeowner who previously received the credit; and</section><section prefix="2.">shall calculate the prior year's taxable assessment for the dwelling as if the credit had not been lost for the 1 intervening taxable year.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The Department shall provide a homeowner the  option to submit the application required under this paragraph  electronically on the Department's Web site.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For each taxable year, the property tax credit under this section is calculated by:<section prefix="(i)">multiplying the prior year's taxable assessment by the homestead credit percentage as provided under paragraph (2) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">subtracting that amount from the current year's assessment; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">if the difference is a positive number, multiplying the difference by the applicable property tax rate for the current year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For each taxable year, the homestead credit percentage under paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection is:<section prefix="(i)">for the State property tax and for any property tax imposed for a bicounty commission, 110%;</section><section prefix="(ii)">for the county property tax:<section prefix="1.">the homestead credit percentage established by the county under paragraph (3) of this subsection; or</section><section prefix="2.">if the county has not set a percentage for the taxable year under paragraph (3) of this subsection or has not notified the Department as required under paragraph (6) of this subsection, the homestead credit percentage in effect for the county for the preceding taxable year; and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">for the municipal corporation property tax:<section prefix="1.">the homestead credit percentage established by the municipal corporation under paragraph (4) of this subsection; or</section><section prefix="2.">if the municipal corporation has not set a percentage under paragraph (4) of this subsection or has not notified the Department as required under paragraph (7) of this subsection, the homestead credit percentage for the taxable year for the county in which the property is located.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to paragraph (5) of this subsection, the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City and the governing body of a county on or before November 15 of any year shall set, by law, the homestead credit percentage for the taxable year beginning the following July 1.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Subject to paragraph (5) of this subsection, on or before November 25 of any year, the governing body of a municipal corporation may set or alter, by law, a homestead credit percentage for the taxable year beginning the following July 1 and any subsequent taxable year.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The homestead credit percentage for any county or municipal corporation property tax:<section prefix="(i)">may not be less than 100% or exceed 110% for any taxable year; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall be expressed in increments of 1 percentage point.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City and the governing body of a county shall notify the Department of any action taken under paragraph (3) of this subsection on or before November 15 preceding the taxable year for which the action is taken.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">A municipal corporation shall notify the Department of any action taken under paragraph (4) of this subsection on or before November 25 preceding the taxable year for which the action is taken.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department shall give notice of the possible property tax credit under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A homeowner who meets the requirements of this section shall be granted the property tax credit under this section against the State, county, and municipal corporation property tax and any property tax imposed for a bicounty commission imposed on the real property of the dwelling.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The tax credit under this section shall be included on the homeowner's property tax bill.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When property that has received a credit under this section for the current taxable year includes improvements that are removed from the assessment roll under &#xA7; 10-304 of this article because of damage due to an accident or a natural disaster:<section prefix="(i)">the full benefit of the property tax abatement under &#xA7; 10-304 of this article may not be diminished by the amount of the credit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the full benefit of that credit may not be diminished by the property tax abatement under &#xA7; 10-304 of this article and shall be reflected in the assessment of the total property, including any new improvements, for the current taxable year; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the property shall be eligible to receive a credit under this section for the current taxable year and the two succeeding taxable years regardless of the existence or condition of the dwelling.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Neither the calculation of the abatement nor the assessment under this subsection shall include an assessment less than zero.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The Department shall adopt rules and regulations to implement this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The tax credit under this section shall be known as the homestead property tax credit.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">The Comptroller shall:<section prefix="(1)">cooperate with the Department in adopting a procedure to audit the application forms submitted under this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">notwithstanding &#xA7; 13-202 of the Tax - General Article, provide additional information to the Department; and</section><section prefix="(3)">assist the Department in a postaudit of each application.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The counties shall reimburse the Department for the administration of the application process under subsection (d)(6) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For each fiscal year, the reimbursement required under this subsection shall be prorated based on the ratio of the number of improved properties that would be eligible for the credit under this section located in the county compared to the total number of improved residential properties eligible for the credit under this section statewide as of July 1 of that fiscal year.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department shall bill each county according to the formula under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who has been granted a property tax credit under this section and is subsequently found to not qualify for the credit by the Department shall be assessed all State, county, and municipal corporation property tax otherwise due for each taxable year the person did not qualify to receive the credit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If a person is found by the Department to have willfully misrepresented facts regarding qualification for the property tax credit under this section, the person shall be assessed a penalty equal to 25% of the amount of the property tax credit received during each taxable year for which the person did not qualify.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The amount of the penalty shall be separately itemized on the person's property tax bill and constitutes a lien on the property until:<section prefix="1.">payment of the penalty in full; or</section><section prefix="2.">if the property is sold in an action to foreclose on a mortgage or deed of trust:</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a lien is released under paragraph (2)(ii)2 of this subsection, any unpaid penalty amount shall remain the personal liability of the person against whom the penalty was assessed.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A person may appeal a determination made under this subsection in accordance with the policies and procedures set forth in &#xA7; 14-506 of this article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
