<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-21-805</section_number>
  <catch_line>This subsection does not apply to:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>805</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">Vehicles used by any utility in the construction, maintenance, or repair of its facilities;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Vehicles used by any highway authority or bridge or highway district in construction, maintenance, repair, inspection, or survey work; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Low speed vehicles.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not drive on a highway any vehicle or combination of vehicles that is designed to be and is driven at a speed of 25 miles an hour or less, unless the rearmost vehicle displays a slow moving vehicle emblem in accordance with this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Any other vehicle or combination of vehicles, when driven at a speed of 25 miles an hour or less, may display a slow moving vehicle emblem in accordance with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The slow moving vehicle emblem specified in this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be a truncated equilateral triangle at least 14 inches high with a red reflective border at least 1.75 inches wide and with a fluorescent orange center;</section><section prefix="(2)">Comply with current standards and specifications of the American Society of Agricultural Engineers; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Be mounted on the rear of the vehicle, base down, at a height of not less than 3 nor more than 5 feet from ground to base.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">New farm equipment designed or intended by the manufacturer to be driven or moved at a speed of 25 miles an hour or less may not be sold in this State unless it is equipped by the manufacturer with a slow moving vehicle emblem in accordance with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The slow moving vehicle emblem shall be displayed and maintained on the farm equipment as long as it can be driven or moved on a highway.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The slow moving vehicle emblem described in this section may be displayed only as permitted or required by this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
