<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-3-510</section_number>
  <catch_line>Bonds under this subtitle may be authorized by trust agreement between the Department and a corporat...</catch_line>
  <order_by>510</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Bonds under this subtitle may be authorized by trust agreement between the Department and a corporate trustee, which may be any trust company, or bank having trust powers, within or without the State. Any such trust agreement shall describe the source or sources of revenue to be pledged to pay debt service on the bonds and may contain:<section prefix="(1)">Subject to then existing agreements with bondholders or noteholders, provisions pledging or assigning all or any part of the revenues of the participating counties, mortgages or loans made by the participating counties or the security therefor, the proceeds of any bonds issued under this subtitle, or any combination of these and any other assets of the participating counties to secure payment of bonds;</section><section prefix="(2)">Provisions protecting and enforcing rights and remedies of bondholders, including restrictions on the rights of holders, and covenants setting forth duties of or restrictions on the Department and the participating counties;</section><section prefix="(3)">Provisions appointing one or more trust companies or banks with trust powers to act as depositaries of the proceeds of any bonds or notes. Any depositary bank or trust company incorporated in the State may furnish indemnifying bonds or pledge securities, as required by the Department;</section><section prefix="(4)">Provisions as to custody, safeguarding, application, and investment of funds credited pursuant to this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(5)">Provisions establishing and controlling all aspects of reserve funds, including debt service reserve funds;</section><section prefix="(6)">Provisions for the payment of debt service on bonds and refunding bonds, including redemption premiums and interest; or</section><section prefix="(7)">Any other provisions deemed reasonable and proper for the security of bondholders.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A trust agreement may provide that the bonds may be sold either at public or private sale and that the maturity of the bonds may not exceed 30 years after their date of issue.</section>
  </text>
</law>
