<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-927</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>927</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When registered with the Administration, every trailer and semitrailer is a Class G (trailer) vehicle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A Class G (trailer) vehicle shall be classified as "freight" or "nonfreight".</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A nonfreight trailer or semitrailer is a vehicle designed for towing by a Class A (passenger) vehicle, a Class M (multipurpose) vehicle, or a Class E (truck) vehicle, and shall:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">If towed by a Class E (truck) vehicle, have a gross weight of 20,000 pounds or less; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If towed by a Class A (passenger) vehicle or a Class M (multipurpose) vehicle, have a gross weight of 10,000 pounds or less; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Be a:<section prefix="(i)">Boat trailer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Camping trailer;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Travel trailer;</section><section prefix="(iv)">House trailer; or</section><section prefix="(v)">Utility trailer.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A freight trailer or semitrailer shall be:<section prefix="(1)">Designed for towing by a Class E (truck) or Class F (tractor) vehicle; and</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">In excess of 20,000 pounds gross weight if towed by a Class E (truck) vehicle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">In excess of 10,000 pounds gross weight if towed by a Class F (tractor) vehicle.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The annual registration fee for a Class G (trailer) vehicle is based on the maximum gross weight as follows:<section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, for a nonfreight trailer or semitrailer:</section><section prefix="(2)">For a nonfreight trailer or semitrailer with a maximum gross weight limit (in pounds) of 10,001 to 20,000 that is titled on or after October 1, 2005:<section prefix="(i)">The fee is $124.00; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The vehicle shall be registered in one of the following weight ranges:</section></section><section prefix="(3)">For a freight trailer or semitrailer the fee is $38.25.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
