<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-320" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-8-320</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Before any property is condemned under this part, the Administration shall:<section prefix="(1)">Complete appropriate engineering and other studies; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Prepare a construction plan that shows:<section prefix="(i)">The location of the highway to be constructed, improved, or reconstructed;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The length of the construction; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The width of the right-of-way necessary for the construction.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">After preparing the construction plan, the Administration shall prepare plats that include:<section prefix="(1)">The construction plan;</section><section prefix="(2)">The fee simple and easement area to be acquired, by showing:<section prefix="(i)">The centerline of the construction;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The length and termini of the construction; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The width of the necessary right-of-way on either side of the centerline; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">According to information obtained by the Administration, the property lines of the property owners whose property will be affected by the acquisition.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">After the plats are prepared, the Administration shall:<section prefix="(1)">Make the engineering and real estate studies, evaluations, and investigations necessary to determine, in its opinion:<section prefix="(i)">The fair value of the property to be acquired; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The fair compensation for any resulting damages to the remaining property of the owner;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Prepare an estimate of this fair value and fair compensation; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Provide for payment of these estimated amounts as required by &#xA7; 8-323 of this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
