<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-602" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-7-602</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "labor dispute" is to be construed broadly and includes any controversy as to:<section prefix="(1)">Wages, salaries, hours, or other working conditions;</section><section prefix="(2)">Benefits, including health and welfare, sick leave, insurance, pension, or retirement provisions;</section><section prefix="(3)">Grievances that arise; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Collective bargaining agreements, including:<section prefix="(i)">The making or maintaining of any collective bargaining agreement;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The terms to be included in it; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Its interpretation or application.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If, in a labor dispute between the Administration and any employees described in &#xA7; 7-601 of this subtitle, collective bargaining does not result in agreement, the Administration shall submit the dispute to an arbitration board.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The arbitration board shall consist of three members appointed as follows:<section prefix="(i)">One by the Administration;</section><section prefix="(ii)">One by the authorized representative of the employees; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">One jointly by the Administration and the authorized representative.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If, within 10 days after the appointment of the second arbitrator, a third arbitrator has not been appointed, either arbitrator may request the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service or any other entity specified by contract between the Administration and the authorized representative to furnish a list of five persons, from which the third arbitrator shall be selected. Promptly after receiving the list, the two appointed arbitrators shall determine the order of elimination by lot and, in the determined order, each shall eliminate one name alternately until only one name remains. The remaining person is the third arbitrator.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The third arbitrator is the chairman of the board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A majority determination of the board is final and binding on all disputed matters.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each party shall pay 50 percent of the arbitration expenses.</section>
  </text>
</law>
