<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-504" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-504</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, if the title or interest of an owner in a registered vehicle passes to another person other than by voluntary transfer:<section prefix="(1)">The registration of the vehicle expires; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The vehicle may not be driven on a highway until the person entitled to possession of the vehicle applies for and obtains a new registration of the vehicle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">However, the person entitled to possession of the vehicle, or his authorized representative, may drive the vehicle on highways in this State for a distance of not more than 200 miles, but only from the place that the person or his authorized representative obtained possession of the vehicle to the person's place of business, residence, or other place where the vehicle is to be kept.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">During the operation of a vehicle described in subsection (b) of this section, the registration plates issued to the former owner may be displayed on the vehicle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">After the operation of a vehicle described in subsection (b) of this section is completed or, even before this operation is completed, on request of the former owner or the Administration, the person who obtained possession of the vehicle shall return its registration plates to the former owner or to the Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">After 24 hours of the earlier of the request or the completion of the operation described in subsection (b) of this section, no person, other than the person to whom the registration plates originally were issued, may have the registration plates in his possession, whether or not they are in use.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If the title or interest of an owner in a registered vehicle passes to a legatee or distributee as a result of testamentary disposition or intestate devolution, the personal representative, legatee, or distributee may drive the vehicle and permit it to be driven on the highways, without applying for a new registration, until the expiration of the last annual registration in the name of the deceased owner.</section>
  </text>
</law>
