<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-24-105</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>105</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">Any vehicle carrying wooden prefabricated roof trusses in an inverted position, if the trusses do not extend more than 10 feet beyond the rear of the bed or body of the vehicle;</section><section prefix="(2)">A combination of vehicles carrying an indivisible load if the load is not over 70 feet long, and the load is being transported during daylight hours; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Any vehicle or combination of vehicles carrying:<section prefix="(i)">Piling, poles, or mill logs;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Nursery stock; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Crew or racing shells.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to the maximum length limits of &#xA7; 24-104.1 of this subtitle, the load on any vehicle operated alone or the load on the front vehicle of a combination of vehicles:<section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in item (2) of this subsection, may not extend more than 3 feet beyond the foremost part of the vehicle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May extend more than 3 feet beyond the foremost part of a vehicle equipped with front-end loading attachments and containers used in collecting garbage, rubbish, refuse, or recyclable materials when the vehicle is actively engaged in collecting garbage, rubbish, refuse, or recyclable materials.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, and subject to the maximum length limits of &#xA7; 24-104.1 of this subtitle, the load on any vehicle operated alone or the load on the rear vehicle of a combination of vehicles may not extend more than 6 feet beyond the rear of the bed or body of the vehicle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The load on the rear of an automobile or boat transporter, including any retractable device on the rear of a combination of vehicles engaged in the transportation of automobiles in use to support a transported vehicle, may not extend more than 4 feet beyond the rear of the permanent bed or body of the automobile; and</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A white, red, or orange fluorescent warning flag made of a reflective material at least 18 inches square shall be displayed on the rearmost portion of the overhanging transported vehicle.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
