<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-210" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-5-210</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Administration issues an order directing compliance with a specific requirement or if the Administration denies, suspends, or revokes a license, certificate, or other approval, the order or the denial, suspension, or revocation, as the case may be, shall state the reasons for the Administration's action and shall specify the acts to be done or requirements to be met before approval by the Administration will be given, the license, certificate, or other approval granted or restored, or the order modified or changed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Orders issued by the Administration shall be served on the affected persons by personal service or certified mail, return receipt requested, bearing a postmark from the United States Postal Service.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If notice and opportunity for hearing are required under any provision of this title:<section prefix="(i)">The order or other action of the Administration shall specify, on not less than 21 days' notice, the time and place of hearing or the time within which the affected person may request a hearing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The order or other action becomes effective on expiration of the time for exercising the opportunity for hearing, unless a hearing is held or requested within the time provided, in which case the order or other action is suspended until the Administration, after the hearing or on default by the affected person, affirms, disaffirms, or modifies the order or other action.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration shall conduct the hearing at or near its principal office.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any person aggrieved by an order of the Administration or by the grant, denial, suspension, or revocation of any license, certificate, or other approval may appeal as provided by the Administrative Procedure Act.</section>
  </text>
</law>
