<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-7-702</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to the provisions of this section, the Administration is liable for its contracts and torts ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>702</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the provisions of this section, the Administration is liable for its contracts and torts and for the torts of its officers, agents, and employees in connection with the performance of the duties and functions of the Administration under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The exclusive remedy for a breach of contract or for a tort committed by the Administration, its officers, agents, or employees is a suit against the Administration. No execution may be levied on any property of this State or of the Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subsection (d) of this section does not apply to a tort claim that is asserted by cross-claim, counterclaim, or third-party claim.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A tort claimant may not institute an action under this section unless:<section prefix="(1)">The claimant submits a written notice of claim to the Administrator or the Administrator's designee within 1 year after the injury to person or property that is the basis of the claim;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Administrator or the Administrator's designee denies the claim; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The action is filed within 3 years after the cause of action arises.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A notice of claim under this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">Contain a concise statement of facts that sets forth the nature of the claim, including the date and place of the alleged tort;</section><section prefix="(2)">State the name and address of the claimant;</section><section prefix="(3)">State the name, address, and telephone number of counsel for the claimant, if any; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Be signed by the claimant, or the legal representative or counsel for the claimant.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A claim under this section is denied:<section prefix="(1)">If the Administrator or the Administrator's designee sends the claimant, or the legal representative or counsel for the claimant, written notice of denial; or</section><section prefix="(2)">If the Administrator or the Administrator's designee fails to give notice of a denial within 6 months after the sending of the notice of claim.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, unless the Administration affirmatively shows that its defense has been prejudiced by the lack of the required notice, a court may allow the action to proceed even if the written notice of claim was not submitted.</section>
  </text>
</law>
