<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-621</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>621</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Educational institution" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Public schools, as defined in &#xA7; 1-101(k) of the Education Article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A public institution of higher education, as defined in &#xA7; 11-206.1(a)(2) of the Education Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Licensed dealer" includes, as to Class 1A (dealer) plates provided for under &#xA7; 13-940 of this title, a licensed manufacturer, licensed distributor, and licensed factory branch.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a licensed dealer owns a vehicle that is mainly used in the dealer's business and that otherwise is required to be registered under this title, the dealer may apply to the Administration for the issuance of as many special, dealer registration plates as the Administration authorizes.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as otherwise provided in &#xA7; 15-305.1 of this article and Subtitle 9 of this title, a licensed dealer may:<section prefix="(1)">Drive, under any one dealer registration plate issued to the dealer:<section prefix="(i)">Any vehicle owned by the dealer and mainly used in the dealer's business; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any vehicle in the possession of the dealer, but not owned by him, if the dealer has the consent of the owner of the vehicle to this use; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">As to any vehicle the dealer owns and to which is attached any one dealer registration plate issued to the dealer:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">Lend the vehicle to a prospective buyer, for demonstration purposes; and</section><section prefix="2.">Permit the prospective buyer to drive the vehicle under that plate for a period of not more than 10 days from the date of delivery of the vehicle to the prospective buyer, regardless of the business in which the prospective buyer is engaged or the use to which the vehicle will be put during the demonstration period; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Lend the vehicle to an educational institution that provides accommodations for the deaf and hard of hearing in its driver's education instruction under a manufacturer-sponsored driver's education loan program approved by the Administration.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
