<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-603" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-603</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department and the Administration shall administer the Motorcycle Safety Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Administration, a State or community college, a State university, an agency of a political subdivision, or any other person approved and designated by the Administration may organize and manage a motorcycle safety training center and may offer motorcycle safety courses at those centers that it operates.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Administration may operate a mobile training center to provide courses at various locations in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the regulations adopted under this subtitle, any resident of this State who possesses a valid Class E or Class M driver's license, a Class E or Class M learner's instructional permit, or is eligible for a Class M learner's instructional permit, may enroll in a course.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A nonresident may apply for and be accepted for enrollment in courses authorized under this subtitle; however, the reimbursement provided under &#xA7; 16-605(b) of this subtitle may not be made for a nonresident trainee.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An eligible individual may take a course more than one time, but the reimbursement provided in &#xA7; 16-605(b) of this subtitle may only be paid one time for any individual.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">For a course that is to be reimbursed under this subtitle, a training center may charge a trainee a reasonable course registration fee.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">For a course offered at a training center operated by the Administration, the Administration may collect a reasonable course registration fee established by the Administration.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The courses may be offered throughout the calendar year.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The successful completion of the Administration approved basic motorcycle safety course shall be considered the equivalent of passing the skills and knowledge test required under &#xA7;&#xA7; 16-105 and 16-110 of this title for obtaining a Class M driver's license.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall provide a program coordinator to organize and administer all tasks related to the achievement of the purpose of the Motorcycle Safety Program as provided under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The program coordinator shall be experienced in the motorcycle safety field and shall possess those qualifications as may be specified by the Secretary.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
