<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-807" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-807</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except when driving under a commercial driver's instructional permit and accompanied by the holder of a driver's license valid for the class of vehicle being driven, an individual may not drive a commercial motor vehicle unless the individual:<section prefix="(i)">Has been issued a commercial driver's license that:</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is in immediate possession of a driver's license valid for the class of vehicle being driven.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">It shall be a valid defense to a charge of violating paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection for the driver to provide a certified record either from the Administration or from the licensing authority of the driver's home state showing that the driver held a valid commercial driver's license on the date of the violation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual may not be issued a commercial driver's license until the individual has passed the knowledge and skill tests for driving a commercial motor vehicle which complies with the minimum federal standards established by the federal Commercial Motor Vehicle Safety Act of 1986 (Title XII of Public Law 99-570), and has satisfied all other requirements of that act as well as any other requirements of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The tests shall be prescribed and conducted at the direction of the Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Administration shall adopt regulations to waive the skill test required under paragraph (1) of this subsection in a manner consistent with 49 C.F.R. &#xA7; 383.77.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A commercial driver's license may be issued only to:<section prefix="(1)">An individual who drives or will drive a commercial motor vehicle and who is a resident of this State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Those nonresidents who may qualify under &#xA7; 16-817 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A commercial driver's license may not be issued to an individual:<section prefix="(1)">While the individual is disqualified from driving a commercial motor vehicle;</section><section prefix="(2)">While the individual's driver's license is suspended, revoked, or canceled in this State or any other state; or</section><section prefix="(3)">While the individual holds a commercial driver's license or driver's license issued by any other jurisdiction, unless the individual surrenders that license for return to the issuing jurisdiction for cancellation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A commercial driver's instructional permit may be issued for the class of commercial driver's license applied for only to an individual who has passed the appropriate knowledge and vision screening tests.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The holder of a commercial driver's instructional permit may drive a commercial motor vehicle on a highway only when the individual is accompanied by and under the immediate supervision of the holder of a driver's license valid for the type of vehicle driven, if the accompanying driver:<section prefix="(i)">Is at least 21 years old; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has been licensed for at least 3 years in this State or in another state to drive vehicles of the class then being driven.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
