<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-409" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-6-409</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as expressly provided in this title, this title does not repeal, modify, or otherwise affect in any manner:<section prefix="(1)">Any certificates of indebtedness issued by the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore before June 1, 1956, under:<section prefix="(i)">Chapter 560 of the Laws of Maryland of 1920, as amended by Chapter 242 of the Laws of Maryland of 1929;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Chapter 201 of the Laws of Maryland of 1951;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Baltimore City Ordinance No. 539, approved October 2, 1928;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Baltimore City Ordinance No. 1097, approved July 16, 1930;</section><section prefix="(v)">Baltimore City Ordinance No. 1613, approved April 4, 1951; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">Any other law;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Anything done or any contract, lease, agreement, or other legal instrument made before June 1, 1956, by the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore, the Commissioners of Finance of Baltimore City, the Board of Estimates of Baltimore City, the Port Development Commission of Baltimore City, or the Port of Baltimore Commission under or in connection with any of the laws listed in item (1) of this subsection or any other law; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Any of the powers or duties of the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore, the Commissioners of Finance of Baltimore City, the Board of Estimates of Baltimore City, or the Port of Baltimore Commission under or in connection with any of the laws listed in item (1) of this subsection or any other law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">After the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore has issued and sold enough of its certificates of indebtedness under the laws listed in subsection (a) (1) of this section or any other law to comply fully with all of its obligations, duties, and responsibilities under the contract, dated April 27, 1955, between the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore and the Western Maryland Railway Company (ratified by Ordinance No. 1483, approved May 19, 1955), the authority of the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore to issue or sell any more certificates of indebtedness under the laws listed in subsection (a) (1) of this section terminates.</section>
  </text>
</law>
