<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-602" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-8-602</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Administration shall:<section prefix="(1)">Keep all State highways reasonably clear of brush, snow, and other debris; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Remove from a State highway, as soon as its presence is made known to the Administration, any animal carcass that will impede traffic or substantially endanger the safety of the traveling public.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In removing snow from highways in Garrett County, the Administration:<section prefix="(i)">Shall avoid blocking completely the entrance to any home or business adjacent to the highway; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May not throw or pile snow against any building in any way that interferes with the use of the building by its owner or occupant.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If, in unusual circumstances, the entrance to any home or business is blocked in the course of snow removal, the Administration shall unblock the entrance within a reasonable time.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Farm truck" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 13-921 of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Local state of emergency" means a local state of emergency declared under &#xA7; 14-111 of the Public Safety Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">"State of emergency" means a state of emergency declared under &#xA7; 14-107 of the Public Safety Article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the event of a state of emergency or a local state of emergency, including snow, hurricane, windstorm, or a similar event, the Administration may request that the owner of a farm truck allow the Administration to use the farm truck to assist in snow removal.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The owner of a farm truck may refuse a request made under paragraph (2) of this subsection to allow the Administration to use the farm truck.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The owner of a farm truck may not allow the farm truck to be used under this subsection to assist in snow removal outside of the county in which the farm truck is registered.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Administration shall compensate the owner of a farm truck that is used by the Administration for snow removal.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">This subsection applies only if the farm truck meets the following minimum requirements:<section prefix="(i)">The farm truck passed its most recent inspection under &#xA7; 23-302 of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The operator of the farm truck possesses a valid commercial driver's license and a current medical card;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The owner of the farm truck meets minimum insurance requirements; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The farm truck uses ultra-low sulfur diesel fuel while being used to assist the Administration in snow removal.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The Administration may adopt regulations to carry out the provisions of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
