<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-15-312</section_number>
  <catch_line>A dealer or an agent or employee of a dealer may not permit any individual to road test a motor vehi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>312</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A dealer or an agent or employee of a dealer may not permit any individual to road test a motor vehicle if he knows that the other individual does not have a license to drive of the appropriate class.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A dealer or an agent or employee of a dealer may not make any material misrepresentation in obtaining a vehicle sales contract.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A dealer or an agent or employee of a dealer may not commit any fraud in the execution of or any material alteration of a contract, power of attorney, or other document incident to a sales transaction.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A dealer or an agent or employee of a dealer may not prepare or accept any promissory note or other evidence of indebtedness on a vehicle sales contract knowing that it requires the debtor to pay an amount greater than that agreed on in the written contract for the sale of the vehicle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A dealer or an agent or employee of a dealer may not willfully fail to perform, without justification, any vehicle sales contract.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A dealer or an agent or employee of a dealer may not materially deviate from or disregard, without the consent of the buyer, any of the original terms of the contract.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A dealer or an agent or employee of a dealer may not willfully fail to comply with the terms of a warranty or guarantee.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A dealer or an agent or employee of a dealer may not rent a dealer registration plate issued by the Administration.</section>
  </text>
</law>
