<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-21-310</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>310</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The driver of a motor vehicle may not follow another vehicle more closely than is reasonable and prudent, having due regard for the speed of the other vehicle and of the traffic on and the condition of the highway.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to the provisions of subsection (d) of this section, whenever conditions permit, the driver of every truck, while traveling on a roadway outside of a business district or a residential district and following any other truck or any other motor vehicle towing another vehicle, shall leave enough space so that an overtaking vehicle may enter and occupy the space without danger.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subject to the provisions of subsection (d) of this section, whenever conditions permit, the driver of every motor vehicle towing another vehicle, while traveling on a roadway outside of a business district or a residential district and following any other truck or any other motor vehicle towing another vehicle, shall leave enough space so that an overtaking vehicle may enter and occupy the space without danger.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A truck or a motor vehicle towing another vehicle may overtake and pass any other vehicle or combination of vehicles.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to a funeral procession.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A motor vehicle being driven on a roadway outside of a business district or a residential district in a caravan or motorcade, whether or not towing another vehicle, shall be driven to allow enough space between each two vehicles or combination of vehicles so that any other vehicle may enter and occupy the space without danger.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
