<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-12-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">On application, the Administration shall issue an identification card to any applicant who:<section prefix="(1)">Is a resident of this State;</section><section prefix="(2)">Does not have a driver's license;</section><section prefix="(3)">Presents a birth certificate or other proof of age and identity acceptable to the Administration;</section><section prefix="(4)">Provides satisfactory documentary evidence that the applicant has lawful status;</section><section prefix="(5)"><section prefix="(i)">Provides satisfactory documentary evidence that the applicant has a valid Social Security number by presenting the applicant's Social Security Administration account card or, if the Social Security Administration account card is not available, any of the following documents bearing the applicant's Social Security number:<section prefix="1.">A current W-2 form;</section><section prefix="2.">A current SSA-1099 form;</section><section prefix="3.">A current non-SSA-1099 form; or</section><section prefix="4.">A current pay stub with the applicant's name and Social Security number on it; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Provides satisfactory documentary evidence that the applicant is not eligible for a Social Security number; and</section></section><section prefix="(6)">Presents a completed application for an identification card on a form furnished by the Administration.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Administration shall establish a fee for the issuance of an identification card and for issuance of a duplicate identification card.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A fee is not required if the applicant for the card:<section prefix="(i)">Is 65 years old or older;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is legally blind;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Has permanently lost the use of a leg or an arm;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Is permanently disabled so severely that the applicant cannot move without the aid of crutches or a wheelchair; or</section><section prefix="(v)">Has a physical or mental impairment that substantially limits a "major life activity" as defined in the federal Americans with Disabilities Act.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not commit any fraud in applying for an identification card issued under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person may not commit any misrepresentation in applying for an identification card issued under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person may not commit any fraud in using an identification card issued under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person may not make any misrepresentation in using an identification card issued under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An identification card shall be:<section prefix="(i)">Of the size and design that the Administration requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Tamperproof, to the extent possible.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The card shall contain:<section prefix="(i)">The name and address of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The birth date of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The sex of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A description of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(v)">A color photograph of the applicant taken by the procedure that the Administration requires;</section><section prefix="(vi)">The expiration date of the identification card;</section><section prefix="(vii)">The signature of the applicant; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">The signature and seal of the issuing agent.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">An identification card may be used as legal identification of the individual to whom it is issued for any purpose.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, an identification card issued to an applicant expires at the end of a period of not more than 8 years determined in regulations adopted by the Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If an applicant has temporary lawful status, the Administration may not issue an identification card to the applicant for a period that extends beyond the expiration date of the applicant's authorized stay in the United States or, if there is no expiration date, for a period longer than 1 year.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Nothing contained in this paragraph may be construed to allow the issuance of an identification card for a period longer than the period described in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Administration shall indicate on the face and in the machine-readable zone of a temporary identification card issued under this paragraph that the card is a temporary identification card.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An identification card may be renewed on application and payment of the fee required by this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The identification card shall be surrendered by the holder upon being issued a Maryland driver's license.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The Administrator may issue an identification card to an applicant:<section prefix="(1)">Whose privilege to drive has been refused, canceled, suspended, or revoked; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Who has been issued a temporary license under &#xA7; 16-205.1(b)(3)(iii) of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration may cancel an identification card issued under this section if the Administration determines that the holder of the identification card:<section prefix="(i)">Was not entitled to be issued the identification card;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Failed to provide accurate or required information in the application for the identification card;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Fraudulently applied for or obtained the identification card; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Is otherwise in violation of subsection (c), (d), (e), or (f) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Administration cancels an identification card under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the holder of the identification card immediately shall surrender the canceled identification card to the Administration.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
