<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-21-1123</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1123</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The provisions of this subsection do not apply if the holder of the provisional driver's license is driving while accompanied by and under the immediate supervision of an individual who:<section prefix="(i)">Is at least 21 years old;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has been licensed for at least 3 years in this State or in another state to drive vehicles of the class then being driven by the holder of the provisional driver's license; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is seated beside the holder of the provisional driver's license.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, a holder of a provisional driver's license who is under the age of 18 years may not drive a motor vehicle with a passenger under the age of 18 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The prohibition under paragraph (2) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">Shall be in effect from the date the provisional license is originally issued until the 151st day after the provisional license was issued; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Does not apply to a passenger who is:<section prefix="1.">A spouse, daughter, son, stepdaughter, stepson, sister, brother, stepsister, or stepbrother of the licensee; or</section><section prefix="2.">A relative of the licensee who resides at the same address as the licensee.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A police officer may enforce this section only as a secondary action when the police officer detains a driver for a suspected violation of another provision of the Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A violation of this section is a moving violation for the purposes of &#xA7; 16-402 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Administration receives satisfactory evidence that an individual has violated this section, the Administration may suspend or revoke the individual's driver's license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual may request a hearing as provided for a suspension or revocation under Title 16, Subtitle 2 of this article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
