<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-14-107</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>107</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Falsify" includes alter, counterfeit, duplicate, or forge.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Identification number" includes any vehicle identification number, serial number, transmission number, federal vehicle certification label, engine number, or other distinguishing number or mark placed on a vehicle or engine:<section prefix="(i)">By its manufacturer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">By authority of the Administration; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">In accordance with the laws of the federal government or another state or country.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Remove" includes deface, cover, or destroy.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not willfully remove any identification number of a vehicle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not willfully falsify any identification number of a vehicle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person may not willfully remove any identification number of an engine for a vehicle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person may not willfully falsify any identification number of an engine for a vehicle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Except as provided in subsection (m) of this section, a person may not buy, receive, possess, sell, or dispose of a vehicle, knowing that an identification number of the vehicle has been removed.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A person may not buy, receive, possess, sell, or dispose of a vehicle, knowing that an identification number of the vehicle has been falsified.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Except as provided in subsection (m) of this section, a person may not buy, receive, possess, sell, or dispose of an engine for a vehicle, knowing that an identification number of the engine has been removed.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A person may not buy, receive, possess, sell, or dispose of an engine for a vehicle, knowing that an identification number of the engine has been falsified.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">A person may not, with intent to conceal or misrepresent the identity of a vehicle or its owner, remove a registration card or registration plate from the vehicle.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">A person may not, with intent to conceal or misrepresent the identity of a vehicle or the owner of the vehicle, attach to the vehicle a registration plate not authorized by law for use on it.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">An identification number may be:<section prefix="(1)">Placed on a vehicle or engine by its manufacturer in the regular course of business; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Placed or restored on a vehicle or engine by authority of the Administration.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An insurance company or its insurance producer may buy, receive, and possess a motor vehicle knowing that the identification number of the vehicle has been removed, if the vehicle is the subject of a total loss settlement by the insurance company.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An insurance company or its insurance producer may sell or dispose of a motor vehicle knowing that the identification number of the vehicle has been removed, if:<section prefix="(i)">The vehicle is the subject of a total loss settlement by the insurance company;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Administration will not issue a distinguishing number under &#xA7; 13-106.1 of this article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The insurance company or its insurance producer determines that the vehicle is not rebuildable; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The transfer is to a licensed automotive dismantler and recycler or licensed scrap processor.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An insurance company or its insurance producer may sell or dispose of a motor vehicle knowing that the identification number of the vehicle has been removed, if:<section prefix="(i)">The vehicle is the subject of a total loss settlement by the insurance company;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Administration will not issue a distinguishing number under &#xA7; 13-106.1 of this article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The insurance company or its insurance producer determines that the vehicle is rebuildable;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The transfer is to a licensed dealer, licensed automotive dismantler and recycler, or licensed scrap processor; and</section><section prefix="(v)">The transferee is advised that the vehicle may not be offered for resale to any other person until after the vehicle has been assigned a distinguishing number under &#xA7; 13-106.1 of this article.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
