<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-208.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-208.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to any suspensions or revocations of an individual's license or privilege to drive provided for in this title, if the individual holds a Class A, B, or C license issued under &#xA7; 16-815 of this title or is operating a commercial motor vehicle, the Administration shall disqualify the individual from operating a commercial motor vehicle if the convictions resulted from an offense or offenses that occurred in this State or any other state that would subject the individual to disqualification under &#xA7; 16-812 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Any disqualification imposed under subsection (a) of this section shall be for the period of time provided in &#xA7; 16-812 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If an individual has been disqualified from operating a commercial motor vehicle pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, but that individual is otherwise eligible for a license or privilege to operate vehicles other than commercial motor vehicles, the Administration may issue a noncommercial driver's license to that individual.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Administration may not issue a commercial driver's license to an individual until the disqualification imposed under subsection (a) of this section has expired.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Notwithstanding any law to the contrary, if an individual has been disqualified from driving a commercial motor vehicle under the provisions of &#xA7; 16-812(i) of this title, that individual may not drive a commercial motor vehicle as defined in &#xA7; 16-812(i) until the period of disqualification is completed and the individual is issued a commercial driver's license by the Administration.</section>
  </text>
</law>
