<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-110.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-110.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">For an unrestricted license, each applicant is required to have:<section prefix="(1)">Simultaneously:<section prefix="(i)">A minimum visual acuity of 20/40 in each eye; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A continuous field of vision of at least 140 degrees; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Binocular vision.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the applicant's vision can be corrected by glasses or contact lenses to meet the standards of this section, the Administration may issue the applicant a restricted license, endorsed "corrective lenses".</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration may issue a restricted license to an applicant who has simultaneously:<section prefix="(i)">A visual acuity of at least 20/40 in one or both eyes; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A continuous field of vision of at least 110 degrees and with at least 35 degrees lateral to the midline of each side.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To qualify for a restricted license under this subsection, the Administration may require an applicant to submit a report of examination by a licensed ophthalmologist or optometrist for evaluation by the Administration or its Medical Advisory Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A license issued under this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">Shall be endorsed "outside mirrors each side"; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May be subject to additional restrictions imposed by the Administration, based on recommendations of the applicant's ophthalmologist or optometrist, or any other evaluation that the Administration determines appropriate.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration may only issue a restricted noncommercial driver's license to an applicant who does not otherwise meet the vision standards under this section but who has simultaneously:<section prefix="(i)">A visual acuity of at least 20/70 in one or both eyes; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A continuous field of vision of at least 110 degrees and with at least 35 degrees lateral to the midline of each side.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To qualify for a restricted license under this subsection, the Administration may require an applicant to submit a report of examination by a licensed ophthalmologist or optometrist for evaluation by the Administration or its Medical Advisory Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A license issued under this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">Shall be endorsed "outside mirrors each side"; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May be subject to additional restrictions imposed by the Administration, based on recommendations of the applicant's ophthalmologist or optometrist, or any other evaluation that the Administration determines appropriate.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If an applicant does not meet the vision standards under this subtitle, the Administration may issue a restricted license to the applicant subject to any restrictions the Administration determines appropriate for public safety, including any restriction described in &#xA7; 16-110.3 of this subtitle, if:<section prefix="(1)">The applicant is evaluated and recommended for approval by the Medical Advisory Board; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The applicant successfully completes a driver's training course required by the Administration.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An individual issued a restricted driver's license under this section who has had vision correction surgery resulting in the individual's meeting the requirements for an unrestricted license may:<section prefix="(1)">Apply to the Administration for a corrected license without the vision restriction; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Until the time of a license renewal or issuance of a corrected license, carry written certification from a licensed ophthalmologist or optometrist that the individual meets the vision requirements for an unrestricted license under this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
