<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-639" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-8-639</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Unless approved by the Secretary on application to him, and notwithstanding any other statute to the contrary:<section prefix="(1)">Except for an industrial track spur or siding, a railroad may not:<section prefix="(i)">Construct, reconstruct, improve, widen, relocate, or otherwise alter a railroad grade crossing over a State, county, or municipal highway, except in Baltimore City, or over a private road; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Change the crossing protection equipment at such a crossing; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">A person may not:<section prefix="(i)">Construct, reconstruct, improve, widen, relocate, or otherwise alter either a railroad grade crossing over a public highway or a private road over a railroad; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Change the crossing protection equipment at such a crossing.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary has authority, subject to the provisions of Division II of the State Finance and Procurement Article, to approve the construction or modification of a railroad grade crossing or a change of crossing protection equipment and to impose conditions necessary to insure public safety at the crossing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">No other approval, safety condition, or protective measure may be required by any public authority.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">When an application is made to the Secretary for approval of the construction or modification of a railroad grade crossing or a change of crossing protection equipment, the Secretary, after notice to all parties in interest, including adjacent property owners, shall hold a hearing on the matter if:<section prefix="(1)">The Secretary considers a hearing to be necessary;</section><section prefix="(2)">A hearing is requested by any party in interest; or</section><section prefix="(3)">The proposed change would diminish or discontinue any crossing protection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">With any technical advice from the Administration that the Secretary considers necessary, the Secretary may:<section prefix="(1)">Approve or disapprove the application; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Impose on the person initiating the crossing project, under uniform standards and regulations, any condition necessary to insure public safety at the crossing, including a requirement for the installation of, payment for, and maintenance of crossing protection equipment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">For purposes of this section, the conversion of a private road grade crossing into a public highway grade crossing is a projection of a public highway over the railroad by the public authority taking jurisdiction of the private road.</section>
  </text>
</law>
