<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-413" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-5-413</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Any person who is or becomes a full-time employee of the Maryland Aviation Administration Fire Rescue Service on or before September 30, 1993 shall remain or become a member of the Baltimore City Fire and Police Employees Retirement System. The Administration shall reimburse the City for the employer's cost of the pension coverage.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notwithstanding any public local or other law, the operator of a taxicab authorized and licensed to operate in a political subdivision of this State may, without being required to obtain an additional permit or license from any other political subdivision:<section prefix="(1)">Transport passengers to Baltimore-Washington International Thurgood Marshall Airport from the political subdivision in which the taxicab is authorized and licensed to operate; and</section><section prefix="(2)">After transporting passengers to the airport from that political subdivision, pick up passengers at the airport and transport them to the political subdivision on its return trip.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Administration may not begin construction of the new parallel transport runway, identified in the Airport Master Plan as runway 10 R/28L, until:<section prefix="(1)">The Administration:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">Adopts the proposed noise assistance programs for residential areas within the airport noise zone including, but not limited to:</section><section prefix="(iii)">Implements a pilot program of homeowner assistance in fiscal year 1988; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The State Highway Administration completes construction of the following highway projects required in conjunction with airport improvements:<section prefix="(i)">Hammonds Ferry Road/Poplar Avenue intersection improvements;</section><section prefix="(ii)">MD 170/Poplar Avenue intersection;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Poplar Avenue widening;</section><section prefix="(iv)">MD 176 widenings;</section><section prefix="(v)">MD 176/Hammonds Ferry Road intersection;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Nursery Road/MD 295 interchange; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">MD 3/MD 176 interchange (auxiliary lane).</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The international terminal at Baltimore-Washington International Thurgood Marshall Airport shall be named the Governor William Donald Schaefer International Terminal.</section>
  </text>
</law>
