<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-811</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>811</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An applicant is entitled to receive the commercial driver's license applied for if the applicant:<section prefix="(1)">Passes the examination required by this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is eligible to drive pursuant to the Commercial Driver's License Information System and the National Driver Register;</section><section prefix="(3)">Surrenders any previously issued commercial driver's instructional permit or license; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Pays the fees prescribed by this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each commercial driver's license issued by the Administration shall be identified clearly as to its specific class. A Class M license may be issued in combination with any other class of license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration shall assign an identifying number to each license it issues.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each commercial driver's license issued by the Administration shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be marked "commercial driver's license" or "CDL"; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Include the following information:<section prefix="(i)">The licensee's:<section prefix="1.">Full name and current mailing address;</section><section prefix="2.">Physical description including sex, height, and weight;</section><section prefix="3.">Color photograph or photo-image;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">The date of issuance;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The date of expiration; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any other information required by the Code of Federal Regulations or the Administration.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Before issuing a commercial driver's license, the Administration shall obtain driving record information from the National Driver Register and any state in which the individual has been licensed.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Within 10 days after issuing a commercial driver's license, the Administration shall notify the Commercial Driver's License Information System of that fact, providing all information required to ensure the identification of the licensee.</section>
  </text>
</law>
