<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not knowingly or fraudulently obtain or attempt to obtain a license to drive or a moped operator's permit by misrepresentation.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not in any application for a license to drive or a moped operator's permit:<section prefix="(1)">Use a false or fictitious name;</section><section prefix="(2)">Knowingly make a false statement;</section><section prefix="(3)">Knowingly conceal a material fact;</section><section prefix="(4)">Use a false, fictitious, or fraudulently altered document; or</section><section prefix="(5)">Otherwise commit a fraud.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not display or cause or permit to be displayed any canceled license.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person may not display or cause or permit to be displayed any revoked license.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person may not display or cause or permit to be displayed any suspended license.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person may not display or cause or permit to be displayed any fictitious license.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A person may not display or cause or permit to be displayed any fraudulently altered license.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A person may not possess any canceled license.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A person may not possess any revoked license.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">A person may not possess any suspended license.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">A person may not possess any fictitious license.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">A person may not possess any fraudulently altered license.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">A person may not lend his license to any other person or knowingly permit the use of his license by another.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">A person may not display or represent as his own any license not issued to him.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">A person may not fail or refuse to surrender to the Administration on its lawful demand any license that has been suspended, revoked, or canceled.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">A person may not permit any unlawful use of a license issued to him.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">A person may not do any act forbidden or fail to perform any act required by this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
