<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-12-406</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>406</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If any jurisdiction permits or requires the licensing of fleets of vehicles in interstate or combined interstate and intrastate commerce and the payment of registration, license, or other fixed fees on an apportionment basis commensurate with and determined by the miles traveled on highways in that jurisdiction, as compared with the miles traveled on highways in other jurisdictions, or on any other equitable basis of apportionment, and if that jurisdiction exempts vehicles registered in other jurisdictions under that apportionment basis from the requirements of full payment of its own registration, license, or other fixed fees, the Administrator by agreement may adopt the exemption as to vehicles of those fleets, whether owned by residents or nonresidents of this State and regardless of where the vehicles are based.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Under the terms, conditions, or restrictions that the Administrator considers proper, these agreements may provide:<section prefix="(1)">That owners of vehicles operated in interstate or combined interstate and intrastate commerce in this State may pay registration, license, or other fixed fees on an apportionment basis commensurate with and determined by the miles traveled on highways in this State, as compared with the miles traveled on highways in other jurisdictions, or on any other equitable basis of apportionment; or</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">For issuance of trip permit registration; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">For collection of a fee for any vehicle or combination of vehicles which may be lawfully operated in the jurisdiction if full registration or proportional registration were obtained.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The registration of fleet vehicles under this section is subject to the rights, terms, and conditions granted by or contained in any applicable agreement, arrangement, or declaration made by the Administrator.</section>
  </text>
</law>
