<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-2-607</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>607</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Program" means the Maryland Pedestrian Safety Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Pedestrian Safety Program within the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Program is funded by:<section prefix="(1)">The Highway Safety Operating Program of the State Highway Administration; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Any other moneys accepted for the benefit of the Program from any governmental or private source.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall award grants under the Program to counties, municipalities, and nonprofit organizations to carry out the provisions of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When awarding grants under the Program, the Secretary shall consider any matching fund an applicant proposes to provide.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Counties, municipalities, and nonprofit organizations may apply for grants under the Program for the following purposes:<section prefix="(1)">To educate automobile drivers and pedestrians about methods to increase pedestrian safety;</section><section prefix="(2)">To enhance efforts to enforce State and local motor vehicle laws that protect the safety of pedestrians;</section><section prefix="(3)">To design or redesign intersections to increase pedestrian safety and access; and</section><section prefix="(4)">To enhance safe pedestrian access to transit facilities as defined in &#xA7; 3-101 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Secretary shall establish procedures for counties, municipalities, and nonprofit organizations to apply for grants under the Program.</section>
  </text>
</law>
