<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-625" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-625</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "transporter" means a person in the business of:<section prefix="(1)">Delivering vehicles of a type required to be registered under this title from a manufacturing, assembling, or distributing plant to point of destination;</section><section prefix="(2)">Transporting or moving these vehicles to or from places of business for repair, painting, remodeling, or installing equipment or for the transportation of recovered stolen vehicles by insurance companies;</section><section prefix="(3)">A licensed auctioneer acting on behalf of a seller exempt from the licensing requirements of &#xA7; 15-101(c)(3)(i), (ii), (iii), (iv), and (vi) of this article; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Transporting new or used mobile or modular homes.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Any transporter may apply to the Administration for:<section prefix="(1)">Registration of its business; and</section><section prefix="(2)">On registration, the issuance of as many special, transporter registration plates as the Administration authorizes.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each application under this section shall be accompanied by evidence that the transporter:<section prefix="(1)">Is engaged in the business of transporting new or used motor vehicles, new or used trailers, or mobile construction equipment;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is subject to at least two written contracts under which the transporter is to repair, paint, remodel, or install equipment on vehicles or auction vehicles;</section><section prefix="(3)">Is a licensed inspection station under Title 23 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Is certified by the Interstate Commerce Commission or the United States government to transport vehicles as evidenced by the applicant's certificate of public convenience and necessity and Interstate Commerce Commission docket number.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A transporter may not be registered under this section unless the business of the transporter:<section prefix="(1)">Is equipped to perform the services indicated on the application; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Has facilities adequate for the type of business that the transporter proposes to conduct.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The registration of a transporter under this section expires at the time that the Administration designates when it registers the transporter.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After the expiration of its registration, a transporter may not exercise the privileges granted by this section until his registration has been renewed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A transporter registered under this section immediately shall notify the Administration in writing of any change of address, business name, business designation, or any other information given on or with his last application for registration or renewal.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Transporter registration plates may be used only:<section prefix="(1)">On a vehicle in the possession of, but not owned by, the transporter, if the vehicle is operated to facilitate delivery, inspection, repair, painting, remodeling, the installation of equipment on it, or relocation among storage facilities and points of pickup and delivery, and not for any personal, private, or public use; and</section><section prefix="(2)">On a new or used mobile or modular home, if the transporter submits evidence of:<section prefix="(i)">Proper registration of the towing vehicle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Commercial insurance as required by the Administration.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
