<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-14-105</section_number>
  <catch_line>If a police officer receives reliable information that a vehicle has been stolen, the police officer...</catch_line>
  <order_by>105</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If a police officer receives reliable information that a vehicle has been stolen, the police officer shall immediately report the theft to the Administration and the Department of State Police, unless the police officer has received reliable information of the recovery of the vehicle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An alleged violation under &#xA7; 7-205 of the Criminal Law Article shall be a reportable theft of a vehicle for purposes of subsection (a) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a police officer receives reliable information that a vehicle which he previously reported stolen has been recovered, he shall immediately report the recovery to the Administration and the Department of State Police.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a vehicle titled or registered in this State has been stolen, the owner or secured party may notify the Administration of the theft.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Every person who has given notice under subsection (d) of this section shall notify the Administration of a recovery of the vehicle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Administration shall maintain and appropriately index cumulative public records of stolen vehicles reported to it under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Administration may suspend the registration of a vehicle whose theft is reported to it under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Until the Administration learns of the recovery of the vehicle or that the report of its theft was erroneous, it may not issue a certificate of title for the vehicle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
