<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-8-626</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>626</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to this section and with the advice and approval of the Administration, the legislative body of any county or municipal corporation in this State may designate an industrial crossing across any State highway located within the county or municipal corporation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An industrial crossing may not be designated if it will endanger traffic on the highway.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any person who desires an industrial crossing across a State highway shall apply for designation of the crossing to the legislative body of the county or municipal corporation where the highway is located.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An industrial crossing may not be designated unless the applicant pays or agrees to pay for:<section prefix="(i)">The costs of any improvement required to strengthen or modify the highway for use as an industrial crossing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any damage to the highway that results from its use as an industrial crossing; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The costs of making, installing, and maintaining any signs, markers, or signal devices that the legislative body, with the approval of the Administration, requires to designate the crossing.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If an industrial crossing is designated under this section, the applicant has the exclusive right to use the industrial crossing, subject to any conditions of use that the Administration requires. When using the crossing, the vehicles of the applicant are exempt from all weight limitations and registration requirements imposed by the Maryland Vehicle Law.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The designation of any industrial crossing continues as long as the applicant actually uses the crossing. However, after notice and hearing, the Administration, the Department of State Police, or the police department of the county or municipal corporation where the crossing is located may terminate the use of the crossing on the ground that the crossing has become a danger to traffic because of increased traffic or for any other good reason.</section>
  </text>
</law>
