<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-23-109</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>109</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An inspection station or any of its employees may not issue an inspection certificate for a vehicle without having inspected its equipment.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An inspection station or any of its employees may not issue a repair order certification for any specified equipment without having inspected that equipment.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An inspection station or any of its employees may not willfully issue an inspection certificate for a vehicle the equipment of which does not meet or exceed the standards established under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An inspection station or any of its employees may not willfully issue a repair order certification for any specified equipment if that equipment does not meet or exceed the standards established under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In this section, "fictitious" includes an imitation, counterfeit, or altered certificate or certification.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person may not make, issue, or knowingly use any fictitious inspection certificate or repair order certification.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A person may not attach or cause or permit to be attached to any vehicle an inspection certificate knowing it to be fictitious or issued without the equipment having been inspected for compliance with this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A person may not issue or cause or permit to be issued a repair order certification knowing it to be fictitious or issued without the equipment having been inspected for compliance with this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">On suspension or revocation of its license, an inspection station shall surrender to the Division, at its request, the license and all related material issued by the Division.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">A person may not materially alter or change any equipment of a vehicle for which an inspection certificate or a repair order certification has been issued under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">A person may not willfully violate any rule or regulation adopted under this subtitle relating to inspection procedures and inspection station requirements.</section>
  </text>
</law>
