<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="21-1128" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-21-1128</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Dirt bike" means any motorcycle or similar vehicle that is not required to be registered under Title 13 of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Dirt bike" includes:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Dirt bike" does not include:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Service station" means a place of business where motor fuel is sold and delivered into the fuel supply tanks of motor vehicles.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section applies only in Baltimore City.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not apply to an owner or employee of a service station who is subject to the provisions of the Baltimore City Code prohibiting the selling, transferring, or dispensing of motor fuel for delivery into a dirt bike.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not dispense motor fuel into a dirt bike from a retail pump at a service station.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a person is convicted of a violation of this section, the court shall notify the Administration of the conviction.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (3) of this subsection, on receipt of the notice described under paragraph (1) of this subsection the Administration:<section prefix="(i)">For a first violation, may suspend the person's driver's license for up to 30 days; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">For a second or subsequent violation, shall suspend the person's driver's license for 30 days.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to the provisions of Title 12, Subtitle 2 of this article, a licensee may request a hearing on a suspension under this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
