<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-111</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>111</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to an applicant who:<section prefix="(1)">Holds a learner's instructional permit under &#xA7; 16-105(d) of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Qualifies for a provisional license under subsection (e) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An applicant is entitled to receive a provisional license if the applicant:<section prefix="(1)">Meets the minimum age required under &#xA7; 16-103(c)(2) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Satisfies the learner's instructional permit requirements under &#xA7; 16-105(d)(2), (3), or (4) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">Passes a driver skills or driver road examination administered under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(4)">Surrenders any learner's instructional permit issued to the applicant; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Pays the fee established under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A provisional license shall be clearly identifiable as a provisional license.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual who holds a provisional license may not receive a license sooner than 18 months following the later of:<section prefix="(i)">The date the individual first obtains the provisional license;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The date the individual is convicted of, or granted probation before judgment under &#xA7; 6-220 of the Criminal Procedure Article for:<section prefix="1.">A moving violation; or</section><section prefix="2.">A violation of a provisional driver's license restriction under &#xA7; 16-113(i) of this subtitle; or</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">The date of restoration of an individual's provisional driver's license or driving privilege that has been suspended, revoked, or canceled for any reason.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, the Administration may issue a license to an individual who was otherwise eligible to receive a license at the time a moving violation was committed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding subsection (d) of this section or any other provision of this subtitle, the Administration may issue a provisional license to an individual who has been licensed to drive in another state or country, or by the armed forces of the United States for less than 18 months.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an individual has been licensed for:<section prefix="(i)">Less than 6 months, the individual shall hold the provisional license for at least 18 months before being eligible for a license under &#xA7; 16-111.1 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">6 months, but less than 12 months, the individual shall hold the provisional license for at least 12 months before being eligible for a license under &#xA7; 16-111.1 of this subtitle as long as the individual has not committed an offense as defined in &#xA7; 16-213(a) of this title during that period; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">12 months, but less than 18 months, the individual shall hold the provisional license for at least 6 months before being eligible for a license under &#xA7; 16-111.1 of this subtitle as long as the individual has not committed an offense as defined in &#xA7; 16-213(a) of this title during that period.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An individual who commits an offense as defined in &#xA7; 16-213(a) of this title while holding a provisional license issued under this subsection is subject to:<section prefix="(i)">The waiting periods under subsection (d)(1)(ii) of this section before qualifying for a license under &#xA7; 16-111.1 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Other sanctions applicable to a holder of a provisional license under this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Notwithstanding &#xA7; 16-103(c)(3) of this subtitle, the Administration may issue a license under &#xA7; 16-111.1 of this subtitle without issuing a learner's instructional permit or a provisional license if the individual has been licensed to drive in another state or country, or by the armed forces of the United States, for at least 18 months.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A provisional license is subject to the expiration and renewal requirements of &#xA7; 16-115 of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
