<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-15-305</section_number>
  <catch_line>A license to deal in new vehicles may not be issued to any person unless the manufacturer or distrib...</catch_line>
  <order_by>305</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A license to deal in new vehicles may not be issued to any person unless the manufacturer or distributor of the vehicles is in compliance with the surety bond requirements of &#xA7; 15-205 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A license to deal in new vehicles may be issued only for a dealer in new vehicles who holds a franchise from:<section prefix="(1)">The manufacturer of the vehicles; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A distributor who is authorized by the manufacturer or the manufacturer's authorized importer of the vehicles.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If an applicant for a license to deal in new vehicles seeks to qualify under subsection (b) of this section, the applicant shall submit with the application an exact copy of the required franchise.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a franchise required by this section is terminated in accordance with &#xA7; 15-209 of this title, the license of the dealer shall be suspended automatically unless, before the effective date of termination, the licensed dealer files satisfactory evidence that the franchise has been extended. The Administration immediately shall notify the licensee of the suspension.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, if a franchise issued to a licensee who deals in Class M motor homes or Class G travel trailers is terminated for any reason, the Administration may authorize the licensee to dispose of the Class M motor homes and Class G travel trailers that were in the dealer's inventory prior to the franchise termination without applying for a certificate of title in the dealership's name or paying the applicable excise tax.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The initial authorization period under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph may not exceed 12 months from the date of the franchise termination.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">After the initial authorization period under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the Administration may review each situation on a case by case basis and determine whether a further extension of time to dispose of remaining inventory is warranted or whether the dealer shall be required to take title to any remaining Class M motor homes and Class G travel trailers in the dealer's inventory.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (f) of this section, a manufacturer or distributor may be licensed as a dealer only if the manufacturer or distributor:<section prefix="(1)">Operates temporarily a dealership that:<section prefix="(i)">Was previously owned by a franchised dealer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is for sale to any qualified person at a reasonable price;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Operates a dealership in a bona fide relationship in which an independent person:<section prefix="(i)">Has made a significant investment, subject to loss, in the dealership; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Can reasonably expect to acquire full ownership of the dealership under reasonable terms and conditions; or</section></section><section prefix="(3)"><section prefix="(i)">Is a second-stage manufacturer as defined in &#xA7; 13-113.2(a)(7) of this article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Deals only in Class E (truck) vehicles with a gross weight limit of 10,000 pounds or more, as defined in &#xA7; 13-916 of this article.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A manufacturer or distributor, or a person who is acting for a partnership or corporation that is owned or controlled by or under common control with a manufacturer or distributor, may not sell a new vehicle to a retail buyer.</section>
  </text>
</law>
