<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-24-109</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>109</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Single axle weight" means the total weight transmitted by all wheels whose centers may be included between 2 parallel transverse vertical planes 40 inches apart extending across the full width of the vehicle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Tandem axle weight" means the total weight transmitted to the road by 2 or more consecutive axles whose centers may be included between parallel vertical planes spaced more than 40 inches apart but not more than 96 inches apart extending across the full width of the vehicle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notwithstanding any other provisions of this title, the overall gross weight on a group of 2 or more consecutive axles may not exceed an amount produced by application of the following formula:</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The following table indicates the permissible overall gross weights based upon the above formula:</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The gross weight of any vehicle or combination of vehicles may not exceed the following limits:</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A trailer with metal tires and a gross weight of more than 6,000 pounds may not be moved on a highway.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except on interstate highways, a single unit vehicle with 3 axles, or a combination of vehicles with a trailer less than 32 feet long or a semitrailer less than 45 feet long, either registered as a farm vehicle or carrying farm products as defined under &#xA7; 10-601 of the Agriculture Article that were loaded in fields or other off-highway locations, is permitted an axle load limit tolerance of 5 percent from subsections (b) and (c) of this section, except during harvest time when an axle load limit tolerance of 15 percent from subsections (b) and (c) of this section is permitted for a vehicle carrying the following agricultural products:<section prefix="(i)">Wheat, for the period from June 1 to August 15;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Corn, for the period from July 1 to December 1;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Soybeans, for the period from September 1 to December 31; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Vegetable crops, for the period from June 1 to October 31.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except on interstate highways, a single unit vehicle with at least 3 axles or a combination of vehicles with a trailer length of less than 32 feet carrying forest products that have been loaded in forests or other similar off-highway locations is permitted an axle load limit tolerance of 10 percent from subsections (b) and (c) of this section, except for the period from June 1 through September 30 when an axle load limit tolerance of 15 percent from subsections (b) and (c) of this section is permitted.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Except on interstate highways, a combination of vehicles with a semitrailer length of 45 feet or less carrying forest products that have been loaded in forests or other similar off-highway locations is permitted an axle load limit tolerance of 5 percent from subsections (b) and (c) of this section, except for the period from June 1 through September 30 when an axle load limit tolerance of 15 percent from subsections (b) and (c) of this section is permitted.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any vehicle that uses an auxiliary power unit or an idle-reduction technology unit in order to promote reduction of fuel use and emissions from engine idling shall be allowed up to an additional 400 pounds total in gross, axle, tandem, or bridge formula weight limits.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To be eligible for the additional weight limit allowed under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the vehicle operator must:<section prefix="(i)">Obtain and make available to law enforcement officers written certification of the weight of the auxiliary power unit or idle-reduction technology unit; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">By demonstration or certification, prove that the idle-reduction technology unit is fully functional at all times.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The additional weight limit allowed under paragraph (1) of this subsection may not exceed the certified weight of the auxiliary power unit or idle-reduction technology unit.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
