<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="23-103" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-23-103</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On receipt of an application and a nonrefundable fee established by the Administration from a facility for an inspection station license, the Division shall:<section prefix="(i)">Inspect the facility as to its ability to inspect and correct equipment; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the facility is qualified, issue to it a license as an inspection station.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On receipt of a renewal application and the annual license fee established by the Administration for an inspection station, the Division shall issue the renewal license if the facility is qualified.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The license authorizes the facility to:<section prefix="(1)">Inspect a used vehicle on request of its transferor or transferee and attach an inspection certificate to the vehicle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Inspect the equipment of a vehicle for which a safety equipment repair order has been issued and issue a repair order certification for the vehicle; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Inspect an ambulance on the request of its owner that is required to be inspected under &#xA7; 13-515 of the Education Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Division may:<section prefix="(1)">For cause, suspend or revoke an inspection station license; and</section><section prefix="(2)">On suspension or revocation of the license, require the surrender of the license and all related material issued by the Division.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Division may establish standards by rule or regulation for the licensing and operation of inspection stations.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Administration may not set a fee under this section that exceeds the administrative cost of the Division under this program.</section>
  </text>
</law>
