<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-304" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-5-304</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration may adopt rules and regulations providing for:<section prefix="(i)">The licensing of commercial use airports and public use airports; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The annual renewal of airport licenses.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For an airport license, the Administration may charge a license fee of not more than:<section prefix="(i)">$25 for each original license; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">$10 for each renewal.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the Administration provides for the licensing of these airports, a person may not operate a commercial use airport or a public use airport unless the person has an airport license as required by the rules and regulations of the Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">On receipt of an application for an original license under this section and payment of the required fee, the Administration shall issue the appropriate license, with reasonable promptness, if it is satisfied that:<section prefix="(1)">The site is adequate for the airport;</section><section prefix="(2)">The airport meets minimum standards of safety, which may not be more stringent than those standards, if any, recommended by the Federal Aviation Administration for similar airports;</section><section prefix="(3)">Safe air traffic patterns have been worked out for the airport and for all existing airports and approved airport sites in its vicinity; and</section><section prefix="(4)">The airport operator has complied with the requirements of this title on environmental noise control.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration may issue an airport license or renewal subject to any reasonable condition that it considers necessary to fulfill any purpose of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before renewal of an airport license and at any other reasonable time, the Administration may require that the airport operator provide the Administration with a list, by serial number and description, of all aircraft, based at the airport for which renewal is sought and the names and addresses of their owners.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration may suspend an airport license pending a hearing if it reasonably determines that:<section prefix="(i)">A condition exists that endangers the lives or property of persons using the airport or that endangers the occupants of the land near the airport; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">It is in the interest of public safety and the general welfare to stop use of the airport.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After notice to the licensee and opportunity for hearing, the Administration may revoke or refuse to renew an airport license if it reasonably determines that:<section prefix="(i)">The site has been abandoned as an airport;</section><section prefix="(ii)">There has been a failure to comply with the conditions of the license or renewal;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Because of a change of physical or legal conditions or circumstances, the airport has become unsafe or unusable for the purposes for which the license or renewal was issued; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">The airport operator has failed to comply with the requirements of this title on environmental noise control.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
