<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="24-111" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-24-111</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section and in &#xA7; 24-111.1 of this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"CVISN" means the Commercial Vehicle Information Systems and Network, a motor carrier program managed by the Department, together with other State agencies.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"CVISN transponder" means an electronic device acquired by motor carriers to allow electronic signaling through CVISN.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Police officer" means:<section prefix="(i)">Any uniformed police officer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any civilian employee of the Department of State Police or the Maryland Transportation Authority Police assigned to enforce this subtitle, but only while acting under written authorization of the Secretary of State Police; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any civilian employee of a local government who is:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The driver of a vehicle must stop and submit the vehicle to a measurement or weighing:<section prefix="(i)">When directed by a police officer who has reason to believe that the size or weight of a vehicle being driven on a highway violates this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">When directed by an electronic signal to a CVISN transponder.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The weighing authorized by this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">May be done with either portable or stationary scales; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">In either case, shall be done by methods established by experts in the field of weights and measures and adopted by rule or regulation of the Department of State Police.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If more than 1 statutory weight limit tolerance applies to a vehicle being weighed under this section, the police officer shall grant only the greatest applicable tolerance.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The operation of a vehicle on any highway in this State constitutes the consent of the driver and the owner of the vehicle to the measurement and weighing provided for in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The driver of a vehicle shall obey every sign and every direction of a police officer or an electronic signal to a CVISN transponder to stop the vehicle and submit it to measurement or weighing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a driver fails or refuses to comply with the direction of a police officer or an electronic signal to a CVISN transponder to submit a vehicle to measurement or weighing, the police officer shall have the authority to take the vehicle and its load into temporary custody for the purpose of weighing and measuring.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The police officer may utilize resources specified in &#xA7; 27-111(b) of this article to conduct the weighing or measuring.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In addition to any fine or penalty attributable to the weighing and measuring, or other offense, the driver is:<section prefix="(i)">Subject to a fine and penalty specified in &#xA7; 27-101(l) of this article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Responsible for any actual costs incurred in weighing and measuring the vehicle and its load because of the driver's failure or refusal to comply with the direction of a police officer or an electronic signal to a CVISN transponder.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A sign used to direct vehicles under this section may be displayed only by a police officer who is assigned to enforce this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
