<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-114</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided in this section, if the interest of an owner in a vehicle for which a c...</catch_line>
  <order_by>114</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, if the interest of an owner in a vehicle for which a certificate of title has been issued passes to another person other than by voluntary transfer, the transferee shall present to the Administration the last certificate of title for the vehicle, if available.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, if the interest of an owner in a vehicle for which a certificate of title has been issued passes to another person other than by voluntary transfer, the transferee shall apply for a new certificate of title.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The application for a new certificate of title under subsection (b) of this section shall be accompanied by such instruments or documents of authority or certified copies of them as are sufficient in law or required by law to evidence or effect a transfer of title or interest in or to chattels in such case.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A written assignment of title or interest is not required if the prior owner's title or interest has passed to the transferee as a result of a judicial decree, order, or proceeding.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the interest of an owner in a vehicle for which a certificate of title has been issued passes to a legatee or distributee as a result of testamentary disposition or intestate devolution:<section prefix="(i)">An application for a new certificate of title need not be made until the expiration of the last annual registration in the name of the deceased owner; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The certificate of title need not be submitted to the Administration until the application for a new certificate of title is made.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If title is assigned properly by the personal representative of the deceased owner, a certificate of letters testamentary or of administration issued by a court of competent jurisdiction in this State is sufficient authority for the Administration to transfer the title of the vehicle of a deceased owner.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration may transfer on its records the ownership of a vehicle that has been repossessed by a secured party, if the secured party submits to the Administration a certification that states:<section prefix="(i)">That the secured party has a security interest in the vehicle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">That, on the basis of the security agreement or other lawful basis, the secured party has a right to the possession of and title to the vehicle;</section><section prefix="(iii)">That the secured party has possession of the vehicle; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any other information that the Administration requires.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On submission of the certification to it, the Administration may issue a new certificate of title if it is satisfied that the secured party is entitled to one.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
