<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-21-1124.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1124.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"9-1-1 system" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 1-301 of the Public Safety Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Text messaging device" means a handheld device used to send a text message or an electronic message via a short message service, wireless telephone service, or electronic communication network.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to subsection (c) of this section, an individual may not use a text messaging device to write, send, or read a text message or an electronic message while operating a motor vehicle in the travel portion of the roadway.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section does not apply to the use of:<section prefix="(1)">A global positioning system; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A text messaging device to contact a 9-1-1 system.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Administration receives satisfactory evidence that an individual who is under the age of 18 years has violated this section, the Administration:<section prefix="(i)">May suspend the individual's driver's license for not more than 90 days; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May issue a restricted license for the period of suspension that is limited to driving a motor vehicle:<section prefix="1.">In the course of the individual's employment;</section><section prefix="2.">For the purpose of driving to or from a place of employment; or</section><section prefix="3.">For the purpose of driving to or from school.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual may request a hearing as provided for a suspension or revocation under Title 12, Subtitle 2 of this article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
