<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-21-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title and Title 25 of this article the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Alley" means a street that:<section prefix="(1)">Is intended to provide access to the rear or side of a lot or building in an urban district; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is not intended for through vehicular traffic.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Bicycle path" means any travelway designed and designated by signing or signing and marking for bicycle use, located within its own right-of-way or in a shared right-of-way, and physically separated from motor vehicle traffic by berm, shoulder, curb, or other similar device.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Bicycle way" means:<section prefix="(i)">Any trail, path, part of a highway, surfaced or smooth shoulder, or sidewalk; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any other travelway specifically signed, marked, or otherwise designated for bicycle travel.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Bicycle way" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Bicycle path; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Bike lane.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Bike lane" means any portion of a roadway or shoulder designated for single directional bicycle flow.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Business district" means an area that adjoins and includes a highway where at least 50 percent of the frontage along the highway, for a distance of at least 300 feet, is occupied by buildings used for business.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Controlled access highway" means a highway or roadway to or from which persons, including the owners or occupants of abutting lands, have no right of access except at the points and in the manner determined by the public authority with jurisdiction over the highway or roadway.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Crossover" means a transverse roadway or opening that connects the separate roadways of a divided highway at a point other than an intersection of the divided highway with another highway.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Crosswalk" means that part of a roadway that is:<section prefix="(1)">Within the prolongation or connection of the lateral lines of sidewalks at any place where 2 or more roadways of any type meet or join, measured from the curbs or, in the absence of curbs, from the edges of the roadway;</section><section prefix="(2)">Within the prolongation or connection of the lateral lines of a bicycle way where a bicycle way and a roadway of any type meet or join, measured from the curbs or, in the absence of curbs, from the edges of the roadway; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Distinctly indicated for pedestrian crossing by lines or other markings.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Electric personal assistive mobility device" or "EPAMD" means a pedestrian device that:<section prefix="(1)">Has two nontandem wheels;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is self-balancing;</section><section prefix="(3)">Is powered by an electric propulsion system;</section><section prefix="(4)">Has a maximum speed capability of 15 miles per hour; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Is designed to transport one person.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Expressway" means a major highway of 2 or more traffic lanes in each direction that is designed to eliminate principal traffic hazards and has the following characteristics:<section prefix="(1)">A median divider separating opposing traffic lanes to eliminate head-on collisions and sideswiping;</section><section prefix="(2)">Grade separation structures to eliminate the conflict of cross streams of traffic at each intersection;</section><section prefix="(3)">Points of entrance and exit limited to predetermined locations;</section><section prefix="(4)">Vertical curves long enough to provide long sight distances; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Shoulders wide enough to permit vehicles to stop or park out of traffic lanes.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Intersection" means:<section prefix="(i)">The area within the prolongation or connection of the lateral curb lines or, in the absence of curbs, the lateral boundary lines of the roadways of two highways that join at or approximately at right angles; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The area within which vehicles traveling on different highways joining at any other angle may come in conflict.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a divided highway includes two roadways that are 30 feet or more apart, every crossing of each roadway of the divided highway by an intersecting highway is a separate intersection. If the intersecting highway also includes two roadways that are 30 feet or more apart, every crossing of two roadways of these highways is a separate intersection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Play vehicle" means a vehicle that:<section prefix="(1)">Has two or three wheels;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is propelled only by human power; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Is not a bicycle, as defined in Title 11 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Private road or driveway" means any way or place that:<section prefix="(1)">Is privately owned; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is used for vehicular travel by its owner and by those having express or implied permission from the owner, but not by other persons.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Public bicycle area" means any highway, bicycle path, or other facility or area maintained by this State, a political subdivision of this State, or any of their agencies for the use of bicycles.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Railroad" means a carrier of people or property on cars that are operated on stationary rails.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Railroad sign" or "railroad signal" means any sign, signal, or device placed by authority of a public body or official or by a railroad to warn of the presence of railroad tracks or the approach of a railroad train.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Railroad train" means any locomotive or any other car, rolling stock, equipment, or other device that, alone or coupled to others, is operated on stationary rails.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Residential district" means an area that:<section prefix="(1)">Is not a business district; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Adjoins and includes a highway where the property along the highway, for a distance of at least 300 feet, is improved mainly with residences or residences and buildings used for business.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Right-of-way" means the right of one vehicle or pedestrian to proceed in a lawful manner on a highway in preference to another vehicle or pedestrian.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">"Safety zone" means an area in a roadway that:<section prefix="(1)">Is officially set apart for the exclusive use of pedestrians; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is protected or is so marked or indicated by adequate signs as to be plainly visible at all times while set apart as a safety zone.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(v)">"Shoulder" means that portion of a highway contiguous with the roadway for the accommodation of stopped vehicles, for emergency use, for use by bicycles and motor scooters, and for the lateral support of the base and surface courses of the roadway.</section>
    <section prefix="(w)">"Sidewalk" means that part of a highway:<section prefix="(1)">That is intended for use by pedestrians; and</section><section prefix="(2)">That is between:<section prefix="(i)">The lateral curb lines or, in the absence of curbs, the lateral boundary lines of a roadway; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The adjacent property lines.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(x)">"Through highway" means a highway or part of a highway:<section prefix="(1)">On which vehicular traffic is given the right-of-way; and</section><section prefix="(2)">At the entrances to which vehicular traffic from intersecting highways is required by law to yield the right-of-way to vehicles on that highway or part of a highway, in obedience to either a stop sign or yield sign placed as provided in the Maryland Vehicle Law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(y)">"Urban district" means an area that:<section prefix="(1)">Adjoins and includes any street; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is built up with structures that are:<section prefix="(i)">Devoted to business, industry, or dwelling houses; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Situated at intervals of less than 100 feet, for a distance of at least a quarter of a mile.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(z)">"Wheelchair" means a mobility aid belonging to any class of three- or four-wheeled devices that:<section prefix="(1)">Is usable indoors;</section><section prefix="(2)">Does not exceed 30 inches in width and 48 inches in length, when measured 2 inches above the ground; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Is designed for and used by a mobility impaired individual, whether operated manually or powered.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
