<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-26-407</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section does not affect or modify the procedures established under Subtitle 3 of this title as ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>407</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not affect or modify the procedures established under Subtitle 3 of this title as to violations of parking ordinances or regulations adopted under that subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each police officer who issues a traffic citation to an alleged violator of any State or local law:<section prefix="(1)">Shall file an electronic or written copy of the citation promptly with the District Court;</section><section prefix="(2)">If the person charged acknowledges receipt on a written copy of the citation, shall keep that copy to produce as evidence in court if required; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Shall dispose of the other copies of the citation in accordance with the regulations adopted by the Administration.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">After the copy of a traffic citation is filed with the District Court, the citation may be disposed of only by:<section prefix="(1)">Trial, dismissal of the charges, or other official action by a judge of the court;</section><section prefix="(2)">Forfeiture of the collateral, if authorized by the court; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Payment of a fine by the person to whom the traffic citation has been issued.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section does not prohibit the entry of a "nol pros" or "stet".</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">For each traffic citation issued by a police officer under the police officer's jurisdiction, the chief executive officer of each traffic enforcement agency shall keep a record of the disposition of the charge by the District Court.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the requirements of this section and in consultation with the Chief Judge of the District Court, the Administration shall adopt regulations:<section prefix="(i)">To govern the distribution and disposition of written and electronic traffic citation forms; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">To specify the records and reports required to be made of the disposition of charges.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">These regulations apply to each traffic enforcement agency and police officer with authority to issue traffic citations for a violation of a State or local law.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each police officer and the chief executive officer of each traffic enforcement agency shall make the records and reports required by these regulations.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">No police officer or other public employee may dispose of a traffic citation, its copies, or the record of the issuance of a traffic citation in any manner other than as required by this section and the regulations adopted by the Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to being unlawful, a violation of this subsection constitutes official misconduct.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
