<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-117</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Administration shall keep a record of:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>117</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Administration shall keep a record of:<section prefix="(1)">Each driver's license application that it receives;</section><section prefix="(2)">Each driver's license that it issues; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Each licensee whose license to drive the Administration has suspended or revoked, and the reasons for the action.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration shall file each accident report and abstract of court disposition records that it receives under the laws of this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Administration shall keep convenient records or make suitable notations showing the convictions or traffic accidents in which each licensee has been involved and every probation before judgment disposition of any violation of the Maryland Vehicle Law. A record or notation of a probation before judgment disposition, or a first offense of driving with an alcohol concentration of 0.08 or more under &#xA7; 16-205.1 of this title, shall be segregated by the Administration and shall be available only to:<section prefix="1.">The Administration;</section><section prefix="2.">Other driver licensing authorities;</section><section prefix="3.">The United States Secretary of Transportation;</section><section prefix="4.">Current and prospective employers, as defined in &#xA7; 16-803(e) of this title, of drivers required to hold commercial drivers' licenses;</section><section prefix="5.">The courts;</section><section prefix="6.">Criminal justice agencies; and</section><section prefix="7.">The defendant or the defendant's attorney.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">However, a record or notation of a probation before judgment, or a first offense of driving with an alcohol concentration of 0.08 or more under &#xA7; 16-205.1 of this title, may not be received or considered by the courts until a plea of guilty or nolo contendere is made by the defendant or a finding of guilty is made by the court.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">These records or notations shall be made so that they are readily available for consideration by the Administration of any license renewal application and at any other suitable time.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Accident reports and abstracts of court convictions pertaining to driving an emergency vehicle, if received by a person who was driving an emergency vehicle pursuant to the provisions of &#xA7; 21-106 of this article, shall be segregated by the Administration and shall be available only to the Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Except as provided in this section, an employee of the Administration may not disclose any records or information regarding probation before judgment, or a first offense of driving with an alcohol concentration of 0.08 or more under &#xA7; 16-205.1 of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a charge of a Maryland Vehicle Law violation against any individual is dismissed by a court of competent jurisdiction, a record of the charge and dismissal may not be included in the individual's driving record.</section>
  </text>
</law>
