<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-24-113.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>Unless otherwise provided by federal law, an exceptional hauling permit issued under this section is...</catch_line>
  <order_by>113.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Unless otherwise provided by federal law, an exceptional hauling permit issued under this section is not valid on the interstate highway system, as defined in &#xA7; 8-101(j) of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, the State Highway Administration may issue an exceptional hauling permit for a combination of vehicles that:<section prefix="(1)">Carries farm products as defined in &#xA7; 10-601(c) of the Agriculture Article that:<section prefix="(i)">Are loaded in fields or other off-highway locations; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Are the only load of the vehicle; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Has an axle configuration of not less than six axles and a front-to-rear centerline axle spacing of not less than 50 feet.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A combination of vehicles operating under the authority of an exceptional hauling permit issued under subsection (b) of this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">Comply with the following weight limits:<section prefix="(i)">A maximum of 20,000 pounds gross weight on a single axle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">For any consecutive axle configuration of two or more axles on individual vehicles in the combination, the maximum gross weight specified in &#xA7; 24-109(c) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">A maximum of 87,000 pounds gross combination weight;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Twice each year, submit to and pass a North American Standard Driver/Vehicle Level 1 inspection; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Be allowed a load limit tolerance of only 1,000 pounds for gross combination weight and 15% for axle weights.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">While operating a combination of vehicles under the authority of an exceptional hauling permit issued under subsection (b) of this section, a person may not:<section prefix="(1)">Violate a highway restriction issued by a competent authority;</section><section prefix="(2)">Operate the combination of vehicles on the interstate highway system, as defined in &#xA7; 8-101(j) of this article;</section><section prefix="(3)">Operate the combination of vehicles if the combination of vehicles exceeds any tire weight rating or tire speed restriction adopted under &#xA7; 25-111 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Fail to comply with the terms and conditions of the exceptional hauling permit.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">While operating a combination of vehicles under the authority of an exceptional hauling permit issued under subsection (b) of this section, a person shall have in the person's possession:<section prefix="(1)">The original exceptional hauling permit issued for the vehicle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">For each vehicle in the combination of vehicles, a copy of a valid North American Standard Driver/Vehicle Level 1 inspection report issued within the preceding 180 days that shows no out-of-service violations.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A violation of this section, regulations adopted to implement this section, or the terms and conditions of an exceptional hauling permit issued under subsection (b) of this section shall:<section prefix="(i)">Void the authority granted under the exceptional hauling permit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Subject the vehicle to all weight requirements and tolerances specified in this article; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">For a violation of a weight restriction specified in this section that exceeds 5,000 pounds, subject the exceptional hauling permit to immediate confiscation by an officer or authorized civilian employee of the Department of State Police, an officer of the Maryland Transportation Authority Police, or any police officer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who confiscates an exceptional hauling permit under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall immediately notify the State Highway Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On notification of the confiscation of an exceptional hauling permit, the State Highway Administration shall review the confiscation, verify the violation of a weight restriction, and, if the State Highway Administration determines that a violation did occur, revoke the permit.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An owner or operator of a combination of vehicles may appeal the revocation of an exceptional hauling permit to the State Highway Administrator or the Administrator's designee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On request from the State Highway Administrator or the Administrator's designee, weight and delivery records of the holder of an exceptional hauling permit that are kept in the normal course of business shall be provided by:<section prefix="(i)">The holder of the exceptional hauling permit; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A facility that receives farm products, as defined in &#xA7; 10-601(c) of the Agriculture Article, delivered by a vehicle operating under the authority of an exceptional hauling permit.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the holder of an exceptional hauling permit or a facility that receives farm products does not comply with a request under this subsection, the State Highway Administration may:<section prefix="(i)">Suspend the holder's exceptional hauling permit; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Prohibit a vehicle from delivering farm products under the authority of the exceptional hauling permit to the noncompliant facility.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant for an exceptional hauling permit shall pay to the State Highway Administration:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">$250 for the issuance of a new annual permit or the annual renewal; or</section><section prefix="2.">$30 for the issuance of a 30-day permit;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">$1,000 for the reinstatement of a permit that was revoked under subsection (f)(3) of this section for a first violation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">$5,000 for the reinstatement of a permit that was revoked under subsection (f)(3) of this section for a second or subsequent violation within the prior 24 months.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A fee paid under this subsection is nonrefundable.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, an exceptional hauling permit is valid for:<section prefix="(1)">1 year from the date of issuance for an annual permit; or</section><section prefix="(2)">30 consecutive days for a 30-day permit.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">In consultation with the Secretary of State Police, the State Highway Administration shall adopt regulations to implement this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An exceptional hauling permit is issued under this section at the discretion of the State Highway Administrator.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Highway Administrator may stop issuing or renewing exceptional hauling permits under this section if the Administrator determines that the use of the permits is adversely affecting any part of the State highway system.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The State Highway Administrator shall promptly report to the General Assembly, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, regarding any decision to stop issuing or renewing exceptional hauling permits under this section and the reason for the decision.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
