<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-21-107</section_number>
  <catch_line>A school crossing guard who meets the qualifications in subsection (b) of this section may stop or o...</catch_line>
  <order_by>107</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A school crossing guard who meets the qualifications in subsection (b) of this section may stop or otherwise direct vehicles and pedestrians on a highway or on school grounds to assist:<section prefix="(1)">Pedestrians in the safe crossing of highways at a school crossing; and</section><section prefix="(2)">School vehicles in entering and leaving school grounds.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A school crossing guard is qualified to direct traffic as described in subsection (a) of this section if the school crossing guard:<section prefix="(1)">Is 18 years of age or older;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is under the control of a local law enforcement agency or a county school board;</section><section prefix="(3)">Has completed training to perform any traffic direction duties to which the guard is assigned as prescribed by the law enforcement agency or county school board that has control over the school crossing guard; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Is wearing an appropriate uniform as specified by the law enforcement agency or county school board that has control over the school crossing guard.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not willfully disobey a lawful direction of a school crossing guard exercising the authority granted in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Nothing in this section prohibits a school crossing guard who does not meet the qualifications specified in subsection (b) of this section from assisting a pedestrian to cross a highway, providing the school crossing guard does not attempt to do so by directing traffic.</section>
  </text>
</law>
