<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-808</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>808</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not drive a commercial motor vehicle on any highway or any property specified in &#xA7; 21-101.1 of this article:<section prefix="(1)">Unless authorized to do so under this title;</section><section prefix="(2)">While the person's driver's license or privilege to drive is refused in this State or any other state;</section><section prefix="(3)">While the person's driver's license or privilege to drive is canceled in this State;</section><section prefix="(4)">While the person's driver's license or privilege to drive is canceled by any other state;</section><section prefix="(5)">While the person's driver's license or privilege to drive is suspended in this State;</section><section prefix="(6)">While the person's driver's license or privilege to drive is suspended by any other state;</section><section prefix="(7)">While the person's driver's license or privilege to drive is revoked in this State;</section><section prefix="(8)">While the person's driver's license or privilege to drive is revoked by any other state; or</section><section prefix="(9)">While the person is:<section prefix="(i)">Disqualified from driving a commercial motor vehicle in this State or any other state; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Disqualified from driving a commercial motor vehicle by the United States Department of Transportation.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">While a person is subject to a driver or vehicle out-of-service order, as defined in &#xA7; 16-812(i)(1)(ii) of this subtitle, the person may not drive a commercial motor vehicle on any highway or any property specified in &#xA7; 21-101.1 of this article:<section prefix="(1)">While transporting nonhazardous materials;</section><section prefix="(2)">While transporting hazardous materials required to be placarded; or</section><section prefix="(3)">While operating a vehicle designed to transport 16 or more passengers, including the driver.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a person has been issued a valid commercial driver's license, the person may not drive a commercial motor vehicle on any highway or any property specified in &#xA7; 21-101.1 of this article without the valid commercial driver's license in the person's possession.</section>
  </text>
</law>
