<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-117.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "criminal offense" does not include any violation of the Maryland Vehicle Law....</catch_line>
  <order_by>117.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "criminal offense" does not include any violation of the Maryland Vehicle Law.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsections (c) and (e) of this section and in Subtitle 8 of this title, if a licensee applies for the expungement of the licensee's public driving record, the Administration shall expunge the record if, at the time of application:<section prefix="(1)">The licensee does not have charges pending for allegedly committing a moving violation or a criminal offense involving a motor vehicle; and</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">The licensee has not been convicted of a moving violation or a criminal offense involving a motor vehicle for the preceding 3 years, and the licensee's license never has been suspended or revoked;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The licensee has not been convicted of a moving violation or a criminal offense involving a motor vehicle for the preceding 5 years, and the licensee's record shows not more than one suspension and no revocations; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Within the preceding 10 years:<section prefix="1.">The licensee has not been convicted of nor been granted probation before judgment for a violation of &#xA7; 20-102 or &#xA7; 21-902 of this article;</section><section prefix="2.">The licensee's driving record shows no convictions from another jurisdiction of a moving violation identical or substantially similar to &#xA7; 20-102 or &#xA7; 21-902 of this article; and</section><section prefix="3.">The licensee has not been convicted of any other moving violation or criminal offense involving a motor vehicle, regardless of the number of suspensions or revocations.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Administration may refuse to expunge a driving record if it determines that the individual requesting the expungement has not driven a motor vehicle on the highways during the particular conviction-free period on which the request is based.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Administration shall expunge from its driver record data base the driving record of an individual or a probation before judgment disposition of an individual:<section prefix="(1)">Who has not been convicted of a moving violation or criminal offense involving a motor vehicle for the preceding 3 years;</section><section prefix="(2)">Who has not been convicted of, or been granted probation before judgment for:<section prefix="(i)">A violation of &#xA7; 20-102 of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A violation of &#xA7; 21-902 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A moving violation identical or substantially similar to &#xA7; 20-102 or &#xA7; 21-902 of this article; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Whose license or privilege to drive never has been suspended or revoked.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the Administration may not expunge any driving records before the expiration of the time they are required to be retained under &#xA7; 16-819 of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
