<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-703" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-703</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">As to any certificate of title, issued to a person under this title, the person may not knowingly permit its use by any other person who is not entitled by law to its use.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">As to any registration card, issued to a person under this title, the person may not knowingly permit its use by any other person who is not entitled by law to its use.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">As to any registration plate issued to a person under this title, the person may not knowingly permit its use by any other person who is not entitled by law to its use.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">As to any special plate issued to a person under this title, the person may not knowingly permit its use by any other person who is not entitled by law to its use.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">As to any permit issued to a person under this title, the person may not knowingly permit its use by any other person who is not entitled by law to its use.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person may not display on or for a vehicle any registration card that is neither:<section prefix="(1)">Issued for the vehicle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Otherwise lawfully used on or for the vehicle under this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A person may not display on or for a vehicle any registration plate that is neither:<section prefix="(1)">Issued for the vehicle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Otherwise lawfully used on or for the vehicle under this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A person may not display on or for a vehicle any permit that is neither:<section prefix="(1)">Issued for the vehicle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Otherwise lawfully used on or for the vehicle under this title.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
