<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-12-118</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>118</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as specifically provided by law, all money received under the Maryland Vehicle Law shall be accounted for and remitted to the State Comptroller.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Out of the money remitted to the State Comptroller under the Maryland Vehicle Law, the State Comptroller shall:<section prefix="(1)">Pay or retain enough to pay all refunds of taxes or fees provided for in the Maryland Vehicle Law;</section><section prefix="(2)">Credit to the Gasoline and Motor Vehicle Revenue Account of the Transportation Trust Fund the revenues specified in &#xA7; 8-402 of this article, after retaining enough to pay:<section prefix="(i)">The salaries and other expenses of the State Highway Administration in enforcing Title 24 of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The salaries and other expenses of the Commercial Vehicle Enforcement Division of the Department of State Police as approved by the Department in enforcing Title 23, Subtitle 4 of this article, Title 24 of this article, the provisions of the Tax - General Article on the motor carrier tax, and the provisions of Title 10 of the Business Regulation Article on motor fuel fraud and motor fuel tax fraud;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Funds required, in addition to the funding provided in &#xA7; 13-804 of this article, for the salaries and other expenses of the Automotive Safety Enforcement Division of the Department of State Police as approved by the Department in enforcing Title 23 of this article and Subtitle 6 of Title 22 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The salaries and other expenses of the Department of State Police and other State agencies, as approved by the Department, in enforcing the provisions of &#xA7; 25-111 of this article; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Credit the balance to the Transportation Trust Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, notwithstanding any other law and in addition to any other exceptions provided by law, all costs, fines, penalties, and forfeitures received by or paid to the District Court under the Maryland Vehicle Law shall be collected and remitted as provided in the Courts Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Comptroller shall distribute revenue from the civil fines collected through use of a work zone speed control system under &#xA7; 21-810 of this article to a special fund, to be used only as provided in subsection (e) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, and except for funds received from the Department and the Maryland Transportation Authority for services rendered under agreements with the Department and the Maryland Transportation Authority, the salaries and expenses of the Department of State Police and the State Police Retirement System shall be paid from the general funds of this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, money in the special fund established under subsection (c)(2) of this section:<section prefix="(i)">Shall be distributed first to the Department of State Police and the State Highway Administration to cover the costs of implementing and administering work zone speed control systems; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">After the distribution under item (i) of this paragraph, for each of fiscal years 2013 through 2015 only, $3,000,000 shall be distributed to the Department of State Police to be used only for the purchase of replacement vehicles and related motor vehicle equipment used to outfit police vehicles.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The balance of the money in the special fund shall be distributed to the Department of State Police to fund roadside enforcement activities.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
