<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="21-1104" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-21-1104</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not drive a vehicle if it is so loaded or there is in the front seat so many passengers as to:<section prefix="(1)">Obstruct the view of the driver to the front or sides of the vehicle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Interfere with the control of the driver over the driving mechanism of the vehicle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A passenger in a vehicle may not ride in any position where he:<section prefix="(1)">Interferes with the view of the driver to the front or sides of the vehicle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Interferes with the control of the driver over the driving mechanism of the vehicle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a person may not drive a vehicle on a highway with any object, material, or obstruction so located in or on the vehicle as to interfere with the clear view of the driver through the windshield.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">Required or permitted equipment of the vehicle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Adjustable, nontransparent sun visors that are not attached to glass; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Direction, destination, or termini signs on any passenger common carrier motor vehicle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, a person may not drive a vehicle with any sign, poster, card, sticker, or other nontransparent material on the windshield, side wings, or side or rear windows of the vehicle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">Materials placed on the windshield or rear window, within a 7 inch square area in the lower corner, or on the side windows of the vehicle to the rear of the driver, if the materials are placed so as not to interfere with the driver's clear view of traffic;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Direction, destination, or termini signs on any passenger common carrier motor vehicle; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Electronic toll collection tags placed in the windshield of a vehicle in accordance with the regulations of the Maryland Transportation Authority.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Administration shall adopt regulations to exempt from the provisions of paragraph (1) of this subsection materials placed on the windshield of a vehicle in compliance with security measures required by a federal or State government agency and approved by the Administration.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
