<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-8-725</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this part the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>725</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this part the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this definition, "commercial or industrial activity" means any activity generally recognized as commercial or industrial by local zoning authorities in this State, except for the following activities:<section prefix="(i)">Outdoor advertising;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Agricultural, forestry, ranching, grazing, farming, and related activities, including wayside fresh produce stands;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Activities normally or regularly in operation less than 3 months of the year;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Transient or temporary activities;</section><section prefix="(v)">Activities conducted in a building principally used as a residence; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Railroad tracks and minor sidings.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Commercial or industrial area" means any area along the side of a highway:<section prefix="(i)">That is reserved under a local zoning ordinance or regulation for business, commerce, or trade;</section><section prefix="(ii)">That is not zoned and on which there are located one or more permanent structures devoted to a commercial or industrial activity or on which a commercial or industrial activity is conducted, whether or not a permanent structure is located there, including the area that, along or parallel to the edge or pavement of that side of the highway, extends 660 feet from the outer edges of the regularly used buildings, parking lots, or storage or processing areas of the commercial or industrial activity.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Double-faced" means abutting and facing the same direction.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Federal-aid primary highway" means any State highway that is part of the national federal-aid primary system as of June 1, 1991, or any highway on the national highway system, as designated by the Administration and approved by the United States Secretary of Transportation under Title 23 of the United States Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Scenic byway" means a transportation corridor designated by the Administration as having special scenic, historic, recreational, cultural, archaeological, or natural qualities that have been recognized as such through legislation or some other official declaration.</section>
  </text>
</law>
