<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-313" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-15-313</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A dealer or an agent or employee of a dealer may not use any advertisement that is in any way false, deceptive, or misleading.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A dealer or an agent or employee of a dealer may not by any means advertise or offer to the public any vehicle without intent to sell it as advertised or offered.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A dealer or an agent or employee of a dealer:<section prefix="(i)">May not state the purchase price of a vehicle in an advertisement unless the price is the full delivered purchase price of the vehicle, excluding only taxes, title fees, and any freight or dealer processing charge disclosed in accordance with &#xA7; 15-311.1 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall print the full delivered purchase price in a vehicle advertisement in the largest font used in the advertisement to provide any information related to the price of the vehicle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The advertisement of a leased vehicle by a dealer is governed under Title 14, Subtitle 20 of the Commercial Law Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A dealer or an agent or employee of a dealer may not place on a vehicle an insignia, logo, or other plate that advertises the name of the dealer, unless:<section prefix="(i)">The contract of sale for the vehicle contains a notice of the rights of the buyer described in this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The buyer of the vehicle consents to the placement of the insignia, logo, or other plate on the vehicle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A dealer or an agent or employee of a dealer may enter into an agreement with a buyer of a vehicle to compensate the buyer in exchange for the buyer's consent to the placement on the vehicle of an insignia, logo, or other plate that advertises the name of the dealer.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a dealer or an agent or employee of a dealer places an insignia, logo, or other plate that advertises the name of the dealer without obtaining a buyer's consent, the dealer shall, at the request of the buyer, remove the advertising and make all repairs necessary to restore the vehicle to its original appearance at no charge to the buyer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A dealer or an agent or employee of a dealer may not sell a Class A (passenger) or Class M (multipurpose) vehicle that has a maximum speed capability of more than 25 miles per hour but less than 55 miles per hour unless the dealer:<section prefix="(1)">Permanently affixes an emblem to the vehicle in accordance with &#xA7; 21-805.1 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Informs the buyer in writing that the vehicle may be driven lawfully only on highways on which the speed capability of the vehicle exceeds the posted maximum speed limit for the highway by at least 5 miles per hour.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
