<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-7-705</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>705</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">It is unlawful for any person entering a transit facility or transit vehicle owned or controlled by the Administration for the purpose of obtaining transit service or a train owned or controlled by the Administration or operated by a railroad company under contract to the Administration to provide passenger railroad service to:<section prefix="(1)">Fail to pay the applicable fare charged by the Administration in the required manner; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Fail to:<section prefix="(i)">Pay the applicable fare;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Exhibit proof of payment; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Provide truthful identification.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">It is unlawful for any person to engage in any of the following acts in any transit vehicle or transit facility, designed for the boarding of a transit vehicle, which is owned or controlled by the Administration or a train owned or controlled by the Administration or operated by a railroad company under contract to the Administration to provide passenger railroad service:<section prefix="(1)">Expectorate;</section><section prefix="(2)">Smoke or carry a lighted or smoldering pipe, cigar, or cigarette;</section><section prefix="(3)">Consume food or drink, or carry any open food or beverage container;</section><section prefix="(4)">Discard litter, except into receptacles designated for that purpose;</section><section prefix="(5)">Play or operate any radio, cassette, cartridge, tape player, or similar electronic device or musical instruments, unless such device is connected to an earphone that limits the sound to the hearing of the individual user;</section><section prefix="(6)">Carry or possess any explosives, acids, concealed weapons or other dangerous articles;</section><section prefix="(7)">Carry or possess any live animals, except seeing-eye animals and hearing-ear animals properly harnessed and accompanied by a blind person or a deaf person, and small animals properly packaged;</section><section prefix="(8)">Board any transit vehicle through the rear exit door, unless so directed by an employee or agent of the Maryland Transit Administration;</section><section prefix="(9)">Urinate or defecate, except in restrooms;</section><section prefix="(10)">Fail to move to the rear of any transit vehicle when requested to do so by the operator or a police officer;</section><section prefix="(11)">Fail to vacate a seat designated for the elderly or handicapped when requested to do so by the transit vehicle operator, train conductor, or a police officer; or</section><section prefix="(12)">Except by contract with the Administration, solicit the purchase of any goods or services.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">As used in this section, "elderly and handicapped person" means any person who, by reason of illness, injury, age, congenital malfunction, or other permanent or temporary incapacity or disability, is unable to use transit facilities and transit services or railroad facilities and railroad services as effectively as a person who is not so affected.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The provisions of subsection (b)(3), (5), (8), and (12) of this section do not apply to charter bus service rendered by the Administration. The provisions of subsection (b)(2) and (12) of this section do not apply to excursion train service rendered by the Administration or by a railroad company under contract to the Administration. The provisions of subsection (b)(3) of this section do not apply to any railroad service rendered by the Administration or by a railroad company under contract to the Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except as provided in subsection (f) of this section, any person who violates any provision of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and is subject to a fine of not more than $500 for each offense.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">It is unlawful for any person to obstruct, hinder, or interfere with:<section prefix="(i)">The operation or operator of a transit vehicle or railroad passenger car; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A person engaged in official duties as a station agent, conductor, or station attendant who is employed by:<section prefix="1.">The Administration;</section><section prefix="2.">An entity that provides transit service under contract with the Administration;</section><section prefix="3.">A local government agency or public transit authority;</section><section prefix="4.">A private entity that provides public transit service; or</section><section prefix="5.">An entity that provides transit service under a transportation compact under Title 10 of this article.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and is subject to a fine of not more than $1,000, imprisonment not exceeding 90 days, or both, for each offense.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">This section does not prohibit enforcement of any other State or local law or regulation that is consistent with the provisions of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
