<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-212</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>212</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Administration may conduct:<section prefix="(1)">A driver improvement program, including a driver improvement program designed specifically for young drivers; and</section><section prefix="(2)">An alcohol education program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The purpose of the programs authorized under this section is to provide driver rehabilitation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration shall determine the content of the programs.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If an individual is convicted of one or more moving violations:<section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding item (2) of this subsection, after a hearing as provided in Title 12, Subtitle 2 of this article, as a condition of reinstatement of a driver's license, the Administration may require an individual to attend a driver improvement program or alcohol education program; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A court may require an individual to attend a driver improvement program or alcohol education program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In carrying out an order of the court, a probation officer or health department officer may assign an individual to attend a driver improvement program or alcohol education program.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual who attends a program under this section shall pay, in advance, a fee as provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration shall set a reasonable fee based on the costs of operating the programs authorized by this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The funds collected by the Administration under this subsection may not be credited to the Gasoline and Motor Vehicle Revenue Account for distribution under &#xA7; 8-403 or &#xA7; 8-404 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration may waive attendance at an alcohol education program conducted by the Administration if an individual attends a private alcohol education program or an alcohol education program provided by a political subdivision of the State that is approved by the Alcohol and Drug Abuse Administration and the Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration may waive attendance at a driver improvement program conducted by the Administration if an individual attends a private driver improvement program or a driver improvement program provided by a political subdivision of the State that is approved by the Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Administration shall establish criteria for approving private providers of alcohol education or driver improvement programs provided by a political subdivision of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Upon application for approval to provide the programs allowed under this section, a private provider shall pay an application fee established by the Administration.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
