<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-113" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-113</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to the vision and other restrictions provided for in this subtitle, when it issues a driver's license, the Administration for good cause may impose on the licensee:<section prefix="(i)">Any restrictions suitable to the licensee's driving ability with respect to the type of special mechanical control devices required on motor vehicles that the licensee may drive;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An alcohol restriction which prohibits the licensee from driving or attempting to drive a motor vehicle while having alcohol in the licensee's blood; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any other restrictions applicable to the licensee that the Administration determines appropriate to assure the safe driving of a motor vehicle by the licensee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An alcohol restriction that prohibits the licensee from driving or attempting to drive a motor vehicle while having alcohol in the licensee's blood may, as described in subsections (b) and (g) of this section, include a restriction that prohibits the licensee from driving or attempting to drive a motor vehicle unless the licensee is a participant in the Ignition Interlock System Program established under &#xA7; 16-404.1 of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding the licensee's driving record, the Administration shall impose on each licensee under the age of 21 years an alcohol restriction that prohibits the licensee from driving or attempting to drive a motor vehicle while having alcohol in the licensee's blood.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An alcohol restriction imposed under this subsection expires when the licensee reaches the age of 21 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This subsection may not be construed or applied to limit:<section prefix="(i)">The authority of the Administration to impose on a licensee an alcohol restriction described in subsection (a)(2) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The application of any other provision of law that prohibits consumption of an alcoholic beverage by an individual under the age of 21 years.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An individual under the age of 21 years who is convicted of a violation of &#xA7; 21-902(a), (b), or (c) of this article may be required, for a period of not more than 3 years, to participate in the Ignition Interlock System Program in order to retain the individual's driver's license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Administration may:<section prefix="(i)">Issue a special restricted license; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Set forth the restrictions on the usual license form.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration shall indicate on the license of a licensee under the age of 21 years that an alcohol restriction has been imposed on the licensee under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding the licensee's driving record, the Administration shall impose an hour restriction on a provisional driver's license issued to an applicant under the age of 18.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The restriction under this subsection shall limit the holder of a provisional license to driving unsupervised only between the hours of 5 a.m. and 12 midnight.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This subsection does not preclude the holder of a provisional license from driving between the hours of 12 midnight and 5 a.m. the following day if the licensee is:<section prefix="(i)">Accompanied and supervised by a licensed driver who is at least 21 years old;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Driving to or from or in the course of the licensee's employment;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Driving to or from a school class or official school activity;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Driving to or from an organized volunteer program; or</section><section prefix="(v)">Driving to or from an opportunity to participate in an athletic event or related training session.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The hour restriction and the supervision requirement under this subsection expire on the date the holder of the provisional license turns 18 years of age.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d-1)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding the licensee's driving record, and subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Administration shall impose a restriction on each provisional driver's license prohibiting the licensee from operating a motor vehicle if the driver and each passenger in the motor vehicle are not restrained by a seat belt or, in accordance with &#xA7; 22-412.2 of this article, by a child safety seat.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">It is not a violation of the restriction under paragraph (1) of this subsection if an individual covered by a medical exception under &#xA7; 22-412.2(f) or &#xA7; 22-412.3(d) and (e) of this article is not restrained.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The restrictions under paragraph (1) of this subsection expire on the date that the holder of a provisional license turns 18 years of age.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to the other restrictions provided under this subtitle, the Administration may issue:<section prefix="(i)">A driver's license that is valid only in the State of Maryland to an applicant who has been suspended in another jurisdiction as a result of failing to comply with the financial responsibility requirements of that jurisdiction; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A temporary driver's license that is valid only in the State of Maryland to an applicant for reinstatement of a suspended or revoked driver's license, renewal of a driver's license, or a duplicate or corrected driver's license if, at the time of application:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A temporary license issued under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be valid for 90 days.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Administration shall adopt regulations for the issuance of temporary licenses under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">After receiving satisfactory evidence of any violation of a restricted or provisional driver's license, the Administration may suspend or revoke the license. However, the licensee may request a hearing as provided for a suspension or revocation under Subtitle 2 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration shall impose an alcohol restriction under subsection (a)(1)(ii) of this section that prohibits an individual for a period of 3 years from driving or attempting to drive with alcohol in the individual's blood on any licensee who is convicted within 5 years of any combination of two or more violations under &#xA7; 21-902(a), (b), or (c) of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a circuit court or the District Court orders a licensee not to drive or attempt to drive a motor vehicle with alcohol in the licensee's blood or orders, under &#xA7; 27-107 of this article, the licensee to participate in the Ignition Interlock System Program established under &#xA7; 16-404.1 of this title, the Administration shall have the licensee's driving record and driver's license reflect that the court ordered restriction was imposed, and shall keep records of the order.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">An individual may not drive a vehicle in any manner that violates any restriction imposed by the Administration in a restricted license issued to the individual.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">An individual may not drive a vehicle in any manner that violates any restriction imposed in a provisional license issued to the individual.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">An individual may not drive or attempt to drive a motor vehicle with alcohol in the individual's blood in violation of a restriction.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">A participant in the Ignition Interlock System Program under &#xA7; 16-404.1 of this title may not drive or attempt to drive a vehicle that is not equipped with an ignition interlock system in violation of an ignition interlock system restriction on a license issued to the participant.</section>
  </text>
</law>
