<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-5-705.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "governing body of a political subdivision" means the Baltimore County Council or t...</catch_line>
  <order_by>705.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "governing body of a political subdivision" means the Baltimore County Council or the County Commissioners of Carroll County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a tower located in Baltimore County or Carroll County is equipped with a fully operational replacement obstruction lighting system that meets applicable State and federal aviation regulations, the governing body of that political subdivision may order the owner of a television or radio transmitting tower that is equipped with a pulsating high intensity white light system, as defined in Federal Communications Commission regulations, to cease nighttime operation of the pulsating high intensity white light system.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A governing body of a political subdivision may issue an order described under subsection (b) of this section only after a public hearing conducted by the governing body.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A governing body that conducts a public hearing under this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">Provide reasonable advance notice of the time, place, and subject matter of the hearing;</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide a reasonable opportunity for all interested persons to present oral and written comments; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Notify the Administration at least 10 days before any hearing is held.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The governing body of a political subdivision or a joint board established under Subtitle 6 of this title, shall hold a public hearing under subsection (b) of this section on the petition of at least 50 individuals who:<section prefix="(1)">Reside within the political subdivision and within a 3-mile radius of a television or radio transmitting tower or other structure that is equipped with a pulsating high intensity white light system; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Claim that the nighttime operation of the pulsating high intensity white light system interferes with the quiet enjoyment of their property.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A political subdivision may grant to an owner who is required to cease operation of a pulsating high intensity white light system under this section, not more than 180 days to convert the pulsating high intensity white light system to a system utilizing red aviation obstruction lights or a dual lighting system as defined in Federal Communications Commission regulations, and which are consistent with other applicable State and federal aviation regulations.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The owner of a pulsating high intensity white light system shall pay the costs of the conversion to a red aviation obstruction or a dual lighting system under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
