<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-935</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>935</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Farm area motor vehicle" means a motor vehicle owned by a farmer and operated only on a farm or on a highway within a 10-mile radius of the farm.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Island vehicle" means a motor vehicle, other than a golf cart, operated exclusively on an island that:<section prefix="(i)">Is not accessible by a highway;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Does not have State maintained highways; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Contains less than 20 miles of highways.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If registered with the Administration under this section, every farm area motor vehicle, every island vehicle, and every vehicle that meets the requirements of subsection (d)(1) of this section is a Class K (farm area/island) vehicle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, for each Class K (farm area/island) vehicle, the annual registration fee is $2.50.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration may issue a temporary registration under this section to a vehicle, other than an island vehicle, that:<section prefix="(i)">Is owned by a resident of another state, or a company operating out of another state, if the individual or company is under contract with a Maryland farmer to conduct seasonal harvesting operations in this State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is used to transport perishable commodities directly between a farm and a packing plant for sorting and processing;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Passes a level 1 safety inspection conducted by the Department of State Police; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Is only operated within a 35-mile radius of the location where the seasonal harvesting operations will occur.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A temporary registration issued under this subsection may not be in effect for more than 90 days.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department of State Police shall establish a weight limitation for vehicles registered under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A vehicle issued temporary registration under this subsection shall meet the mandatory minimum security requirements of Title 17, Subtitle 1 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A person may not operate a vehicle registered under this subsection unless the person holds a driver's license issued under Title 16 of this article, or a license to drive issued by the state of the person's residence.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Administration may establish a fee for a temporary registration issued under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An island vehicle registered under this section may not be operated on a highway in the State that is not on an island described in subsection (a)(3) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
