<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="17-209" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-17-209</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">On due notice to the judgment creditor, a judgment debtor may apply to the court that rendered the judgment for the privilege of paying the judgment in installments. In its discretion, the court may order payment of the judgment in installments and may set and modify from time to time the amounts and times of the installment payments.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the judgment debtor obtains an order permitting payment of the judgment in installments:<section prefix="(1)">The Administration shall reinstate any license or registration of the judgment debtor suspended under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">As long as the installment payments are not in default, the Administration may not suspend the license or registration of the judgment debtor under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On notice that the judgment debtor has failed to pay any installment as specified in the order, the Administration shall suspend:<section prefix="(i)">The license to drive of the judgment debtor; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The registration of all vehicles owned by the judgment debtor and registered in this State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, the license and registration shall remain suspended until the judgment is satisfied as provided in this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as provided for in subsection (e) of this section, after default and on due notice to the judgment creditor, if past-due installments have been paid, the judgment debtor again may apply to the court that allowed the installment payments for the resumption of the privilege of installment payments. In its discretion, the court may order resumption of the installment payments as provided in subsection (a) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A judgment debtor under Title 20, Subtitle 6 of the Insurance Article who has been suspended at least 3 times under subsection (c) of this section may not resume the privilege of installment payments unless:<section prefix="(1)">The Fund receives payment in an amount satisfactory to the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The Fund consents to the resumption of installment payments.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The actions of a court under this section are without prejudice to any other legal remedy of the judgment creditor.</section>
  </text>
</law>
