<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-18-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person may not rent a motor vehicle, trailer, or semitrailer to any other person unless the indivi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not rent a motor vehicle, trailer, or semitrailer to any other person unless the individual who will operate the rented vehicle:<section prefix="(1)">Holds a driver's license issued under Title 16 of this article, which license authorizes him to drive or tow, as the case may be, vehicles of the class rented;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is a nonresident who:<section prefix="(i)">Has with him a license to drive issued to him by the state or country of his residence, which license authorizes him in that state or country to drive or tow, as the case may be, vehicles of the class rented; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is at least the same age as that required of a resident to drive or tow, as the case may be, the vehicle rented; or</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Otherwise is specifically authorized by Title 16 of this article to drive or tow, as the case may be, vehicles of the class rented.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not rent a motor vehicle, trailer, or semitrailer to any other person unless the lessor or his agent:<section prefix="(1)">Has inspected the license to drive of the individual who will operate the rented vehicle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Has compared and verified:<section prefix="(i)">The signature on the license with the signature of the individual, as written in the presence of the lessor or agent; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The physical description on the license with the physical appearance of the individual.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each person who rents a motor vehicle, trailer, or semitrailer to another person shall keep a record of:<section prefix="(1)">The registration number of the rented vehicle and, if only a semitrailer or trailer is rented, the registration number of the motor vehicle to be used to tow the trailer or semitrailer;</section><section prefix="(2)">The name and address of the lessee;</section><section prefix="(3)">The number of the license to drive of the individual who will drive or tow, as the case may be, the rented vehicle; and</section><section prefix="(4)">The date and place of issuance of the license to drive.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Any police officer or authorized representative of the Administration may inspect the records kept under subsection (c) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
