<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="21-1306.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-21-1306.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to any individual riding in an enclosed cab.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An individual may not operate or ride on a moped or motor scooter unless the individual is wearing protective headgear that meets the standards provided under 49 C.F.R. &#xA7; 571.218.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An individual may not operate a moped or motor scooter unless:<section prefix="(1)">The individual is wearing an eye-protective device of a type approved by the Administrator; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The moped or motor scooter is equipped with a windscreen.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Administrator:<section prefix="(1)">May approve or disapprove protective headgear and eye-protective devices required by this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">May adopt and enforce regulations establishing standards and specifications for the approval of protective headgear and eye-protective devices; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Shall publish lists of all protective headgear and eye-protective devices that the Administrator approves, by name and type.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The failure of an individual to wear protective headgear required under subsection (b) of this section may not:<section prefix="(i)">Be considered evidence of negligence;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be considered evidence of contributory negligence;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Limit liability of a party or an insurer; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Diminish recovery for damages arising out of the ownership, maintenance, or operation of a moped or motor scooter.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (3) of this subsection, a party, witness, or counsel may not make reference to protective headgear during a trial of a civil action that involves property damage, personal injury, or death if the damage, injury, or death is not related to the design, manufacture, supplying, or repair of protective headgear.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Nothing contained in this subsection may be construed to prohibit the right of a person to institute a civil action for damages against a dealer, manufacturer, distributor, factory branch, or other appropriate entity or person arising out of an incident that involves protective headgear alleged to be defectively designed, manufactured, or repaired.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In a civil action described under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph in which two or more parties are named as joint tort-feasors, interpleaded as defendants, or impleaded as defendants, and at least one of the joint tort-feasors or defendants is not involved in the design, manufacture, supplying, or repair of protective headgear, a court shall order on a motion of any party separate trials to accomplish the ends of justice.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
