<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-646" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-8-646</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as permitted by this section or in accordance with a permit obtained from the Administration, a person may not:<section prefix="(1)">Make an opening in any State highway;</section><section prefix="(2)">Place any structure on any State highway;</section><section prefix="(3)">Change or renew any structure placed on any State highway;</section><section prefix="(4)">Dig up any State highway for any purpose, including the placement of pipes, sewers, poles, wires, or rails;</section><section prefix="(5)">Plant or remove any tree on any State highway; or</section><section prefix="(6)">Place any obstruction or improvement on any State highway.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration may issue a permit for work otherwise prohibited by subsection (a) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Work done under the permit shall be performed to the satisfaction of the Administration and under its supervision.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The person to whom the permit is issued or by whom the work is done shall pay the cost of replacing the highway in as good a condition as before the work was done.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Administration shall require a nongovernment applicant for a permit issued under this subsection who is a developer to submit a performance bond, letter of credit, or other surety acceptable to the Administration.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Administration shall require a nongovernment applicant for a permit issued under this subsection to submit a payment bond, letter of credit, or other surety acceptable to the Administration if:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Administration may apply to the circuit court in the subdivision in which the violation occurred or is threatened for appropriate injunctive relief.</section>
  </text>
</law>
