<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-21-801</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person may not drive a vehicle on a highway at a speed that, with regard to the actual and potenti...</catch_line>
  <order_by>801</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not drive a vehicle on a highway at a speed that, with regard to the actual and potential dangers existing, is more than that which is reasonable and prudent under the conditions.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">At all times, the driver of a vehicle on a highway shall control the speed of the vehicle as necessary to avoid colliding with any person or any vehicle or other conveyance that, in compliance with legal requirements and the duty of all persons to use due care, is on or entering the highway.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Consistent with the requirements of this section, the driver of a vehicle shall drive at an appropriate, reduced speed when approaching and crossing an intersection at which cross traffic is not required to stop by a traffic control device.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Consistent with the requirements of this section, the driver of a vehicle shall drive at an appropriate, reduced speed when approaching and crossing a railroad grade crossing.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Consistent with the requirements of this section, the driver of a vehicle shall drive at an appropriate, reduced speed when approaching and going around a curve.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Consistent with the requirements of this section, the driver of a vehicle shall drive at an appropriate, reduced speed when approaching the crest of a grade.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Consistent with the requirements of this section, the driver of a vehicle shall drive at an appropriate, reduced speed when traveling on any narrow or winding roadway.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Consistent with the requirements of this section, the driver of a vehicle shall drive at an appropriate, reduced speed when any special danger exists as to pedestrians or other traffic or because of weather or highway conditions.</section>
  </text>
</law>
