<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="24-112" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-24-112</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Highway Administration may issue a permit allowing an oversized vehicle to use the highways in this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For each permit issued under this subsection, the State Highway Administration shall charge a fee of not less than $30.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Highway Administration may issue a permit allowing an overweight vehicle to use the highways in this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For each permit issued under this subsection, the State Highway Administration shall charge a fee of not less than:<section prefix="(i)">$30 for the first 45 tons (90,000 pounds) or less of gross weight of the vehicle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">$5 for each additional ton (2,000 pounds) or part of a ton in excess of 45 tons.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary is authorized to promulgate rules and regulations for the purpose of establishing a schedule of fees for permits issued under this section using dollar amounts that will recover but not exceed the administrative costs associated with issuance and use of the permits, including compliance monitoring.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each permit issued under this section shall specify:<section prefix="(1)">The maximum size or weight permitted;</section><section prefix="(2)">The route to be followed; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The date and hour on which the trip is to be made.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not violate any condition of a permit issued under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not move an oversized or overweight load which requires a permit under this section without first obtaining the permit and having the permit in the person's possession.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
