<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-601" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-7-601</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated:<section prefix="(1)">"Accredited representative" includes the representative of any labor organization, or its successor, authorized to act for the employees described in subsection (b) of this section. As of December 31, 1983, "accredited representative" included only:<section prefix="(i)">The Amalgamated Transit Union, Division No. 1300;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Office and Professional Employees International Union, Local 2; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees, Local 1859, Council 67.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">"Employees" means those employees who are validly represented by an accredited representative.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Administration shall bargain collectively and enter into written collective bargaining agreements as to wages, salaries, hours, working conditions, and pension and retirement provisions with the accredited representatives of its employees who are employed in:<section prefix="(1)">Job classifications that on December 31, 1983, were included in recognized bargaining units pursuant to agreements in force on that date between the Administration and an accredited representative identified in subsection (a)(1)(i), (ii), or (iii) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">New or revised classifications comparable to those described in paragraph (1) of this subsection, provided, however, that supervisory, managerial, professional, confidential, including secretaries or assistants to administrative department and section heads or to other management staff personnel, and engineering classifications shall not be included.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Administration may provide its employees with automatic cost-of-living wage adjustments in accordance with any applicable formula in a collective bargaining agreement between the parties, provided that the aggregate of automatic cost-of-living wage adjustments provided to any employee in any contract year does not exceed 5 percent of the employee's base wage rate as that base wage rate existed immediately prior to commencement of the contract year.</section>
  </text>
</law>
