<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person may not drive a motor vehicle on any highway or on any property specified in &#xA7; 21-101.1 of...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not drive a motor vehicle on any highway or on any property specified in &#xA7; 21-101.1 of this article while the person's license or privilege to drive is refused in this State or any other state.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not drive a motor vehicle on any highway or on any property specified in &#xA7; 21-101.1 of this article while the person's license or privilege to drive is canceled in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not drive a motor vehicle on any highway or on any property specified in &#xA7; 21-101.1 of this article while the person's license or privilege to drive is suspended in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person may not drive a motor vehicle on any highway or on any property specified in &#xA7; 21-101.1 of this article while the person's license or privilege to drive is revoked in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person may not drive a motor vehicle on any highway or on any property specified in &#xA7; 21-101.1 of this article while the person's license issued by any other state is canceled.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person may not drive a motor vehicle on any highway or on any property specified in &#xA7; 21-101.1 of this article while the person's license issued by any other state is suspended.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A person may not drive a motor vehicle on any highway or on any property specified in &#xA7; 21-101.1 of this article while the person's license issued by any other state is revoked.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A person may not drive a motor vehicle on any highway or on any property specified in &#xA7; 21-101.1 of this article while the person's license or privilege to drive is suspended under &#xA7; 17-106, &#xA7; 26-204, &#xA7; 26-206, or &#xA7; 27-103 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only to a person whose license or privilege to drive is suspended under the traffic laws or regulations of another state for:<section prefix="(i)">Failure to comply with a notice to appear in a court of that state contained in a traffic citation issued to the person; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Failure to pay a fine for a violation of any traffic laws or regulations of that state.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not drive a motor vehicle on any highway or on any property specified in &#xA7; 21-101.1 of this article while the person's license or privilege to drive is suspended under the traffic laws or regulations of any other state as described in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, any individual who violates a provision of this section shall be assessed the points as provided for in &#xA7; 16-402(a)(31) of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any individual who violates a provision of subsection (h) or subsection (i) of this section shall be assessed the points as provided for in &#xA7; 16-402(a)(12) of this title.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
