<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-507" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-8-507</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Municipality" means any municipal corporation in this State that is entitled to receive federal-aid urban funds.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Urban area" means an area with boundaries fixed by the Administration that includes and is adjacent to a municipality or other urban place having a population of at least 5,000, as determined by the latest federal census.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a County Highway Construction Fund in the Transportation Trust Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">There is a Municipality-Urban Area Highway Construction Fund in the Transportation Trust Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In accordance with this section and Part II of Title 7, Subtitle 2 of the State Finance and Procurement Article, and with the consent of the Secretary, the Administration in any fiscal year may allocate from the Transportation Trust Fund:<section prefix="(1)">To the County Highway Construction Fund, an amount equal to the amount of federal-aid secondary highway funds that:<section prefix="(i)">Are available to the Administration from the Federal Highway Administration;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Are allocated by the Administration to the counties; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The counties later release to the Administration for use on the State highway system; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">To the Municipality-Urban Area Highway Construction Fund, with the approval of the releasing municipalities or urban areas, an amount equal to the amount of federal-aid urban highway funds that:<section prefix="(i)">Are available to the Administration from the Federal Highway Administration;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Are allocated by the Administration to the municipalities and urban areas; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The municipalities or urban areas later release to the Administration for use on the State highway system.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration may apportion the amounts in each fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each county, municipality, or urban area that participates in a program under this section shall furnish matching construction amounts.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The County Highway Construction Fund, the Municipality-Urban Area Highway Construction Fund, and the matching amounts required by this section may be spent only for highway construction and reconstruction under rules and regulations adopted by the Administration.</section>
  </text>
</law>
