<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-107</section_number>
  <catch_line>Each certificate of title issued for a vehicle by the Administration shall contain:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>107</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each certificate of title issued for a vehicle by the Administration shall contain:<section prefix="(1)">The date issued;</section><section prefix="(2)">The name and Maryland address of the owner of the vehicle;</section><section prefix="(3)">The names and addresses of all secured parties, in the order of their priority as shown on the application or, if the application is based on a certificate of title, as shown on the certificate;</section><section prefix="(4)">The title number assigned to the vehicle;</section><section prefix="(5)">A description of the vehicle including, to the extent that the information exists, its make, model, year, vehicle identification number, and type of body;</section><section prefix="(6)">In the case of a vehicle returned to the manufacturer or factory branch under Title 14, Subtitle 15 of the Commercial Law Article and subsequently retitled in the State, a permanent notation that informs all subsequent transferees that:<section prefix="(i)">Prior to its sale to the transferee, the vehicle was returned to the manufacturer or factory branch under the Automotive Warranty Enforcement Act; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A history of the vehicle is on file with the Administration;</section></section><section prefix="(7)">The classification or weight for which the vehicle is registered; and</section><section prefix="(8)">Any other information that the Administration determines.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The certificate of title:<section prefix="(1)">Shall contain forms for:<section prefix="(i)">Assignment and warranty of title by the owner; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Assignment and warranty of title by a dealer; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">May contain forms for:<section prefix="(i)">An application for a certificate of title by a transferee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The naming of secured parties; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The assignment or release of security interests.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A certificate of title issued by the Administration is prima facie evidence of the facts appearing on it.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A certificate of title for a vehicle is not subject to garnishment, attachment, or execution, but this subsection does not prevent a lawful levy on the vehicle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
