<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="17-106" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-17-106</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If the required security for any vehicle lapses at any time, the registration of that vehicle:<section prefix="(1)">Is suspended automatically as of the date of the lapse effective not later than 60 days after notification to the Administration that the lapse has occurred; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Remains suspended until:<section prefix="(i)">The required security is replaced and the vehicle owner submits evidence of replaced security on a form as prescribed by the Administration and certified by an insurer or insurance producer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any uninsured motorist penalty fee assessed is paid to the Administration.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, each insurer or other provider of required security immediately shall notify the Administration electronically of those terminations or other lapses that are final.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each insurer or other provider of required security for a vehicle registered as a Class B (for hire) vehicle under Title 13 of this article shall notify the Administration within 45 days of a termination or other lapse that is final and occurs anytime after the required security is issued or provided.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">On receipt of a notice under subsection (b) of this section, the Administration shall make a reasonable effort to notify the owner of the vehicle that his registration has been suspended.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 48 hours after an owner is notified by the Administration of the suspension of registration, the owner shall surrender all evidences of that registration to the Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the owner fails to surrender the evidences of registration within the 48-hour period, the Administration:<section prefix="(i)">Shall attempt to recover from the owner the evidences of registration; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May suspend his license to drive until he returns to the Motor Vehicle Administration the evidences of registration.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Administration may enter into contracts with private parties to procure the services of independent agents to assist in the recovery of the evidences of registration as authorized in paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In addition to any other penalty provided for in the Maryland Vehicle Law, if the required security for a vehicle terminates or otherwise lapses during its registration year, the Administration may assess the owner of the vehicle with a penalty of $150 for each vehicle without the required security for a period of 1 to 30 days. If a fine is assessed, beginning on the 31st day the fine shall increase by a rate of $7 for each day.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Each period during which the required security for a vehicle terminates or otherwise lapses shall constitute a separate violation.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The penalty imposed under this subsection may not exceed $2,500 for each violation in a 12-month period.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A penalty assessed under this subsection shall be paid as follows:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For the fiscal year beginning July 1, 2001, the percentage of the penalties specified under subparagraph (i)1 of this paragraph shall be allocated among the Vehicle Theft Prevention Fund, the Motor Vehicle Registration Enforcement Fund, the School Bus Safety Enforcement Fund, the Transportation Trust Fund, and the General Fund as follows:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">For the fiscal year beginning July 1, 2002, the percentage of the penalties specified under subparagraph (i)1 of this paragraph shall be allocated among the Vehicle Theft Prevention Fund, the Maryland Automobile Insurance Fund, the Motor Vehicle Registration Enforcement Fund, the School Bus Safety Enforcement Fund, and the General Fund as follows:</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">For each fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2003, the percentage of the penalties specified under subparagraph (i)1 of this paragraph shall be allocated among the School Bus Safety Enforcement Fund, the Vehicle Theft Prevention Fund, the Maryland Automobile Insurance Fund, and the General Fund as follows:</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">For each fiscal year beginning on July 1, 2013, the percentage of the penalties specified under subparagraph (i)1 of this paragraph shall be allocated among the School Bus Safety Enforcement Fund, the Vehicle Theft Prevention Fund, the Maryland Automobile Insurance Fund, and the General Fund as follows:</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">For each fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2014, the percentage of the penalties specified under subparagraph (i)1 of this paragraph shall be allocated among the School Bus Safety Enforcement Fund, the Vehicle Theft Prevention Fund, the Maryland Automobile Insurance Fund, and the General Fund as follows:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the Administration assesses a vehicle owner or co-owner with a penalty under this subsection, the Administration may not take any of the following actions until the penalty is paid:<section prefix="(i)">Reinstate a registration suspended under this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Except for a temporary registration as provided under &#xA7; 13-602(a)(2) of this article, issue a new registration for any vehicle that is owned or co-owned by that person and is titled after the violation date; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Renew a registration for a vehicle that is owned or co-owned by that person.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this paragraph, "family member" means any individual whose relationship to the vehicle owner is one of those listed under &#xA7; 13-810(c)(1) of this article as being exempt from paying the excise tax imposed on the transfer of a vehicle.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The monetary penalties provided in this subsection may not be avoided by transferring title to the vehicle.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Regardless of whether money or other valuable consideration is involved in the transfer, if title to a vehicle is transferred by an individual who has violated this subtitle to a family member, any suspension of the vehicle's registration that occurred before the transfer shall continue as if no transfer had occurred and a new registration may not be issued until the penalty fee is paid.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">An amount equal to the monetary penalties paid to the Administration under paragraph (2) of this subsection may be used by the Administration only for the enforcement of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">From the amount distributed to the Administration under subsection (e)(2)(i)2 of this section, expenditures to fund contracts entered into under subsection (d)(3) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">May not exceed $1,000,000 in any fiscal year; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May be made only:<section prefix="(i)">Pursuant to an appropriation approved by the General Assembly in the annual State budget; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Through the budget amendment procedure provided for in &#xA7; 7-209 of the State Finance and Procurement Article, provided that:</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
