<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-113.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>113.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Completed vehicle" means a two-stage vehicle that does not require any additional manufacturing operation to perform its intended function, except for the addition of readily attachable components or minor finishing operations.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"First-stage manufacturer" means:<section prefix="(i)">Any person who manufactures an incomplete vehicle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any person who distributes an incomplete vehicle of that manufacturer; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any dealer who has a franchise for the particular make of the incomplete vehicle of that manufacturer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Incomplete vehicle" means an assemblage that:<section prefix="(i)">Consists of at least a frame and chassis structure, power train, steering system, and braking system, to the extent that those systems are to be a part of the completed vehicle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Requires additional manufacturing operations, other than the addition of readily attachable components or minor finishing operations, to become a completed vehicle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Minor finishing operations" includes painting, upholstering, or other cosmetic modifications.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Readily attachable components" includes any mirror, extra light, or tire and rim assembly.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Second-stage manufacturer" means:<section prefix="(i)">A person who performs manufacturing operations on an incomplete vehicle so that it becomes a completed vehicle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any person who distributes a completed vehicle of that manufacturer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Two-stage vehicle" means a motor vehicle that requires manufacturing operations performed by two separate manufacturers to produce a completed vehicle capable of performing its intended function.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Transfers of two-stage vehicles by manufacturers shall be made as provided in subsections (c) and (d) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">At the time that any first-stage manufacturer transfers to a second-stage manufacturer a new incomplete vehicle that is to be sold or registered in this State, the first-stage manufacturer shall give the second-stage manufacturer a manufacturer's certificate of origin for the incomplete vehicle, assigned to the second-stage manufacturer by the first-stage manufacturer.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">At the time that any second-stage manufacturer transfers to a dealer a new completed vehicle that is to be sold or registered in this State, the second-stage manufacturer shall give the dealer the manufacturer's certificates of origin issued by both the second-stage manufacturer and the first-stage manufacturer and assigned to the dealer by the second-stage manufacturer.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Transfers of new completed vehicles by dealers shall be made as provided in subsections (f), (g), and (h) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Each dealer who holds a new completed vehicle for sale shall have a franchise in this State for the particular make of at least one stage of that vehicle.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If the dealer's franchise is for the make of only the first stage of the completed vehicle, the dealer may transfer the vehicle, without obtaining a certificate of title, by executing an assignment and warranty of title accompanied by the certificates of origin issued by the first-stage manufacturer and the second-stage manufacturer.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">If the dealer's franchise is for the make of only the second stage of the completed vehicle, the dealer may transfer the vehicle, without obtaining a certificate of title, by executing an assignment and warranty of title accompanied by the certificates of origin issued by the first-stage manufacturer and the second-stage manufacturer, if the certificate of origin issued by the first-stage manufacturer is assigned to the second-stage manufacturer.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A dealer shall include in a contract for sale of a completed vehicle a notice in writing of:<section prefix="(1)">The make and year of the first stage; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The make, model, and year of the second stage.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
