<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="24-106.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-24-106.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section:<section prefix="(1)">"Loose material" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Dirt, sand, gravel, wood chips, or other material that can blow, fall, or spill from a vehicle as a result of movement or of exposure to air, wind, or weather; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any other kind of material that can blow, fall, or spill, as specified in rules and regulations adopted by the Administrator; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">"Loose material" does not include agricultural products, including sod, in their natural state.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not, in violation of this section, carry any loose material in any vehicle on or across any highway in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not, in violation of this section, load any loose material for carrying in any vehicle on or across any highway in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of subsection (e) of this section, the bed of the vehicle carrying a load of loose material shall be fully enclosed:<section prefix="(i)">On both sides, by sideboards or sidepanels;</section><section prefix="(ii)">On the front, by a board or panel or by the cab of the vehicle; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">On the rear, by a tailgate, board, or panel.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The enclosures required by paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be constructed so as to prevent any part of the load from blowing, falling, or spilling out of the vehicle.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">No part of the load touching any of these enclosures may be within 6 inches of the top of the part of the enclosure that it touches, unless the load is covered with a firmly secured canvas or similar type covering.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If the vehicle manufacturer's original design specifications for bed enclosures have been altered to increase the vehicle's load capacity, no part of the load touching any of these enclosures may be within 6 inches of the top of the part of the enclosure that it touches and the highest point of the load may not be higher than any of these enclosures, unless the load is covered with a canvas or other type cover approved by the Administration that is secured as provided in subsection (e)(3) of this section.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This subsection does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">Any load-carrying vehicle with a compartment that fully encloses the load; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A vehicle in which the load is suitably covered or secured by other means that prevent the escape of the loose material.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The provisions of this subsection do not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">Any Class K (farm area) vehicle as defined in &#xA7; 13-935 of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any Class E (truck) vehicle registered or capable of being registered under &#xA7; 13-917 of this article if the vehicle manufacturer's original design specifications for bed enclosures have not been altered to increase the vehicle's load capacity;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any construction vehicle working within the confines of a public works construction project site as outlined in the construction project's plans and specifications, provided the distance traveled does not exceed 1 mile or the distance specified in an extension granted under subsection (g) of this section;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any construction vehicle or mining equipment while crossing a highway between construction or mining sites;</section><section prefix="(v)">Any Class G (trailer) vehicle registered or capable of being registered under &#xA7; 13-927 of this article, provided no part of the load is higher than 6 inches below the top of any of the enclosures required under subsection (d)(1) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">Within the Port of Baltimore for a distance not to exceed 1 mile, any vehicle carrying a load of loose material between a stockpile or storage facility and a vessel docked at the port.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A vehicle carrying a load of loose material shall have its bed fully enclosed on the top by a canvas or other type cover approved by the Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any cover required under this section shall be secured in a manner to prevent:<section prefix="(i)">Any part of the load from blowing, falling, or spilling out of the vehicle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The cover from blowing off the vehicle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to any construction vehicle or mining equipment that:<section prefix="(i)">Is moving between construction barricades on a public works project; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Only is crossing a highway.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A vehicle used for carrying loose material may not be operated on any highway unless:<section prefix="(i)">All spillage from loading loose material is removed from the nonload-carrying parts of the vehicle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Whether the vehicle is loaded or empty, the tailgate is closed securely to prevent spillage of a load or of any residue;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The bed does not have any holes, cracks, or openings through which loose material can escape; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">After unloading loose material, all residue is removed from the nonload-carrying parts of the vehicle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Upon application by the supervisor of a construction project of the Department, the Department may grant a reasonable extension of the 1-mile limitation established in subsection (e)(1)(iii) of this section if the Department determines that the extension request meets the criteria developed under paragraph (2) of this subsection and the provisions of paragraph (3) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Department shall adopt regulations establishing criteria for granting an extension under this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In adopting regulations under this subsection, the Administration shall consider:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An extension granted under this subsection may not exceed the confines of the Department's construction project.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
