<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="21-803" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-21-803</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If, on the basis of an engineering and traffic investigation, a local authority determines that any maximum speed limit specified in this subtitle is greater or less than reasonable or safe under existing conditions on any part of a highway in its jurisdiction, it may establish a reasonable and safe maximum speed limit for that part of the highway, which may:<section prefix="(i)">Decrease the limit at an intersection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Increase the limit in an urban district to not more than 50 miles an hour;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Decrease the limit in an urban district; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Decrease the limit outside an urban district to not less than 25 miles an hour.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An engineering and traffic investigation is not required to conform a posted maximum speed limit in effect on December 31, 1974, to a different limit specified in &#xA7; 21-801.1(b) of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In school zones designated and posted by the local authorities of any county:<section prefix="(1)">The county may decrease the maximum speed limit to 15 miles per hour during school hours, provided the county pays the cost of placing and maintaining the necessary signs; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Any municipality within each county may decrease the maximum speed limit in a school zone within the municipality to 15 miles per hour during school hours, provided the municipality pays the cost of placing and maintaining the necessary signs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An altered maximum speed limit established under this section is effective when posted on appropriate signs giving notice of the limit.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except in Baltimore City, any alteration by a local authority of a maximum speed limit on a part or extension of a State highway is not effective until it is approved by the State Highway Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a local authority determines that any maximum speed limit specified in this subtitle is greater than reasonable or safe in an alley in its jurisdiction, the local authority may establish a reasonable and safe maximum speed limit for the alley.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The local authority shall post a speed limit established under this subsection on appropriate signs giving notice of the speed limit.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
