<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-110.3</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Administration may only issue a restricted Class C noncommercial driver's license to an applican...</catch_line>
  <order_by>110.3</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Administration may only issue a restricted Class C noncommercial driver's license to an applicant who does not otherwise meet the vision standards under &#xA7; 16-110.1 of this subtitle but:<section prefix="(1)">Has simultaneously:<section prefix="(i)">A visual acuity of worse than 20/70, but no worse than 20/100, in one or both eyes as determined by the Administration in consultation with the Medical Advisory Board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A continuous field of vision of at least 110 degrees and with at least 35 degrees lateral to the midline of each side; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Is recommended for consideration for licensure by the applicant's licensed ophthalmologist or optometrist in accordance with subsection (b) of this section and regulations of the Administration concerning limited vision licenses.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The ophthalmologist's or optometrist's recommendation for an applicant seeking a license under this section shall be based on the best standard spectacle or contact lens correction in the applicant's better eye.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration shall refer any application for a license under this section to the Medical Advisory Board appointed under &#xA7; 16-118 of this subtitle for review.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless the Medical Advisory Board determines that it can make a favorable recommendation to the Administration based on the record before it, the Board shall offer the applicant an opportunity to appear before the Board to present medical information pertinent to the Board's review.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An applicant who chooses to appear before the Medical Advisory Board may be accompanied by the applicant's ophthalmologist or optometrist or by any other individual to assist the applicant in presenting pertinent medical information to the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An appearance before the Medical Advisory Board is not a matter subject to the contested case provisions under Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant seeking a license under this section shall successfully complete a driver's training course in accordance with regulations of the Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The required driver's training course:<section prefix="(i)">Shall consist of at least 20 hours; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May vary based on an applicant's previous driving experience or the driver trainer's recommendation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the ophthalmologist or optometrist recommends that the applicant use a bioptic telescopic lens while driving, the Administration may require additional driver's training using the bioptic telescopic lens.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A license granted under this section:<section prefix="(i)">Shall be endorsed "outside mirrors each side";</section><section prefix="(ii)">Subject to subsection (f) of this section, shall be endorsed "daylight driving only"; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">May be subject to additional restrictions imposed by the Administration, based on recommendations of the applicant's ophthalmologist or optometrist, or any other evaluation that the Administration determines appropriate.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Restrictions that may be imposed under paragraph (1)(iii) of this subsection include:<section prefix="(i)">Type of highways where the licensee may drive;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Maximum speed limits under which driving is allowed;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Maximum driving distances; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Other factors that the Administration determines appropriate.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A license endorsed "daylight driving only" authorizes the licensee to operate a motor vehicle only during the period beginning one-half hour after sunrise and ending one-half hour before sunset.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual licensed under this section may apply to eliminate the daylight only restriction if the individual:<section prefix="(i)">Has been licensed under this section for at least 1 year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">During the previous year, has not committed a traffic infraction or been involved in a traffic accident where the licensee was at fault;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Has passed a nighttime vision test prescribed by the Administration; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Has received a driver's training certificate based on nighttime driving skills, from an entity that the Administration has determined is qualified to evaluate drivers under this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before the elimination of the daytime only restriction, an applicant who meets the requirements of paragraph (1) of this subsection shall pass a nighttime driving test administered by at least two Administration examiners.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
