<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-4-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Authority" means the Maryland Transportation Authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Cost", as applied to any transportation facilities project, includes the cost of and all expenses incident to the construction, reconstruction, acquisition, improvement, extension, alteration, modernization, planning, maintenance, and repair of the project, including the cost and expenses of:<section prefix="(1)">All property acquired in connection with it;</section><section prefix="(2)">Financial, architectural, consulting, engineering, and legal services;</section><section prefix="(3)">Plans, specifications, surveys, estimates, feasibility reports, and direct and indirect labor, material, equipment, and administrative expenses; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Financing the project, including financing charges and interest before, during, and for 1 year after completion of construction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Outstanding and unpaid" does not include:<section prefix="(1)">Bonds purchased and held in sinking funds by or for the Authority; or</section><section prefix="(2)">If the money for their payment or redemption has been provided:<section prefix="(i)">Matured bonds not presented for payment; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Bonds called for redemption but not presented for redemption.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Refunding" means the retirement and cancellation of bonds, including revenue bonds of prior issues, after their acquisition by or for the Authority, whether before, at, or after maturity, either in exchange for other bonds or by payment, purchase, or redemption with the proceeds of the sale of other bonds.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Resolution", as used with respect to the Authority, means a resolution adopted by the affirmative vote of a majority of the appointed members of the Authority and concurred in by the Chairman.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Revenue bonds of prior issues" means:<section prefix="(1)">"State of Maryland Bridge and Tunnel Revenue Bonds" dated as of October 1, 1954;</section><section prefix="(2)">"State of Maryland Northeastern Expressway Revenue Bonds" dated as of January 1, 1962;</section><section prefix="(3)">"State of Maryland Bridge and Tunnel Revenue Bonds":<section prefix="(i)">"(Series 1968)" dated as of October 1, 1968; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">"(Series 1975)" dated as of July 1, 1975; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">Any other revenue bonds issued under the same provisions of law that authorized the issuance of the bonds listed in this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Transportation facilities project" includes:<section prefix="(1)">The Susquehanna River Bridge, the Harry W. Nice Memorial Potomac River Bridge, the William Preston Lane, Jr. Memorial Chesapeake Bay Bridge and parallel Chesapeake Bay Bridge, the Baltimore Harbor Tunnel, the Fort McHenry Tunnel, the Francis Scott Key Bridge, and the John F. Kennedy Memorial Highway, together with their appurtenant causeways, approaches, interchanges, entrance plazas, toll stations, and service facilities;</section><section prefix="(2)">A vehicle parking facility located in a priority funding area as defined in &#xA7; 5-7B-02 of the State Finance and Procurement Article;</section><section prefix="(3)">Any other project for transportation facilities that the Authority authorizes to be acquired or constructed; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Any additions, improvements, or enlargements to any of these projects, whenever authorized.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Transportation facility" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 3-101 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Vehicle parking facility" means a controlled entrance and exit building, structure, surface lot, and other facility for parking vehicles, for which fees or charges are established for the use of the facility.</section>
  </text>
</law>
