<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-208" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-15-208</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A manufacturer may not refuse to deliver new motor vehicles, new two-stage vehicles, or truck component parts, as the case may be, to a licensed dealer or distributor, in reasonable quantities and within a reasonable time after receipt of a written order, if:<section prefix="(1)">The manufacturer specifically advertises that these vehicles or truck component parts are available for immediate delivery; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The dealer or distributor has a franchise or other contract with the manufacturer for the sale of these vehicles or truck component parts to the public.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A distributor may not refuse to deliver new motor vehicles, or new two-stage vehicles, as the case may be, to a licensed dealer, in reasonable quantities and within a reasonable time after receipt of a written order, if:<section prefix="(1)">The distributor specifically advertises that these vehicles are available for immediate delivery; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The dealer has a franchise or other contract with the distributor for the sale of these vehicles to the public.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A factory branch may not refuse to deliver new motor vehicles, or new two-stage vehicles, as the case may be, to a licensed dealer, in reasonable quantities and within a reasonable time after receipt of a written order, if:<section prefix="(1)">The factory branch specifically advertises that these vehicles are available for immediate delivery; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The dealer has a franchise or other contract with the factory branch for the sale of these vehicles to the public.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A failure to deliver vehicles because of a labor strike, government regulation, or other cause not the fault of the manufacturer, distributor, or factory branch is not a violation of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a dealer has a franchise or other contract with a manufacturer, distributor, or factory branch for the sale of vehicles or truck component parts of a specific line or make, the manufacturer, distributor, or factory branch shall allow the dealer to:<section prefix="(1)">Purchase the vehicles or truck component parts at the same price and on the same terms as all other dealers with a franchise or other contract for the sale of vehicles or truck component parts of the same line or make; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Receive the same right to incentive payments that is given to all other dealers with a franchise or other contract for the sale of vehicles or truck component parts of the same line or make.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
