<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-8-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to the specific powers granted and duties imposed by this title, the Administration has the powers and duties set forth in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Administration may adopt rules and regulations to carry out the provisions of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration shall:<section prefix="(i)">Determine and may change from time to time the location, construction, geometrics, design, and maintenance of the State highway system; and</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">If the Administration and a local government designate an area as a bicycle and pedestrian priority area, implement a plan developed in cooperation with the local government to increase safety and access for bicycle or pedestrian traffic.</section><section prefix="2.">If there is no State highway within the limits of the bicycle and pedestrian priority area, the plan shall be developed by the local government.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A plan for traffic management in a bicycle and pedestrian priority area shall provide for:<section prefix="(i)">Appropriate changes to the location, construction, geometrics, design, and maintenance of the State highway system to increase safety and access for bicycle or pedestrian traffic in the bicycle and pedestrian priority area; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The appropriate use of traffic control devices including pedestrian control signals, traffic signals, stop signs, and speed bumps.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Administration may consult, confer, and contract with any agency or representative of the federal government, this State, or any other state or with any other person in furtherance of the duties of the Administration and the purposes of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to &#xA7; 2-103.4 of this article, the Administration may employ engineers, accountants, professional and technical experts, surveyors, skilled and unskilled laborers, advisors, consultants, and any other agents and employees that it considers necessary to carry out its powers and duties.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any employee of the Administration may be bonded under Title 9, Subtitle 17 of the State Government Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Administration may determine the compensation of executive management positions, as recommended by the Secretary of Transportation and approved by the Governor, subject to approval in the budget.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Administration may purchase any machines, tools, implements, appliances, supplies, materials, and working agencies that it considers necessary to carry out any of its powers or duties under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Administration may rent or lease any offices and other places that it considers necessary to carry out its powers and duties.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">By rules or regulations consistent with the safety and welfare of the traveling public, the Administration may govern the control and use of rest areas, scenic overlooks, roadside picnic areas, and other public use areas within State highway rights-of-way.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Administration shall:<section prefix="(1)">Plan, select, construct, improve, and maintain the State highway system; and</section><section prefix="(2)">By July 1, 1997, in coordination with local governments, draft a plan for a bicycle priority route system that provides a viable network for bicycle transportation throughout the State.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
