<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="25-204" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-25-204</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">As soon as reasonably possible and within 7 days at most after it takes an abandoned vehicle into custody, a police department shall send a notice, by certified mail, return receipt requested, bearing a postmark from the United States Postal Service, to:<section prefix="(1)">The last known registered owner of the vehicle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Each secured party, as shown on the records of the Administration.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The notice shall:<section prefix="(1)">State that the abandoned vehicle has been taken into custody;</section><section prefix="(2)">Describe the year, make, model, and vehicle identification number of the vehicle;</section><section prefix="(3)">Give the location of the facility where the vehicle is held;</section><section prefix="(4)"><section prefix="(i)">Inform the owner and secured party of the owner's and secured party's right to reclaim the vehicle within 3 weeks after the date of the notice, on payment of all towing, preservation, and storage charges resulting from taking or placing the vehicle in custody; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">In Baltimore City and Montgomery County, be sent by certified mail, return receipt requested, and inform the owner and secured party of the owner's and secured party's right to reclaim the vehicle within 11 working days after the receipt of the notice, on payment of all towing, preservation, and storage charges resulting from taking or placing the vehicle in custody; and</section></section><section prefix="(5)">State that the failure of the owner or secured party to exercise this right in the time provided is:<section prefix="(i)">A waiver by the owner or secured party of all of the owner's or secured party's right, title, and interest in the vehicle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A consent to the sale of the vehicle at public auction; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">A consent by the owner other than a lessor to the retention of the vehicle for public purposes as provided in &#xA7; 25-207 of this subtitle.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In Baltimore City, Prince George's County, and Montgomery County, a police department or its agent may seek to recover costs of impoundment, storage, and sale of a vehicle as provided by &#xA7;&#xA7; 25-206.1 and 25-206.2 of this subtitle. If a police department or its agent seeks to apply the provisions of &#xA7;&#xA7; 25-206.1 and 25-206.2 of this subtitle, the notice required by this section shall also state that the failure of the owner or secured party to exercise the right to reclaim the vehicle in the time provided may cause:<section prefix="(1)">Continuing liability of the owner for costs of:<section prefix="(i)">Impoundment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Storage within the chargeable limit for storage as provided in &#xA7; 25-206.1(b) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Sale of the vehicle; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Denial of any application by the owner to renew the registration of any vehicle as required by &#xA7; 25-206.2 of this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
