<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-909" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-909</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, the Administration may adopt a system of staggered registration for any motor vehicle class.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">During the registration period in which the system is initiated, vehicle registrations may be issued for periods varying from 7 months to 18 months with fees prorated according to the number of months for which the registration is issued.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Vehicle registration plates or validation tabs shall be issued and displayed in accordance with a schedule established by the Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any new registration or renewal issued during the year may be issued initially for other than a 12-month period to facilitate an equal volume of monthly issuances and the registration fee shall be prorated for the period issued.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">For the purpose of maintaining relatively uniform work loads, the Administration shall evaluate monthly volumes of registration renewals from time to time and any portion of a monthly issuance may be rescheduled by applying a different expiration date and prorating the fee accordingly.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Administration shall refund a registration fee on surrender of a registration card and unused registration plates by the owner as provided under &#xA7; 13-938 of this subtitle only if the return is made prior to the expiration date of the registration period for which the application for refund is made.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">When the Administration assesses a prorated fee, it shall be calculated by multiplying one-twelfth of the applicable fee by the number of months for which the issuance or renewal is made and adjusting this amount to the nearest dollar amount.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Administration may adopt regulations to implement and operate a staggered registration system as provided under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
