<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-2-103.6</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>103.6</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Job access project" means a program to provide reasonable transportation services to employment or job-related activities for low-income workers that:<section prefix="(i)">Facilitates trips to and from jobs and other employment related activities, including child care, job skills enhancement, and employment seeking activities; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Serves low-income workers within a service area that is specified by a transportation provider.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Low-income worker" means a person that meets the poverty threshold that is established by the U.S. Department of Commerce, Bureau of the Census for a given year.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Transportation provider" means a public or private entity that provides transit service to more than one individual.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a job access program to provide grants to transportation providers for job access projects.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to the limitations provided in subsection (c) of this section and subject to the availability of funds in the annual State budget, the Secretary shall make grants to a transportation provider that:<section prefix="(i)">Operates a job access project that:<section prefix="1.">Takes into account the transportation needs of low-income workers within the area of service defined by the transportation provider; and</section><section prefix="2.">Is not restricted to clients of social service agencies;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Files a written application with the Department in the form and detail the Secretary requires; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Receives approval from the Secretary.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Before approving an application from a transportation provider, the Secretary shall consult with the local department of social services.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">When allocating funds under the job access program, the Secretary shall give priority to the areas of the State that the Secretary determines are most in need of a job access project.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A transportation provider that receives funds for a capital expenditure under the job access program shall expend a matching fund of at least 20% of the total cost of the proposed capital expenditure.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A transportation provider that receives funds for operating expenditures under the job access program shall expend a matching fund of at least 25% of the total cost of the proposed operating expenditures.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A transportation provider shall use funds distributed under this section only for the acquisition or replacement of equipment or the operating costs of a job access project.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A transportation provider that receives a grant under this section shall consult with the local department of social services to determine the most effective means of serving the transportation needs of low-income workers in the proposed service area.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A transportation provider shall cooperate with other transportation providers in the proposed service area to best serve the transportation needs of low-income workers.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit a transportation provider from:<section prefix="(i)">Contracting with nonprofit organizations, public transportation providers, or private carriers for the provision of transportation service to low-income workers;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Modifying or expanding an existing local transportation system;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Developing a new transportation system with the use or assistance of subsidized volunteers; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Allowing individuals other than low-income workers to use the transportation services provided by the job access project to the extent excess capacity is available.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Each transportation provider that receives a grant under this section shall submit a report to the Secretary that details how the grant was expended on the job access project.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall encourage a transportation provider to:<section prefix="(i)">Continue to maximize use of existing funding programs for a job access project; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Enter into cooperative agreements with other local or State transportation providers.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary may adopt regulations that are necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Any funds provided under this section shall be used to supplement and shall not supplant existing funds used by a transportation provider for transportation services.</section>
  </text>
</law>
