<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="21-1124.2" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-21-1124.2</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Handheld telephone" means a handheld device used to access wireless telephone service.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"9-1-1 system" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 1-301 of the Public Safety Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">Emergency use of a handheld telephone, including calls to:<section prefix="(i)">A 9-1-1 system;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A hospital;</section><section prefix="(iii)">An ambulance service provider;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A fire department;</section><section prefix="(v)">A law enforcement agency; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">A first aid squad;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Use of a handheld telephone by the following individuals when acting within the scope of official duty:<section prefix="(i)">Law enforcement personnel; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Emergency personnel;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Use of a handheld telephone as a text messaging device as defined in &#xA7; 21-1124.1 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Use of a handheld telephone as a communication device utilizing push-to-talk technology by an individual operating a commercial motor vehicle, as defined in 49 CFR Part 390.5 of the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Regulations.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The following individuals may not use a handheld telephone while operating a motor vehicle:<section prefix="(1)">A driver of a Class H (school) vehicle that is carrying passengers and in motion; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A holder of a learner's instructional permit or a provisional driver's license who is 18 years of age or older.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to an individual specified in subsection (c) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A driver of a motor vehicle that is in motion may not use the driver's hands to use a handheld telephone other than to initiate or terminate a wireless telephone call or to turn on or turn off the handheld telephone.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A police officer may enforce this section only as a secondary action when the police officer detains a driver for a suspected violation of another provision of the Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person convicted of a violation of this section is subject to the following penalties:<section prefix="(i)">For a first offense, a fine of not more than $40; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">For a second or subsequent offense, a fine of $100.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For a first offense under this section, points may not be assessed against the individual under &#xA7; 16-402 of this article unless the offense contributes to an accident.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The court may waive a penalty under subsection (f) of this section for a person who:<section prefix="(1)">Is convicted of a first offense under this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Provides proof that the person has acquired a hands-free accessory, an attachment or add-on, a built-in feature, or an addition for the person's handheld telephone that will allow the person to operate a motor vehicle in accordance with this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
