<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="21-1209" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-21-1209</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, the driver of a vehicle shall:<section prefix="(1)">Exercise due care to avoid colliding with any bicycle, EPAMD, or motor scooter being ridden by a person; and</section><section prefix="(2)">When overtaking a bicycle, an EPAMD, or a motor scooter, pass safely at a distance of not less than 3 feet, unless, at the time:<section prefix="(i)">The bicycle, EPAMD, or motor scooter rider fails to operate the vehicle in conformance with &#xA7; 21-1205(a) of this subtitle ("Riding to right side of roadway") or &#xA7; 21-1205.1(b) of this subtitle ("Roadway with bike lane or shoulder paved to smooth surface");</section><section prefix="(ii)">A passing clearance of less than 3 feet is caused solely by the bicycle, EPAMD, or motor scooter rider failing to maintain a steady course; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">The highway on which the vehicle is being driven is not wide enough to lawfully pass the bicycle, EPAMD, or motor scooter at a distance of at least 3 feet.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not throw any object at or in the direction of any person riding a bicycle, an EPAMD, or a motor scooter.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not open the door of any motor vehicle with intent to strike, injure, or interfere with any person riding a bicycle, an EPAMD, or a motor scooter.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Unless otherwise specified in this title, the driver of a vehicle shall yield the right-of-way to a person who is lawfully riding a bicycle, an EPAMD, or a motor scooter in a designated bike lane or shoulder if the driver of the vehicle is about to enter or cross the designated bike lane or shoulder.</section>
  </text>
</law>
