<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-815</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>815</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Excise tax" means the tax imposed under &#xA7; 13-809 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Qualified plug-in electric drive vehicle" means a motor vehicle that:<section prefix="(i)">Is made by a manufacturer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is manufactured primarily for use on public streets, roads, and highways;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Has not been modified from original manufacturer specifications;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Is acquired for use or lease by the taxpayer and not for resale;</section><section prefix="(v)">Is rated at not more than 8,500 pounds unloaded gross vehicle weight;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Has a maximum speed capability of at least 55 miles per hour;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Is propelled to a significant extent by an electric motor that draws electricity from a battery that:<section prefix="1.">For a 4-wheeled motor vehicle, has a capacity of not less than 4 kilowatt-hours;</section><section prefix="2.">For a 2-wheeled or 3-wheeled motor vehicle, has a capacity of not less than 2.5 kilowatt-hours; and</section><section prefix="3.">Is capable of being recharged from an external source of electricity; and</section></section><section prefix="(viii)">Is titled by the taxpayer on or after October 1, 2010, but before July 1, 2013.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A credit is allowed against the excise tax imposed for a qualified plug-in electric drive vehicle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to the limitations under subsections (c) through (e) of this section, the credit allowed under this section equals 100% of the excise tax imposed for a vehicle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The credit allowed under this section may not exceed $2,000.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The credit allowed under this section is limited to the acquisition of:<section prefix="(1)">One vehicle per individual; and</section><section prefix="(2)">10 vehicles per business entity.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A credit may not be claimed under this section:<section prefix="(1)">For a vehicle unless the vehicle is registered in the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">Unless the manufacturer has already conformed to any applicable State or federal laws or regulations governing clean-fuel vehicle or electric vehicle purchases applicable during the calendar year in which the vehicle is titled; or</section><section prefix="(3)">For a vehicle that was initially registered in another state.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Motor Vehicle Administration shall administer the credit under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
