<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-8-627</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>627</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Defense-related activity" means:<section prefix="(i)">The preparation of the United States or a state for defense or war; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The prosecution of war by the United States or a country with which the United States maintains friendly relations.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Highway authority" means a governing body or individual with the authority under law to restrict or close a highway to the public.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Political subdivision" means a county, municipal corporation, special taxing district, or public corporation of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Public utility" includes a pipeline, gas, electric, heat, water, oil, sewer, communication, radio, transportation, railroad, airplane, or other system owned or operated for public use.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to property owned by a person, the State, or a political subdivision:<section prefix="(1)">Engaged in, or preparing to engage in, the manufacture, transportation, or storage of a product to be used in a defense-related activity;</section><section prefix="(2)">Engaged in, or preparing to engage in, the manufacture, transportation, distribution, or storage of gas, oil, coal, electricity, or water; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Operating a public utility.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An owner of property described in subsection (b) of this section, who believes that the property will be endangered if public use and travel is not restricted or prohibited on a highway abutting the property, may petition the highway authority of the State or a political subdivision, as appropriate, to close or restrict public use of and travel on the highway.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">On receiving the petition, the highway authority shall:<section prefix="(1)">Set a hearing date; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide notice of the hearing at least 7 days before the hearing by publication in a newspaper of general circulation in the political subdivision where the property is located.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After the hearing, the highway authority may by order close or reasonably restrict the use of a public highway if the highway authority determines that the public safety and the safety of the property require the closure or restriction.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The highway authority shall conspicuously post a notice in letters at least 3 inches high at each end of a highway that the highway authority closes or restricts.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The highway authority may issue a written permit to persons to travel on a closed or restricted highway under conditions that the highway authority establishes.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The highway authority may revoke or modify an order issued under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A person who violates an order issued under this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 90 days or a fine not exceeding $500 or both.</section>
  </text>
</law>
