<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-605</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>605</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration may award contracts out of the appropriation to the Department for the Motorcycle Safety Program to qualifying motorcycle safety training centers for the conduct of approved motorcycle safety courses. These contracts may provide funding, equipment, and materials to establish and maintain the training centers.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration may award contracts in accordance with Division II of the State Finance and Procurement Article out of the appropriation to the Department for the Motorcycle Safety Program for the procurement of services and products to be used to achieve the purpose of the Motorcycle Safety Program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">From the funds appropriated for the Motorcycle Safety Program, the Department shall fund the costs incurred in the implementation and operation of activities under this subtitle, including administrative costs. The Administration may reimburse a motorcycle safety training center at a rate established by the Administration for each eligible person completing the course. The reimbursement rate may be in addition to the assistance provided under subsection (a) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The funds provided under this section shall be in addition to any other State aid.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Administration may not contract for the provision of any services under this program the aggregate costs of which exceed the funds appropriated for the Motorcycle Safety Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Administration shall recover the full costs of operating the Program from any miscellaneous fees as defined in &#xA7; 12-120(a) of this article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
