<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-936</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>936</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "historic motor vehicle" means a motor vehicle, including a passenger vehicle, motorcycle, or truck that:<section prefix="(1)">Is at least 20 years old;</section><section prefix="(2)">Has not been substantially altered from the manufacturer's original design; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Meets criteria contained in regulations adopted by the Administration.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In this section, "historic motor vehicle" does not include a vehicle that has been remanufactured or reconstructed as a replica of an original vehicle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If registered with the Administration under this section, every historic motor vehicle is a Class L (historic) vehicle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as provided in subsection (i) of this section, for each Class L (historic) vehicle, the annual registration fee is $25.50.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In applying for registration of a historic motor vehicle under this section, the owner of the vehicle shall submit with the application a certification that the vehicle for which the application is made:<section prefix="(1)">Will be maintained for use in exhibitions, club activities, parades, tours, occasional transportation, and similar uses; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Will not be used:<section prefix="(i)">For general daily transportation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Primarily for the transportation of passengers or property on highways.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 13-936.1 of this subtitle, on registration of a vehicle under this section, the Administration shall issue a special, historic motor vehicle registration plate of the size and design that the Administration determines.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Unless the presence of the equipment was specifically required by a statute of this State as a condition of sale when the vehicle was manufactured, the presence of any specific equipment is not required for the operation of a vehicle registered under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A vehicle registered under this section is exempt from any statute that requires periodic vehicle inspections or that requires the use and inspection of emission controls.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For a motor vehicle manufactured at least 60 years prior to the current model year, there is a onetime registration fee of $50.00.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Registration of a motor vehicle manufactured under this subsection is not transferable to a subsequent owner.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
