<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-21-1414</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1414</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Electronic toll collection" means a system of collecting tolls or charges that is capable of charging an account holder for the appropriate toll by electronic transmission of information between a device on a motor vehicle and a device in a toll lane at a toll collection facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Pay" means paying a toll by cash, by permitting a charge against a valid account with the Maryland Transportation Authority, or by another means of payment approved by the Authority at the time.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Video-monitoring system" means a motor vehicle sensor installed to work in conjunction with a toll collection facility that automatically produces a photograph, microphotograph, videotape, or other recorded image of the license plate of a motor vehicle when the operator of the motor vehicle fails to pay a toll.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the operator of a motor vehicle fails to pay the prescribed toll at any Authority highway where tolls are collected by means of electronic toll collection, the registered owner of the motor vehicle shall be liable to the Maryland Transportation Authority for payment of the toll and a civil penalty as provided for in the regulations of the Maryland Transportation Authority.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A registered owner of a vehicle shall not be liable for a civil penalty imposed under this section if the operator of the vehicle has been convicted of failure or refusal to pay a toll under &#xA7; 21-1413 of this subtitle for the same violation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Maryland Transportation Authority or its duly authorized agent shall send a citation via first-class mail, no later than 60 days after the alleged violation, to each person alleged to be liable under this section as a registered owner.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Personal service upon the registered owner shall not be required, and a record of mailing kept in the ordinary course of business shall be admissible evidence of the mailing of the citation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A citation shall contain:<section prefix="(i)">The name and address of the registered owner alleged to be liable under this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The registration number of the motor vehicle involved in such violation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The location where such violation took place;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The date and time of such violation;</section><section prefix="(v)">The amount of the toll not paid;</section><section prefix="(vi)">The amount of the civil penalty; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">The date by which the toll and penalty must be paid.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A citation shall also include:<section prefix="(i)">Information advising the person liable under this section of the manner and the time in which liability alleged in the citation may be contested;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The statutory defenses described in subsection (f) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">A warning that failure to pay the toll and civil penalty or to contest liability in the manner and time prescribed is an admission of liability and a waiver of available defenses, and may result in the entry of a default judgment or in the refusal or suspension of the motor vehicle registration.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A person receiving the citation for a violation under this section may:<section prefix="(i)">Pay the toll and the civil penalty directly to the Maryland Transportation Authority; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Elect to stand trial for the alleged violation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">If the registered owner of a motor vehicle who is liable under this section fails to pay the prescribed toll and civil penalty within 60 days after mailing of the citation, the Maryland Transportation Authority or its duly authorized agent may:<section prefix="(i)">Collect the toll, the civil penalty, and administrative expenses by civil action commenced in the District Court for the jurisdiction in which the alleged failure to pay a toll occurred; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Notify the Administration of the failure to pay the toll and civil penalty in accordance with &#xA7; 27-110 of this article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A certificate alleging that a failure to pay a toll occurred, sworn to or affirmed by a duly authorized agent of the Maryland Transportation Authority, based upon inspection of photographs, videotape, or other electronically recorded images of the license plate of a motor vehicle produced by an electronic toll collection video-monitoring system shall be evidence of the facts contained therein and shall be admissible in any proceeding alleging a violation under this section.  </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Adjudication of liability under this section:<section prefix="(1)">Shall be based upon a preponderance of evidence;</section><section prefix="(2)">May not be deemed a conviction of a registered owner of a motor vehicle under the Motor Vehicle Code;</section><section prefix="(3)">May not be made part of the registered owner's motor vehicle operating record; and</section><section prefix="(4)">May not be considered in the provision of motor vehicle insurance coverage.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a person other than the registered owner of the motor vehicle is adjudicated responsible for the failure to pay the toll, then the registered owner is not liable under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the registered owner is a lessor of motor vehicles, and at the time of the failure to pay a toll the motor vehicle involved was in the possession of a lessee, and the lessor within 30 days of the citation provides the Maryland Transportation Authority or its duly authorized agent with a copy of the lease agreement identifying the lessee, then the lessee shall be liable under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the motor vehicle involved in a failure to pay a toll is operated using a dealer or transporter registration plate, and at the time of the violation the motor vehicle was under the custody and control of a person other than the dealer or transporter, and if the dealer or transporter within 30 days of the citation identifies to the Maryland Transportation Authority or its duly authorized agent the person who had custody and control over the motor vehicle at the time of the violation, then that person and not the dealer or transporter shall be liable under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If a motor vehicle is reported to a law enforcement agency as stolen at the time of the failure to pay a toll, or within a reasonable period of time after the registered owner becomes aware of the theft, then the registered owner of the motor vehicle is not liable under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If within 30 days of notice of a violation, a registered owner provides to the Maryland Transportation Authority or its duly authorized agent substantial evidence of the identity of the person who was operating the motor vehicle at the time of the violation, then that person shall be subject to liability under this section and shall be sent a citation under subsection (c) of this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If that person subsequently admits to or is adjudicated responsible for failure to pay the toll, then the registered owner is not liable under this section.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
