<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-25-207.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies to any vehicle:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>207.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to any vehicle:<section prefix="(1)">Which is impounded by a police department either as abandoned or pursuant to other State or local law;</section><section prefix="(2)">From which the engine or vehicle serial number has been removed or defaced; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Of which neither the owner nor any secured party can be identified from records of the Administration or other reasonable steps taken by the police department.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The police department on whose authority the vehicle was impounded may apply to the Administration for an assignment of an identification number under &#xA7;&#xA7; 13-106.1 and 14-107 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The police department on whose authority the vehicle was impounded may apply to the Administration for a certificate of title to a vehicle, and shall submit as evidence of ownership:<section prefix="(1)">A copy of the return receipt or certified mail notice returned as undeliverable, received under &#xA7; 25-204 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A copy of the notice published under &#xA7; 25-205 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding the provisions of &#xA7; 25-207 of this subtitle, the police department, after satisfying the requirements of subsections (b) and (c) of this section, may retain and use the vehicle for public purposes.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Any vehicle retained for use under this section:<section prefix="(1)">May not be dismantled or disassembled for the purpose of using its component parts; and</section><section prefix="(2)">When no longer usable for public purposes, shall be transferred by the police department to a scrap processor licensed under &#xA7; 15-502 of this article.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
