<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-613" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-8-613</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In calendar year 1978, the Administration shall prepare for each county a 6-year construction and reconstruction program for primary and secondary highways, the secondary program to include bicycle trails and sidewalks.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration shall submit this program to the General Assembly for its review by January 15, 1979.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the program shall be updated annually and submitted to the General Assembly for its review by January 15 of each year.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The program shall:<section prefix="(i)">Advise on priorities among the projects approved for construction, following completion of the project planning phase; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">As to each item included in it, contain a proposed schedule of property acquisition, detailed engineering, and construction.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Before the annual submission of the highway construction and reconstruction program to the General Assembly, the Administration shall consult with the local governing body, municipalities, and local legislative delegation of each county concerning construction priorities.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the Administration is unable for any reason to perform in accordance with the schedule set forth in the annual primary highway program, it shall, if so requested by resolution of either house of the General Assembly, explain in writing to the next session of the General Assembly any change in the scheduling of a particular project included in the preceding year's program.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If there is any change in the scheduling of a particular project in the secondary highway program for which funds have been appropriated in the preceding year, the Administration, on written request of a majority of the local legislative delegation from the county for which the project is programmed, shall explain that change in writing to the members of the General Assembly from that county.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Administration's budget for Fiscal Year 1981 and for each fiscal year following, as submitted to the General Assembly, shall include funds for projects scheduled for the first year of the highway construction and reconstruction program established under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
