<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-111.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-111.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An applicant is entitled to receive the driver's license applied for if the applicant:<section prefix="(1)">Passes the examination provided for in this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Surrenders the last learner's instructional permit issued to him, if any; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Pays the fees provided for by this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to an applicant who holds a provisional license under &#xA7; 16-111 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An applicant is entitled to receive a license if the applicant:<section prefix="(i)">Meets the minimum age required under &#xA7; 16-103(c)(3) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Satisfies the provisional license requirements under &#xA7; 16-111(d) or (e) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Surrenders any provisional license issued to the applicant; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Pays the fee established under this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each license issued by the Administration shall be identified clearly as to its specific class. A Class M license may be issued in combination with any one of the other classes.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration shall assign an identifying number to each license it issues.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Administration may not use, include, or encode, in any form, an individual's Social Security number on the individual's driver's license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, each noncommercial Class A, B, C, or M license issued by the Administration shall be of the size, design, and content that the Administration specifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A noncommercial Class A, B, C, or M license shall include:<section prefix="(i)">The name and residence address of the licensee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The date of birth of the licensee;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A description of the licensee, which shall include the height, weight, and sex of the licensee;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A color photograph of the applicant that is taken in accordance with a procedure that the Administration requires;</section><section prefix="(v)">The type or class of vehicles that the license authorizes the licensee to drive;</section><section prefix="(vi)">The signature and seal of the issuing agent; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">A space for the signature of the licensee.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A license is not valid unless the licensee signs the license in the licensee's usual signature.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When issued and signed, a driver's license authorizes the licensee to drive any vehicle of the type or class specified on it, subject to any restrictions endorsed on the license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Only one current driver's license may be issued by the Administration to and held by any individual at any one time.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before issuing a license, the Administration shall require the applicant to surrender any license issued to the applicant by any other jurisdiction.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
