<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-5-1104</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If a person is apprehended by a police officer for the violation of any provision of this title that is punishable as a misdemeanor or for the violation of any rule, regulation, or order adopted under this title that is punishable as a misdemeanor, the officer shall prepare and sign a written citation.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The citation shall contain:<section prefix="(1)">A notice to the person charged to appear in court;</section><section prefix="(2)">The name and address of the person charged;</section><section prefix="(3)">The State registration number of any aircraft involved in the offense;</section><section prefix="(4)">The offense charged;</section><section prefix="(5)">The time and place the person charged is required to appear in court;</section><section prefix="(6)">A form for the written promise of the person charged to appear in court; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Any other necessary information.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The person charged may give his written promise to appear in court by signing the form for written promise on the citation prepared by the police officer. In this event, the officer need not take the person into physical custody for the violation unless:<section prefix="(1)">The person charged does not furnish satisfactory evidence of identity; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The officer has reasonable grounds to believe the person charged will disregard a written promise to appear.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Regardless of the disposition of the charge for which the citation was issued, a person may not violate his written promise to appear given on the issuance of a citation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A written promise to appear in court may be complied with by an appearance by counsel.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
