<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="22-404.3" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-22-404.3</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Every truck, truck tractor, and bus operated on highways in this State, except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, shall be identified with the name or trade name of its owner, operator, or lessee and shall display:<section prefix="(1)">A United States Department of Transportation number; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The number issued by a State agency.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to the following if operated intrastate only:<section prefix="(1)">Vehicles registered as:<section prefix="(i)">Farm trucks under &#xA7; 13-921 of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Farm truck tractors under &#xA7; 13-924 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Farm area motor vehicles under &#xA7; 13-935 of this article;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Trucks registered at 10,000 pounds capacity or less;</section><section prefix="(3)">Emergency vehicles;</section><section prefix="(4)">Vehicles used primarily to transport money or commercial paper;</section><section prefix="(5)">Vehicles owned or operated by the State or any political subdivision of the State; or</section><section prefix="(6)">Vehicles operating within 15 days from the date of purchase.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The display of identification required by this section shall comply with the regulations promulgated by the federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration relating to vehicles operating interstate, as codified in 49 C.F.R., Part 390.21.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section does not prohibit the display of any additional identification required by other laws of this State or any other state, or by any agency or department of the federal government.</section>
  </text>
</law>
