<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-207" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-10-207</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Eligible local bus service":<section prefix="(i)">Means the number of annual platform miles and annual platform hours of fixed route, scheduled local bus service, that previously replaced comparable service operated by the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority, plus the number of annual platform miles and annual platform hours of any new fixed route, scheduled local bus service added after June 30, 1989; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is limited to service operated by or on behalf of and in Montgomery County or Prince George's County.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Costs" means operating costs of eligible local bus service, plus operating costs under &#xA7; 10-205 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Service deficit" means costs less:<section prefix="(i)">The greater of:</section><section prefix="(ii)">All federal operating assistance.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the appropriation requirements and budgetary provisions of &#xA7; 3-216 of this article and upon receipt of an approval of a grant application in the form or detail as the Secretary shall reasonably require, the Department shall provide for annual grants to Prince George's County and Montgomery County for eligible local bus service as defined in this section. The amount of these grants shall be equal to:<section prefix="(i)">100 percent of the service deficit attributable to each county; less</section><section prefix="(ii)">Each county's share of the Department's annual grant to the Washington Suburban Transit District as determined under &#xA7; 10-205(b) of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding the provisions of this section, the Secretary may authorize payments to Prince George's County and Montgomery County:<section prefix="(i)">To subsidize new bus service for a period of 36 months from the initiation of service; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">For the loss of revenues from fare modifications for a period of 36 months from the date of the modification.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department's grant for any eligible local bus service may not be greater than the operating grant that the Department would incur from the same bus service if operated by the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority. This requirement shall be applied on a line by line basis.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except with the specific approval of the Secretary, notwithstanding the provisions of &#xA7; 10-205 of this subtitle, the combined grants for bus service to each county under this section and &#xA7; 10-205(b) of this subtitle may not exceed the level of the combined grants for the prior fiscal year adjusted for inflation by the projected Consumer Price Index CPI-U for the fiscal year in which the grant under this section is being awarded, using the actual Consumer Price Index CPI-U at the close of the fiscal year. Adjustments shall be made to increase or decrease the combined grants in the subsequent fiscal year to reflect the actual inflation rate.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall provide an annual capital grant to Prince George's County and Montgomery County for the purchase of buses to be used in eligible local bus service.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Grants provided under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be in addition to any federal funds received by the State for bus services operated by Prince George's County and Montgomery County.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For fiscal year 2001 and thereafter, Prince George's County and Montgomery County shall implement performance indicators, in addition to the farebox recovery indicator, to track service efficiency for mass transit in their respective jurisdictions, including:<section prefix="(i)">Operating expenses per vehicle mile;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Operating expenses per passenger trip; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Passenger trips per vehicle mile.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The counties shall submit an annual performance report to the Senate Budget and Taxation Committee, House Ways and Means Committee, and House Appropriations Committee by December 1 of each year on:<section prefix="(i)">The status of the performance indicators for the prior fiscal year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The status of any performance goals of their jurisdictions as they pertain to mass transit service; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Comparisons of performance indicators for mass transit in their jurisdictions and other similar systems nationwide.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Prince George's County and Montgomery County shall each provide for an independent management audit of the operational costs and revenues of mass transit in their respective jurisdictions every 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The audit shall provide data on fares, cost containment measures, comparisons with other similar mass transit systems, and other information necessary in evaluating the operations of their transit systems.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The findings from the audit shall be used as a benchmark for the annual performance reports.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
