<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-24-104.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>104.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Automobiles" means all assembled motor vehicles:<section prefix="(i)">Capable of being operated on a highway; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Authorized under this article to be operated on a highway.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Maxi-cube vehicle" means a nonarticulating straight truck:<section prefix="(i)">In combination with a semitrailer which does not exceed 34 feet, and is designed to be loaded and unloaded through the semitrailer; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">In combination with a trailer that does not exceed 28 feet.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Saddle-mount and full-mount combinations" means a truck tractor or unloaded truck towing one or more other truck tractors or unloaded trucks in combination.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Stinger-steered automobile transporter" means a truck tractor and semitrailer combination:<section prefix="(i)">Designed for and engaged exclusively in the transportation of automobiles or boats; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">In which the fifth wheel is located on a drop frame behind and below the rear axle of the power unit.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For purposes of this section, the length of a vehicle includes its front and rear bumpers and any part of its load that extends beyond the vehicle, but is exclusive of nonload bearing safety and energy conservation devices, such as marker lamps, steps and handholds for entry and egress, front-mounted refrigeration units, and front-mounted air compressors.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The measurement of a combination of vehicles engaged in the transportation of automobiles or boats shall not include the overhang of the transported vehicles or boats or any retractable device on the rear of the combination when in use to support a transported vehicle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section does not apply to any vehicle or combination of vehicles carrying:<section prefix="(i)">Piling, poles, or mill logs; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Crew or racing shells.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not prohibit the use of a combination of vehicles to carry an indivisible load if the load is not over 70 feet long.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as otherwise provided in this section:<section prefix="(1)">A bus, single unit truck, or Class M motor home may not be over 40 feet long; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A publicly owned rigid bus may not be over 41 feet long.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to a publicly owned rigid bus.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A bus or a Class M motor home may be over 40 feet long but may not be over 45 feet long:<section prefix="(i)">When operated on an interstate highway or any part of the State highway system designated by the Secretary in conjunction with the United States Department of Transportation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">When operated on a highway that is not specified in item (i) of this paragraph if the bus or motor home is using the highway to travel the shortest practical route between a highway specified in item (i) of this paragraph and:<section prefix="1.">The point of origin or destination of the bus or motor home on a particular day;</section><section prefix="2.">A bus terminal; or</section><section prefix="3.">For a distance not to exceed 1 mile, facilities for food, fuel, repairs, or rest.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, a publicly owned articulated three-axle bus may not be over 60 feet long.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Any other vehicle may not exceed a length of 35 feet.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">When a semitrailer and a trailer (double) are being operated in combination with a truck tractor, the combination of vehicles shall not be subject to an overall length limitation. This combination may only be operated on any part of the interstate system or other State system highways that are designated by the Secretary in conjunction with the U.S. Department of Transportation, or on a highway that is the shortest practical route between a designated highway and a truck terminal, or point of origin/destination for cargo, or for a distance not to exceed 1 mile, facilities for food, fuel, repairs, or rest. A semitrailer or trailer being operated in this combination may not exceed 28 feet in length for each unit.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">When a semitrailer (single) is being operated in combination with a truck tractor, the combination of vehicles shall not be subject to an overall length limit, however, the semitrailer may not exceed 48 feet in length.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">Except as otherwise provided in this section:<section prefix="(1)">In a combination of vehicles with a power unit that is a cargo-carrying vehicle, the overall length of the combination may not exceed 62 feet;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any other combination of vehicles may not exceed 55 feet; and</section><section prefix="(3)"><section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">A truck or truck tractor and semitrailer combination designed for and engaged exclusively in the transportation of automobiles or boats may not exceed 65 feet in length;</section><section prefix="2.">A stinger-steered automobile transporter may not exceed 75 feet in length;</section><section prefix="3.">A. A maxi-cube vehicle described in subsection (a)(4)(i) of this section may not exceed 65 feet in length; and</section><section prefix="4.">Saddle-mount and full-mount combinations may not exceed 97 feet in length;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">No other length requirements may be applied to the combinations of vehicles described in item (i) of this item; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The combinations of vehicles described in item (i) of this item may only be operated on any part of the interstate system or other State system highways that are designated by the Secretary in conjunction with the U.S. Department of Transportation, or on a highway that is the shortest practical route between a designated highway and:<section prefix="1.">A truck terminal;</section><section prefix="2.">A point of origin/destination for cargo; or</section><section prefix="3.">For a distance not to exceed 1 mile, facilities for food, fuel, repairs, or rest.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(j-1)">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (j) of this section, when a semitrailer is being operated in combination with a power unit that is equipped with a dromedary box being used to transport explosives and munitions classified under 49 C.F.R. Part 173.50 that are intended for use by the United States Department of Defense, the combination of vehicles is not subject to an overall length limit, but the semitrailer may not exceed 48 feet in length.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (h) of this section, nothing shall prevent the operation of a combination of vehicles in which the semitrailer (single) does not exceed 48 1/2 feet in length or a combination of vehicles in which the semitrailer or trailer (double) does not exceed 28 1/2 feet in length for each unit; provided, the combination has been lawfully operated on the highways of this State prior to December 1, 1982.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (j)(1) of this section, nothing shall prevent a power unit, which was equipped with a dromedary box, deck, or plate and was legally operated in Maryland prior to December 1, 1982, in combination with a semitrailer or trailer from exceeding the overall length limit of 55 feet.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "vehicle" means:<section prefix="(i)">A semitrailer as defined in &#xA7; 11-158 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A trailer as defined in &#xA7; 11-169 of this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding the overall length of the combination, a truck tractor may not be operated on a highway in the State in combination with more than 2 vehicles.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, a combination of noncommercial vehicles consisting of a power unit and a travel trailer may not exceed 65 feet in length.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The combination of vehicles exceeding 55 feet but authorized under this subsection may only be operated on:<section prefix="(i)">Any part of the interstate system or other State system highways that are designated by the Secretary in conjunction with the U.S. Department of Transportation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A highway that is the shortest practical route between a designated highway and:<section prefix="1.">A point of origin or destination on a particular day; or</section><section prefix="2.">For a distance not to exceed 1 mile, facilities for food, fuel, repairs, or rest.</section></section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
