<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-10-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>** CONTINGENCY - NOT IN EFFECT - CHAPTER 494 OF 1995 AND CHAPTERS 10 AND 599  OF 1996  **...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>** CONTINGENCY - NOT IN EFFECT - CHAPTER 494 OF 1995 AND CHAPTERS 10 AND 599  OF 1996  **<section prefix=""><section prefix="1.">"Bridge" means the existing Woodrow Wilson Memorial Bridge.</section><section prefix="2.">"Cost", as applied to the project, means the cost of acquisition of all lands, structures, rights-of-way, franchises, easements, and other property rights and interests; the cost of lease payments; the cost of construction; the cost of demolishing, removing, or relocating any buildings or structures on lands acquired, including the cost of acquiring any lands to which such buildings or structures may be moved or relocated; the cost of demolition of the current structure; the cost to relocate residents or businesses from properties acquired for the project; the cost of any extensions, enlargements, additions, and improvements; the cost of all labor, materials, machinery, and equipment, financing charges, and interest on all bonds prior to and during construction and, if deemed advisable by the Woodrow Wilson Memorial Bridge and Tunnel Authority, of such construction; the cost of engineering, financial and legal services, plans, specifications, studies, surveys, estimates of costs and revenues, and other expenses necessary or incident to determining the feasibility or practicability of constructing the project, administrative expenses, provisions for working capital, and reserves for interest and for extensions, enlargements, additions, and improvements; the cost of bond insurance and other devices designed to enhance the creditworthiness of the bonds; and such other expenses as may be necessary or incidental to the construction of the project, the financing of such construction, and the planning of the project in operation.</section><section prefix="3.">"Owner" includes all persons as defined in Article 1, &#xA7; 19 of the Code having any interest or title in and to property, rights, franchises, easements, and interests authorized to be acquired by this Compact.</section><section prefix="4.">"Project" means the upgrading of the Interstate Route 95 Potomac River crossing in accordance with the selected alternative developed by the Woodrow Wilson Bridge Coordinating Committee. "Project" includes on-going short-term rehabilitation and repair of the bridge and may include one or more of the following:</section><section prefix="a.">Construction of a new bridge in the vicinity of the bridge;</section><section prefix="b.">Construction of a tunnel in the vicinity of the bridge;</section><section prefix="c.">Long-term rehabilitation or reconstruction of the bridge;</section><section prefix="d.">Upon the bridges or within the tunnel described in subparagraphs a, b, and c, of this paragraph, or in conjunction with work on Interstate Route 95 and other approach roadways as described in subparagraph e of this paragraph:<section prefix="(1)">Work necessary to provide rights-of-way for a rail transit facility or bus or high occupancy vehicle lanes including the construction or modification of footings, piers, bridge deck, roadways, other structural support systems, and related improvements; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The construction of travel lanes for high occupancy vehicles or buses;</section></section><section prefix="e.">Work on Interstate Route 95 and other approach roadways if necessitated by, or necessary to accomplish, an activity described in subparagraphs a, b, or c of this paragraph; and</section><section prefix="f.">Construction or acquisition of any building, improvement, addition, replacement, appurtenance, land, interest in land, water right, air right, machinery, equipment, furnishing, landscaping, easement, utility, roadway, or other facility that is necessitated by, or necessary to accomplish an activity described in this paragraph.</section><section prefix="1.">The Authority shall be governed by a board of nine voting members and two nonvoting members appointed as follows:</section><section prefix="a.">Three members shall be appointed by and serve at the pleasure of the Governor of the Commonwealth of Virginia;</section><section prefix="b.">Three members shall be appointed by the Governor of the State of Maryland, with the advice and consent of the Senate of Maryland, and shall serve at the pleasure of the Governor of the State of Maryland;</section><section prefix="c.">Two members shall be appointed with the concurrence of the Governors of the Commonwealth of Virginia and the State of Maryland and the Mayor of the District of Columbia;</section><section prefix="d.">One member shall be appointed by the U.S. Secretary of Transportation; and</section><section prefix="e.">Two additional members, who shall be non-voting members, shall be appointed by the Mayor of the District of Columbia.</section><section prefix="2.">Members, other than members who are elected officials, shall have backgrounds in finance, construction lending, and infrastructure policy disciplines. At least one member of the Board from Maryland and one member of the Board from Virginia shall be elected officials each of whom represents a political subdivision that has jurisdiction over the area at an end of the bridge, bridges, or tunnel.</section><section prefix="3.">No person in the employment of or holding any official relationship to any person or company doing business with the Authority, or having any interest of any nature in any such person or company or affiliate or associate thereof, shall be eligible for appointment as a member or to serve as an employee of the Authority or to have any power or duty or receive any compensation in relation thereto.</section><section prefix="4.">The Chairperson of the Authority shall be elected from among the voting members on a biennial basis.</section><section prefix="5.">The voting members may also elect a secretary and a treasurer, or a secretary-treasurer, who may be members of the Authority, and prescribe their duties and powers.</section><section prefix="6."><section prefix="a.">Members appointed by the signatories shall serve a six-year term, except that each signatory shall make its appointments as follows:</section><section prefix="(1)">The initial terms of the three members appointed solely by each Governor shall be as follows:<section prefix="(i)">One member shall be appointed for a six-year term;</section><section prefix="(ii)">One member shall be appointed for a four-year term; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">One member shall be appointed for a two-year term.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The initial terms of the members appointed jointly by the Governors of the Commonwealth of Virginia and the State of Maryland and the Mayor of the District of Columbia shall be as follows:<section prefix="(i)">One member shall be appointed for a six-year term; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">One member shall be appointed for a four-year term.</section></section><section prefix="(3)">The initial terms of the nonvoting members appointed by the Mayor of the District of Columbia shall be as follows:<section prefix="(i)">One member shall be appointed for a six-year term; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">One member shall be appointed for a four-year term.</section></section></section><section prefix="b.">The term of the member appointed by the U.S. Secretary of Transportation shall be for two years.</section><section prefix="7.">The failure of a signatory or the Secretary of Transportation to appoint one or more members shall not impair the Authority's creation when the signatories are in compliance with the other terms of the Compact.</section><section prefix="8.">Any person appointed to fill a vacancy shall serve for the unexpired term. A member of the Authority may not serve for more than two terms.</section><section prefix="9.">The members of the Authority, including nonvoting members, if any, shall not be personally liable for any act done or action taken in their capacities as members of the Authority, nor shall they be personally liable for any bond, note, or other evidence of indebtedness issued by the Authority.</section><section prefix="10.">Six voting members shall constitute a quorum and a majority of the quorum shall be required for any action by the Authority, with the following exceptions:</section><section prefix="a.">Seven affirmative votes shall be required to approve bond issues and the annual budget of the Authority; and</section><section prefix="b.">A motion may not be approved if all three members appointed solely by each Governor cast negative votes.</section><section prefix="11.">Any sole source procurement of goods, services, or construction in excess of $250,000 shall require the prior approval of a majority of all of the voting members of the Authority.</section><section prefix="12.">Members shall serve without compensation and shall reside in the metropolitan Washington area. Members shall be entitled to reimbursement for their expenses incurred in attending the meetings of the Authority and while otherwise engaged in the discharge of their duties as members of the Authority.</section><section prefix="13.">The Authority may employ such engineering, technical, legal, clerical, and other personnel on a regular, part-time, or consulting basis as in its judgment, subject to the provisions of Chapter I, Article X of this Compact, may be necessary for the discharge of its duties. The Authority shall not be bound by any statute or regulation of any signatory in the employment or discharge of any officer or employee of the Authority, except as may be contained in this Compact.</section><section prefix="14."><section prefix="a.">The Authority shall establish its office for the conduct of its affairs at a location to be determined by the Authority and shall publish rules and regulations governing the conduct of its operations.</section></section><section prefix="b."><section prefix="(1)">These rules and regulations shall include, but shall not be limited to, an ethics code, public access to information, administrative procedures, and open meetings, and shall be consistent with similar practices currently adopted in Maryland, Virginia, and the District of Columbia.</section><section prefix="(2)">The Authority may adopt regulations after publication of notice of intention to adopt the regulations published in a newspaper of general circulation in the metropolitan Washington, D.C. area and after an opportunity for public comment.</section><section prefix="(3)">The Authority shall also publish a notice to adopt the regulations in the Maryland Register.</section></section><section prefix="1.">Any signatory may withdraw from the Compact upon one year's written notice to that effect to the other signatories. In the event of a withdrawal of one of the signatories from the Compact, the Compact shall be terminated; provided, however, that no revenue bonds, notes, or other evidence of obligation issued pursuant to Chapter II, Article VI or any other financial obligations of the Authority remain outstanding and that the withdrawing signatory has made a full accounting of its financial obligations, if any, to the other signatories.</section><section prefix="2.">Upon the termination of this Compact, the jurisdiction over the matters and persons covered by this Compact shall revert to the signatories and the federal government, as their interests may appear.</section><section prefix="1.">The Authority shall not undertake the ownership of the bridge, or any duties or responsibilities associated therewith, nor undertake any of the responsibilities and powers provided in this Compact until the Governors of the State of Maryland and the Commonwealth of Virginia and the Mayor of the District of Columbia have entered into an agreement with the U.S. Secretary of Transportation including provisions governing the transfer of the bridge from the federal government to the Authority, and which shall provide for a contractual commitment by the federal government to provide federal funding for the project including, at a minimum, a 100% share for the following:</section><section prefix="a.">The cost of the continuing rehabilitation of the bridge until such time as the project is operational;</section><section prefix="b.">An amount, as determined by the Woodrow Wilson Memorial Bridge Coordination Committee, equivalent to the cost of replacing the bridge with a comparable modern bridge designed according to current engineering standards;</section><section prefix="c.">The cost of planning, preliminary engineering and design, right-of-way acquisition, environmental studies and documentation, and final engineering for the project; and</section><section prefix="d.">A substantial contribution towards remaining project costs.</section><section prefix="2.">Such federal funds shall be in addition to and shall not diminish the federal transportation funding allocated or apportioned to the Commonwealth of Virginia and the State of Maryland. Upon all parties' approval of this agreement, the Authority shall have sole responsibility for duties concerning ownership, construction, operation, and maintenance of the project. At least 30 days before the Governor of Maryland enters into an agreement under this article, the Governor shall submit the agreement to the Legislative Policy Committee for its review and comment.</section><section prefix="1.">Within a reasonable period after this Compact becomes effective under Article VI of this Chapter, the Authority shall prepare and submit to the Governors of the Commonwealth of Virginia and the State of Maryland, and the Mayor of the District of Columbia, a management plan that includes:</section><section prefix="a.">An organizational structure;</section><section prefix="b.">A staffing plan that includes job descriptions; and</section><section prefix="c.">A proposed salary schedule consistent with existing salary schedules for similar positions in the State of Maryland, the Commonwealth of Virginia, and the District of Columbia.</section><section prefix="2.">The Authority shall not implement the provisions of this Compact until the Governors of the Commonwealth of Virginia and the State of Maryland and the Mayor of the District of Columbia have approved the management plan.</section><section prefix="3.">Subsequent to the approval of the management plan, the Authority may increase the number of its employees and their salary levels, provided that such increases do not result in a 20% increase above the level in the approved management plan. Increases in excess of 20% shall require an amendment to the approved plan. A proposed amendment shall be submitted to, and approved by, the Governors of the Commonwealth of Virginia and the State of Maryland, and the Mayor of the District of Columbia, prior to becoming effective.</section><section prefix="4.">In the conduct of its responsibilities and duties, the Authority shall maximize the use of existing public and private sector entities to provide necessary services, including management, construction, legal, accounting, and other services, as the Authority may deem necessary.</section><section prefix="1.">Except as provided herein, the Authority shall be liable for its contracts and for its torts and those of its directors, officers, employees, and agents. For tort actions arising out of conduct occurring in Maryland, Maryland tort and sovereign immunity law shall apply. The exclusive remedy for such breach of contracts and torts for which the Authority shall be liable, as herein provided, shall be by suit against the Authority. Nothing contained in this Act shall be construed as a waiver by the State of Maryland, the Commonwealth of Virginia, or the District of Columbia of any immunity from suit.</section><section prefix="2.">The United States district courts shall have original jurisdiction, concurrent with the courts of the Commonwealth of Virginia, the State of Maryland, and the District of Columbia, of all actions brought by or against the Authority. Any such action initiated in a state court or the Superior Court of the District of Columbia shall be removable to the appropriate United States district court in the manner provided by act of June 25, 1948, as amended (28 U.S.C. 1446).</section><section prefix="1.">If any part or provision of this Compact or the application thereof to any person or circumstance is adjudged invalid by any court of competent jurisdiction, the judgment shall be confined in its operation to the part, provision, or application directly involved in the controversy in which such judgment shall have been rendered and shall not affect or impair the validity of the remainder of this Compact or the application thereof to other persons or circumstances, and the signatories hereby declare that they would have entered into this Compact or the remainder thereof had the invalidity of such provision or application thereof been apparent.</section><section prefix="2.">This Compact shall be liberally construed to effectuate the purposes for which it is created.</section><section prefix="1.">To establish, finance, construct, maintain, repair, and operate the project;</section><section prefix="2.">To assume full rights of ownership of the bridge;</section><section prefix="3.">Subject to the approval of the Governors of the Commonwealth of Virginia and the State of Maryland and the Mayor of the District of Columbia of the portions of the project in their respective jurisdictions, and in accordance with the recommendations of the Woodrow Wilson Memorial Bridge Coordinating Committee, to determine the location, character, size, and capacity of the project; to establish, limit, and control such points of ingress to and egress from the project as may be necessary or desirable in the judgment of the Authority to ensure the proper operation and maintenance of the project; and to prohibit entrance to such project from any point or points not so designated;</section><section prefix="4.">To secure all necessary federal, state, and local authorizations, permits, and approvals for the construction, maintenance, repair, and operation of the project;</section><section prefix="5.">To adopt and amend bylaws for the regulation of its affairs and the conduct of its business;</section><section prefix="6.">To adopt and amend rules and regulations to carry out the powers granted by this section;</section><section prefix="7.">To acquire, by purchase or condemnation, in the name of the Authority; and to hold and dispose of real and personal property for the corporate purposes of the Authority;</section><section prefix="8.">To employ consulting engineers, a superintendent or manager of the project, and such other engineering, architectural, construction, and accounting experts, and inspectors, attorneys, and such other employees as may be deemed necessary, and within the limitations prescribed in this Act, and to prescribe their powers and duties and to fix their compensation;</section><section prefix="9.">To pay, from any available moneys, the cost of plans, specifications, surveys, estimates of cost and revenues, legal fees, and other expenses necessary or incident to determining the feasibility or practicability of financing, constructing, maintaining, repairing, and operating the project;</section><section prefix="10.">To issue revenue bonds, notes, or other evidence of obligation of the Authority, for any of its corporate purposes, payable solely from the tolls and revenues pledged for their payment, and to refund its bonds, all as provided in this Act;</section><section prefix="11.">To fix and revise from time to time and to charge and collect tolls and other charges for the use of the project;</section><section prefix="12.">To make and enter into all contracts or agreements, as the Authority may determine, which are necessary or incidental to the performance of its duties and to the execution of the powers granted under this Act;</section><section prefix="13.">To accept loans and grants of money, or materials or property at any time from the United States of America, the Commonwealth of Virginia, the State of Maryland, the District of Columbia, or any agency or instrumentality thereof;</section><section prefix="14.">To adopt an official seal and alter the seal at its pleasure;</section><section prefix="15.">Subject to Chapter I, Article IX, to sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, all in the name of the Authority;</section><section prefix="16.">To exercise any power usually possessed by private corporations performing similar functions, including the right to expend, solely from funds provided under the authority of this Act, such funds as may be considered by the Authority to be advisable or necessary in advertising its facilities and services to the traveling public;</section><section prefix="17.">To enter into contracts with existing governmental entities in the Commonwealth of Virginia, the State of Maryland, or the District of Columbia, or with private business entities for the purpose of allowing those entities to undertake all or portions of the project, including, but not limited to, design, engineering, financing, construction, and operation of the project, as the Authority may deem necessary;</section><section prefix="18.">To establish and maintain a police force, or to enter into a contract with an existing governmental entity in the State of Maryland, the Commonwealth of Virginia, or the District of Columbia to provide police services, as the Authority may deem necessary;</section><section prefix="19.">To enter into partnerships or grant concessions between the public and private sectors for the purpose of:</section><section prefix="A.">Financing, constructing, maintaining, improving, or operating the project; or</section><section prefix="B.">Fostering development of new transportation related technologies to be used in the construction and operation of the project, utilizing the law of any signatory in the discretion of the Authority;</section><section prefix="20.">To carry out or contract with other entities to carry out maintenance of traffic activities during the construction of the project that are considered necessary by the Authority to manage traffic and minimize congestion, such as public information campaigns, improvements designed to encourage appropriate use of alternative routes, use of high occupancy vehicles and transit services, and deployment and operation of intelligent transportation technologies; and</section><section prefix="21.">To do all acts and things necessary or incidental to the performance of its duties and the execution of its powers under this Act.</section><section prefix="1.">Except as provided in subsections 2, 3, and 6 of this Section B, and except in the case of procurement procedures otherwise expressly authorized by law, the Authority in conducting a procurement of goods, services, or construction shall: a. obtain full and open competition through the use of competitive procedures in accordance with the requirements of this section; and b. use the competitive procedure or combination of competitive procedures that is best suited under the circumstances of the procurement. In determining the competitive procedure appropriate under the circumstances, the Authority shall: a. solicit sealed bids if: (i) time permits the solicitation, submission, and evaluation of sealed bids; (ii) the award will be made on the basis of price and other price-related factors; (iii) it is not necessary to conduct discussions with the responding sources about their bids; and (iv) there is a reasonable expectation of receiving more than one sealed bid; or b. request competitive proposals if sealed bids are not appropriate under clause a. of this sentence.</section><section prefix="2.">The Authority may use procedures other than competitive procedures if: a. the goods, services, or construction needed by the Authority are available from only one responsible source and no other type of goods, services, or construction will satisfy the needs of the Authority; b. the Authority's need for the goods, services, or construction is of such an unusual and compelling urgency that the Authority would be seriously injured unless the Authority limits the number of sources from which it solicits bids or proposals; or c. the goods or services needed can be obtained through federal or other governmental sources at reasonable prices.</section><section prefix="3.">For the purpose of applying subsection 2.a. of this section: a. in the case of a contract for goods, services, or construction to be awarded on the basis of acceptance of an unsolicited proposal, the goods, services, or construction shall be deemed to be available from only one responsible source if the source has submitted an unsolicited proposal that demonstrates a concept: (i) that is unique and innovative or, in the case of a service, for which the source demonstrates a unique capability to provide the service; and (ii) the substance of which is not otherwise available to the Authority and does not resemble the substance of a pending competitive procurement. b. In the case of a follow-on contract for the continued development or production of a major system or highly specialized equipment or the continued provision of highly specialized services, the goods, services, or construction may be deemed to be available from only the original source and may be procured through procedures other than competitive procedures if it is likely that award to a source other than the original source would result in: (i) substantial duplication of cost to the Authority that is not expected to be recovered through competition; or (ii) unacceptable delays in fulfilling the Authority's needs.</section><section prefix="4.">If the Authority uses procedures other than competitive procedures to procure property, services, or construction under subsection 2.b. of this section, the Authority shall request offers from as many potential sources as is practicable under the circumstances.</section><section prefix="5."><section prefix="a.">To promote efficiency and economy in contracting, the Authority may use simplified acquisition procedures for purchases of property, services, and construction. b. For the purposes of this subsection, simplified acquisition procedures may be used for purchases for an amount that does not exceed the simplified acquisition threshold adopted by the federal government. c. A proposed purchase or contract for an amount above the simplified acquisition threshold may not be divided into several purchases or contracts for lesser amounts in order to use the procedures under paragraph a. of this subsection. d. In using simplified acquisition procedures, the Authority shall promote competition to the maximum extent practicable.</section></section><section prefix="6.">The Authority shall adopt policies and procedures to implement this section. The policies and procedures shall provide for publication of notice of procurements and other actions designed to secure competition where competitive procedures are used.</section><section prefix="7.">The Authority in its sole discretion may reject any and all bids or proposals received in response to a solicitation.</section><section prefix="8.">In structuring all procurements, the Authority shall comply with federal laws, regulations, or other federal requirements set forth in grant agreements or elsewhere, as they may be amended from time to time, governing minority business enterprise participation.</section><section prefix="(1)">Engaged in fresh pursuit of a suspected offender;</section><section prefix="(2)">Specially requested or permitted to do so in a political subdivision by its chief executive officer or its chief police officer; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Ordered to do so by the Governors of the State of Maryland, the Commonwealth of Virginia, or the Mayor of the District of Columbia, as the circumstances may require.</section></section></text>
</law>
