<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="21-106" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-21-106</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the conditions stated in this section, the driver of an emergency vehicle registered in any state may exercise the privileges set forth in this section while:<section prefix="(1)">Responding to an emergency call;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pursuing a violator or suspected violator of the law; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Responding to, but not while returning from, a fire alarm.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Under the circumstances stated in subsection (a) of this section, the driver of an emergency vehicle may:<section prefix="(1)">Park or stand without regard to the other provisions of this title;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pass a red or stop signal, a stop sign, or a yield sign, but only after slowing down as necessary for safety;</section><section prefix="(3)">Exceed any maximum speed limit, but only so long as the driver does not endanger life or property; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Disregard any traffic control device or regulation governing direction of movement or turning in a specified direction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the privileges set forth in this section apply only while the emergency vehicle is using audible and visual signals that meet the requirements of &#xA7; 22-218 of this article, except that an emergency vehicle operated as a police vehicle need not be equipped with or display the visual signals.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The privileges set forth in subsection (b)(1) of this section apply only while the emergency vehicle is using visual signals that meet the requirements of &#xA7; 22-218 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The driver of an emergency vehicle may not use flashing lights or a bell, siren, or exhaust whistle while returning from an emergency call or fire alarm, except that fire apparatus carrying standing firemen may use flashing lights that are visible only to the rear.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The driver of an emergency vehicle, while parking or backing the emergency vehicle, may use flashing lights within 100 feet of the entrance ramp to a:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section does not relieve the driver of an emergency vehicle from the duty to drive with due regard for the safety of all persons.</section>
  </text>
</law>
