<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-22-219</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>219</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Any vehicle may be equipped with and, when required under the Maryland Vehicle Law, shall be equipped with a stop lamp or lamps on the rear of the vehicle, which:<section prefix="(1)">Shall display a red or amber light, or any shade of color between red and amber, visible from a distance of not less than 300 feet to the rear in normal sunlight;</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall be actuated on application of the service (foot) brake; and</section><section prefix="(3)">May, but need not, be incorporated with one or more other rear lamps.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Any vehicle may be equipped with and, when required under &#xA7; 22-206(b) of this subtitle, shall be equipped with electric turn signals that indicate an intention to turn by flashing lights showing to the front and rear of a vehicle or on a combination of vehicles on the side of the vehicle or combination toward which the turn is to be made.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The lamps showing to the front shall be mounted on the same level and as widely spaced laterally as practicable and, when signaling, shall emit white or amber light, or any shade of light between white and amber.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The lamps showing to the rear shall be mounted on the same level and as widely spaced laterally as practicable, and, when signaling, shall emit a red or amber light, or any shade of color between red and amber.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Turn signal lamps on vehicles 80 inches or more in overall width shall be visible from a distance of not less than 500 feet in normal sunlight.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Turn signal lamps on vehicles less than 80 inches wide shall be visible at a distance of not less than 300 feet in normal sunlight.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">No lamp may project a glaring or dazzling light.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Turn signal lamps may, but need not, be incorporated in other lamps on the vehicle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
