<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-8-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this title the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Administration" means the State Highway Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Administrator" means the State Highway Administrator.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Bicycle and pedestrian priority area" means a geographical area where the enhancement of bicycle or pedestrian traffic is a priority.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Commission" means the State Roads Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Controlled access highway" means a major highway with the same characteristics as an expressway, except that the conflict of cross streams of traffic is not eliminated necessarily at each intersection by grade separation structures.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"County road" means any public highway:<section prefix="(1)">The title to which or the easement for the use of which, is vested in a public body or governmental agency; and</section><section prefix="(2)">That is not a State highway or located in Baltimore City.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Expressway" means a major highway of two or more traffic lanes in each direction that is designed to eliminate principal traffic hazards and has the following characteristics:<section prefix="(1)">A median divider separating opposing traffic lanes to eliminate head-on collisions and sideswiping;</section><section prefix="(2)">Grade separation structures to eliminate the conflict of cross streams of traffic at each intersection;</section><section prefix="(3)">Points of entrance and exit limited to predetermined locations;</section><section prefix="(4)">Vertical curves long enough to provide long sight distances; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Shoulders wide enough to permit vehicles to stop or park out of traffic lanes.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Highway" includes:<section prefix="(1)">Rights-of-way, roadway surfaces, roadway subgrades, shoulders, median dividers, drainage facilities and structures, related stormwater management facilities and structures, roadway cuts, roadway fills, guardrails, bridges, highway grade separation structures, railroad grade separations, tunnels, overpasses, underpasses, interchanges, entrance plazas, approaches, and other structures forming an integral part of a street, road, or highway, including bicycle and walking paths; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Any other property acquired for the construction, operation, or use of the highway.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Interstate highway" means a State highway that is part of the national interstate system in this State, as designated by the Administration and approved by the United States Secretary of Transportation under Title 23 of the United States Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Maintenance" means the upkeep and repair by which a highway, building, equipment, and other property is kept in an ordinarily efficient operating condition.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Maintenance" does not include construction, reconstruction, or relocation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Primary highway" means a State highway that has been designated a primary highway by the Administration with the approval of the Secretary.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Project" means the construction, reconstruction, or relocation of one or more sections or parts of the State highway system.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Railroad grade separation" means any overpass or underpass that eliminates a railroad grade crossing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Railroad grade separation" includes:<section prefix="(i)">The overpass and underpass structure and the approaches to them;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any related entrance plazas, interchanges, connecting highways, and other structures; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any other property acquired for the construction, operation, or use of the railroad grade separation.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Road" means a highway.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Secondary highway" means a State highway that is neither a primary highway nor interstate highway.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"State highway" means any public highway owned by this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"State highway system" means the system of State-owned primary and secondary highways throughout this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Street" means a highway.</section>
  </text>
</law>
