<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-210</section_number>
  <catch_line>If an omission or error in the filing, recording, or indexing of a security interest has been made b...</catch_line>
  <order_by>210</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an omission or error in the filing, recording, or indexing of a security interest has been made by an employee of the Administration in the course of employment and, as a result of the omission or error, any interested person has sustained loss or damage, the person may file a claim with the Administration for payment of the loss or damage out of the Assurance Fund maintained under &#xA7; 13-209 of this subtitle. The claim for payment shall include a request for a hearing on the matter and shall be made in the manner and on the form that the Administration requires.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A claim for payment under this section may not be made unless it is filed with the Administration within 3 years from the date the cause of action arose.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The amount of payment made for a claim under this section may not exceed $100,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Payment for a single claim may not be made from both the Assurance Fund and from the State Insurance Trust Fund under &#xA7; 12-104 of the State Government Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">After notice to all interested parties and a hearing on the claim, the Administration may:<section prefix="(1)">Order that any loss or damage sustained by the claimant be paid out of the Assurance Fund, subject to the limitations set forth in this section; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Order that the claim be dismissed and deny payment of the claim.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any aggrieved party to a hearing under this section may appeal from the decision of the Administration as follows:<section prefix="(i)">To the circuit court for the county in which the party resides or has his principal place of business; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the party does not reside or have a principal place of business in this State, to the Circuit Court for Anne Arundel County.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The circuit court to which an appeal is made under this section has jurisdiction to examine the facts of the case and to determine if the claimant is entitled under this section to recover for any loss or damage. The Administration shall pay the amount of any judgment recovered against the Assurance Fund up to the amount of the security interest to which the claim relates.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Assurance Fund is not liable under any circumstances for:<section prefix="(1)">Any loss or damage that exceeds the amount of the security interest to which the claim relates; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Any loss or damage that results from:<section prefix="(i)">The claimant's breach of any trust, whether expressed, implied, or constructive;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The improper use of the seal of any corporation to deal with the property or interest involved or to execute or take the benefit of the instrument recorded; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">The recording of an instrument executed by a person under legal disability, unless the fact of the disability is disclosed on the instrument.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If, in an appeal against the Administration, judgment is given in favor of the Administration or the appeal is dismissed at the request of the claimant, the claimant shall pay the full costs of the appeal.</section>
  </text>
</law>
