<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-208" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-5-208</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration may perform any act, issue and amend any order, adopt and amend any general or special rule, regulation, or procedure, and establish any minimum standard consistent with this title and necessary:<section prefix="(i)">To perform its duties and carry out the provisions of this title;</section><section prefix="(ii)">To protect the general public safety, the safety of persons who operate, use, or travel in aircraft, the safety of persons who receive instructions in flying or ground subjects that relate to aeronautics, or the safety of persons and property on land or water; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">To develop and promote aeronautics in this State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration may adopt rules and regulations by which a person engaging in aeronautics may be required to establish financial responsibility for any damage or injury that might be caused by the person.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Administration shall adopt rules and regulations requiring the use of security identification badges in airports consistent with any airport security program regulations adopted under this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">After notice and opportunity for a hearing as provided under &#xA7; 5-210 of this subtitle, the Administration may order a civil penalty not exceeding $1,000 for the misuse of a security identification badge in violation of an airport security program adopted under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A rule or regulation adopted by the Administration may not apply to any airport, airport facility, or air navigation facility that is owned or operated by the United States.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A rule, regulation, order, or standard of the Administration may not be inconsistent with or contrary to federal law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Copies of all rules, regulations, and standards shall be filed in accordance with the Administrative Procedure Act and the State Documents Law and shall be made available to the public.</section>
  </text>
</law>
