<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-210" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-4-210</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each year, the Authority shall develop and adopt a 6-year financial forecast for the operations of the Authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the Authority shall submit to the General Assembly:<section prefix="(1)">A draft of the financial forecast on submission of the budget bill to the presiding officers of the General Assembly; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The financial forecast as approved by the Authority on or before July 1 of each year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The financial forecast shall include the following components:<section prefix="(1)">A schedule of operating expenses;</section><section prefix="(2)">A schedule of revenues, including concessions income, investment income, other income, and transfers from the Department;</section><section prefix="(3)">A schedule of toll revenues, including the average toll per vehicle, the average toll increase, the number of paid vehicles, and the toll revenue by toll facility by fiscal year;</section><section prefix="(4)">A schedule of planned bond issuances, including a detailed summary of bonds issued to fund the capital program and bonds issued to fund capitalized interest;</section><section prefix="(5)">A schedule of debt service in each fiscal year for each bond issuance of all debt issued by the Authority, including debt service estimates of planned bond issuances; and</section><section prefix="(6)">A summary schedule for the Authority that includes:<section prefix="(i)">The total cash balance;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The amount of the cash balance that is encumbered;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The annual cash surplus or deficit;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Revenues;</section><section prefix="(v)">Transfers to the Department from the Authority;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Transfers to the Authority from the Department;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Bond sales;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Expenditures for debt service;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Operating expenses;</section><section prefix="(x)">Capital expenses;</section><section prefix="(xi)">Maintenance and operations expense reserve accounts;</section><section prefix="(xii)">Forecasted bond interest rates;</section><section prefix="(xiii)">Total bonds outstanding; and</section><section prefix="(xiv)">Financial coverage ratios, including the ratio of total cash to toll revenues, the debt service coverage ratio, and the rate covenant compliance ratio.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The financial forecast shall include, for each of the components specified in subsection (c) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">Actual information for the last full fiscal year; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Forecasts of the information for each of the 6 subsequent fiscal years, including the current fiscal year, the fiscal year for the proposed budget, and the next 4 subsequent fiscal years.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
