<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-22-201.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>201.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, if a driver of a vehicle on a highway operates the vehicle's windshield wipers for a continuous period of time because of impaired visibility resulting from unfavorable atmospheric conditions, the driver shall light the vehicle's headlamps or fog lights.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A violation of this section is not considered a moving violation for purposes of &#xA7; 16-402 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a person is convicted under this section, the conviction may not:<section prefix="(i)">Be considered evidence of negligence;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be considered evidence of contributory negligence;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Limit liability of a party or an insurer; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Diminish recovery for damages arising out of the ownership, maintenance, or operation of a motor vehicle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (3) of this subsection, a party, witness, or counsel may not make reference to a violation of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Nothing contained in this subsection may be construed to prohibit the right of a person to institute a civil action for damages against a dealer, manufacturer, distributor, factory branch, or other appropriate entity arising out of an incident that involves a defectively installed or defectively operating headlamp or fog light.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person who is convicted of a violation of subsection (a) of this section is subject to a fine not to exceed $25.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A police officer may enforce the provisions of this section only as a secondary action when the police officer detains a driver of a motor vehicle for a suspected violation of another provision of the Code.</section>
  </text>
</law>
