<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-12-113</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to &#xA7; 12-111 of this subtitle and &#xA7; 10-616(p) of the State Government Article, the Administ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>113</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to &#xA7; 12-111 of this subtitle and &#xA7; 10-616(p) of the State Government Article, the Administrator or any other officer or employee of the Administration designated by the Administrator may furnish on request a copy or a certified copy of any record of the Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration may establish and charge a fee for each record it furnishes or certifies. The revenue from the fee shall not be subject to the distribution provisions of Title 8, Subtitle 4 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">No charge shall be made to a police agency, fire department, or court in this or any other state or a police agency or court of the United States government.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The fee established and charged under this section may exceed the amounts authorized under &#xA7; 10-621 of the State Government Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A certified copy of any record of the Administration or comparable agency of any state is admissible in any judicial proceeding in the same manner as the original of the record.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A computer printout of any driving record or vehicle registration record of the Administration that has been obtained by a law enforcement unit, as defined in &#xA7; 10-101(f) of the Criminal Procedure Article, or court through a computer terminal tied into the Administration is admissible in any judicial proceeding in the same manner as the original of the record.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The computer printout of the driving record or vehicle registration record shall contain:<section prefix="1.">The date the record was printed; and</section><section prefix="2.">A jurisdiction code identifying the site where the record was printed.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a subpoena is issued to the Administrator or any other official or employee of the Administration for the production in any judicial proceeding of the original or a copy of any book, paper, entry, record, proceeding, or other document of the Administration:<section prefix="(i)">The Administrator or other official or employee of the Administration need not appear personally; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Submission of a certified copy or photostat  of the requested document is full compliance with the subpoena.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On motion and for good cause shown, the court may compel the attendance of an authorized representative of the Administration to answer the subpoena for the production of documents.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
