<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-27-110</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>110</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Administration may not register or transfer the registration of any vehicle involved in a failure to pay a toll violation under &#xA7; 21-1414 of this article if:<section prefix="(1)">It is notified by the Maryland Transportation Authority that a registered owner who has received a notice of violation of &#xA7; 21-1414 of this article has failed to either:<section prefix="(i)">Pay the toll and the civil penalty for the violation by the date specified in the notice of violation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">File a notice of intention to contest liability for the violation; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">It is notified by the District Court that a person who elected to contest liability for a violation of &#xA7; 21-1414 of this article has failed to appear for trial.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, the Administration may suspend the registration of a vehicle involved in a failure to pay a toll violation under &#xA7; 21-1414 of this article if notified by the Maryland Transportation Authority that the violator is a chronic offender.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In conjunction with the Maryland Transportation Authority, the Administration may adopt rules and regulations to define chronic offender and to develop procedures to carry out the suspension and refusal to register or transfer registration authorized by this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The procedures specified in this section are in addition to any other penalty provided by law for the failure to pay a toll or appear for trial for a failure to pay a toll violation under &#xA7; 21-1414 of this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
