<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="18-102" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-18-102</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration may not register any motor vehicle, trailer, or semitrailer to be rented until the owner of the vehicle certifies to the satisfaction of the Administration that the owner has security for the vehicle in the same form and providing for the same minimum benefits as the security required by Title 17 of this article for motor vehicles.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this paragraph, "replacement vehicle" means a vehicle that is loaned by an auto repair facility or a dealer, or that an individual rents temporarily, to use while a vehicle owned by the individual is not in use because of loss, as "loss" is defined in that individual's applicable private passenger automobile insurance policy, or because of breakdown, repair, service, or damage.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subject to subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph, an owner of a replacement vehicle may satisfy the requirement of paragraph (1) of this subsection by maintaining the required security described in &#xA7; 17-103 of this article that is secondary to any other valid and collectible coverage and that extends coverage to the owner's vehicle in amounts required under &#xA7; 17-103(b) of this article while it is used as a replacement vehicle.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If an owner of a replacement vehicle provides coverage as provided under subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the agreement for the replacement vehicle to be signed by the renter or the individual to whom the vehicle is loaned shall contain a provision on the face of the agreement, in at least 10 point bold type, that informs the individual that the coverage on the vehicle being serviced or repaired is primary coverage for the replacement vehicle and the coverage maintained by the owner on the replacement vehicle is secondary.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notwithstanding any provision of the rental agreement to the contrary, the security required under this section shall cover the owner of the vehicle and each person driving or using the vehicle with the permission of the owner or lessee.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the Administration finds that the vehicle owner has failed or is unable to maintain the required security, the Administration shall suspend the registration of the vehicle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
