<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="22-405.5" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-22-405.5</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not sell or offer for sale, at the point of final retail sale to the consumer, an unsafe tire, for use on a highway, that does not meet or exceed the requirements set forth in subsection (b) of this section or in regulations promulgated under &#xA7; 22-405(c) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A tire shall be considered unsafe if it:<section prefix="(1)">Has tread wear indicators and the tire is worn to the point that the tread wear indicators are flush with the tread at any place on the tire;</section><section prefix="(2)">Does not have tread wear indicators and the tire is worn so that less than 2/32 of an inch tread remains when measured in any groove at three locations spaced approximately equally around the outside of the tire; provided that motorcycle tires shall be allowed to be worn down to 1/32 of an inch, if measured under this paragraph;</section><section prefix="(3)">Has a worn spot that exposes the cord through the tread;</section><section prefix="(4)">Has tread cuts, snags, or sidewall cracks in any direction which are deep enough to expose body cords;</section><section prefix="(5)">Has visible bumps, bulges, or knots indicating partial failure or separation of the tire structure;</section><section prefix="(6)">Has unrepaired fabric breaks or the sidewall has damaged body cords;</section><section prefix="(7)">Has been regrooved or recut except as authorized in &#xA7; 22-405.1 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(8)">Is marked:<section prefix="(i)">For farm use only;</section><section prefix="(ii)">For off-highway use only; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">For racing use only.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A tire failing to meet the requirements of subsection (b) of this section may be sold for off-highway use only if the tire has permanently inscribed on its sidewall the letters "OH" at least 3/4 of an inch in height.</section>
  </text>
</law>
