<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-111.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>111.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When an applicant applies for an initial driver's license or for a class of driver's license other than that which the applicant currently holds, the applicant shall pay the Administration a license fee established by the Administration. This fee covers issuance of a learner's instructional permit and, if the applicant qualifies before the learner's instructional permit expires, issuance of a driver's license or provisional license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a learner's instructional permit is not required, the applicant shall pay the Administration, when the driver's license is issued, a license fee established by the Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If an appointment to take a driver's license examination made by the applicant is not kept, the Administration may charge the applicant a missed appointment fee established by the Administration.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, for the renewal of a noncommercial Class A, B, C, D, E, or M driver's license, a licensee shall pay the Administration a renewal fee established by the Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration may not charge a licensee who is a recipient of the Medal of Honor a fee for the renewal of the licensee's noncommercial Class A, B, C, D, E, or M driver's license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For issuance of a duplicate or corrected noncommercial Class A, B, C, D, E, or M driver's license, a licensee shall pay the Administration a duplicate or corrected driver's license fee established by the Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For conversion of a provisional license to a driver's license issued under &#xA7; 16-111.1 of this subtitle, a licensee shall pay the Administration a fee established by the Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A licensee shall pay a fee established by the Administration if the license is issued or renewed under &#xA7; 16-104.1 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whenever an applicant or licensee pays a fee required under subsection (a)(1) or (2) or (b) of this section, the Administration shall offer the individual the option to make a voluntary contribution of $1 to the Organ and Tissue Donation Awareness Fund established under Title 13, Subtitle 9 of the Health - General Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">All moneys collected under this subsection shall be paid to the Comptroller of the State and deposited into the Organ and Tissue Donation Awareness Fund established under Title 13, Subtitle 9 of the Health - General Article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
