<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-26-305</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>305</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Administration may not register or transfer the registration of any vehicle involved in a parking violation under this subtitle, a violation under any federal parking regulation that applies to property in this State under the jurisdiction of the U.S. government, a violation of &#xA7; 21-202(h) of this article as determined under &#xA7; 21-202.1 of this article or Title 21, Subtitle 8 of this article as determined under &#xA7; 21-809 or &#xA7; 21-810 of this article, or a violation of the State litter control law or a local law or ordinance adopted by Baltimore City relating to the unlawful disposal of litter as determined under &#xA7; 10-112 of the Criminal Law Article, if:<section prefix="(1)">It is notified by a political subdivision or authorized State agency that the person cited for the violation under this subtitle, &#xA7; 21-202.1, &#xA7; 21-809, or &#xA7; 21-810 of this article, or &#xA7; 10-112 of the Criminal Law Article has failed to either:<section prefix="(i)">Pay the fine for the violation by the date specified in the citation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">File a notice of his intention to stand trial for the violation;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">It is notified by the District Court that a person who has elected to stand trial for the violation under this subtitle, under &#xA7; 21-202.1, &#xA7; 21-809, or &#xA7; 21-810 of this article, or under &#xA7; 10-112 of the Criminal Law Article has failed to appear for trial; or</section><section prefix="(3)">It is notified by a U.S. District Court that a person cited for a violation under a federal parking regulation:<section prefix="(i)">Has failed to pay the fine for the violation by the date specified in the federal citation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Either has failed to file a notice of the person's intention to stand trial for the violation, or, if electing to stand trial, has failed to appear for trial.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, the Administration may suspend the registration of a vehicle involved in a parking violation under this subtitle or a violation under any federal parking regulation that applies to property in this State under the jurisdiction of the U.S. government if notified in accordance with subsection (a) of this section that the violator is a chronic offender.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration may adopt rules and regulations to define chronic offender and develop procedures to carry out the suspension of registration as authorized by this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Administration shall continue the suspension and refusal to register or transfer a registration of the vehicle until:<section prefix="(1)">If the suspension or refusal was required under subsection (a)(1) or (b)(1) of this section, the political subdivision or State agency notifies the Administration that the charge has been satisfied;</section><section prefix="(2)">If the suspension or refusal was required under subsection (a)(2) or (b)(1) of this section, the District Court notifies the Administration that the person cited has appeared for trial or has pleaded guilty and paid the fine for the violation; or</section><section prefix="(3)">If the suspension or refusal was required under subsection (a)(3) or (b)(1) of this section, the U.S. District Court notifies the Administration that the charge has been satisfied.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the registration of the vehicle has been suspended in accordance with subsection (b)(1) of this section, a person may not drive the vehicle on any highway in this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person convicted under paragraph (1) of this subsection is subject to the penalty set forth in &#xA7; 27-101(b) of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The procedures specified in this section are in addition to any other penalty provided by law for the failure to pay a fine or stand trial for a parking violation.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Administration shall adopt procedures by which the political subdivisions, State agencies, the District Court, and the U.S. District Court shall notify it of any restrictions and any rescission of restrictions placed on the registration of vehicles under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to any other fee or penalty provided by law, an owner of a vehicle who is denied registration of the vehicle under the provisions of this section shall pay a fee established by the Administration before renewal of the registration of the vehicle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The fee described under paragraph (1) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">May be distributed in part to a political subdivision acting as an agent of the Administration in the registration of a vehicle under &#xA7; 13-404 of this article if, based upon information provided to the Administration by the political subdivision under this section, the vehicle's prior registration was suspended or the vehicle's registration renewal was denied; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Except as provided under item (i) of this paragraph, shall be retained by the Administration and may not be credited to the Gasoline and Motor Vehicle Revenue Account for distribution under &#xA7; 8-403 or &#xA7; 8-404 of this article.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
