<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-920</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "tow truck" means a vehicle that:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>920</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section, "tow truck" means a vehicle that:<section prefix="(i)">Is a Class E (truck) vehicle that is designed to lift, pull, or carry a vehicle by a hoist or mechanical apparatus;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has a manufacturer's gross vehicle weight rating of 10,000 pounds or more; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is equipped as a tow truck or designed as a rollback as defined in &#xA7; 11-151.1 of this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In this section, "tow truck" does not include a truck tractor as defined in &#xA7; 11-172 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">When registered with the Administration every tow truck as defined in this section is a Class T vehicle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A tow truck registered under this section may be used to tow vehicles for repair, storage, or removal from the highway.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, for each vehicle registered under this section, the annual registration fee is based on the manufacturer's gross vehicle weight rating as follows:</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The annual registration fee for a vehicle registered under this section that is used for any purpose other than that described in subsection (c) of this section shall be determined under subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph if the maximum gross weight of the vehicle or combination of vehicles:<section prefix="1.">Exceeds 18,000 pounds and the vehicle has a manufacturer's gross weight rating of 26,000 pounds or less; or</section><section prefix="2.">Exceeds 35,000 pounds and the vehicle has a manufacturer's gross weight rating of more than 26,000 pounds.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual registration fee shall be the greater of:<section prefix="1.">The fees set forth in paragraph (1) of this subsection; or</section><section prefix="2.">The fees set forth in &#xA7; 13-916(b) of this subtitle.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Notwithstanding &#xA7;&#xA7; 24-104.1, 24-108, and 24-109 of this article, a tow truck registered under this section, while engaged in a tow, may move a vehicle or vehicle combination on a highway for safety reasons if:<section prefix="(1)">The tow truck and the vehicle or vehicle combination being towed comply with all applicable statutory weight and size restrictions under Title 24 of this article when measured or weighed separately; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The vehicle or vehicle combination is being towed by the safest and shortest practical route possible to the vehicle's destination.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, while engaged in towing, a tow truck registered under this section is subject to:<section prefix="(1)">Weight restrictions imposed on restricted bridges; and</section><section prefix="(2)">All applicable statutory weight and size restrictions under Title 24 of this article while being operated within the limits of Baltimore City, unless the vehicle is being operated on an interstate highway.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Except for tow trucks operated by dealers, automotive dismantlers and recyclers, and scrap processors displaying special registration plates issued under this title, the vehicle shall display a distinctive registration plate as authorized by the Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Subject to &#xA7; 25-111.1 of this article, a person who registers a tow truck under this section, including a dealer, an automotive dismantler and recycler, or a scrap processor who operates a tow truck in the State, or a person who operates a tow truck in this State that is registered under the laws of another state, shall:<section prefix="(1)">Obtain commercial liability insurance in the amount required by federal law for transporting property in interstate or foreign commerce; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide a federal employer identification number and, if applicable to the tow truck under federal requirements:<section prefix="(i)">A U.S. Department of Transportation motor carrier number; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">An Interstate Commerce Commission motor carrier authority number.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided under paragraph (2) of this subsection, a person may not operate a rollback in combination with a vehicle being towed unless the rollback is registered as a tow truck.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection does not apply to a vehicle that is registered and operated in accordance with &#xA7; 13-621 or &#xA7; 13-622 of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only to a vehicle required to be registered in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not operate a tow truck for hire unless the tow truck is registered under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A person convicted of operating a tow truck in violation of this subsection shall be subject to a fine not exceeding $3,000 or imprisonment not exceeding 1 year or both.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A tow truck that is improperly registered or unregistered shall be impounded.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
