<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-24-106.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>106.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A vehicle used to carry logs, poles, unfinished or unfabricated lumber, pipe, steel, or other materials of a similar kind, size, shape, or characteristic may not be driven on any highway unless its load is enclosed entirely within the sides and ends of the body of the vehicle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A vehicle used to carry logs, poles, unfinished or unfabricated lumber, pipe, steel, or other materials of a similar kind, size, shape, or characteristic may not be driven on any highway unless its load is fastened securely to both the front and rear of the vehicle at both the front and rear of the load, as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The fastening of a load to a vehicle shall be:<section prefix="(1)">By two separate common coil B.B. chains, the links of which may not be less than:<section prefix="(i)">3/8 of an inch in diameter for loads of 3 tons or less; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">1/2 of an inch in diameter for loads over 3 tons;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">If they have at least as much tensile strength as the chains, by:<section prefix="(i)">Wire rope not less than 5/16 of an inch in diameter;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Steel strapping;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Logistic webbing of synthetic fibers; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any fastening device specified in regulations adopted jointly by the Administration and the Department of State Police; or</section></section><section prefix="(3)">As specified in Part 393.102(b) (securement systems) of the federal Motor Carrier Safety Regulations.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The fastening devices specified in this section shall be fastened with an adequate load binder of standard make or other appropriate fastening device.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The fastening devices specified in this section may not be repaired or replaced by any material other than of the size, strength, and material specified in this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
