<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-619.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>The owner of a motor vehicle, or a lessee of the vehicle under a lease not intended as security, or ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>619.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The owner of a motor vehicle, or a lessee of the vehicle under a lease not intended as security, or a director, officer, employee, or partner of a business entity that owns the vehicle may apply to the Administration for the assignment of a special registration number and special registration plates under this section for a vehicle included in one of the following classes:<section prefix="(i)">A Class A (passenger) vehicle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A Class E (truck) vehicle with a one ton or less manufacturer's rated capacity;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A Class M (multipurpose) vehicle; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">A Class D (motorcycle) vehicle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To be eligible for a special registration described under subsection (c)(2)(i) of this section, an applicant shall provide proof that is satisfactory to the Administration that the applicant is a recipient of an individually earned, combat-related, armed forces medal.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">To be eligible for a special registration described under subsection (c)(2)(ii) of this section, an applicant shall provide proof that is satisfactory to the Administration that the applicant is an honorably discharged veteran of a branch of the armed forces of the United States.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">To be eligible for a special registration described under subsection (c)(2)(iii) of this section, an applicant shall provide proof that is satisfactory to the Administration that the applicant is a recipient of the U.S. Department of Defense Gold Star for surviving spouses, parents, and next of kin of members of the armed forces who lost their lives in combat.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to the annual registration fee otherwise required under this title, an owner of a vehicle assigned a special registration under this section shall pay a fee as determined by the Administration each time new registration plates are issued for the vehicle. The fee shall be calculated to recover the costs incurred by the Administration in carrying out the provisions of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The additional fee charged under this section shall be retained by the Administration for the purpose of recovering the Administration's costs under this section, and may not be credited to the Gasoline and Motor Vehicle Revenue Account for distribution under &#xA7; 8-403 or &#xA7; 8-404 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Special registration plates issued under this section:<section prefix="(1)">May consist of any combination of letters, numerals, or both; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall include:<section prefix="(i)">For registration plates issued for an applicant described in subsection (a)(2) of this section:<section prefix="1.">An emblem or logo as authorized by the Administration that depicts the applicant's armed forces medal; and</section><section prefix="2.">Except on plates issued for Class D (motorcycle) vehicles, words describing the medal printed across the bottom of the plates;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Words or an emblem or logo indicating that the special registration plate holder is an honorably discharged veteran of a branch of the armed forces of the United States; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">An emblem or logo indicating that the registration plate holder is the recipient of the U.S. Department of Defense Gold Star.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration, in consultation with the U.S. Department of Defense and appropriate representatives of the various branches of the armed forces, shall adopt regulations specifying those armed forces medals that are of the type described in subsection (a)(2) of this section and which, when awarded to an individual, qualify that individual to apply for special registration under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration may adopt other regulations as necessary to govern the issuance of special registration numbers and special registration plates under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If, whether by act of the parties or by operation of law, the title or ownership interest in a vehicle assigned a special registration under this section is transferred from the joint names of a husband and wife to the individual name of either spouse, the transferee may continue to use the same special registration plates issued under this section on the vehicle after the transfer.</section>
  </text>
</law>
