<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="23-206.2" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-23-206.2</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A motor vehicle for which special registration plates have been issued under &#xA7; 13-616 of this article is exempt from the mandatory inspections required by this subtitle if:<section prefix="(i)">All of the owners of the motor vehicle meet the disability requirements of &#xA7; 13-616(b)(1) of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The motor vehicle is driven 5,000 miles or less annually; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The exemption is not otherwise prohibited by federal law.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In order to qualify for an exemption under paragraph (1) of this subsection, all owners of the motor vehicle shall certify the following:<section prefix="(i)">That the owner of the motor vehicle meets the disability requirements of &#xA7; 13-616(b)(1) of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">That the motor vehicle has been issued a special disabled person's registration number and special registration plates under &#xA7; 13-616 of this article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">That the motor vehicle is driven 5,000 miles or less annually; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The motor vehicle's odometer reading at the time of the certification.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The certification required in paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be made on a form provided by the Administration.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A motor vehicle owned by an individual who is at least 70 years of age at the time of a scheduled mandatory inspection under this subtitle is exempt from the mandatory inspections required by this subtitle if:<section prefix="(i)">All of the owners of the motor vehicle are at least 70 years of age at the time of the scheduled mandatory inspection under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The motor vehicle is being driven 5,000 miles or less annually; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The exemption is not otherwise prohibited by federal law.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In order to qualify for an exemption under paragraph (1) of this subsection, all owners of the motor vehicle shall certify the following:<section prefix="(i)">That all of the owners of the motor vehicle are at least 70 years of age at the time of a scheduled mandatory inspection under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">That the motor vehicle is being driven 5,000 miles or less annually; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The motor vehicle's odometer reading at the time of the certification.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The certification required in paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be made on a form provided by the Administration.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Administrator may adopt regulations as necessary to administer or enforce the provisions of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
