<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-22-105</section_number>
  <catch_line>If any Class A (passenger) vehicle, any Class E truck with a manufacturer's rating or registered gro...</catch_line>
  <order_by>105</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If any Class A (passenger) vehicle, any Class E truck with a manufacturer's rating or registered gross vehicle weight of 18,000 pounds or less, or any Class M (multipurpose) vehicle has been altered in any manner that would reduce the effectiveness of its bumpers or suspension or render the vehicle dangerous in the event of a single vehicle accident or a collision with another vehicle, it may not be operated on any highway in this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Nothing in this section may be construed to exempt a vehicle from the application of paragraph (1) of this subsection solely because the vehicle is in compliance with the provisions of subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not operate a vehicle on any highway in the State if, as a result of post-manufacture alterations, the height of the vehicle's frame side rails or either of the vehicle's bumpers exceeds:<section prefix="(1)">In the case of a Class A (passenger) vehicle, 20 inches;</section><section prefix="(2)">In the case of a Class M (multipurpose) vehicle, 28 inches;</section><section prefix="(3)">In the case of a Class E truck with a manufacturer's rating or registered gross vehicle weight of 10,000 pounds or less, 28 inches; or</section><section prefix="(4)">In the case of a Class E truck with a manufacturer's rating or registered gross vehicle weight of more than 10,000 pounds but not more than 18,000 pounds:<section prefix="(i)">30 inches; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the truck is used for spraying agricultural crops, 32 inches.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Administration and the Automotive Safety Enforcement Division of the Department of State Police jointly shall adopt regulations relating to bumpers, frame side rails, and vehicle suspensions as necessary to implement and enforce the provisions of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
