<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="21-707" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-21-707</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Unless otherwise directed by a police officer or traffic control signal, the driver of a vehicle approaching a stop sign at an intersection shall stop at the near side of the intersection at a clearly marked stop line.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Unless otherwise directed by a police officer or traffic control signal, the driver of a vehicle approaching a stop sign at an intersection shall stop at the near side of the intersection and, if there is no clearly marked stop line, before entering any crosswalk.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Unless otherwise directed by a police officer or traffic control signal, the driver of a vehicle approaching a stop sign at an intersection shall stop at the near side of an intersection and, if there is no crosswalk, at the nearest point before entering the intersection that gives the driver a view of traffic approaching on the intersecting roadway.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The driver of a vehicle approaching a yield sign at an intersection, if required for safety to stop, shall stop at the near side of the intersection at a clearly marked stop line.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The driver of a vehicle approaching a yield sign at an intersection, if required for safety to stop, shall stop at the near side of the intersection and, if there is no clearly marked stop line, before entering any crosswalk.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The driver of a vehicle approaching a yield sign at an intersection, if required for safety to stop, shall stop at the near side of the intersection and, if there is no crosswalk, at the nearest point before entering the intersection that gives the driver a view of traffic approaching on the intersecting roadway.</section>
  </text>
</law>
