<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-23-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Division" means the Automotive Safety Enforcement Division of the Department of State Police.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Equipment" includes all mechanisms that form part of or relate to vehicle equipment.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Facility" means a licensed dealer or a vehicle garage, repair shop, or gasoline service station.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Inspection certificate" means a written certification by an inspection station that:<section prefix="(1)">Certifies that, as of its date, a specified vehicle meets or exceeds the standards for equipment established under this title; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is signed and dated on behalf of the inspection station by the registered individual who personally inspected the vehicle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Inspection station" means a facility that is licensed by the Division under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Police officer" means:<section prefix="(1)">Any uniformed police officer; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Any civilian employee of the Department of State Police or the Maryland Transportation Authority Police assigned to enforce this subtitle or any regulation adopted under this subtitle, but only while acting under written authorization of the Secretary of State Police.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Repair order certification" means a written certification by an inspection station or police department that:<section prefix="(1)">Certifies that, as of its date, the equipment specified in a safety equipment repair order meets or exceeds the standards established under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is signed and dated:<section prefix="(i)">On behalf of the inspection station by the registered individual who personally inspected the vehicle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">On behalf of the police department by the authorized police officer who personally inspected the vehicle.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Vehicle" means, except as otherwise provided in this subsection, any vehicle registered or to be registered in this State as:<section prefix="(i)">A Class A (passenger) vehicle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A Class M (multipurpose) vehicle;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A Class J (vanpool) vehicle;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A Class E (truck) vehicle;</section><section prefix="(v)">A Class F (tractor) vehicle;</section><section prefix="(vi)">A Class G (trailer) vehicle;</section><section prefix="(vii)">A Class B (for-hire) vehicle; or</section><section prefix="(viii)">A Class D (motorcycle) vehicle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of safety equipment repair orders only, "vehicle" means, except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, any motor vehicle, trailer, or semitrailer.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Vehicle" does not include any Class L (historic) vehicle, or any trailer which is a mobile home as defined by &#xA7; 11-134 of this article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
