<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="26-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-26-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Any person who commits a violation of the Maryland Vehicle Law, whether as a principal, agent, or accessory, is guilty of the violation.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Any person who attempts to commit a violation of the Maryland Vehicle Law, whether as a principal, agent, or accessory, is guilty of the violation.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any person who conspires to commit a violation of the Maryland Vehicle Law, whether as a principal, agent, or accessory, is guilty of the violation.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Any person who aids another in the commission of a violation of the Maryland Vehicle Law, whether as a principal, agent, or accessory, is guilty of the violation.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Any person who abets another in the commission of a violation of the Maryland Vehicle Law, whether as a principal, agent, or accessory, is guilty of the violation.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Any person who intentionally induces another to commit a violation of the Maryland Vehicle Law is guilty of the violation.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Any person who intentionally causes another to commit a violation of the Maryland Vehicle Law is guilty of the violation.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Any person who intentionally coerces another to commit a violation of the Maryland Vehicle Law is guilty of the violation.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Any person who intentionally permits another to commit a violation of the Maryland Vehicle Law is guilty of the violation.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">Any person who intentionally directs another to commit a violation of the Maryland Vehicle Law is guilty of the violation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
