<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="20-105.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-20-105.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to the information that is required to be given under &#xA7;&#xA7; 20-104 and 20-105 of this title, the driver of each vehicle involved in an accident under either of those sections shall also give the following information:<section prefix="(1)">Name and address of the insurance carrier or other provider of security for the person giving the information;</section><section prefix="(2)">Policy or other identifying number of the liability insurance or other security, if it is available;</section><section prefix="(3)">Name and address of the local insurance producer or local office of the insurance carrier or other provider of security, if it is available; and</section><section prefix="(4)">For a vehicle that is self-insured under the Administration's self-insurance program, evidence of self-insurance in the form required by the Administration.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration shall adopt regulations that:<section prefix="(i)">Establish the form and content of the evidence of self-insurance required under subsection (a)(4) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Require each self-insurer to maintain the evidence of self-insurance in each vehicle covered under the self-insurer's self-insurance certificate.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Regulations adopted by the Administration under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall require the evidence of self-insurance to include:<section prefix="(i)">The name, address, and self-insurance certificate number of the self-insurer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The name, address, and telephone number of the self-insurer's third party administrator or third party adjuster; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The vehicle identification number of the self-insured vehicle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The information specified in subsections (a) and (b) of this section shall be given to any person required to be notified under &#xA7; 20-104 or &#xA7; 20-105 of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
