<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-102" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-2-102</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The head of the Department is the Secretary of Transportation, who shall be appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary serves at the pleasure of the Governor and is responsible directly to the Governor. The Secretary shall counsel and advise the Governor on all matters assigned to the Department and is responsible for carrying out the Governor's policies on these matters.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Secretary is responsible for the operation of the Department and shall establish guidelines and procedures to promote the orderly and efficient administration of the Department. He may establish, reorganize, or abolish areas of responsibility in the Department as necessary to fulfill effectively the duties assigned to him. He may designate staff assistants to be in charge of the areas of responsibility he establishes.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Secretary may establish for employees of the Department a human resources management system under &#xA7; 2-103.4 of this subtitle that is not subject to or controlled by the provisions of State law relating to other State employees.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary is entitled to the salary provided in the State budget.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With the approval of the Governor, the Secretary shall appoint a deputy secretary who has the duties provided by law or delegated by the Secretary.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The deputy secretary is the acting secretary during periods when the Secretary is absent or disabled.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The deputy secretary serves at the pleasure of the Secretary and is entitled to the salary provided in the State budget.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The deputy secretary shall serve as acting chairman of the Maryland Transportation Authority, acting chairman of the Maryland Aviation Commission, and acting chairman of the Maryland Port Commission during periods when the Secretary is absent or disabled.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary may have in the Department the staff assistants, professional consultants, and employees provided in the State budget.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each staff assistant in charge of an area of responsibility and each professional consultant shall be appointed by and serves at the pleasure of the Secretary.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as otherwise provided by law, the Secretary shall appoint and remove all other personnel in accordance with:<section prefix="(i)">The provisions of the State Personnel and Pensions Article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A human resources management system established by the Secretary under &#xA7; 2-103.4 of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Secretary may delegate the authority to appoint and remove personnel of any unit to the head of that unit.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Wherever the Secretary is authorized by law to make an appointment to a particular position in the Department with the approval of the Governor, the Secretary may not remove the appointee without first obtaining the Governor's approval.</section>
  </text>
</law>
