<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-15-804</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>804</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to the information required under &#xA7; 15-102 of this title, each application for a license shall include:<section prefix="(1)">The name and business address of the drivers' school by whom the applicant is or will be employed; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A statement that the applicant himself is licensed to conduct a drivers' school.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "Central Repository" means the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository of the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration shall apply to the Central Repository for a State and national criminal history records check for each applicant.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">As part of the application for a criminal history records check, the Administration shall submit to the Central Repository:<section prefix="(i)">Two complete sets of the applicant's legible fingerprints taken on forms approved by the Director of the Central Repository and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The fee authorized under &#xA7; 10-221(b)(7) of the Criminal Procedure Article for access to Maryland criminal history records; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The mandatory processing fee required by the Federal Bureau of Investigation for a national criminal history records check.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-201 through 10-234 of the Criminal Procedure Article, the Central Repository shall forward to the applicant and the Administration the applicant's criminal history records information.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Information obtained from the Central Repository under this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">Is confidential and may not be redisseminated; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall be used only for the licensing purpose authorized by this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The subject of a criminal history records check under this subsection may contest the contents of the printed statement issued by the Central Repository as provided in &#xA7; 10-223 of the Criminal Procedure Article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
