<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-104.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-12-104.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Administrator may designate employees of the Investigative Division of the Administration to exercise the powers specified in subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An employee appointed under this section may issue citations to the extent authorized by the Administration for violations of:<section prefix="(i)">Those provisions of Title 13 of this article relating to:</section><section prefix="(ii)">Those provisions of Title 17 of this article relating to required security;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Those provisions of Title 14 of this article relating to falsified, altered, or forged documents and plates;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Those provisions of Title 16 of this article relating to unlawful application for a license and vehicle operation during periods of cancellation, revocation, and suspension of a driver's license;</section><section prefix="(v)">Those provisions of Title 21 of this article relating to special residential parking permits issued by the Administration;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Those provisions of &#xA7;&#xA7; 15-113 and 15-113.1 of this article relating to maintenance of and access to required business records;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Those provisions of Title 15 of this article relating to unlicensed business activity; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">Those provisions of this title relating to the issuance of an identification card.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The issuance of citations under this section shall comply with the requirements of &#xA7; 26-201 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Administration shall adopt regulations establishing:<section prefix="(1)">Qualifications for employees appointed under this section including prerequisites of character, training, experience, and education; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Standards for the performance of the duties assigned to employees appointed under this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
