<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-21-202.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>202.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Agency" means:<section prefix="(i)">For a traffic control signal operated and maintained at an intersection under the control of the State, the law enforcement agency primarily responsible for traffic control at that intersection; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">For a traffic control signal operated and maintained at an intersection under the control of a political subdivision, a law enforcement agency of the political subdivision that is authorized to issue citations for a violation of the Maryland Vehicle Law or of local traffic laws or regulations.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Owner" means the registered owner of a motor vehicle or a lessee of a motor vehicle under a lease of 6 months or more.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Owner" does not include a motor vehicle rental or leasing company or a holder of a special registration plate issued under Part III of Title 13, Subtitle 9 of this article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Recorded images" means images recorded by a traffic control signal monitoring system:<section prefix="(i)">On:<section prefix="1.">Two or more photographs;</section><section prefix="2.">Two or more microphotographs;</section><section prefix="3.">Two or more electronic images;</section><section prefix="4.">Videotape; or</section><section prefix="5.">Any other medium; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Showing the rear of a motor vehicle and, on at least one image or portion of tape, clearly identifying the registration plate number of the motor vehicle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Traffic control signal monitoring system" means a device with one or more motor vehicle sensors working in conjunction with a traffic control signal to produce recorded images of motor vehicles entering an intersection against a red signal indication.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The agency primarily responsible for traffic control at an intersection monitored by a traffic control signal monitoring system shall ensure that the length of time that a traffic control signal displays a yellow light before changing to a red signal indication is set in accordance with regulations adopted by the State Highway Administration consistent with standards or guidelines established by the Federal Highway Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section applies to a violation of &#xA7; 21-202(h) of this subtitle at an intersection monitored by a traffic control signal monitoring system.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless the driver of the motor vehicle received a citation from a police officer at the time of the violation, the owner or, in accordance with subsection (g)(5) of this section, the driver of a motor vehicle is subject to a civil penalty if the motor vehicle is recorded by a traffic control signal monitoring system while being operated in violation of &#xA7; 21-202(h) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A civil penalty under this subsection may not exceed $100.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For purposes of this section, the District Court shall prescribe:<section prefix="(i)">A uniform citation form consistent with subsection (e)(1) of this section and &#xA7; 7-302 of the Courts and Judicial Proceedings Article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A civil penalty, which shall be indicated on the citation, to be paid by persons who choose to prepay the civil penalty without appearing in District Court.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of paragraphs (2) through (4) of this subsection, an agency shall mail to the owner liable under subsection (d) of this section a citation which shall include:<section prefix="(i)">The name and address of the registered owner of the vehicle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The registration number of the motor vehicle involved in the violation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The violation charged;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The location of the intersection;</section><section prefix="(v)">The date and time of the violation;</section><section prefix="(vi)">A copy of the recorded image;</section><section prefix="(vii)">The amount of the civil penalty imposed and the date by which the civil penalty should be paid;</section><section prefix="(viii)">A signed statement by a technician employed by the agency that, based on inspection of recorded images, the motor vehicle was being operated in violation of &#xA7; 21-202(h) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ix)">A statement that recorded images are evidence of a violation of &#xA7; 21-202(h) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(x)">Information advising the person alleged to be liable under this section:<section prefix="1.">Of the manner and time in which liability as alleged in the citation may be contested in the District Court; and</section><section prefix="2.">Warning that failure to pay the civil penalty or to contest liability in a timely manner is an admission of liability and may result in refusal or suspension of the motor vehicle registration.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The agency may mail a warning notice in lieu of a citation to the owner liable under subsection (d) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in subsection (g)(5) of this section, a citation issued under this section shall be mailed no later than 2 weeks after the alleged violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An agency may not mail a citation to a person who is not an owner under subsection (a)(3)(ii) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A person who receives a citation under paragraph (1) of this subsection may:<section prefix="(i)">Pay the civil penalty, in accordance with instructions on the citation, directly to the political subdivision or to the District Court; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Elect to stand trial for the alleged violation.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A certificate alleging that the violation of &#xA7; 21-202(h) of this subtitle occurred, sworn to or affirmed by a duly authorized agent of the agency, based on inspection of recorded images produced by a traffic control signal monitoring system shall be evidence of the facts contained therein and shall be admissible in any proceeding alleging a violation under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Adjudication of liability shall be based on a preponderance of evidence.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The District Court may consider in defense of a violation:<section prefix="(i)">That the driver of the vehicle passed through the intersection in violation of &#xA7; 21-202(h) of this subtitle:<section prefix="1.">In order to yield the right-of-way to an emergency vehicle; or</section><section prefix="2.">As part of a funeral procession in accordance with &#xA7; 21-207 of this subtitle;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, that the motor vehicle or registration plates of the motor vehicle were stolen before the violation occurred and were not under the control or possession of the owner at the time of the violation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">That under &#xA7; 21-201 of this subtitle, this section is unenforceable against the owner because at the time and place of the alleged violation, the traffic control signal was not in proper position and legible enough to be seen by an ordinarily observant individual;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, evidence that the person named in the citation was not operating the vehicle at the time of the violation; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Any other issues and evidence that the District Court deems pertinent.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In order to demonstrate that the motor vehicle or the registration plates were stolen before the violation occurred and were not under the control or possession of the owner at the time of the violation, the owner must submit proof that a police report about the stolen motor vehicle or registration plates was filed in a timely manner.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">To satisfy the evidentiary burden under paragraph (1)(iv) of this subsection, the person named in the citation shall provide to the District Court evidence to the satisfaction of the court of who was operating the vehicle at the time of the violation, including, at a minimum, the operator's name and current address.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The provisions of this paragraph apply only to a citation that involves a Class E (truck) vehicle with a registered gross weight of 26,001 pounds or more, Class F (tractor) vehicle, Class G (trailer) vehicle operated in combination with a Class F (tractor) vehicle, and Class P (passenger bus) vehicle.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">To satisfy the evidentiary burden under paragraph (1)(iv) of this subsection, the person named in a citation described under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph may provide to the District Court a letter, sworn to or affirmed by the person and mailed by certified mail, return receipt requested, that:<section prefix="1.">States that the person named in the citation was not operating the vehicle at the time of the violation; and</section><section prefix="2.">Provides the name, address, and driver's license identification number of the person who was operating the vehicle at the time of the violation.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the District Court finds that the person named in the citation was not operating the vehicle at the time of the violation or receives evidence under paragraph (4)(ii)2 of this subsection identifying the person driving the vehicle at the time of the violation, the clerk of the court shall provide to the agency issuing the citation a copy of any evidence substantiating who was operating the vehicle at the time of the violation.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Upon the receipt of substantiating evidence from the District Court under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, an agency may issue a citation as provided in subsection (e) of this section to the person that the evidence indicates was operating the vehicle at the time of the violation.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A citation issued under subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph shall be mailed no later than 2 weeks after receipt of the evidence from the District Court.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">If the civil penalty is not paid and the violation is not contested, the Administration may refuse to register or reregister or may suspend the registration of the motor vehicle.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A violation for which a civil penalty is imposed under this section:<section prefix="(1)">Is not a moving violation for the purpose of assessing points under &#xA7; 16-402 of this article and may not be recorded by the Administration on the driving record of the owner or driver of the vehicle;</section><section prefix="(2)">May be treated as a parking violation for purposes of &#xA7; 26-305 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(3)">May not be considered in the provision of motor vehicle insurance coverage.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">In consultation with local governments, the chief judge of the District Court shall adopt procedures for the issuance of citations, the trial of civil violations, and the collection of civil penalties under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
