<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="22-218" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-22-218</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Every emergency vehicle, in addition to any other equipment and distinctive markings required by this subtitle, shall be equipped with a siren, exhaust whistle, or bell capable of giving an audible signal.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Every emergency vehicle, in addition to any other equipment and distinctive markings required by the Maryland Vehicle Law, shall be equipped with signal lamps mounted as high as practicable, which shall be capable of displaying to the front and to the rear a flashing red light or lights. These lights shall have sufficient intensity to be visible at 500 feet in normal sunlight.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Every school vehicle meeting the requirements established by the Administrator shall be equipped with alternately flashing warning lights in accordance with the standards adopted under &#xA7; 22-228 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not drive or move on any highway any vehicle or equipment that is equipped with or displays any light or signal device designed to emit an oscillating, rotating, blinking, or other type of emission of light, unless designated and authorized by the Administrator as indicated in paragraphs (2) through (12) of this subsection. The provisions of this section do not prohibit the display and use of any lighting device that may be permitted or required elsewhere in the Maryland Vehicle Law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Vehicles of the police department and other city, county, State, or federal law enforcement agencies may be equipped with and display red, white, or blue lights or signal devices.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Vehicles of city, county, State, or federal fire departments or duly constituted volunteer fire departments or rescue squads, or the Maryland Institute for Emergency Medical Services System, may be equipped with or display red and/or white lights or signal devices.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In each volunteer fire company, no more than five of the following officers may have their privately owned vehicles equipped with red lights or signal devices which may be displayed only while on route to or at the scene of an emergency:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)"/>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Ambulances may be equipped with or display red and/or white lights or signal devices.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">State vehicles used in response to oil or hazardous materials spills may be equipped with or display red and/or white lights or signal devices.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Service vehicles, rural letter carrier vehicles, slow moving farm vehicles, and tow trucks may be equipped with or display yellow or amber lights or signal devices.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">State vehicles designated for emergency use by the Commissioner of Correction may be equipped with or display red lights or signal devices.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">A vehicle used to provide public transit service may be equipped with and display:<section prefix="(i)">Amber flashing lights; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A white flashing light installed on the roof of the vehicle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(9)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraphs (ii) and (iii) of this paragraph, the blue, red, or white lights or signal devices may be flashed or oscillated or otherwise used only while on route to or at the scene of an emergency, and their use does not relieve an emergency vehicle from otherwise giving an audible warning as required elsewhere in the Maryland Vehicle Law.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The driver of an emergency vehicle may use flashing lights within 100 feet of the entrance ramp of a fire or rescue station while parking or backing the emergency vehicle.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The driver of an emergency vehicle of a fire department or rescue squad shall, at the discretion of the officer in charge, flash or oscillate or otherwise use red and white lights or signal devices while stopped, standing, or parked on the roadway at the scene of an emergency.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(10)">A stationary emergency vehicle serving as a mobile command unit may be equipped with or display a flashing, blinking, or oscillating green light or signal device to designate the vehicle as the command post.</section>
      <section prefix="(11)">The yellow or amber lights or signal devices permitted on vehicles under paragraph (6) of this subsection may be flashed or oscillated or otherwise used only in the course of official duties, to indicate to the public that the vehicle is a slow moving vehicle or otherwise is impeding traffic.</section>
      <section prefix="(12)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An emergency vehicle of any foreign state may be equipped with any lights or signals:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iii)">In addition to the penalties provided in Title 27 of this article, any person convicted of a violation of this section may have his driving privileges suspended for a period of 30 days, and the registration of the vehicle may be suspended for a period of 30 days, notwithstanding that the owner of the vehicle may not be the operator at the time of the offense, unless the owner proves to the satisfaction of the Administration that he had no control over the use or display of a light or signal device and could not prevent the violation of this section.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A police vehicle when used as an emergency vehicle may, but need not be, equipped with the flashing red and/or blue lights specified in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except as provided in subsection (c)(3) of this section, the flashing lighting described in subsections (b) and (c) of this section may not be used on any vehicle other than an emergency vehicle, service vehicle, or school vehicle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The use of the signal equipment described in this section imposes on drivers of other vehicles the obligation to yield the right-of-way and stop as required in Title 21 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">On taxicabs, the flashing green lights known as emergency hold-up lights may be mounted on the roof or outside rear and front of the vehicle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
