<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-5-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Administration" means the Maryland Aviation Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Aeronautics" means the science and art of flight.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Aeronautics" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Transportation by aircraft;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The operation, construction, repair, or maintenance of aircraft, aircraft power plants, and their accessories;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The repair, packing, and maintenance of parachutes;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The design, acquisition, establishment, construction, extension, operation, improvement, repair, regulation, or maintenance of airports, airport facilities, and air navigation facilities; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Instruction in flying and related ground subjects.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Air navigation facility" means any facility that is used in, available for use in, or designed for use in the aid of air navigation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Air navigation facility" includes any one or more or combination of structures, mechanisms, lights, beacons, markers, communication systems, and other instrumentalities or devices useful or designed for use as an aid or constituting an advantage or convenience to the safe taking off, navigation, and landing of aircraft or the safe and efficient operation or maintenance of an airport or airport facility.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Aircraft" means any device used or designed for navigation of or flight in the air.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Airport" means any area established for the landing and taking off of aircraft, including any appurtenant airport facilities.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Airport facility" includes any one or more or combination of:<section prefix="(1)">Lands, airfield improvements, terminal area improvements, general aviation facilities, air cargo facilities, general site improvements, utilities, roads, streets, parking lots, and other facilities useful or designed for use in connection with the operation of an airport; and</section><section prefix="(2)">All other appurtenances and equipment useful or designed for use in the handling of air carrier service, general aviation activities, and other related activities.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Airport hazard" means any structure, tree or other vegetation, or use of land that:<section prefix="(1)">Obstructs the airspace required for the landing and taking off of aircraft at an airport;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is hazardous to the landing or taking off of aircraft at an airport; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Interferes with communication between an airport and aircraft.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Commission" means the Maryland Aviation Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Executive Director" means the Executive Director of the Maryland Aviation Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Operate aircraft" means to navigate, pilot, or otherwise use aircraft in the air or on land or water.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Police officer" means any State or local officer authorized to make arrests for violations of State or local laws.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Structure" means any object constructed or placed on or above the ground, including any building, fence, derrick, haystack, pole, wire, tower, or smokestack.</section>
  </text>
</law>
