<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="21-1003" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-21-1003</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The provisions of this section apply except as necessary to avoid conflict with other traffic or in compliance with law or the directions of a police officer or traffic control device.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not stop, stand, or park a vehicle in front of a public driveway.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not stop, stand, or park a vehicle on a sidewalk.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person may not stop, stand, or park a vehicle in an intersection.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person may not stop, stand, or park a vehicle on a crosswalk.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person may not stop, stand, or park a vehicle between a safety zone and the adjacent curb or within 30 feet of points on the curb immediately opposite the ends of a safety zone, unless the State Highway Administration or local authority indicates a different length by signs or markings.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A person may not stop, stand, or park a vehicle alongside or opposite any highway excavation or obstruction if to do so would obstruct traffic.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A person may not stop, stand, or park a vehicle on any bridge or other elevated structure on a highway.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A person may not stop, stand, or park a vehicle in a highway tunnel.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">A person may not stop, stand, or park a vehicle at any place where stopping is prohibited by an official sign.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">A person may not stop, stand, or park a vehicle on any entrance or exit ramp of any highway with two or more lanes for traffic moving in the same direction.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">A person may not stand or park a vehicle in front of a private driveway without the consent of the owner or occupant of the premises.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">A person may not stand or park a vehicle within 15 feet of a fire hydrant.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply in Baltimore City.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not stand or park a vehicle within 20 feet of a crosswalk at an intersection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">A person may not stand or park a vehicle within 30 feet on the approach to any flashing signal, stop sign, yield sign, or traffic control signal located at the side of a roadway.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">A person may not stand or park a vehicle within 20 feet of the driveway entrance to any fire station or on the side of a highway opposite the entrance to any fire station within 75 feet of the entrance, if properly signposted.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">A person may not stand or park a vehicle at any place where standing is prohibited by an official sign.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">A person may not stand or park a vehicle on the roadway side of any other vehicle that is stopped or parked at the edge or curb of a highway.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">A person may not stand or park a vehicle on a curve or hill where solid lines on the surface of the roadway indicate a zone in which passing is prohibited.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">A person may not park a vehicle within 50 feet of the nearest rail in a railroad grade crossing.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">A person may not stop, stand, or park a vehicle unless for the use of an individual with a disability, in a space or zone marked as restricted for the use of individuals with disabilities.</section>
    <section prefix="(v)">A person may not park a vehicle on any property owned by the Board of Education of Montgomery County or Montgomery College where parking is prohibited by an official sign.</section>
    <section prefix="(w)">A person may not park a vehicle on any property owned by the Board of Education of Baltimore County or the community colleges of Baltimore County where parking is prohibited by an official sign.</section>
    <section prefix="(x)">A person may not park a vehicle on any property owned by the Board of Education of Wicomico County or the community colleges of Wicomico County where parking is prohibited by an official sign.</section>
    <section prefix="(y)">A person may not park a vehicle on any property owned by the Board of Education of Prince George's County where parking is prohibited by an official sign.</section>
    <section prefix="(z)">A person may not park a vehicle on any property owned by the Board of Education of Calvert County, Charles County, or St. Mary's County or the community colleges of Calvert County, Charles County, or St. Mary's County where parking is prohibited by an official sign.</section>
    <section prefix="(aa)">A person may not park a vehicle at any other place where parking is prohibited by an official sign.</section>
    <section prefix="(bb)">A person may not move a vehicle that he does not lawfully control into any prohibited area.</section>
    <section prefix="(cc)">A person may not move a vehicle that the person does not lawfully control away from a curb for an unlawful distance.</section>
    <section prefix="(dd)">A person may not stop, stand, or park a vehicle in front of a curb ramp designed for the use of individuals with disabilities.</section>
    <section prefix="(ee)">A person may not stop, stand, or park a vehicle in front of or on a passenger loading zone designed or marked for the use of individuals with disabilities.</section>
  </text>
</law>
