<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="24-102" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-24-102</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, for purposes of this section, the width of a vehicle includes any load that it carries and shall be exclusive of safety and energy conservation devices, such as side mirrors, turn signal lamps, marker lamps, steps and handholds for entry and egress, flexible fender extensions, mudflaps and spray suppressant devices, and load-induced tire bulges; providing the equipment or device, other than mirrors, does not extend more than 3 inches on each side of the vehicle beyond the statutory width limitation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of this section, the width of a motor home or travel trailer shall be exclusive of retractable awnings installed by the vehicle manufacturer or dealer, provided that the awnings do not extend more than 6 inches from each side of the vehicle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to any:<section prefix="(1)">Farm equipment;</section><section prefix="(2)">Vehicle transporting farm equipment; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Vehicle carrying a load of forage crops in connection with harvesting operations, if the distance traveled with the load on the highways in this State is less than 5 miles.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a vehicle may not be driven on any highway if the width of the vehicle exceeds 102 inches unless:<section prefix="(i)">It has a permit issued by the State Highway Administration under &#xA7; 24-112 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">As to a highway under the jurisdiction of a local authority, it has special permission from the local authority.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, the State Highway Administration or a local authority may prohibit the use of a highway or part of a highway under its jurisdiction by a vehicle exceeding a certain width if it finds that a vehicle exceeding a certain width likely would:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the State Highway Administration or a local authority imposes a vehicle width restriction under subparagraph (i) of this subsection, it shall place and maintain a sign providing notice of the restriction before the affected location.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
