<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-420" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-420</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A school type vehicle operated on a regular daily basis to transport students attending grades K through 12 shall be registered under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A school type vehicle otherwise operated to transport persons for educational purposes or maintained by an educational institution as part of a transportation system shall be registered, at the option of the registrant:<section prefix="(i)">Under this section; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Under any other appropriate section of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Administration may establish guidelines for the registration of school type vehicles in accordance with this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If it is only operated for the transportation of children, students, or teachers for educational purposes or in connection with a school activity or if it is operated, with approval from a board of education in any county, to provide transportation for persons 60 years old or older to civic, educational, social, or recreational activities, a Type I school vehicle (school bus) shall:<section prefix="(1)">Display distinctive "school bus" registration plates issued by the Administration; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Comply with all the requirements of the Maryland Vehicle Law and the regulations of the Administration that relate to a Type I school vehicle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If it is operated for any purpose in addition to those specified in subsection (b) of this section, a Type I school vehicle (school bus) shall display distinctive "school charter" registration plates issued by the Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration shall issue "school charter" plates:<section prefix="(i)">In place of and not in addition to "school bus" plates; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Only to vehicles complying with all the requirements of the Maryland Vehicle Law and the regulations of the Administration that relate to a Type I school vehicle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A Type II school vehicle shall:<section prefix="(1)">Display distinctive registration plates issued by the Administration; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Comply with all the requirements of the Maryland Vehicle Law and the regulations of the Administration that relate to a Type II school vehicle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
