<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-25-201</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Abandoned vehicle" means any motor vehicle, trailer, or semitrailer:<section prefix="(1)">That is inoperable and left unattended on public property for more than 48 hours;</section><section prefix="(2)">That has remained illegally on public property for more than 48 hours;</section><section prefix="(3)">That has remained on private property for more than 48 hours without the consent of the owner or person in control of the property;</section><section prefix="(4)">That has remained in a garage for more than 10 days after the garage keeper has given the owner of the vehicle notice by certified mail, return receipt requested, bearing a postmark from the United States Postal Service, to remove the vehicle;</section><section prefix="(5)">That has remained in a garage for more than 10 days after the period when, by contract, the vehicle was to remain in the garage;</section><section prefix="(6)">That was left for more than 10 days in a garage by:<section prefix="(i)">Someone other than its registered owner; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A person authorized to have possession of the vehicle under a contract of use, service, storage, or repair;</section></section><section prefix="(7)">That has remained on public property for more than 48 hours and:<section prefix="(i)">Is not displaying currently valid registration plates; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is displaying registration plates of another vehicle;</section></section><section prefix="(8)">That has been left unattended on any portion of a "controlled access highway" as defined in &#xA7; 8-101(f) of this article for more than 24 hours;</section><section prefix="(9)">That has been left unattended on any portion of a primary or secondary highway or controlled access highway, as defined in &#xA7; 8-101 of this article, and is in violation of any of the provisions of &#xA7; 22-408 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(10)">That is not reclaimed as provided under &#xA7; 27-111 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Garage" means any of the following, if operated for commercial purposes:<section prefix="(1)">A parking place or establishment;</section><section prefix="(2)">A vehicle storage facility; or</section><section prefix="(3)">An establishment for the servicing, repair, or maintenance of vehicles.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Lessor" means a person who regularly leases or offers to lease motor vehicles.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Lessor" includes:<section prefix="(i)">An assignee of leases; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A person who during any 12-month period offers to lease 5 or more motor vehicles or who is assigned 5 or more leases.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Police department" means:<section prefix="(1)">The Department of State Police;</section><section prefix="(2)">The police department of any political subdivision of this State;</section><section prefix="(3)">In Baltimore City, the appropriate agency designated by the Board of Estimates;</section><section prefix="(4)">The police forces of public colleges and universities;</section><section prefix="(5)">In Prince George's County, if designated by the County Executive, the Prince George's County Department of Environmental Resources;</section><section prefix="(6)">In any municipality in Prince George's County or Montgomery County, an appropriate agency or department designated by the governing body of the municipality; and</section><section prefix="(7)">The police force of any State government agency.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
