<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-114.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>To obtain a corrected photo commercial driver's license, an individual shall:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>114.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To obtain a corrected photo commercial driver's license, an individual shall:<section prefix="(1)">Apply for a corrected commercial driver's license on the form required by the Administration;</section><section prefix="(2)">Surrender the individual's original license; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Pay the required fee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A corrected photo commercial driver's license shall expire on the date that the individual's original license expired.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If an individual other than one who holds a commercial driver's license desires a corrected photo license in lieu of a correction card for a desired or required correction, the individual shall:<section prefix="(1)">Apply for a corrected photo license on the form required by the Administration;</section><section prefix="(2)">Surrender the individual's original license; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Pay the required fee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A corrected photo license issued under subsection (c) of this section to a driver at least 21 years old shall expire on the birth date of the licensee in the fifth year following the issuance of the license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A corrected photo license issued under subsection (c) of this section to a driver under age 21 years shall expire 60 days after the driver's 21st birthday.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a licensee applies for a photo license to correct an error made by the Administration, the Administration shall issue the corrected license without charging the licensee a fee.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an individual, other than one who holds a commercial driver's license, is temporarily absent from the State and desires a corrected license, the Administration may issue a nonphoto corrected license bearing the notation that it is valid without a photo until 15 days after the licensee first returns to this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The licensee shall:<section prefix="(i)">Apply for the corrected license on the form required by the Administration; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Pay the required fee.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
