<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-25-108</section_number>
  <catch_line>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL SEPTEMBER 30, 2013 PER CHAPTER 492 OF 2010 //...</catch_line>
  <order_by>108</order_by>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL SEPTEMBER 30, 2013 PER CHAPTER 492 OF 2010 //<section prefix="(a)"><section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section><section prefix="(2)">"HOV lane" means a high occupancy vehicle lane, the use of which is restricted by a traffic control device during specified times to vehicles carrying at least a specified number of occupants.</section><section prefix="(3)">"Plug-in vehicle" means a motor vehicle that:<section prefix="(i)">Is made by a manufacturer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is manufactured primarily for use on public streets, roads, and highways;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Has not been modified from original manufacturer specifications;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Is rated at not more than 8,500 pounds unloaded gross vehicle weight;</section><section prefix="(v)">Has a maximum speed capability of at least 65 miles per hour; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Is propelled to a significant extent by an electric motor that draws electricity from a battery that:<section prefix="1.">Has a capacity of not less than 4 kilowatt-hours for 4-wheeled motor vehicles and not less than 2.5 kilowatt-hours for 2-wheeled or 3-wheeled motor vehicles; and</section><section prefix="2.">Is capable of being recharged from an external source of electricity.</section></section></section></section><section prefix="(b)">Whenever the State Highway Administration designates a portion of a highway as an HOV lane, the HOV lane may be used at all times by plug-in vehicles that have obtained a permit from the Administration under this section, regardless of the number of passengers in the vehicle.</section><section prefix="(c)"><section prefix="(1)">The Administration, the State Highway Administration, and the Department of State Police shall consult to design a permit to designate a vehicle as a plug-in vehicle authorized to use an HOV lane.</section><section prefix="(2)">The Administration may charge a fee, not to exceed $20, for issuing a permit under this section.</section><section prefix="(3)">The Administration, on the recommendation of the State Highway Administration, may limit the number of permits issued to ensure HOV lane operations are not degraded to an unacceptable level.</section></section><section prefix="(d)">On or before January 1 of each year, the Administration and the State Highway Administration jointly shall report to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly on the effect of the use of the plug-in vehicle permits issued under this section on the operation of HOV lanes in the State.</section></text>
</law>
