<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-21-1207</section_number>
  <catch_line>If a bicycle or a motor scooter is used on a highway at any time when, due to insufficient light or ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1207</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a bicycle or a motor scooter is used on a highway at any time when, due to insufficient light or unfavorable atmospheric conditions, persons and vehicles on the highway are not clearly discernible at a distance of 1,000 feet, the bicycle or motor scooter shall be equipped:<section prefix="(i)">On the front, with a lamp that emits a white light visible from a distance of at least 500 feet to the front; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">On the rear, with a red reflector of a type approved by the Administration and visible from all distances from 600 feet to 100 feet to the rear when directly in front of lawful upper beams of head lamps on a motor vehicle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A bicycle or bicyclist may be equipped with a functioning lamp that acts as a reflector and emits a red light or a flashing amber light visible from a distance of 500 feet to the rear instead of or in addition to the red reflector required by paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to subsection (c) of this section, a person may operate a bicycle or a motor scooter that is equipped with a bell or other device capable of giving a signal audible for a distance of at least 100 feet.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A bicycle or motor scooter may not be equipped with nor may any person use on a bicycle any siren or whistle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Every bicycle and motor scooter shall be equipped with a braking system capable of stopping from a speed of 10 miles per hour within 15 feet on dry, level, clean pavement.</section>
  </text>
</law>
