<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-801" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-8-801</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Automobile graveyard" means an establishment or place of business that is maintained, operated, or used for storing wrecked, scrapped, ruined, or dismantled motor vehicles or motor vehicle parts.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Automotive dismantler and recycler facility" means an establishment or place of business that is maintained, operated, or used for storing, keeping, buying, or selling wrecked, scrapped, ruined, or dismantled motor vehicles or motor vehicle parts. All requirements in any statute, rule, or regulation applicable to automobile graveyards also apply to automobile dismantler and recycler facilities.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Junk" means old or scrap copper, brass, rope, rags, batteries, paper, trash, rubber debris, waste, iron, steel, and any other old or scrap material.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Junkyard" means an establishment or place of business that is maintained, operated, or used:<section prefix="(1)">For storing, keeping, buying, or selling junk;</section><section prefix="(2)">For an automobile graveyard; or</section><section prefix="(3)">As a garbage dump or sanitary fill.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Main traveled way" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 8-701 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Primary highway" means any State highway that is designated under this title as a primary highway and approved by the United States Secretary of Transportation under Title 23 of the United States Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Scrap metal processing facility" means an establishment:<section prefix="(1)">That has facilities for processing iron, steel, or nonferrous scrap metal; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The principal product of which is scrap iron, scrap steel, or nonferrous scrap for sale only for resmelting purposes.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
