<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-104.2" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-104.2</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Essential parts" means all integral and body parts, whether new or used, the removal, addition, alteration, or substitution of which would tend to conceal the identity of the vehicle or substantially alter its appearance, model, type, or mode of operation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Reconstructed vehicle" means any vehicle that:<section prefix="(i)">Is of a type required to be registered under this title; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has been materially altered from its original construction by the removal, addition, alteration, or substitution of essential parts.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Specially constructed vehicle" means any vehicle that:<section prefix="(i)">Is of a type required to be registered under this title;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Was not originally constructed under a distinctive name, make, model, or type by a generally recognized manufacturer of vehicles; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Has not been materially altered from its original construction.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If an application for a certificate of title is for a foreign vehicle previously titled or registered in another state or country, for a reconstructed vehicle, or for a specially constructed vehicle, the application also shall be accompanied by:<section prefix="(1)">Any information or documents the Administration reasonably requires to establish the ownership of the vehicle and the existence or nonexistence of security interests in it;</section><section prefix="(2)">Either:<section prefix="(i)">The certification of a person authorized by the Administration stating that the vehicle identification number of the vehicle has been inspected and found to conform to the description given in the application; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any other proof of the identity of the vehicle that the Administration reasonably requires; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">As to a foreign vehicle previously titled or registered in another state or country:<section prefix="(i)">Any certificate of title issued by the other state or country; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the other state or country does not issue a certificate of title for vehicles of the type to which the application refers, a certified bill of sale and any registration documents issued by that state or country.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
