<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-15-201</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Distributor" means a distributor who is authorized by the manufacturer or the manufacturer's authorized importer to enter into franchise agreements with dealers of:<section prefix="(1)">New motor vehicles constructed or assembled outside of the United States; or</section><section prefix="(2)">New two-stage vehicles completed outside of the United States by a second-stage manufacturer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Factory branch" means a branch office of a manufacturer from which the manufacturer:<section prefix="(1)">Sells or promotes the sale to dealers in this State of a particular brand or make of new motor vehicles, or new completed two-stage vehicles;</section><section prefix="(2)">Directs and supervises its representatives in this State; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Supervises or contacts its dealers or prospective dealers in this State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"License" means a manufacturer's, distributor's, or factory branch's license issued by the Administration under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Manufacturer" means:<section prefix="(1)">A manufacturer of new motor vehicles constructed or assembled in the United States;</section><section prefix="(2)">A second-stage manufacturer of new two-stage vehicles completed in the United States; and</section><section prefix="(3)">In the case of trucks, a person engaged in the business of manufacturing truck component parts.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Second-stage manufacturer" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 13-113.2 of this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
