<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-304" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-15-304</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, a person may not be licensed under this subtitle unless:<section prefix="(1)">The business to be conducted under the license is the only or principal business conducted from the fixed location specified in the application;</section><section prefix="(2)">That business is conducted from a building that is adequate and appropriate for the sale of the vehicles that may be sold under the license; and</section><section prefix="(3)">That business either:<section prefix="(i)">Maintains and operates an automotive repair facility equipped for reasonably adequate and proper servicing of the vehicles to be sold by it; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has an existing contract, approved by the Administration, that requires the contractor to service, at a reasonably convenient location, the vehicles to be sold by the business.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">As to trailers, semitrailers, motorcycles, Class C (funeral and ambulance) vehicles, or emergency vehicles as defined in &#xA7; 11-118(2), (5), and (6) of this article, the sale of these vehicles need not be the only or principal business conducted from the fixed location, but shall be subject to any reasonable location requirements determined by the Administration by rule or regulation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A wholesale dealer may be licensed under this subtitle regardless of whether the wholesale dealer meets the requirements of subsection (a)(1) and (3) of this section, but a wholesale dealer shall be subject to any reasonable location requirements determined by the Administration by rule or regulation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding the provisions of this section:<section prefix="(1)">A new vehicle dealer, or a licensed vehicle salesman who is employed by the dealer, may participate in 2 annual vehicle shows for each dealer location.</section><section prefix="(2)">A display or exhibit of vehicles provided by a vehicle manufacturer is not a vehicle show under this section if buyers' orders are not executed and deposits are not accepted.</section><section prefix="(3)">A new vehicle dealer franchised to sell Class M motor homes or Class G trailers, or a licensed salesman who is employed by the dealer, may participate in more than 2 annual vehicle shows, if the shows are limited to Class M motor homes or Class G trailers.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A vehicle dealer or licensed vehicle salesman listed in subsection (c) of this section may participate in a vehicle show if:<section prefix="(1)">The dealer holds a valid license issued under this title; and</section><section prefix="(2)">At least 60 days before the vehicle show, an application is filed with the Administration, for approval by the Administration, that contains:<section prefix="(i)">A list of the names and business addresses of participating dealers;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The location of the vehicle show;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The specific dates on which the vehicle show will be held; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Other reasonable information required by the Administration; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">The vehicle show does not exceed 10 consecutive days and is restricted to new vehicles only.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensed dealer, or a licensed vehicle salesman who is employed by the dealer, who participates in a vehicle show may execute a buyer's order and accept a deposit as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A licensed dealer may not accept a deposit that:<section prefix="(i)">For an order for any vehicle, except a Class M motor home, exceeds 5 percent of the cost of the vehicle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">For an order of a Class M motor home, exceeds 10 percent of the cost of the motor home.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as otherwise provided in paragraph (1) of this subsection, a licensed dealer, or a licensed vehicle salesman who is employed by the dealer, shall conduct activities involved in a vehicle sale, including the completion of the sales contract, the issuance of temporary registration plates and a temporary registration certificate, and delivery of the vehicle, at the dealer's fixed location as shown in the dealer's application for the license.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
