<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-112</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>112</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 13-113 of this subtitle, if an owner transfers his interest in a vehicle, other than by the creation of a security interest, the owner shall, at the time of the delivery of the vehicle, execute an assignment and warranty of title to the transferee, with a statement of each security interest, lien, or other encumbrance on the vehicle, in the space provided for that purpose on the certificate.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 13-113 of this subtitle, if an owner transfers his interest in a vehicle, other than by the creation of a security interest, the owner shall, at the time of the delivery of the vehicle, deliver the certificate of title to the transferee.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 13-113 of this subtitle, promptly after delivery to the transferee of the vehicle, the transferee shall:<section prefix="(i)">Complete an application for a new certificate of title, either in the space provided for that purpose on the certificate or as the Administration otherwise requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Mail or deliver the certificate and application to the Administration.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Administration does not receive the certificate and application within 30 days after delivery of the vehicle to the transferee, the Administration, in its discretion, may assess the applicant with an additional service fee established by the Administration for making the transfer of title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not knowingly sell, transfer, or otherwise dispose of any vehicle that has been used as a taxicab unless the person attaches to the certificate of title a signed statement to the effect that the vehicle has been used as a taxicab.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On receipt of a certificate of title to which is attached the information required by this subsection, the Administration shall place on the new certificate of title it issues a notation appropriate to convey this information to the new owner of the vehicle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">No person other than a dealer may buy in this State and no person may sell in this State any used vehicle of a type for which a certificate of title is required under this subtitle unless:<section prefix="(1)">A certificate of title of the vehicle has been issued by the Administration or by another state or country; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A certificate of registration of the vehicle has been issued by a state or country that does not issue certificates of title of such vehicles.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
