<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-506" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-506</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A salvage certificate shall be issued in accordance with the provisions of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A salvage certificate issued under this section shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be issued in the name of the applicant; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Serve as an ownership document.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(a-1)">For purposes of this section, a vehicle has not been acquired by an insurance company if an owner retains possession of the vehicle upon settlement of a claim concerning the vehicle by the insurance company in accordance with &#xA7; 13-506.1 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Administration shall issue a salvage certificate:<section prefix="(1)">To an insurance company or its authorized agent that:<section prefix="(i)">Is licensed to insure automobiles in this State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Acquires a vehicle as the result of a claim settlement; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Within 10 days after the date of settlement, applies for a salvage certificate as provided in subsection (c) of this section;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">To an automotive dismantler and recycler that:<section prefix="(i)">Acquires a salvage vehicle from a source other than an insurance company licensed to insure automobiles in this State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Acquires a salvage vehicle by a means other than a transfer of a salvage certificate; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Applies for a salvage certificate as provided in subsection (d) of this section; or</section></section><section prefix="(3)">To any other person who:<section prefix="(i)">Acquires or retains ownership of a vehicle that is salvage, as defined in &#xA7; 11-152 of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Applies for a salvage certificate on a form provided by the Administration; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Pays a fee established by the Administration.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For each vehicle that is acquired as a result of a claim settlement arising from an accident that occurred in the State, an insurance company or its authorized agent shall apply:<section prefix="(i)">For a salvage certificate on a form provided by the Administration for a vehicle titled in the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Electronically for a salvage certificate for a vehicle titled in a foreign jurisdiction.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The application under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be accompanied by:<section prefix="(i)">The certificate of title of the vehicle or, if the certificate of title is defective, lost, or destroyed, an affidavit of ownership on a form and in a manner prescribed by the Administration and a copy of the settlement check or other evidence of final payment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A statement by the insurance company that:</section><section prefix="(iii)">A fee established by the Administration.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to the provisions of &#xA7; 13-507(c)(2) of this subtitle, a salvage certificate issued under this paragraph shall contain a conspicuous notation by the Administration that describes which of the statements under paragraph (2)(ii) of this subsection applies to the vehicle.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">To determine the cost to repair a vehicle for highway operation for purposes of &#xA7; 11-152 of this article and paragraph (2)(ii) of this subsection, a person may not use the cost of:<section prefix="(i)">Towing, storage, or vehicle rental; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Repairing cosmetic damage.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The calculation under the 75% cost of repair threshold under paragraph (2) of this subsection may not affect the right of an insurer or a vehicle owner to make an economic or safety related decision to not repair the vehicle.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Administration, in consultation with the Department of State Police and other interested parties, shall adopt regulations to implement this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An automotive dismantler and recycler may apply for a salvage certificate on a form provided by the Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The application under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be accompanied by:<section prefix="(i)">The document through which ownership of the vehicle was acquired; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A fee established by the Administration.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Administration shall maintain records to indicate that a vehicle:<section prefix="(1)">Was transferred as salvage; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May not be titled or registered for operation in this State except in accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 13-506.1 and 13-507 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Administration shall establish a fee for:<section prefix="(1)">A duplicate salvage certificate; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A corrected salvage certificate.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
