<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-208" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-7-208</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the authority of the Secretary and, where applicable, the Maryland Transportation Authority, the Administration has jurisdiction:<section prefix="(1)">Consistent with the provisions of Division II of the State Finance and Procurement Article, for planning, developing, constructing, acquiring, financing, and operating the transit facilities authorized by this title; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Over the services performed by and the rentals, rates, fees, fares, and other charges imposed for the services performed by transit facilities owned or controlled by the Administration.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For fiscal year 2009 and each fiscal year thereafter, the Administration shall separately recover from fares and other operating revenues at least 35 percent of the total operating costs for:<section prefix="(i)">The Administration's bus, light rail, and Metro subway services in the Baltimore region; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">All passenger railroad services under the Administration's control.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration shall submit, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, an annual report to the Senate Budget and Taxation Committee, House Ways and Means Committee, and House Appropriations Committee by December 1 of each year that includes:<section prefix="(i)">Separate farebox recovery ratios for the prior fiscal year for:</section><section prefix="(ii)">A discussion of the success or failure to achieve the farebox recovery requirement established in paragraph (1) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Comparisons of farebox recovery ratios for the Administration's mass transit services and other similar transit systems nationwide; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The estimated fare prices necessary to achieve the farebox recovery requirement established in paragraph (1) of this subsection for the next fiscal year.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b-1)">Subject to &#xA7; 7-506 of this title, the Administration:<section prefix="(1)">Shall set the fare prices and collect other operating revenues in an amount sufficient to achieve the farebox recovery requirement established in subsection (b) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May not reduce the level of services provided by the Administration for the purpose of achieving the farebox recovery requirement.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For fiscal year 2009 and each fiscal year thereafter, the Administration shall implement performance indicators to track service efficiency for the Administration's mass transit services, including:<section prefix="(i)">Operating expenses per revenue vehicle mile;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Operating expenses per passenger trip; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Passenger trips per revenue vehicle mile.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration shall submit, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, an annual performance report to the Senate Budget and Taxation Committee, House Ways and Means Committee, and House Appropriations Committee by December 1 of each year on:<section prefix="(i)">The status of the performance indicators listed in paragraph (1) of this subsection for the prior fiscal year, including a discussion of the failure or success in meeting the goals established for the prior fiscal year by the Administration;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The status of managing-for-results goals of the Administration as they pertain to mass transit service in the Baltimore area;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Comparisons of performance indicators for the Administration's mass transit services and other similar systems nationwide; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The Administration's goals for each of the measures in paragraph (1) of this subsection for the next fiscal year.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration shall provide for an independent management audit of the operational costs and revenues of the Administration's mass transit services every 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The audit shall provide data on fares, cost containment measures, comparisons with other similar mass transit systems, and other information necessary in evaluating the operations of the Administration's mass transit system.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The findings from the audit shall be used as a benchmark for the annual performance reports.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The determinations of the Secretary, Administration, or Maryland Transportation Authority as to the type of service performed or the rentals, rates, fees, fares, and other charges imposed are not subject to judicial review or to the processes of any court.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this title or the Public Utilities Article, the Public Service Commission does not have any jurisdiction over transit facilities owned or controlled by the Administration or over any contractor operating these facilities.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Except as provided in this title, the Administration does not have any jurisdiction over transportation in the District by private carriers.</section>
  </text>
</law>
