<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-404.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>404.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Approved service provider" means a person who is certified by:<section prefix="(i)">The Administration to service, install, monitor, calibrate, and provide information on ignition interlock systems; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A manufacturer to be qualified to service, install, monitor, calibrate, and provide information on ignition interlock systems.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Manufacturer" means a person who manufactures ignition interlock systems and who certifies that approved service providers are qualified to service, install, monitor, calibrate, and provide information on ignition interlock systems.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Participant" means a participant in the Ignition Interlock System Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Program" means the Ignition Interlock System Program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration shall establish an Ignition Interlock System Program in accordance with this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration shall establish a protocol for the Program by regulations that require certain minimum standards for all service providers who service, install, monitor, calibrate, and provide information on ignition interlock systems and include requirements that:<section prefix="(i)">A service provider who applies to the Administration for certification as an approved service provider shall demonstrate that the service provider is able to competently service, install, monitor, calibrate, and provide information to the Administration at least every 30 days on individuals required to use ignition interlock systems;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A service provider who applies to the Administration for certification as an approved service provider shall be certified by a signed affidavit from the manufacturer that the service provider has been trained by an authorized manufacturer and that the service provider is competent to service, install, monitor, calibrate, and provide information on ignition interlock systems;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Approved service providers be deemed to be authorized representatives of a manufacturer; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any service of notice upon an approved service provider, who has violated any laws or regulations or whose ignition interlock system has violated any laws or regulations, be deemed as service upon the manufacturer who certified the approved service provider.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An individual may be a participant if:<section prefix="(1)">The individual's license is suspended or revoked under &#xA7; 16-205 of this title for a violation of &#xA7; 21-902(a), (b), or (c) of this article or &#xA7; 16-404 of this subtitle for an accumulation of points under &#xA7; 16-402(a)(25) or (34) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">The individual's license has an alcohol restriction imposed under &#xA7; 16-113(g)(1) of this title; or</section><section prefix="(3)">The Administration modifies a suspension or issues a restrictive license to the individual under &#xA7; 16-205.1 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Notwithstanding subsection (c) of this section, an individual shall be a participant if the individual is convicted of a violation of &#xA7; 21-902(a) of this article and had an alcohol concentration at the time of testing of 0.15 or more.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If an individual is subject to this paragraph and fails to participate in the Program or successfully complete the Program, the Administration shall suspend, notwithstanding &#xA7; 16-208 of this title, the individual's license until the individual successfully completes the Program.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Nothing contained in this paragraph limits the authority of the Administration to modify a suspension imposed under this paragraph to allow an individual to be a participant in accordance with subsection (e) or (o) of this section.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Notwithstanding subsection (c) of this section, an individual shall be a participant as a condition of modification of a suspension or revocation of a license or issuance of a restrictive license if the individual:<section prefix="1.">Is required to be a participant by a court order under &#xA7; 27-107 of this article;</section><section prefix="2.">Is convicted of a violation of &#xA7; 21-902(a) or (b) of this article and within the preceding 5 years the individual has been convicted of any violation of &#xA7; 21-902 of this article; or</section><section prefix="3.">Was under the age of 21 years on the date of a violation by the individual of:</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If an individual is subject to this paragraph and the individual fails to participate in the Program or does not successfully complete the Program, the Administration shall suspend the individual's license for 1 year.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Nothing contained in this paragraph limits the authority of the Administration to modify a suspension imposed under this paragraph to allow an individual to be a participant in accordance with subsection (e) or (o) of this section.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An individual who is subject to this subsection shall participate in the Program for:<section prefix="(i)">6 months the first time the individual is required under this subsection to participate in the Program;</section><section prefix="(ii)">1 year the second time the individual is required under this subsection to participate in the Program; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">3 years the third or any subsequent time the individual is required under this subsection to participate in the Program.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Paragraph (3) of this subsection does not limit a longer period of Program participation that is required by:<section prefix="(i)">A court order under &#xA7; 27-107 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Administration in accordance with another provision of this title.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If an individual subject to subsection (c) or (d) of this section does not initially become a participant:<section prefix="(1)">The individual may apply later to the Administration to be a participant; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The Administration may reconsider any suspension or revocation of the driver's license of the individual arising out of the same circumstances and allow the individual to participate in the Program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration may:<section prefix="(i)">Issue a restrictive license to an individual who is a participant in the Program during the suspension period as provided under &#xA7; 16-205 or &#xA7; 16-205.1 of this title or &#xA7; 16-404 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Reinstate the driver's license of a participant whose license has been revoked for a violation of &#xA7; 21-902(a), (b), or (c) of this article or revoked for an accumulation of points under &#xA7; 16-402(a)(34) of this subtitle for a violation of &#xA7; 21-902(a) of this article; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, impose on a participant a period of suspension in accordance with &#xA7; 16-404(c)(2) and (3) of this subtitle in lieu of a license revocation for:<section prefix="1.">A violation of &#xA7; 21-902(a), (b), or (c) of this article; or</section><section prefix="2.">An accumulation of points under &#xA7; 16-402(a)(34) of this subtitle for a violation of &#xA7; 21-902(a) of this article.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A notice of suspension or revocation sent to an individual under this title shall include information about the Program and how individuals participate in the Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Administration shall establish a fee for the Program that is sufficient to cover the costs of the Program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Subject to &#xA7; 27-107(g)(2) of this article, the Administration shall impose a restriction on the individual's license that prohibits the individual from driving a motor vehicle that is not equipped with an ignition interlock system for the period of time that the individual is required to participate in the Program under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A participant is considered to begin participation in the Program when the participant provides evidence of the installation of an ignition interlock system by an approved service provider in a manner required by the Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">An individual whose license is suspended under &#xA7; 16-404(c)(2)(iv) of this subtitle is a habitual offender whose license may not be reinstated unless the individual participates in the Program for at least 24 months.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For purposes of an ignition interlock system used under &#xA7; 16-205(f) of this title, this section, or a court order under &#xA7; 27-107 of this article, the Administration shall permit only the use of an ignition interlock system that meets or exceeds the technical standards for breath alcohol ignition interlock devices published in the Federal Register from time to time.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of an ignition interlock system used under this section, the Administration shall require the Program protocol adopted by the Administration.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual required to use an ignition interlock system under a court order or this section:<section prefix="(i)">Shall be monitored by the Administration; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, shall pay the fee required by the Administration under subsection (f)(3) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration shall waive the fee required under this subsection for an individual who is indigent.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">A court order that requires the use of an ignition interlock system is not affected by &#xA7; 16-404(c)(3) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">If an individual participates in the Program under this section and participates in the Program in accordance with any other provision of law arising out of the same incident, the periods of participation in the Program shall be concurrent.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">If an individual successfully completes the Program and the individual's license is not refused, revoked, suspended, or canceled under another provision of this article, the Administration shall immediately issue a license to the licensee.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding &#xA7; 16-208 of this title, if the Administration removes an individual from the Program because the individual violated requirements of the Program, the Administration may allow the individual to reenter the Program after a period of 30 days from the date of removal.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an individual reenters the Program under this subsection, the individual shall participate in the Program for the entire period of time that was initially necessary for successful completion of the Program without any credit for the period of participation before the individual was removed from the Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Nothing contained in paragraph (2) of this subsection limits a period of participation in the Program required under any other provision of this title or &#xA7; 27-107 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">A suspension or revocation of a license of an individual subject to subsection (c) or (d) of this section that is imposed as a result of the failure of the individual to participate in the Program or successfully complete the Program shall be concurrent with any other suspension or revocation arising out of the same incident for which the individual is subject to subsection (c) or (d) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a person is convicted of any violation of &#xA7; 21-902 of this article, the Administration shall include in the notice of proposed suspension or revocation a warning in bold conspicuous type that the person shall participate in the Program if the person is subsequently convicted of a violation of &#xA7; 21-902(a) or (b) of this article as described in this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the time that the Administration issues a license to a person who is under the age of 21 years, the Administration shall provide to the person a written warning in bold conspicuous type that the person shall participate in the Program if the Administration finds the person violated the alcohol restriction on a driver under the age of 21 years or the person violated any provision of &#xA7; 21-902 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A person may not raise the absence of the warning described under this subsection or the failure to receive that warning as a basis for limiting the authority of the Administration to require that the person participate in the Program in accordance with this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
