<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-606" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-2-606</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Governor shall appoint a Bicycle and Pedestrian Advisory Committee to provide guidance to State agencies concerning:<section prefix="(1)">Funding of bicycle and pedestrian related programs;</section><section prefix="(2)">Public education and awareness of bicycling and pedestrian related activities;</section><section prefix="(3)">Public education and awareness of bicycling and pedestrian safety; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Any other issue directly related to bicycling and pedestrians.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Committee shall consist of the following:<section prefix="(1)">One representative each from:<section prefix="(i)">The Department of Transportation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Department of Natural Resources;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The State Department of Education;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The Department of State Police;</section><section prefix="(v)">The Department of Business and Economic Development;</section><section prefix="(vi)">The Department of Health and Mental Hygiene;</section><section prefix="(vii)">The Department of Planning;</section><section prefix="(viii)">The Department of Disabilities; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">The Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">One citizen member from each of the following areas:<section prefix="(i)">The Eastern Shore;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Western Maryland; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Southern Maryland;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Two citizen members from each of the following areas:<section prefix="(i)">The Baltimore metropolitan area; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Washington metropolitan area; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">Up to six citizen members selected to represent the interests of bicyclists, pedestrians, and the disabled community to include:<section prefix="(i)">A representative of individuals who are visually impaired; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A representative of individuals who are mobility impaired.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">One of the citizen members selected under subsection (b) of this section shall have an expertise in bicycle and pedestrian safety.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The total membership of the Committee may not exceed 22 members.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Governor shall select a chairman from among the citizen members.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Committee on October 1, 2001.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Committee may adopt procedures necessary to ensure the orderly transaction of business.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Committee shall hold regular meetings as it deems appropriate.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A member of the Committee may not receive compensation but shall be reimbursed for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided for in the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The Department shall provide staff, administrative support, and operating expenses for the Committee as provided in the State budget.</section>
  </text>
</law>
