<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-206" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-6-206</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to Subtitle 4 of this title, the Administration may:<section prefix="(1)">Provide for the preservation of navigation within its territorial jurisdiction, including the establishment of lines beyond which piers, bulkheads, wharves, pilings, structures, obstructions, or extensions may not be made or extended;</section><section prefix="(2)">In order to foster and facilitate navigation and prevent injury to persons or property:<section prefix="(i)">Prohibit, provide for, and regulate within its territorial jurisdiction the shipment, storage, handling, and transportation of explosives and other materials that it determines to be dangerous;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provide for the stationing, anchoring, and moving of vessels or other watercraft; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Adopt rules and regulations to prevent any refuse or other matter from being thrown into, deposited in, or placed where it may fall or be washed into any navigable waters;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Make surveys or charts of navigable waters within its territorial jurisdiction and ascertain the depth and course of the channels of these waters;</section><section prefix="(4)">In order to prevent injury to navigation or health:<section prefix="(i)">Erect, maintain, and authorize the erection and maintenance of wharves, bulkheads, piers, and pilings; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Adopt regulations governing their erection, maintenance, and repair, including regulations concerning the erection, maintenance, or repair of any wharf, dock, pier, bulkhead, or piling that is associated with the construction of a dwelling unit or other nonwater dependent structure on a pier; and</section></section><section prefix="(5)">As to wharves, docks, piers, bulkheads, or pilings, it owns or controls:<section prefix="(i)">Regulate their use;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Lease or rent them;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Impose and collect dockage from vessels and watercraft lying at or using them; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Collect wharfage and other charges on goods, wares, merchandise, or other articles landed at, shipped from, stored on, or passed over them.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except for docks or wharves owned, controlled, or operated by the Administration, this title does not:<section prefix="(1)">Impose any duty on the Administration as to the safety of any person using any waters;</section><section prefix="(2)">Render the Administration liable for any loss of life, injury, or damage to any person or property because of any obstruction in or unsafe condition of any part of the waters; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Render the Administration liable for any failure to adopt or enforce any rule or regulation under this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The powers in this section may not be exercised in any county unless the county approves the operations of the Administration in the county.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any ordinance or regulation that was adopted before June 1, 1959 by any State agency, political subdivision, or other public body and that relates to a subject matter over which authority is granted to the Administration by subsection (a) of this section:<section prefix="(i)">Continues to be in effect, except as otherwise provided in this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has the status of a regulation adopted by the Administration; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Like other regulations of the Administration, may be readopted, amended, or repealed by the Administration.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Only the Administration may readopt, amend, or repeal these ordinances or regulations.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
