<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-21-1107</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1107</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to subsection (c) of this section, this section applies to:<section prefix="(1)">A truck that has a gross vehicle weight rating of 10,001 pounds or more; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A truck/trailer or truck tractor/semitrailer or trailer combination that has a combined gross vehicle weight rating of 10,001 pounds or more.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">While a vehicle subject to this section is being operated on a highway:<section prefix="(1)">The driver may not allow a person to occupy the area of the vehicle primarily intended to carry cargo; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A person may not occupy the area of the vehicle primarily intended to carry cargo.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">An attendant delegated to care for livestock;</section><section prefix="(2)">A vehicle that is controlled or operated by a farmer and is:<section prefix="(i)">Used to transport agricultural products, farm machinery, or farm supplies to or from a farm;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Not used in the operations of a common or contract motor carrier; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Used within 150 miles of the farmer's farm;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">A vehicle owned or operated by the U.S. Department of Defense if the vehicle is controlled or operated by:<section prefix="(i)">Active duty military personnel; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A member of the military reserves or National Guard on active duty, including personnel on full-time National Guard duty and personnel on part-time training; or</section></section><section prefix="(4)">A vehicle traveling at a speed of not more than 25 miles per hour.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
