<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-15-113.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>113.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Automotive repair facility" means a facility where malfunctions of a motor vehicle are diagnosed or corrected for compensation.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Automotive repair facility" includes a body shop.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Major component part" means:<section prefix="(i)">An air bag;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A bumper;</section><section prefix="(iii)">An engine;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A front fender;</section><section prefix="(v)">A front or rear side door;</section><section prefix="(vi)">A hood;</section><section prefix="(vii)">A pickup box or cargo box;</section><section prefix="(viii)">A rear quarter panel;</section><section prefix="(ix)">A rear door, deck lid, hatchback, or tailgate;</section><section prefix="(x)">A side assembly;</section><section prefix="(xi)">A sliding or cargo door; or</section><section prefix="(xii)">A transmission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Used major component part" does not include a:<section prefix="(i)">Remanufactured part that has not been installed on a motor vehicle since remanufacture;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Core element that is held solely for the purpose of being returned for remanufacture; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Part that is unsuitable for reuse in or on a motor vehicle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Vehicle storage facility" means a facility where disabled vehicles are stored at any time for compensation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person who operates an automotive repair facility shall keep accurate and complete records at the location where motor vehicle repairs are conducted of:<section prefix="(1)">The name and address of the owner of each motor vehicle repaired or stored at the automotive repair facility or each customer who leaves a motor vehicle for repair or storage at the automotive repair facility;</section><section prefix="(2)">The date a motor vehicle was left at the automotive repair facility;</section><section prefix="(3)">The year, model, and, when repairs involve a used major component part, the vehicle identification number of the vehicle; and</section><section prefix="(4)">For a used major component part at the automotive repair facility, proof of ownership or proof of the right of possession, including, if available, the vehicle identification number on the component part.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person who operates a vehicle storage facility shall keep accurate and complete records at the location where vehicles are stored of:<section prefix="(1)">The name and address of the individual who requested storage of each vehicle;</section><section prefix="(2)">The date that each vehicle was brought into the vehicle storage facility;</section><section prefix="(3)">The year, model, and, if available, the vehicle identification number of each vehicle; and</section><section prefix="(4)">The date and manner of disposition of each vehicle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Records required under subsection (b) or (c) of this section shall be kept for at least 1 year after the date:<section prefix="(i)">Of the transaction to which the record applies; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">On which a part or vehicle is at the automotive repair facility or vehicle storage facility.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who operates an automotive repair facility or vehicle storage facility may satisfy the record requirement if the required record is a computerized record that is accessible at the automotive repair facility or vehicle storage facility.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">During business hours or other hours of operation, an automotive repair facility or vehicle storage facility shall make available for inspection by the Administration, by the Department of State Police, or by a law enforcement officer with a county or municipal police department or sheriff's office who is assigned to an antitheft unit:<section prefix="(i)">Records required under this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Used major component parts and vehicles for which records are required.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an automotive repair facility or a vehicle storage facility is unable to produce a record required under this section, the automotive repair facility or vehicle storage facility may produce other evidence satisfactory to the Administration or law enforcement officer of proof of ownership or right of possession.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person who fails to comply with any requirement under this section is subject to a civil penalty not exceeding:<section prefix="(1)">For a first offense, $500; or</section><section prefix="(2)">For a second or subsequent offense, $1,000.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
