<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-928</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>928</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The owner of a fleet of trailers or semitrailers may apply to the Administration for registration under this section of the Class G (trailer) vehicles in the fleet, if:<section prefix="(i)">The fleet consists of at least 25 Class G (trailer) vehicles that are rented or offered for rent for periods of 364 days or less; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The fleet consists of at least five Class G (trailer) vehicles with a permitted gross weight of over 10,000 pounds.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each application made under this section shall contain the information that the Administration requires.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the applicant pays the fees required by this section and meets the other conditions required by the Administration, the Administration shall issue a special registration plate and registration card for each vehicle for which application is made.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A special registration plate and registration card issued under this section:<section prefix="(1)">May be issued for any period of up to 8 years as the Administration determines;</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall expire on the date that the Administration determines; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Until they expire, are valid only:<section prefix="(i)">As long as the applicant retains ownership of the vehicle for which they are issued; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the registration is made on a prorated annual fee basis, as long as the owner pays the required annual fees before the date on which regular Class G registration plates expire.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The fee for registration under this section shall be paid to the Administration, at the election of the applicant, either:<section prefix="(i)">At the time of registration, for the full registration period; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Annually, on a prorated fee basis.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The fee for the full registration period for each vehicle is the regular annual fee required for the vehicle under &#xA7; 13-927 of this subtitle, multiplied by the number of years in the registration period.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the application is made on a prorated annual fee basis, the applicant shall submit with the application acceptable evidence of a surety bond or irrevocable letter of credit that is:<section prefix="(1)">In a form and with a surety or insured Maryland financial institution approved by the Administration; and</section><section prefix="(2)">In an amount equal to the total annual fees required for all vehicles registered to the applicant under this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
