<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-213</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>213</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Education and employment only restriction" means a restriction that allows a licensed driver to drive only:<section prefix="(i)">To or from a school class or an official school activity; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">To or from, or in the course of, the licensee's employment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Offense" means a moving violation committed by an individual who:<section prefix="(i)">Held a provisional license under &#xA7; 16-111 of this title on the date the violation was committed;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Was convicted of, or granted a probation before judgment under &#xA7; 6-220 of the Criminal Procedure Article for, the violation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Was not eligible for a license under &#xA7; 16-111.1 of this title at the time of the violation.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 16-205(d-1) or &#xA7; 16-206(b) of this subtitle, the sanctions under this section are in addition to any other penalty or sanctions that might apply as a result of a moving violation.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Administration:<section prefix="(1)">For a first offense, shall require the offender to attend a driver improvement program under &#xA7; 16-212 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">For a second offense:<section prefix="(i)">For an adult, may suspend the offender's license for up to 30 days; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">For an individual under the age of 18 years, may:<section prefix="1.">Suspend the offender's license for up to 30 days; and</section><section prefix="2.">Impose, on completion of the suspension, an education and employment only restriction on the offender's license effective for 90 days;</section></section></section><section prefix="(3)">For a third offense:<section prefix="(i)">For an adult, may suspend the offender's license for up to 180 days; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">For an individual under the age of 18 years, may:<section prefix="1.">Suspend the offender's license for up to 180 days;</section><section prefix="2.">Require the offender to attend a driver improvement program designed for young drivers under &#xA7; 16-212 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="3.">Impose, on completion of the suspension, an education and employment only restriction on the offender's license effective for 180 days; and</section></section></section><section prefix="(4)">For a fourth or subsequent offense:<section prefix="(i)">For an adult, may suspend or revoke the offender's license for up to 180 days; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">For an individual under the age of 18 years, may:<section prefix="1.">Revoke the offender's license for not less than 180 days; and</section><section prefix="2.">Require the offender, in addition to applying for reinstatement as required under &#xA7; 16-208(b) of this subtitle, to pass the examinations required under &#xA7; 16-110 of this title.</section></section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
