<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-15-211</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>211</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A manufacturer, whether directly or through an agent, employee, affiliate, or representative, may not prevent, by contract or otherwise, any owner, partner, or stockholder of any dealership from transferring any ownership interest in the dealership to any other person.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A distributor, whether directly or through an agent, employee, affiliate, or representative, may not prevent, by contract or otherwise, any owner, partner, or stockholder of any dealership from transferring any ownership interest in the dealership to any other person.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A factory branch, whether directly or through an agent, employee, affiliate, or representative, may not prevent, by contract or otherwise, any owner, partner, or stockholder of any dealership from transferring any ownership interest in the dealership to any other person.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A dealer or an owner, partner, or stockholder of a dealership may not sell, assign, or otherwise transfer a franchise or any right under a franchise without the consent of the manufacturer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding the terms of any franchise agreement or agreement related to a franchise, a manufacturer may not exercise a right of first refusal in the event of a sale or transfer or proposed sale or transfer of a dealer's business or any equity interest in a dealer's business to a person who meets the manufacturer's reasonable qualifications for ownership and is:<section prefix="(i)">A member of the dealer's immediate family;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A qualified manager with at least 2 years management experience at the dealer's business;</section><section prefix="(iii)">An existing dealer in good standing; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">A business entity controlled by a person described in item (i), (ii), or (iii) of this paragraph.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a manufacturer exercises a right of first refusal in the event of a sale or transfer or proposed sale or transfer of the dealer's business or an equity interest in the dealer's business, the manufacturer shall pay the reasonable expenses, including customary attorney's fees, incurred by the prospective purchaser in negotiating and implementing the contract for the proposed sale or transfer, provided that the dealer has given the manufacturer at least 45 days' notice of an intent to sell or transfer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A manufacturer may not unreasonably withhold consent to the transfer of a franchise under subsection (d) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A dealer or an owner, partner, or stockholder of a dealership may not sell, assign, or otherwise transfer a franchise or any right under a franchise without the consent of the distributor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding the terms of any agreement related to the franchise, a distributor may not exercise a right of first refusal in the event of a sale or transfer or proposed sale or transfer of a dealer's business or any equity interest in a dealer's business to a person who meets the distributor's reasonable qualifications for ownership and is:<section prefix="(i)">A member of the dealer's immediate family;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A qualified manager with at least 2 years management experience at the dealer's business;</section><section prefix="(iii)">An existing dealer in good standing; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">A business entity controlled by a person described in item (i), (ii), or (iii) of this paragraph.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a distributor exercises a right of first refusal in the event of a sale or transfer or proposed sale or transfer of the dealer's business or an equity interest in the dealer's business, the distributor shall pay the reasonable expenses, including customary attorney's fees, incurred by the prospective purchaser in negotiating and implementing the contract for the proposed sale or transfer, provided that the dealer has given the distributor at least 45 days' notice of an intent to sell or transfer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">However, the distributor may not unreasonably withhold consent to the transfer of a franchise under subsection (f) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A dealer or an owner, partner, or stockholder of a dealership may not sell, assign, or otherwise transfer a franchise or any right under a franchise without the consent of the factory branch.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding the terms of any agreement related to the franchise, a factory branch may not exercise a right of first refusal in the event of a sale or transfer or proposed sale or transfer of a dealer's business or any equity interest in a dealer's business to a person who meets the factory branch's reasonable qualifications for ownership and is:<section prefix="(i)">A member of the dealer's immediate family;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A qualified manager with at least 2 years management experience at the dealer's business;</section><section prefix="(iii)">An existing dealer in good standing; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">A business entity controlled by a person described in item (i), (ii), or (iii) of this paragraph.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a factory branch exercises a right of first refusal in the event of a sale or transfer or proposed sale or transfer of the dealer's business or an equity interest in the dealer's business, the factory branch shall pay the reasonable expenses, including customary attorney's fees, incurred by the prospective purchaser in negotiating and implementing the contract for the proposed sale or transfer, provided that the dealer has given the factory branch at least 45 days' notice of an intent to sell or transfer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">However, the factory branch may not unreasonably withhold consent to the transfer of a franchise under subsection (h) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">A manufacturer, distributor, or factory branch may not impose a condition on the approval of the sale or transfer of the ownership of a dealership, by the sale of the business, stock transfer, or otherwise, if the condition would violate the provisions of this title if imposed on an existing dealer.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A manufacturer, distributor, or factory branch violates this section if, without a statement of specific grounds consistent with this title for the action, the manufacturer, distributor, or factory branch takes action to prevent or refuse to approve:<section prefix="(i)">The sale, assignment, or transfer of the ownership of a dealership by the sale of the business, stock transfer, or otherwise;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The sale, transfer, or assignment of a dealer franchise; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A change in the executive management or principal operator of the dealership.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An existing dealer denied the sale, assignment, transfer, or change under this section may request that the Administrator conduct a hearing to review the denial or the imposition of a condition in violation of this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the Administrator finds that the action leading to the denial or the imposition of a condition was in violation of this section, the Administrator may order the sale, assignment, or transfer to be approved by the manufacturer, distributor, or factory branch without imposition of the condition.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An applicant for approval of a sale, assignment, or transfer of ownership of a dealership or an existing dealer denied the sale, assignment, or transfer may institute an action for damages in the circuit court for the county in which the dealer's principal place of business is located, if:<section prefix="1.">The existing dealer does not request a hearing by the Administrator; and</section><section prefix="2.">The action taken in violation of this section to deny the sale, assignment, or transfer of ownership or the change in executive management or the condition imposed on the sale, assignment, or transfer is the proximate cause of the failure of the contract for the sale, assignment, or transfer of ownership of the dealership.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An action for damages under this section must be instituted within 2 years of the violation of this section.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
