<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "Child Support Enforcement Administration" means the Child Support Enforcement Admi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Child Support Enforcement Administration" means the Child Support Enforcement Administration of the Department of Human Resources.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On notification by the Child Support Enforcement Administration in accordance with &#xA7; 10-119 of the Family Law Article that an obligor is 60 days or more out of compliance with the most recent order of the court in making child support payments, the Administration:<section prefix="(1)">Shall suspend an obligor's license or privilege to drive in the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May issue a work-restricted license or work-restricted privilege to drive.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Prior to the suspension of a license or the privilege to drive in the State and the issuance of a work-restricted license or work-restricted privilege to drive under subsection (b) of this section, the Administration shall send written notice of the proposed action to the obligor, including notice of the obligor's right to contest the accuracy of the information.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any contest under this subsection shall be limited to whether the Administration has mistaken the identity of the obligor or the individual whose license or privilege to drive has been suspended.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An obligor may appeal a decision of the Administration to suspend the obligor's license or privilege to drive.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At a hearing under this subsection, the issue shall be limited to whether the Administration has mistaken the identity of the obligor or the individual whose license or privilege to drive has been suspended.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Administration shall reinstate an obligor's license or privilege to drive in the State if:<section prefix="(1)">The Administration receives a court order to reinstate the license or privilege to drive; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The Child Support Enforcement Administration notifies the Administration that:<section prefix="(i)">The individual whose license or privilege to drive was suspended is not in arrears in making child support payments;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The obligor has paid the support arrearage in full; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">The obligor has demonstrated good faith by paying the ordered amount of support for 6 consecutive months.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Secretary of Transportation, in cooperation with the Secretary of Human Resources and the Office of Administrative Hearings, shall adopt regulations to implement this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
