<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="26-301" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-26-301</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle, "officer" means a police officer or a person other than a police officer who is authorized to issue a citation for a violation of an ordinance or regulation that is adopted under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to subsection (c) of this section, any State agency authorized by law and any political subdivision of this State may adopt ordinances or regulations that:<section prefix="(1)">Regulate the parking of vehicles;</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide for the impounding of vehicles parked in violation of the ordinances or regulations;</section><section prefix="(3)">Regulate the towing of vehicles from publicly owned and privately owned parking lots; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Provide for the issuance of a citation by an officer for a violation of an ordinance or regulation that is adopted under this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A political subdivision may not adopt or enforce an ordinance or regulation that prohibits the parking of more than one motorcycle within a space served by a single parking meter.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "rental vehicle" means a vehicle that is rented or leased for a period not exceeding 180 days.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a parking citation is issued for a rental vehicle, the owner is not liable for any penalty in excess of the original fine for a parking violation unless the owner fails to pay the fine or file a notice of intention to stand trial for the violation within the time specified in a notice of the infraction mailed to the business address of the owner.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a political subdivision or State agency receives payment for a parking violation from both the owner of the vehicle and the person who had possession of the rental vehicle at the time the parking citation was issued, the political subdivision or State agency shall reimburse the owner of the vehicle for the amount paid by the owner for the violation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Any State agency authorized by law and any political subdivision of the State may establish public outreach efforts to educate law enforcement officers, businesses, medical practitioners, and the general public as to parking laws and regulations, including:<section prefix="(1)">The authority of law enforcement officers to enter private parking lots used by the public; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Specific eligibility criteria for, and requirements for the lawful use of, special registration plates and placards issued under Title 13, Subtitle 6 of this article for individuals with disabilities.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
