<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-616.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>616.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may apply to the Administration for a temporary parking placard on a form provided by the Administration if:<section prefix="(1)">The applicant, a dependent of the applicant, or any individual who depends on the applicant for transportation has a disability, as described in &#xA7; 13-616(b)(1) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A licensed physician, licensed chiropractor, licensed optometrist, or licensed podiatrist, as defined in &#xA7; 13-616(a) of this subtitle, certifies that the disability is not permanent but would substantially impair the applicant's mobility or limit or impair the applicant's ability to walk for at least 3 weeks, and is so severe that the applicant would endure a hardship or be subject to risk of injury if the temporary parking placard were denied.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An application under subsection (a) of this section shall be accompanied by:<section prefix="(1)">Proof satisfactory to the Administration that the applicant, the dependent of the applicant, or the individual who depends on the applicant for transportation is a person with a disability under subsection (a) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The certification of a licensed physician, licensed chiropractor, licensed optometrist, or licensed podiatrist that the applicant, the dependent of the applicant, or the individual who depends on the applicant for transportation is disabled, including an estimate of the length of time the disability will continue.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A temporary parking placard for a person with a disability issued under this section shall be valid for a period of time the licensed physician, licensed chiropractor, licensed optometrist, or licensed podiatrist has determined that the applicant, the dependent of the applicant, or the individual who depends on the applicant for transportation is likely to have the disability, not to exceed 6 months.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The person to whom a temporary parking placard was issued under this section shall return the placard to the Administration within 5 calendar days of the placard's expiration.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A temporary parking placard for a person with a disability shall be issued in the form, size, and design determined by the Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person to whom a temporary parking placard is issued shall display the placard described in this section in a vehicle described in &#xA7; 13-616.1(e)(2) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This section applies only to vehicles defined in &#xA7;&#xA7; 13-616(b)(3) and 13-616.1(e)(2) of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, when displayed by the person to whom a temporary parking placard is issued, the temporary parking placard shall be hung from the inside rearview mirror when the vehicle is parked.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not drive a vehicle while a temporary parking placard described under paragraph (1) of this subsection is hanging from the inside rearview mirror.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The temporary parking placard shall be placed inside a vehicle that is not equipped with an inside rearview mirror, in a position from which the temporary parking placard can be viewed from the outside of the vehicle through the lower portion of the windshield on the driver's side of the vehicle.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">When displayed, the person to whom a temporary parking placard is issued under this section or under a similar provision of law of any state or country is accorded the privileges contained in &#xA7; 13-616(f) of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not commit any fraud or make any misrepresentations in certifying a person's disability or applying for or using a temporary parking placard.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">To determine if the eligibility requirements continue to be met, the Administration may conduct a review of a temporary parking placard that is issued by the Administration under this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the Administration finds it necessary to review the severity of a placard holder's disability or the current status of the temporary disability, the Administration may request a review and recommendations from the Medical Advisory Board established under &#xA7; 16-118 of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If the Administration determines that eligibility requirements are not being met, the Administration may revoke the temporary parking placard.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Any person who violates the provisions of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Administration shall:<section prefix="(1)">Administer the temporary parking placard program in accordance with the provisions of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">By July 1, 2001, establish an automated system for recording the issuance, renewal, and expiration of temporary placards in a timely manner to ensure that the objectives of the temporary placard program are achieved in an efficient and orderly manner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">In accordance with the provisions of this section, by July 1, 2001, each board for licensed physicians, licensed chiropractors, licensed optometrists, or licensed podiatrists shall be responsible for the development and maintenance of a database system with which the Administration can interface and verify licensure.</section>
  </text>
</law>
