<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-303" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-7-303</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A transit plan is not effective and steps may not be taken to implement it until the plan has been adopted by the Secretary.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary may not approve or adopt the location of corridors, routes, stations, and terminals in any political subdivision unless the locations have been approved by the legislative body of the political subdivision.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the legislative body does not advise the Secretary in writing of its action within 180 days after its receipt of notice of the proposed locations, the legislative body is deemed to have approved the location.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before the adoption, revision, or amendment of any transit plan, the Secretary shall send the proposed plan, revision, or amendment to the following, for comment to be made within the time that the Secretary specifies:<section prefix="(1)">The Governor;</section><section prefix="(2)">The chief executive officers and the councils or the boards of county commissioners in the District;</section><section prefix="(3)">The Public Service Commission;</section><section prefix="(4)">The Baltimore Regional Council of Governments;</section><section prefix="(5)">The Department of Planning;</section><section prefix="(6)">Each private carrier operating in the District;</section><section prefix="(7)">Each labor union representing employees engaged in transit operations in the District;</section><section prefix="(8)">The legislative representatives of any affected political subdivisions; and</section><section prefix="(9)">Any other agency that the Secretary determines.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
