<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-24-108</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>108</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection and except as otherwise provided in this section, the gross weight imposed on the ground surface by the wheels of an axle of a vehicle may not exceed the following limits:</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except for vehicles operated under a permit issued under &#xA7; 24-112 of this subtitle, the gross weight imposed on the ground surface by the wheels of a front axle of a vehicle combination may not exceed either the lesser of:<section prefix="(i)">The sum of the rated load capacities for each tire on the axle, except as provided in subsection (b) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The sum of the rated load capacities indicated by the manufacturer as to each tire on the axle with which the vehicle is currently equipped.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraphs (ii) and (iii) of this paragraph, any vehicle with a gross maximum weight in excess of 73,000 pounds may travel only on State highways, except while making a delivery or pickup, and then only when traveling by the shortest available legal route to or from the State highway for the purpose of making such delivery or pickup. In Baltimore City, the shortest available legal route shall be only on designated truck routes.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If approved by the local governing body and the State Highway Administration, in Dorchester County, a vehicle with a gross maximum weight in excess of 73,000 pounds may use the Linkwood Road when traveling between East New Market and Linkwood.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">
          <section prefix="1.">The County Commissioners of Garrett County may, by ordinance, establish the authorized gross maximum weight of a vehicle that:</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The gross maximum weight established under this subparagraph may not exceed 87,000 pounds.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except on interstate highways, a vehicle carrying farm products as defined under &#xA7; 10-601 of the Agriculture Article or forest products that have been loaded in fields or other off-highway locations is permitted an axle load limit tolerance of 10 percent.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Anne Arundel County and Baltimore County, garbage and refuse trucks that make collections on a fixed route and are owned by or doing business with any governmental entity in the respective county are permitted rear axle load limit tolerances of 10 percent if:<section prefix="(i)">The overweight is due to bad weather; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The truck does not exceed its registered gross weight limit.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A privately owned truck is permitted this tolerance only while actually engaged in the business of the governmental entity.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Any over-the-road bus or any vehicle that is regularly and exclusively used as an intrastate public agency transit passenger bus may not exceed:<section prefix="(1)">A single axle weight limit of 24,000 pounds; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The tire manufacturer's rated load capacity for any tire on the vehicle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
