<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="21-1205.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-21-1205.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, a person may not ride a bicycle or a motor scooter:<section prefix="(1)">On any roadway where the posted maximum speed limit is more than 50 miles an hour; or</section><section prefix="(2)">On any expressway, except on an adjacent bicycle path or way approved by the State Highway Administration, or on any other controlled access highway signed in accordance with &#xA7; 21-313 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Where there is not a bike lane paved to a smooth surface, a person operating a bicycle or a motor scooter may use the roadway or the shoulder.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Where there is a bike lane paved to a smooth surface, a person operating a bicycle or a motor scooter shall use the bike lane and may not ride on the roadway, except in the following situations:<section prefix="(i)">When overtaking and passing another bicycle, motor scooter, pedestrian, or other vehicle within the bike lane if the overtaking and passing cannot be done safely within the bike lane;</section><section prefix="(ii)">When preparing for a left turn at an intersection or into an alley, private road, or driveway;</section><section prefix="(iii)">When reasonably necessary to leave the bike lane to avoid debris or other hazardous condition; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">When reasonably necessary to leave the bike lane because the bike lane is overlaid with a right turn lane, merge lane, or other marking that breaks the continuity of the bike lane.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A person operating a bicycle or a motor scooter may not leave a bike lane until the movement can be made with reasonable safety and then only after giving an appropriate signal.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Department shall adopt regulations pertaining to this subsection, including a definition of "smooth surface".</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A motor scooter may not be operated at a speed in excess of 30 miles per hour.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, a person may not operate an EPAMD on any roadway where there are sidewalks adjacent to the roadway or the posted maximum speed limit is more than 30 miles an hour.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An EPAMD may not be operated at a speed in excess of 15 miles per hour.</section>
  </text>
</law>
