<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-24-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When located on the right--amp--ndash;of--amp--ndash;way of any State highway, a mobile seafood or produce vendor may not sell, or offer for sale, any seafood or produce, unless the vendor has a lease from the State that allows the vendor to sell, or offer for sale, seafood or produce.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State may require a mobile seafood or produce vendor to submit an application and pay a reasonable fee to be applied to administrative costs.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The State may not enter into a lease with a mobile produce vendor unless the applicable county licenses mobile produce vendors.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A mobile seafood or produce vendor may not sell, or offer for sale, any seafood or produce, when located:<section prefix="(1)">Within 50 yards of any vehicular entrance to or exit from a school or place of worship, unless the vendor has written permission of the applicable school board or person who is responsible for the buildings and grounds of the place of worship;</section><section prefix="(2)">Within 100 yards of any vehicular entrance to or exit from any shopping center;</section><section prefix="(3)">In the parking lot of any shopping center, unless the vendor has written permission of the owner of the shopping center and conforms to applicable local laws and ordinances;</section><section prefix="(4)">Within an unsafe distance, as determined by the local authorities, from the edge of any roadway;</section><section prefix="(5)">On any roadway; or</section><section prefix="(6)">On private property adjoining a State highway, unless the vendor owns or leases the property or has written permission from the property owner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The State Highway Administration may adopt regulations to implement this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
