<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-404</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Administration shall take the following actions for points accumulated within any 2-year period:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>404</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Administration shall take the following actions for points accumulated within any 2-year period:<section prefix="(1)">Send a warning letter to each individual who accumulates 3 points;</section><section prefix="(2)">Require attendance at a driver improvement program conducted under &#xA7; 16-212 of this title by each individual who accumulates 5 points, except that a Class A, B, or C licensee who submits evidence acceptable to the Administration that he is a professional driver may not be called in until he accumulates 8 points; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 16-405 of this subtitle:<section prefix="(i)">Suspend the license of each individual who accumulates 8 points; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Revoke the license of each individual who accumulates 12 points.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 16-405 of this subtitle:<section prefix="(i)">If an individual accumulates 8 points, the Administration shall issue a notice of suspension; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">If an individual accumulates 12 points, the Administration shall issue a notice of revocation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each notice shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be personally served or sent by certified mail, bearing a postmark from the United States Postal Service;</section><section prefix="(ii)">State the duration of the suspension or revocation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Advise the individual of his right, within 10 days after the notice is sent (Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays excepted), to file a written request for a hearing before the Administrator.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Unless a hearing is requested, each notice of suspension or revocation is effective at the end of the 10-day period after the notice is sent.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">An initial suspension may not be for less than 2 days nor more than 30 days; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any subsequent suspension may not be for less than 15 days nor more than 90 days.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (3) of this subsection, the following suspension periods may apply to a suspension for an accumulation of points under &#xA7; 16-402(a)(25) of this subtitle for a violation of &#xA7; 21-902(b) or (c) of this article or a suspension imposed under &#xA7; 16-404.1(f)(1)(iii) of this subtitle:<section prefix="(i)">For a first conviction, not more than 6 months;</section><section prefix="(ii)">For a second conviction at least 5 years after the date of the first conviction, not more than 9 months;</section><section prefix="(iii)">For a second conviction less than 5 years after the date of the first conviction or for a third conviction, not more than 12 months; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">For a fourth or subsequent conviction, not more than 24 months.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Administration may issue a restrictive license for the period of the suspension to an individual who participates in the Administration's Ignition Interlock System Program under &#xA7; 16-404.1 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">This subsection does not limit the authority of the Administration to issue a restrictive license or modify a suspension imposed under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the holder of a provisional driver's license who is under the age of 18 years accumulates 5 or more points in a 12-month period, the Administration shall suspend the individual's driver's license:<section prefix="(i)">For a first offense, for 6 months; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">For a second or subsequent offense, for 1 year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual subject to a license suspension under this subsection may request a hearing as provided for a suspension or revocation under Title 12, Subtitle 2 of this article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
