<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-10-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>1....</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>1.<section prefix="(a)">"Board" means the board of directors of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority;</section><section prefix="(b)">"Director" means a member of the board of directors of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority;</section><section prefix="(c)">"Private transit companies" and "private carriers" means corporations, persons, firms or associations rendering transit service within the zone pursuant to a certificate of public convenience and necessity issued by the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Commission or by a franchise granted by the United States or any signatory party to this title;</section><section prefix="(d)">"Signatory" means the State of Maryland, the Commonwealth of Virginia and the District of Columbia;</section><section prefix="(e)">"State" includes District of Columbia;</section><section prefix="(f)">"Transit facilities" means all real and personal property located in the zone, necessary or useful in rendering transit service between points within the zone, by means of rail, bus, water or air and any other mode of travel, including without limitation, tracks, rights-of-way, bridges, tunnels, subways, rolling stock for rail, motor vehicle, marine and air transportation, stations, terminals and ports, areas for parking and all equipment, fixtures, buildings and structures and services incidental to or required in connection with the performance of transit service;</section><section prefix="(g)">"Transit services" means the transportation of persons and their packages and baggage by means of transit facilities between points within the zone including the transportation of newspapers, express and mail between such points and charter service which originates within the zone but does not include taxicab service or individual-ticket-sale sightseeing operations;</section><section prefix="(h)">"Transit zone" or "zone" means the Washington metropolitan area transit zone created by and described in &#xA7; 3, as well as any additional area that may be added pursuant to &#xA7; 83(a); and</section><section prefix="(i)">"WMATC" means Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Commission.</section><section prefix="(a)">The Authority shall be governed by a Board of eight Directors consisting of two Directors for each signatory and two for the federal government (one of whom shall be a regular passenger and customer of the bus or rail service of the Authority). For Virginia, the Directors shall be appointed by the Northern Virginia Transportation Commission; for the District of Columbia, by the Council of the District of Columbia; for Maryland, by the Washington Suburban Transit Commission; and for the federal government, by the Administrator of General Services. For Virginia and Maryland, the Directors shall be appointed from among the members of the appointing body, except as otherwise provided herein, and shall serve for a term coincident with their term on the appointing body. A Director for a signatory may be removed or suspended from office only as provided by the law of the signatory from which he was appointed. The nonfederal appointing authorities shall also appoint an alternate for each Director. In addition, the Administrator of General Services shall also appoint two nonvoting members who shall serve as the alternates for the federal Directors. An alternate Director may act only in the absence of the Director for whom he has been appointed an alternate, except that, in the case of the District of Columbia where only one Director and his alternate are present, such alternate may act on behalf of the absent Director. Each alternate, including the federal nonvoting Directors, shall serve at the pleasure of the appointing authority. In the event of a vacancy in the Office of Director or alternate, it shall be filled in the same manner as an original appointment.</section><section prefix="(b)">Before entering upon the duties of his office each Director and alternate director shall take and subscribe to the following oath (or affirmation) of office or any such other oath or affirmation, if any, as the constitution or laws of the Government he represents shall provide:</section><section prefix="(a)">Four Directors or alternates consisting of at least one Director or alternate appointed from each Signatory, shall constitute a quorum and no action by the Board shall be effective unless a majority of the Board present and voting, which majority shall include at least one Director or alternate from each Signatory, concur therein; provided, however, that a plan of financing may be adopted or a mass transit plan adopted, altered, revised or amended by the unanimous vote of the Directors representing any two Signatories.</section><section prefix="(b)">The actions of the Board shall be expressed by motion or resolution. Actions dealing solely with internal management of the Authority shall become effective when directed by the Board, but no other action shall become effective prior to the expiration of thirty days following its adoption; provided, however, that the Board may provide for the acceleration of any action upon a finding that such acceleration is required for the proper and timely performance of its functions.</section><section prefix="(a)">The officers of the Authority, none of whom shall be members of the board, shall consist of a general manager, a secretary, a treasurer, a comptroller, an inspector general, and a general counsel and such other officers as the board may provide. Except for the office of general manager, inspector general, and comptroller, the board may consolidate any of such other offices in one person. All such officers shall be appointed and may be removed by the board, shall serve at the pleasure of the board and shall perform such duties and functions as the board shall specify. The board shall fix and determine the compensation to be paid to all officers and, except for the general manager who shall be a full-time employee, all other officers may be hired on a full-time or part-time basis and may be compensated on a salary or fee basis, as the board may determine. All employees and such officers as the board may designate shall be appointed and removed by the general manager under such rules of procedure and standards as the board may determine.</section><section prefix="(b)">The general manager shall be the chief administrative officer of the Authority and, subject to policy direction by the board, shall be responsible for all activities of the Authority.</section><section prefix="(c)">The treasurer shall be the custodian of the funds of the Authority, shall keep an account of all receipts and disbursements and shall make payments only upon warrants duly and regularly signed by the chairman or vice-chairman of the board, or other person authorized by the board to do so, and by the secretary or general manager; provided, however, that the board may provide that warrants not exceeding such amounts or for such purposes as may from time to time be specified by the board may be signed by the general manager or by persons designated by him.</section><section prefix="(d)">The inspector general shall report to the Board and head the Office of the Inspector General, an independent and objective unit of the Authority that conducts and supervises audits, program evaluations, and investigations relating to Authority activities; promotes economy, efficiency, and effectiveness in Authority activities; detects and prevents fraud and abuse in Authority activities; and keeps the board fully and currently informed about deficiencies in Authority activities as well as the necessity for and progress of corrective action.</section><section prefix="(e)">An oath of office in the form set out in &#xA7; 5(b) of this article shall be taken, subscribed and filed with the board by all appointed officers.</section><section prefix="(f)">Each director, officer and employee specified by the board shall give such bond in such form and amount as the board may require, the premium for which shall be paid by the Authority.</section><section prefix="(a)">No director, officer or employee shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be financially interested, either directly or indirectly, in any contract, sale, purchase, lease or transfer of real or personal property to which the board or the Authority is a party;</section><section prefix="(2)">In connection with services performed within the scope of his official duties, solicit or accept money or any other thing of value in addition to the compensation or expenses paid to him by the Authority;</section><section prefix="(3)">Offer money or anything of value for or in consideration of obtaining an appointment, promotion or privilege in his employment with the Authority.</section></section><section prefix="(b)">Any director, officer or employee who shall willfully violate any provision of this section shall, in the discretion of the board, forfeit his office or employment.</section><section prefix="(c)">Any contract or agreement made in contravention of this section may be declared void by the board.</section><section prefix="(d)">Nothing in this section shall be construed to abrogate or limit the applicability of any federal or state law which may be violated by any action prescribed by this section.</section><section prefix="(a)">Sue and be sued;</section><section prefix="(b)">Adopt and use a corporate seal and alter the same at pleasure;</section><section prefix="(c)">Adopt, amend, and repeal rules and regulations respecting the exercise of the powers conferred by this title;</section><section prefix="(d)">Construct, acquire, own, operate, maintain, control, sell and convey real and personal property and any interest therein by contract, purchase, condemnation, lease, license, mortgage or otherwise but all of said property shall be located in the zone and shall be necessary or useful in rendering transit service or in activities incidental thereto.</section><section prefix="(e)">Receive and accept such payments, appropriations, grants, gifts, loans, advances and other funds, properties and services as may be transferred or made available to it by any signatory party, any political subdivision or agency thereof, by the United States, or by any agency thereof, or by any other public or private corporation or individual, and enter into agreements to make reimbursement for all or any part thereof;</section><section prefix="(f)">Enter into and perform contracts, leases and agreements with any person, firm or corporation or with any political subdivision or agency of any signatory party or with the federal government, or any agency thereof, including, but not limited to, contracts or agreements to furnish transit facilities and service;</section><section prefix="(g)">Create and abolish offices, employments and positions (other than those specifically provided for herein) as it deems necessary for the purposes of the Authority, and fix and provide for the qualification, appointment, removal, term, tenure, compensation, pension and retirement rights of its officers and employees without regard to the laws of any of the signatories;</section><section prefix="(h)">Establish, in its discretion, a personnel system based on merit and fitness and, subject to eligibility, participate in the pension and retirement plans of any signatory, or political subdivision or agency thereof, upon terms and conditions mutually acceptable;</section><section prefix="(i)">Contract for or employ any professional services;</section><section prefix="(j)">Control and regulate the use of facilities owned or controlled by the Authority, the service to be rendered and the fares and charges to be made therefor;</section><section prefix="(k)">Hold public hearings and conduct investigations relating to any matter affecting transportation in the zone with which the Authority is concerned and, in connection therewith, subpoena witnesses, papers, records and documents; or delegate such authority to any officer. Each director may administer oaths or affirmations in any proceeding or investigation.</section><section prefix="(l)">Make or participate in studies of all phases and forms of transportation, including transportation vehicle research and development techniques and methods for determining traffic projections, demand motivations, and fiscal research and publicize and make available the results of such studies and other information relating to transportation; and</section><section prefix="(m)">Exercise, subject to the limitations and restrictions herein imposed, all powers reasonably necessary or essential to the declared objects and purposes of this title.</section><section prefix="(a)">The board shall develop and adopt, and may from time to time review and revise, a mass transit plan for the immediate and long-range needs of the zone. The mass transit plan shall include one or more plans designating (1) the transit facilities to be provided by the Authority, including the locations of terminals, stations, platforms, parking facilities and the character and nature thereof; (2) the design and location of such facilities; (3) whether such facilities are to be constructed or acquired by lease, purchase or condemnation; (4) a time table for the provision of such facilities; (5) the anticipated capital costs; (6) estimated operating expenses and revenues relating thereto; and (7) the various other factors and considerations, which, in the opinion of the board, justify and require the projects therein proposed. Such plan shall specify the type of equipment to be utilized, the areas to be served, the routes and schedules of service expected to be provided and the probable fares and charges therefor.</section><section prefix="(b)">In preparing the mass transit plan, and in any review or revision thereof, the board shall make full utilization of all data, studies, reports and information available from the National Capital Transportation Agency and from any other agencies of the federal government, and from signatories and the political subdivisions thereof.</section><section prefix="(a)">The mass transit plan, and any revisions, alterations or amendments thereof, shall be coordinated, through the procedures hereinafter set forth, with<section prefix="(1)">Other plans and programs affecting transportation in the zone in order to achieve a balanced system of transportation, utilizing each mode to its best advantage;</section><section prefix="(2)">The general plan or plans for the development of the zone; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The development plans of the various political subdivisions embraced within the zone.</section></section><section prefix="(b)">It shall be the duty and responsibility of each member of the Board to serve as liaison between the Board and the body which appointed him to the Board. To provide a framework for regional participation in the planning process, the Board shall create technical committees concerned with planning and collection and analyses of data relative to decision-making in the transportation planning process and the Mayor and Council of the District of Columbia, the component governments of the Northern Virginia Transportation District and the Washington Suburban Transit District shall appoint representatives to such technical committees and otherwise cooperate with the Board in the formulation of a mass transit plan, or in revisions, alterations or amendments thereof.</section><section prefix="(c)">The Board, in the preparation, revision, alteration or amendment of a mass transit plan, shall<section prefix="(1)">Consider data with respect to current and prospective conditions in the zone, including, without limitation, land use, population, economic factors affecting development plans, goals or objectives for the development of the zone and the separate political subdivisions, transit demands to be generated by such development, travel patterns, existing and proposed transportation and transit facilities, impact of transit plans on the dislocation of families and businesses, preservation of the beauty and dignity of the nation's capital, factors affecting environmental amenities and aesthetics and financial resources;</section><section prefix="(2)">Cooperate with and participate in any continuous, comprehensive transportation planning process cooperatively established by the highway agencies of the signatories and the local political subdivisions in the zone to meet the planning standards now or hereafter prescribed by the federal-aid highway act; and</section><section prefix="(3)">To the extent not inconsistent with or duplicative of the planning process specified in subparagraph (2) of this paragraph (c), cooperate with the National Capital Planning Commission, the National Capital Regional Planning Council, the Washington Metropolitan Council of Governments, the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Commission, the highway agencies of the signatories, the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission, the Northern Virginia Regional Planning and Economic Development Commission, the Maryland Department of Planning and the Commission of Fine Arts. Such cooperation shall include the creation, as necessary, of technical committees composed of personnel, appointed by such agencies, concerned with planning and collection and analysis of data relative to decision-making in the transportation planning process.</section></section><section prefix="(a)">Before a mass transit plan is adopted, altered, revised or amended, the Board shall transmit such proposed plan, alteration, revision or amendment for comment to the following and to such other agencies as the Board shall determine:<section prefix="(1)">The Mayor and Council of the District of Columbia, the Northern Virginia Transportation Commission and the Washington Suburban Transit Commission;</section><section prefix="(2)">The governing bodies of the counties and cities embraced within the zone;</section><section prefix="(3)">The transportation agencies of the Signatories;</section><section prefix="(4)">The Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Commission;</section><section prefix="(5)">The Washington Metropolitan Council of Governments;</section><section prefix="(6)">The National Capital Planning Commission;</section><section prefix="(7)">The National Capital Regional Planning Council;</section><section prefix="(8)">The Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission;</section><section prefix="(9)">The Northern Virginia Regional Planning and Economic Development Commission;</section><section prefix="(10)">The Maryland Department of Planning; and</section><section prefix="(11)">The private transit companies operating in the zone and the labor unions representing the employees of such companies and employees of contractors providing service under operating contracts.</section></section><section prefix="(b)">A copy of the proposed mass transit plan, amendment or revision, shall be kept at the office of the Board and shall be available for public inspection. Information with respect thereto shall be released to the public. After thirty days' notice published once a week for two successive weeks in one or more newspapers of general circulation within the zone, a public hearing shall be held with respect to the proposed plan, alteration, revision or amendment. The thirty-days' notice shall begin to run on the first day the notice appears in any such newspaper. The Board shall consider the evidence submitted and statements and comments made at such hearing and may make any changes in the proposed plan, amendment or revision which it deems appropriate and such changes may be made without further hearing.</section><section prefix="(a)">The Authority, in conformance with said policy, shall prepare and adopt a plan for financing the construction, acquisition and operation of facilities specified in a mass transit plan adopted pursuant to Article VI hereof, or in any alteration, revision or amendment thereof. Such plan of financing shall specify the facilities to be constructed or acquired, the cost thereof, the principal amount of revenue bonds, equipment trust certificates and other evidences of debt proposed to be issued, the principal terms and provisions of all loans and underlying agreements and indentures, estimated operating expenses and revenues and the proposed allocation among the federal, District of Columbia and participating local governments of the remaining costs and deficits, if any, and such other information as the Commission may consider appropriate.</section><section prefix="(b)">Such plan of financing shall constitute a proposal to the interested governments for financial participation and shall not impose any obligation on any government and such obligations shall be created only as provided in &#xA7; 18 of this Article VII.</section><section prefix="(a)">Commitments on behalf of the portion of the zone located in Virginia shall be by contract or agreement by the Authority with the Northern Virginia Transportation District, or its component governments, as authorized in the Transportation District Act of 1964 (ch. 631, 1964 Acts of Virginia Assembly), to contribute to the capital required for the construction and/or acquisition of facilities specified in a mass transit plan adopted as provided in Article VI, or any alteration, revision or amendment thereof, and for meeting expenses and obligations in the operation of such facilities. No such contract or agreement, however, shall be entered into by the Authority with the Northern Virginia Transportation District unless said District has entered into the contracts or agreements with its member governments, as contemplated by &#xA7; 1(b)(4) of Article 4 of said act, which contracts or agreements expressly provide that such contracts or agreements shall inure to the benefit of the Authority and shall be enforceable by the Authority in accordance with the provisions of &#xA7; 2, Article 5 of said act, and such contracts or agreements are acceptable to the Board. The General Assembly of Virginia hereby authorizes and designates the Authority as the agency to plan for and provide transit facilities and services for the area of Virginia encompassed within the zone within the contemplation of Article 1, &#xA7; 3(c) of said act.</section><section prefix="(b)">Commitments on behalf of the portion of the zone located in Maryland shall be by contract or agreement by the Authority with the Washington Suburban Transit District, pursuant to which the Authority undertakes to provide transit facilities and service in consideration for the agreement by said district to contribute to the capital required for the construction and/or acquisition of facilities specified in a mass transit plan adopted as provided in Article VI, or in any alteration, revision or amendment thereof, and for meeting expenses and obligations incurred in the operation of such facilities.</section><section prefix="(c)">With respect to the federal government, the commitment or obligation to render financial assistance shall be created by appropriation or in such other manner, or by such other legislation, as the Congress shall determine. Commitments by the District of Columbia shall be by contract or agreement between the governing body of the District of Columbia and the Authority, pursuant to which the Authority undertakes, subject to the provisions of Section 20 hereof, to provide transit facilities and service in consideration for the undertaking by the District of Columbia to contribute to the capital required for the construction and/or acquisition of facilities specified in a mass transit plan adopted as provided in Article VI, or in any alteration, revision or amendment thereof, and for meeting expenses and obligations incurred in the operation of such facilities.</section><section prefix="(d)"><section prefix="(1)">All payments made by the local Signatory governments for the Authority for the purpose of matching federal funds appropriated in any given year as authorized under Title VI, &#xA7; 601, P.L. 110-432 regarding funding of capital and preventive maintenance projects of the Authority shall be made from amounts derived from dedicated funding sources.</section><section prefix="(2)">For purposes of this paragraph (d), a "dedicated funding source" means any source of funding that is earmarked or required under State or local law to be used to match federal appropriations authorized under Title VI, &#xA7; 601, P.L. 110-432 for payments to the Authority.</section></section><section prefix="(a)">The Authority is authorized to acquire by purchase, lease or grant or in any manner other than condemnation, from the federal government, or any agency thereof, from the District of Columbia, Maryland or Virginia, or any political subdivision or agency thereof, any transit and related facilities, including real and personal property and all other assets, located within the zone, whether in operation or under construction. Such acquisition shall be made upon such terms and conditions as may be agreed upon and subject to such authorization or approval by the Congress and the governing body of the District of Columbia, as may be required; provided, however, that if such acquisition imposes or may impose any further or additional obligation or liability upon the Washington Suburban Transit District, the Northern Virginia Transportation District, or any component government thereof, under any contract with the Authority, the Authority shall not make such acquisition until any such affected contract has been appropriately amended.</section><section prefix="(b)">For such purpose, the Authority is authorized to assume all liabilities and contracts relating thereto, to assume responsibility as primary obligor, endorser or guarantor on any outstanding revenue bonds, equipment trust certificates or other form of indebtedness authorized in this title issued by such predecessor agency or agencies and, in connection therewith, to become a party to, and assume the obligations of, any indenture or loan agreement underlying or issued in connection with any outstanding securities or debts.</section><section prefix="(a)">Following the adoption by the board of annual capital and current expense budgets, the general manager shall transmit certified copies of such budgets to the principal budget officer of the federal government, the District of Columbia, the Washington Suburban Transit District and of the component governments of the Northern Virginia Transportation Commission at such time and in such manner as may be required under the respective budgetary procedures.</section><section prefix="(b)">Each budget shall indicate the amounts, if any, required from the federal government, the government of the District of Columbia, the Washington Suburban Transit District and the component governments of the Northern Virginia Transportation District, determined in accordance with the commitments made pursuant to Article VII, &#xA7; 18 of this title, to balance each of said budgets.</section><section prefix="(a)">Specify the services and functions to be performed by the contractor;</section><section prefix="(b)">Provide that the contractor shall hire, supervise and control all personnel required to perform the services and functions assumed by it under the operating contract and that all such personnel shall be employees of the contractor and not of the Authority;</section><section prefix="(c)">Require the contractor to assume the obligations of the labor contract or contracts of any transit company which may be acquired by the Authority and assume the pension obligations of any such transit company;</section><section prefix="(d)">Require the contractor to comply in all respects with the labor policy set forth in Article XIV of this title;</section><section prefix="(e)">Provide that no transfer of ownership of the capital stock, securities or interests in any contractor, whose principal business is the operating contract, shall be made without written approval of the board and the certificates or other instruments representing such stock, securities or interests shall contain a statement of this restriction;</section><section prefix="(f)">Provide that the board shall have the sole authority to determine the rates or fares to be charged, the routes to be operated and the service to be furnished;</section><section prefix="(g)">Specify the obligations and liabilities which are to be assumed by the contractor and those which are to be the responsibility of the Authority;</section><section prefix="(h)">Provide for an annual audit of the books and accounts of the contractor by an independent certified public accountant to be selected by the board and for such other audits, examinations and investigations of the books and records, procedures and affairs of the contractor at such times and in such manner as the board shall require, the cost of such audits, examinations and investigations to be borne as agreed by the parties in the operating contract; and</section><section prefix="(i)">Provide that no operating contract shall be entered into for a term in excess of five years; provided, that any such contract may be renewed for successive terms, each of which shall not exceed five years. Any such operating contract shall be subject to termination by the board for cause only.</section><section prefix="(a)">The Authority --<section prefix="(1)">Except as herein provided, shall not, directly or through a contractor, perform transit service by bus or similar motor vehicles;</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall, in cooperation with the private carriers and WMATC, coordinate to the fullest extent practicable, the schedules for service performed by its facilities with the schedules for service performed by private carriers; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Shall enter into agreements with the private carriers to establish and maintain, subject to approval by WMATC, through routes and joint fares and provide for the division thereof, or, in the absence of such agreements, establish and maintain through routes and joint fares in accordance with orders issued by WMATC directed to the private carriers when the terms and conditions for such through service and joint fares are acceptable to it.</section></section><section prefix="(b)">The WMATC, upon application, complaint, or upon its own motion, shall --<section prefix="(1)">Direct private carriers to coordinate their schedules for service with the schedules for service performed by facilities owned or controlled by the Authority;</section><section prefix="(2)">Direct private carriers to improve or extend any existing services or provide additional service over additional routes;</section><section prefix="(3)">Authorize a private carrier, pursuant to agreement between said carrier and the Authority, to establish and maintain through routes and joint fares for transportation to be rendered with facilities owned or controlled by the Authority if, after hearing held upon reasonable notice, WMATC finds that such through routes and joint fares are required by the public interest; and</section><section prefix="(4)">In the absence of such an agreement with the Authority, direct a private carrier to establish and maintain through routes and joint fares with the Authority, if, after hearing held upon reasonable notice, WMATC finds that such through service and joint fares are required by the public interest; provided, however, that no such order, rule or regulation of WMATC shall be construed to require the Authority to establish and maintain any through route and joint fare.</section></section><section prefix="(c)">WMATC shall not authorize or require a private carrier to render any service, including the establishment or continuation of a joint fare for a through-route service with the Authority which is based on a division thereof between the Authority and private carrier which does not provide a reasonable return to the private carrier, unless the carrier is currently earning a reasonable return on its operation as a whole in performing transportation subject to the jurisdiction of WMATC. In determining the issue of reasonable return, WMATC shall take into account any income attributable to the carrier, or to any corporation, firm or association owned in whole or in part by the carrier, from the Authority whether by way of payment for services or otherwise.</section><section prefix="(d)">If the WMATC is unable, through the exercise of its regulatory powers over the private carriers granted in paragraph (b) hereof or otherwise, to bring about the requisite coordination of operations and service between the private carriers and the Authority, the Authority may in the situations specified in paragraph (b) hereof, cause such transit service to be rendered by its contractor by bus or other motor vehicle, as it shall deem necessary to effectuate the policy set forth in &#xA7; 55 hereof. In any such situation, the Authority, in order to encourage private carriers to render bus service to the fullest extent practicable, may, pursuant to agreement, make reasonable subsidy payments to any private carrier.</section><section prefix="(e)">The Authority may acquire the capital stock or the transit facilities of any private transit company and may perform transit service, including service by bus or similar motor vehicle, with transit facilities so acquired or with transit facilities acquired pursuant to Article VII, &#xA7; 20. Upon acquisition of the capital stock or the transit facilities of any private transit company, the Authority shall undertake the acquisition, as soon as possible, of the capital stock or the transit facilities of each of the other private transit companies within the zone requesting such acquisition. Lack of such request, however, shall not be construed to preclude the Authority from acquiring the capital stock or the transit facilities of any such company pursuant to &#xA7; 82 of Article XVI.</section><section prefix="(a)">The board may accept grants from and enter into loan agreements with the Housing and Home Finance Administrator, pursuant to the provisions of the Urban Mass Transportation Act of 1964 (78 Stat. 302), or with any successor agency or under any law of similar purport, for the purpose of rendering financial assistance to private carriers.</section><section prefix="(b)">An application by the board for any such grant or loan shall be based on and supported by a report from WMATC setting forth for each private carrier to be assisted (1) the equipment and facilities to be acquired, constructed, reconstructed, or improved, (2) the service proposed to be rendered by such equipment and facilities, (3) the improvement in service expected from such facilities and equipment, (4) how the use of such facilities and equipment will be coordinated with the transit facilities owned by the Authority, (5) the ability of the affected private carrier to repay any such loans or grants and (6) recommended terms for any such loans or grants.</section><section prefix="(c)">Any equipment or facilities acquired, constructed, reconstructed or improved with the proceeds of such grants or loans shall be owned by the Authority and may be made available to private carriers only by lease or other agreement which contain provisions acceptable to the Housing and Home Finance Administrator assuring that the Authority will have satisfactory continuing control over the use of such facilities and equipment.</section><section prefix="(a)">Pay the operating expenses and provide for repairs, maintenance and depreciation of the transit system owned or controlled by the Authority;</section><section prefix="(b)">Provide for payment of all principal and interest on outstanding revenue bonds and other obligations and for payment of all amounts to sinking funds and other funds as may be required by the terms of any indenture or loan agreement;</section><section prefix="(c)">Provide for the purchase, lease or acquisition of rolling stock, including provisions for interest, sinking funds, reserve funds, or other funds required for the payment of any obligations incurred by the Authority for the acquisition of rolling stock; and</section><section prefix="(d)">Provide funds for any purpose the board deems necessary and desirable to carry out the purposes of this title.</section><section prefix="(a)">The Board shall not raise any fare or rate, nor implement a major service reduction, except after holding a public hearing with respect thereto.</section><section prefix="(b)">Any Signatory, any political subdivision thereof, any agency of the federal government and any person, firm or association served by or using the transit facilities of the Authority and any private carrier may file a request with the Board for a hearing with respect to any rates or charges made by the Board or any service rendered with the facilities owned or controlled by the Authority. Such request shall be in writing, shall state the matter on which a hearing is requested and shall set forth clearly the matters and things on which the request relies. As promptly as possible after such a request is filed, the Board, or such officer or employee as it may designate, shall confer with the protestant with respect to the matters complained of. After such conference, the Board, if it deems the matter meritorious and of general significance, may call a hearing with respect to such request.</section><section prefix="(c)">The Board shall give at least fifteen days' notice for all public hearings. The notice shall be given by publication in a newspaper of daily circulation throughout the Transit Zone and such notice shall be published once a week for two successive weeks. The notice period shall start with the first day of publication. Notices of public hearings shall be posted in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Board.</section><section prefix="(d)">Prior to calling a hearing on any matter specified in this section, the Board shall prepare and file at its main office and keep open for public inspection its report relating to the proposed action to be considered at such hearing. Upon receipt by the Board of any report submitted by WMATC, in connection with a matter set for hearing, pursuant to the provisions of &#xA7; 63 of this Article XIII, the Board shall file such report at its main office and make it available for public inspection. For hearings called by the Board pursuant to paragraph (b), above, the Board also shall cause to be lodged and kept open for public inspection the written request upon which the hearing is granted and all documents filed in support thereof.</section><section prefix="(a)">The board shall refer to WMATC for its consideration and recommendations, any matter which the board considers may affect the operation of the publicly and privately owned or controlled transit facilities as a coordinated regional transit system and any matter for which the board has called a hearing, pursuant to &#xA7; 62 of this Article XIII, except that temporary or emergency changes in matters affecting service shall not be referred; and</section><section prefix="(b)">WMATC, upon such reference of any matter to it, shall give the referred matter preference over any other matters pending before it and shall, as expeditiously as practicable, prepare and transmit its report thereon to the board. The board may request WMATC to reconsider any part of its report or to make any supplemental reports it deems necessary. All of such reports shall be advisory only.</section><section prefix="(c)">Any report submitted by WMATC to the board shall consider, without limitation, the probable effect of the matter or proposal upon the operation of the publicly and privately owned or controlled transit facilities as a coordinated regional system, passenger movements, fare structures, service and the impact on the revenues of both the public and private facilities.</section><section prefix="(a)">The rights, benefits, and other employee protective conditions and remedies of &#xA7; 13(c) of the Urban Mass Transportation Act of 1964, as amended (49 U.S.C. 1609(c)), as determined by the Secretary of Labor, shall apply to the operation by the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority of any mass transit facilities owned or controlled by it and to any contract or other arrangement for the operation of transit facilities. Whenever the Authority shall operate any transit facility or enter into any contractual or other arrangements for the operation of such transit facility the Authority shall extend to employees of affected mass transportation systems first opportunity for transfer and appointment as employees of the Authority in accordance with seniority, in any nonsupervisory job in respect to such operations for which they can qualify after a reasonable training period. Such employment shall not result in any worsening of the employee's position in his former employment nor any loss of wages, hours, working conditions, seniority, fringe benefits and rights and privileges pertaining thereto.</section><section prefix="(b)">The Authority shall deal with and enter into written contracts with employees as defined in &#xA7; 152 of Title 29, United States Code, through accredited representatives of such employees or representatives of any labor organization authorized to act for such employees concerning wages, salaries, hours, working conditions, and pension or retirement provisions.</section><section prefix="(c)">In case of any labor dispute involving the Authority and such employees where collective bargaining does not result in agreement, the Authority shall submit such dispute to arbitration by a board composed of three persons, one appointed by the Authority, one appointed by the labor organization representing the employees, and a third member to be agreed upon by the labor organization and the Authority. The member agreed upon by the labor organization and the Authority shall act as chairman of the board. The determination of the majority of the board of arbitration, thus established shall be final and binding on all matters in dispute. If after a period of ten days from the date of the appointment of the two arbitrators representing the Authority and the labor organization, the third arbitrator has not been selected, then either arbitrator may request the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service to furnish a list of five persons from which the third arbitrator shall be selected. The arbitrators appointed by the Authority and the labor organization, promptly after the receipt of such list shall determine by lot the order of elimination, and thereafter each shall in that order alternately eliminate one name until only one name remains. The remaining person on the list shall be the third arbitrator. The term "labor dispute" shall be broadly construed and shall include any controversy concerning wages, salaries, hours, working conditions, or benefits including health and welfare, sick leave, insurance or pension or retirement provisions but not limited thereto, and including any controversy concerning any differences or questions that may arise between the parties including but not limited to the making or maintaining of collective bargaining agreements, the terms to be included in such agreements, and the interpretation or application of such collective bargaining agreements and any grievance that may arise and questions concerning representation. Each party shall pay one half of the expenses of such arbitration.</section><section prefix="(d)">The Authority is hereby authorized and empowered to establish and maintain a system of pensions and retirement benefits for such officers and employees of the Authority as may be designated or described by resolution of the Authority; to fix the terms of and restrictions on admission to such system and the classifications therein; to provide that persons eligible for admission in such pension system shall not be eligible for admission to, or receive any benefits from, any other pension system (except Social Security benefits), which is financed or funded, in whole or in part, directly or indirectly by funds paid or appropriated by the Authority to such other pension system, and to provide in connection with such pension system, a system of benefits payable to the beneficiaries and dependents of any participant in such pension system after the death of such participant (whether accidental or otherwise, whether occurring in the actual performance of duty or otherwise, or both) subject to such exceptions, conditions, restrictions and classifications as may be provided by resolution of the Authority. Such pension system shall be financed or funded by such means and in such manner as may be determined by the Authority to be economically feasible. Unless the Authority shall otherwise determine, no officer or employee of the Authority and no beneficiary or dependent of any such officer or employee shall be eligible to receive any pension or retirement or other benefits both from or under any such pension system and from or under any pension or retirement system established by an acquired transportation system or established or provided for, by or under the provisions of any collective bargaining agreement between the Authority and the representatives of its employees.</section><section prefix="(e)">Whenever the Authority acquires existing transit facilities from a public or privately owned utility either in proceeding by eminent domain or otherwise, the Authority shall assume and observe all existing labor contracts and pension obligations. When the Authority acquires an existing transportation system, all employees (except executive officers) who are necessary for the operation thereof by the Authority shall be transferred to and appointed as employees of the Authority, subject to all the rights and benefits of this title. These employees shall be given seniority credit and sick leave, vacation, insurance and pension credits in accordance with the records or labor agreements from the acquired transportation system. Members and beneficiaries of any pension or retirement system or other benefits established by the acquired transportation system shall continue to have rights, privileges, benefits, obligations and status with respect to such established system. The Authority shall assume the obligations of any transportation system acquired by it with regard to wages, salaries, hours, working conditions, sick leave, health and welfare and pension or retirement provisions for employees. It shall assume the provisions of any collective bargaining agreement between such acquired transportation system and the representatives of its employees. The Authority and the employees, through their representatives for collective bargaining purposes, shall take whatever action may be necessary to have pension trust funds presently under the joint control of the acquired transportation system and the participating employees through their representative transferred to the trust fund to be established, maintained and administered jointly by the Authority and the participating employees through their representatives. No employee of any acquired transportation system who is transferred to a position with the Authority shall by reason of such transfer be placed in any worse position with respect to workmen's compensation, pension, seniority, wages, sick leave, vacation, health and welfare insurance or any other benefits, than he enjoyed as an employee of such acquired transportation system.</section><section prefix="(a)">The board may provide for the creation and administration of such funds as may be required. The funds shall be disbursed in accordance with rules established by the board and all payments from any fund shall be reported to the board. Moneys in such funds and other moneys of the Authority shall be deposited, as directed by the board, in any branch or subsidiary of any state or national bank which has operations within the zone, and having a total paid-in capital of at least one million dollars ($1,000,000). The trust department of any such state or national bank may be designated as a depositary to receive any securities acquired or owned by the Authority. The restriction with respect to paid-in capital may be waived for any such bank which agrees to pledge federal securities to protect the funds and securities of the Authority in such amounts and pursuant to such arrangements as may be acceptable to the board.</section><section prefix="(b)">Any moneys of the Authority may, in the discretion of the board and subject to any agreement or covenant between the Authority and the holders of any of its obligations limiting or restricting classes of investments, be invested in:<section prefix="(1)">Direct obligations of or obligations guaranteed by the United States of America;</section><section prefix="(2)">Bonds, debentures, notes or other evidences of indebtedness issued by agencies of the United States of America, including but not limited to the following: Bank for Cooperatives; Federal Intermediate Credit Banks; Federal Home Loan Bank System; Export-Import Bank of the United States; Federal Land Banks; Federal National Mortgage Association; Student Loan Marketing Association; Government National Mortgage Association; Tennessee Valley Authority; or United States Postal Service;</section><section prefix="(3)">Securities that qualify as lawful investments and may be accepted as security for fiduciary, trust and public funds under the control of the United States or any officer or officers thereof, or securities eligible as collateral for deposits of moneys of the United States, including United States Treasury tax and loan accounts;</section><section prefix="(4)">Domestic and Eurodollar certificates of deposit; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Bonds, debentures, notes or other evidences of indebtedness issued by a domestic corporation, such as a corporation organized under the laws of one of the states of the United States, provided that such obligations are nonconvertible and at the time of their purchase are rated in the highest rating categories by a nationally recognized bond rating agency.</section></section><section prefix="(a)">As soon as practical after the closing of the fiscal year, an audit shall be made of the financial accounts of the Authority. The audit shall be made by qualified certified public accountants selected by the board, who shall have no personal interest direct or indirect in the financial affairs of the Authority or any of its officers or employees. The report of audit shall be prepared in accordance with generally accepted auditing principles and shall be filed with the chairman and other officers as the board shall direct. Copies of the report shall be distributed to each director, to the Congress, to the Mayor and Council of the District of Columbia, to the Governors of Virginia and Maryland, to the Washington Suburban Transit Commission, to the Northern Virginia Transportation Commission and to the governing bodies of the political subdivisions located within the zone which are parties to commitments for participation in the financing of the Authority and shall be made available for public distribution.</section><section prefix="(b)">The financial transactions of the board shall be subject to audit by the United States General Accounting Office in accordance with the principles and procedures applicable to commercial corporate transactions and under such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by the Comptroller General of the United States. The audit shall be conducted at the place or places where the accounts of the board are kept.</section><section prefix="(c)">Any director, officer or employee who shall refuse to give all required assistance and information to the accountants selected by the board or who shall refuse to submit to them for examination such books, documents, records, files, accounts, papers, things or property as may be requested shall, in the discretion of the board, forfeit his office.</section><section prefix="(a)"><section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsections (b), (c), and (f) of this section and except in the case of procurement procedures otherwise expressly authorized by statute, the Authority in conducting a procurement of property, services, or construction shall:<section prefix="(i)">Obtain full and open competition through the use of competitive procedures in accordance with the requirements of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Use the competitive procedure or combination of competitive procedures that is best suited under the circumstances of the procurement.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">In determining the competitive procedure appropriate under the circumstances, the Authority shall:<section prefix="(i)">Solicit sealed bids if:<section prefix="1.">Time permits the solicitation, submission, and evaluation of sealed bids;</section><section prefix="2.">The award will be made on the basis of price and other price-related factors;</section><section prefix="3.">It is not necessary to conduct discussions with the responding sources about their bids; and</section><section prefix="4.">There is a reasonable expectation of receiving more than one sealed bid; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Request competitive proposals if sealed bids are not appropriate under item (i) of this paragraph.</section></section></section><section prefix="(b)">The Authority may provide for the procurement of property, services, or construction covered by this section using competitive procedures but excluding a particular source in order to establish or maintain an alternative source or sources of supply for that property, service, or construction if the Authority determines that excluding the source would increase or maintain competition and would likely result in reduced overall costs for procurement of property, services, or construction.</section><section prefix="(c)">The Authority may use procedures other than competitive procedures if:<section prefix="(1)">The property, services, or construction needed by the Authority is available from only one responsible source, and no other type of property, services or construction will satisfy the needs of the Authority; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The Authority's need for the property, services, or construction is of such an unusual and compelling urgency that the Authority would be seriously injured unless the Authority limits the number of sources from which it solicits bids or proposals; or</section><section prefix="(3)">The Authority determines that it is necessary in the public interest to use procedures other than competitive procedures in the particular procurement; or</section><section prefix="(4)">The property or services needed can be obtained through federal or other governmental sources at reasonable prices.</section></section><section prefix="(d)">For the purpose of applying subsection (c)(1) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">In the case of a contract for property, services, or construction to be awarded on the basis of acceptance of an unsolicited proposal, the property, services, or construction shall be deemed to be available from only one responsible source if the source has submitted an unsolicited proposal that demonstrates a concept:<section prefix="(i)">That is unique and innovative or, in the case of a service, for which the source demonstrates a unique capability to provide the service; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The substance of which is not otherwise available to the Authority and does not resemble the substance of a pending competitive procurement.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">In the case of a follow-on contract for the continued development or production of a major system or highly specialized equipment or the continued provision of highly specialized services, the property, services, or construction may be deemed to be available from only the original source and may be procured through procedures other than competitive procedures if it is likely that award to a source other than the original source would result in:<section prefix="(i)">Substantial duplication of cost to the Authority that is not expected to be recovered through competition; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Unacceptable delays in fulfilling the Authority's needs.</section></section></section><section prefix="(e)">If the Authority uses procedures other than competitive procedures to procure property, services or construction under subsection (c)(2) of this section, the Authority shall request offers from as many potential sources as is practicable under the circumstances.</section><section prefix="(f)"><section prefix="(1)">To promote efficiency and economy in contracting, the Authority may use simplified acquisition procedures for purchases of property, services, and construction.</section><section prefix="(2)">For the purposes of this subsection, simplified acquisition procedures may be used for purchases for an amount that does not exceed the simplified acquisition threshold adopted by the federal government.</section><section prefix="(3)">A proposed purchase or contract for an amount above the simplified acquisition threshold may not be divided into several purchases or contracts for lesser amounts in order to use the procedures under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section><section prefix="(4)">In using simplified acquisition procedures, the Authority shall promote competition to the maximum extent practicable.</section></section><section prefix="(g)">The board shall adopt policies and procedures to implement this section. The policies and procedures shall provide for publication of notice of procurements and other actions designed to secure competition where competitive procedures are used.</section><section prefix="(h)">The Authority in its discretion may reject any and all bids or proposals received in response to a solicitation.</section><section prefix="(a)">The Authority is authorized to establish and maintain a regular police force, to be known as the metro transit police, to provide protection for its patrons, personnel, and transit facilities. The metro transit police shall have the powers and duties and shall be subject to the limitations set forth in this section. It shall be composed of both uniformed and plainclothes personnel and shall be charged with the duty of enforcing the laws of the signatories, and the laws, ordinances and regulations of the political subdivisions thereof in the transit zone, and the rules and regulations of the Authority. The jurisdiction of the metro transit police shall be limited to all the transit facilities (including bus stops) owned, controlled or operated by the Authority, but this restriction shall not limit the power of the metro transit police to make arrests in the transit zone for violations committed upon, to or against such transit facilities committed from within or outside such transit facilities, while in hot or close pursuit or to execute traffic citations and criminal process in accordance with subsection (c) below. The members of the metro transit police shall have concurrent jurisdiction in the performance of their duties with the duly constituted law enforcement agencies of the signatories and of the political subdivisions thereof in which any transit facility of the Authority is located or in which the Authority operates any transit service. Nothing contained in this section shall either relieve any signatory or political subdivision or agency thereof from its duty to provide police, fire and other public safety service and protection, or limit, restrict or interfere with the jurisdiction of or the performance of duties by the existing police, fire and other public safety agencies. For purposes of this section, "bus stop" means that area within 150 feet of a metrobus bus stop sign, excluding the interior of any building not owned, controlled, or operated by the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority.</section><section prefix="(b)">A member of the metro transit police shall have the same powers, including the power of arrest, and shall be subject to the same limitations, including regulatory limitations, in the performance of his duties as a member of the duly constituted police force of the political subdivision in which the metro transit police member is engaged in the performance of his duties. A member of the metro transit police is authorized to carry and use only such weapons, including handguns, as are issued by the Authority. A member of the metro transit police is subject to such additional limitations in the use of weapons as are imposed on the duly constituted police force for the political subdivision in which he is engaged in the performance of his duties.</section><section prefix="(c)">Members of the metro transit police shall have power to execute on the transit facilities owned, controlled, or operated by the Authority any traffic citation or any criminal process issued by any court of any signatory or of any political subdivision of a signatory, for any felony, misdemeanor or other offense against laws, ordinances, rules, or regulations of the Authority, or of the signatory or its political subdivision as specified in subsection (a). With respect to offenses committed upon, to, or against the transit facilities owned, controlled or operated by the Authority, the metro transit police shall have power to execute criminal process within the transit zone.</section><section prefix="(d)">Upon the apprehension or arrest of any person by a member of the metro transit police pursuant to the provisions of subsection (b), the arresting officer, as required by the law of the place of arrest, shall either issue a summons or a citation against the person, or book or deliver the person to the duly constituted judicial officer of the signatory or political subdivision where the arrest is made, for disposition as required by law.</section><section prefix="(e)">The Authority shall have the power to adopt rules and regulations for the safe, convenient and orderly use of the transit facilities owned, controlled, or operated by the Authority, including the payment and the manner of the payment of fares or charges therefor, the protection of the transit facilities, the control of traffic and parking upon the transit facilities, and the safety and protection of the riding public. In the event that any such rules and regulations contravene the laws, ordinances, rules, or regulations of a signatory or any political subdivision thereof which are existing or subsequently enacted, these laws, ordinances, rules, or regulations of the signatory or the political subdivision shall apply and the conflicting rule or regulation, or portion thereof, of the Authority shall be void within the jurisdiction of that signatory or political subdivision. In all other respects, the rules and regulations of the Authority shall be uniform throughout the transit zone. The rules or regulations established under this subsection shall be adopted by the Board following public hearings held in accordance with Section 62(c) and (d) of this Compact. The final regulation shall be published in a newspaper of general circulation within the zone at least 15 days before its effective date. Any person violating any rule or regulation of the Authority shall be subject to arrest and, upon conviction by a court of competent jurisdiction, shall pay a fine of not more than $250 and costs. Criminal violations of any rule or regulation of the Authority shall be prosecuted by the signatory or political subdivision in which the violation occurred, in the same manner by which violations of law, ordinances, rules, and regulations of the signatory or political subdivisions are prosecuted.</section><section prefix="(f)">With respect to members of the metro transit police, the Authority shall<section prefix="(1)">Establish classifications based on the nature and scope of duties, and fix and provide for their qualifications, appointment, removal, tenure, term, compensation, pension and retirement benefits;</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide for their training and, for this purpose, the Authority may enter into contracts or agreements with any public or private organization engaged in police training, and this training and the qualifications of the uniformed and plainclothes personnel shall at least equal the requirements of each signatory and of the political subdivisions therein in the transit zone for their personnel performing comparable duties; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Prescribe distinctive uniforms to be worn.</section></section><section prefix="(g)">The Authority shall have the power to enter into agreements with the signatories, the political subdivisions thereof in the transit zone and public safety agencies located therein, including those of the federal government, for the delineation of the functions and responsibilities of the metro transit police and other duly constituted police, fire and other public safety agencies, and for mutual assistance.</section><section prefix="(h)">Before entering upon the duties of office, each member of the metro transit police shall take or subscribe to an oath or affirmation, before a person authorized to administer oaths, faithfully to perform the duties of that office.</section><section prefix="(a)">The Authority shall have the power to acquire by condemnation, whenever in its opinion it is necessary or advantageous to the Authority to do so, any real or personal property, or any interest therein, necessary or useful for the transit system authorized herein, except property owned by the United States, by a signatory, or any political subdivision thereof, whenever such property cannot be acquired by negotiated purchase at a price satisfactory to the Authority.</section><section prefix="(b)">Proceedings for the condemnation of property in the District of Columbia, shall be instituted and maintained under the Act of December 23, 1963 (77 Stat. 577-581, D.C. Code 1961, Supp. IV, &#xA7;&#xA7; 1351-1368). Proceedings for the condemnation of property located elsewhere within the zone shall be instituted and maintained, if applicable, pursuant to the provisions of the Act of August 1, 1888, as amended (25 Stat. 357, 40 D.S.C. 257) and the Act of June 25, 1948 (62 Stat. 935 and 937, 28 U.S.C. 1358 and 1403) or any other applicable act; provided, however, that if there is no applicable federal law, condemnation proceedings shall be in accordance with the provisions of the state law of the signatory in which the property is located governing condemnation by the highway agency of such state. Whenever the words "real property," "realty," "land," "easement," "right-of-way," or words of similar meaning are used in any applicable federal or state law relating to procedure, jurisdiction and venue, they shall be deemed, for the purposes of this title, to include any personal property authorized to be acquired hereunder.</section><section prefix="(c)">Any award or compensation for the taking of property pursuant to this title shall be paid by the Authority, and none of the signatory parties nor any other agency, instrumentality or political subdivision thereof shall be liable for such award of compensation.</section><section prefix="(a)">When advised in writing by the Northern Virginia Transportation Commission or the Washington Suburban Transit Commission that the geographical area embraced therein has been enlarged, the board, upon such terms and conditions as it may deem appropriate, shall by resolution enlarge the zone to embrace the additional area.</section><section prefix="(b)">The duration of this title shall be perpetual but any signatory thereto may withdraw therefrom upon two years' written notice to the board.</section><section prefix="(c)">The withdrawal of any signatory shall not relieve such signatory, any transportation district, county or city or other political subdivision thereof from any obligation to the Authority, or inuring to the benefit of the Authority, created by contract or otherwise.</section></text>
</law>
