<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-24-104.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>Notwithstanding any other provision of this title and subject to subsections (b), (c), and (d) of th...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this title and subject to subsections (b), (c), and (d) of this section, a person may operate a semitrailer (single) in combination with a truck tractor that exceeds 48 feet in length up to a length not to exceed 53 feet.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A vehicle combination described under subsection (a) of this section may be operated only on:<section prefix="(i)">Those parts of the national interstate highway system and those State highways that are designated by the Secretary, after consultation with either the county executive, the county commissioners, the County Council of Talbot County or Wicomico County, or the Mayor of Baltimore City, or their designees, as appropriate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Except in Baltimore City, a highway, authorized by the Secretary, that is the shortest practical access route between a highway designated under item (i) of this paragraph and:<section prefix="1.">A truck terminal;</section><section prefix="2.">A port;</section><section prefix="3.">A point of origin or destination; or</section><section prefix="4.">For a distance not to exceed one-half mile, facilities for food, fuel, repairs, or rest; or</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">In Baltimore City, a street authorized by the Mayor or the Mayor's designee in conjunction with the Secretary that is the safest practical route between a highway designated under item (i) of this paragraph and:<section prefix="1.">A truck terminal;</section><section prefix="2.">A port facility;</section><section prefix="3.">A point of origin; or</section><section prefix="4.">A point of destination.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary shall adopt regulations establishing designated highways, a method for approving access routes, and other criteria necessary to implement this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A vehicle combination operating under this section may operate in this State only under the following conditions:<section prefix="(1)">The wheelbase of the semitrailer, measured as the distance from the kingpin to the center of the rear tandem axles, may not exceed 41 feet in length.</section><section prefix="(2)">The kingpin setback, measured as the distance from the kingpin to the front of the semitrailer, may not exceed 4 feet in length.</section><section prefix="(3)">The rear overhang, measured as the distance from the center of the rear tandem axles to the rear of the semitrailer, may not exceed 35 percent of the wheelbase of the semitrailer.</section><section prefix="(4)"><section prefix="(i)">The width of the semitrailer shall be at least 96 inches and not more than 102 inches.</section><section prefix="(ii)">The distance between the outside edges of the semitrailer's tires shall be equal to the width of the semitrailer.</section></section><section prefix="(5)">The semitrailer shall be equipped with:<section prefix="(i)">Vehicle lights which comply with or exceed federal standards; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">After December 31, 1993, or a date established by the Secretary that is at least 6 months after the effective date of the applicable federal standards, whichever is later, reflective material that is consistent with the standards for conspicuity promulgated by the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration.</section></section><section prefix="(6)">The semitrailer shall be equipped with a rear underride guard of sufficient strength to prevent a motor vehicle from penetrating underneath the semitrailer. The rear underride guard shall extend across the rear of the semitrailer to within 4 inches of the lateral extremities of the semitrailer, and placed at a height not exceeding 22 inches from the surface as measured when the semitrailer is on a level surface.</section><section prefix="(7)">Conspicuous warnings shall be displayed on the semitrailer, in a manner prescribed by the Administration, indicating that the vehicle combination has a wide turning radius.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, if the Secretary determines that the provisions of subsection (b) or (c) of this section are violated by a substantial number of persons or if specific provisions of subsection (b) or (c) of this section are held invalid by a binding determination of the Federal Highway Administration or a court of competent jurisdiction:<section prefix="(1)">The Department, after a public hearing, may issue a special permit to allow a semitrailer (single), when operating in combination with a truck tractor, to exceed 48 feet in length up to a length not to exceed 53 feet;</section><section prefix="(2)">A person may not drive or permit to be driven on any publicly maintained highway a semitrailer (single), when operating in combination with a truck tractor, that exceeds 48 feet in length up to a length not to exceed 53 feet, unless a valid special permit issued under paragraph (1) of this subsection or a facsimile of a valid special permit is carried in or on the vehicle combination; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The Secretary may adopt regulations:<section prefix="(i)">That are consistent with the standards established in this section, for the issuance of permits for vehicle combinations described under subsection (a) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">That exempt from the requirements of, or provide alternative requirements to, subsection (c) of this section for a vehicle manufactured before July 1, 1991, if the vehicle cannot meet the requirements.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A special permit issued under subsection (d)(1) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">May be issued without a fee;</section><section prefix="(2)">May be a renewable blanket permit; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Shall expire on a date determined by the Secretary.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
