<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-1204" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-5-1204</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of this subtitle, the Administration shall establish a homeowners assistance pilot program for existing residentially occupied real property in those communities and neighborhoods identified by the Administration as being situated entirely or in part within the 65 LDN noise contour as established by the most recently adopted airport noise zone.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The pilot program established under this subsection shall provide at least 2 homeowner assistance options including:<section prefix="(i)">An option enabling homeowners to sell their real property, with the Administration assuring the resale value of the property; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">An option enabling homeowners who occupy single-family housing or rent such property for residential use to receive financial assistance from the Administration for noise-attenuating improvements which may include weather stripping, caulking, window glazing, augmentation of wall, door, ceiling, and attic insulation, and installation of forced air ventilation or other types of air conditioning systems.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Administration shall select at least 40 residential properties situated within the airport noise zone to participate in the pilot program, including at least 20 properties in each of the program options described in paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before conveying a fee interest in residential real property to a third party, a homeowner participating in the pilot program option described in subsection (a)(2)(i) of this section shall grant to the Administration an avigation easement.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A homeowner participating in the pilot program option described in subsection (a)(2)(ii) of this section shall grant to the Administration an avigation easement.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Administration shall:<section prefix="(1)">Implement the homeowners assistance pilot program in fiscal year 1988;</section><section prefix="(2)">Submit to the 1988 Session of the General Assembly, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, a report on the results of the program, including a study of the feasibility of making noise-attenuating improvements to schools; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Make recommendations as part of the Department's fiscal year 1989 budget request for the continued funding of the program.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
