<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-704.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-7-704.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "unattended transit vehicle or facility" means a transit vehicle or facility the entrance of which is not controlled by the presence of an authorized fare collection agent of the Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Any person entering an unattended transit vehicle or facility owned or controlled by the Administration for the purpose of obtaining transit service shall prepay the applicable fare charged by the Administration in the required manner.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a person engages in an act prohibited under &#xA7; 7-705 of this subtitle and a police officer or an authorized agent of the Administration requests the person to provide identification, the person shall provide:<section prefix="(1)">The person's true name and address; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Any written verification of the person's true name and address in the person's possession.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Upon receipt of satisfactory evidence of identification and a written promise to appear in court, a person who is charged with any of the offenses specified in &#xA7; 7-705 of this subtitle, may be issued a citation by an authorized agent of the Administration or a police officer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A police officer may arrest a person in lieu of the issuance of a citation when:<section prefix="(i)">The officer is not furnished satisfactory evidence of identity;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The officer has reasonable grounds to believe the person will disregard a written promise to appear; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">The person refuses to sign a written promise to appear after being advised by the officer that such refusal may result in the person's arrest.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The form of the citation shall be prescribed by the District Court and shall contain:<section prefix="(1)">The offense charged;</section><section prefix="(2)">A notice to appear in District Court on the date shown on the citation or when notified by the court;</section><section prefix="(3)">A promise to appear to be signed by the person charged;</section><section prefix="(4)">The signature and title of the authorized issuer; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Such other information as the Administration and the court shall require.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person shall comply with the notice to appear in District Court by:<section prefix="(i)">Appearing in person;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Appearance by counsel; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Payment of the fine in advance of trial.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A person who fails to comply with the notice to appear shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and subject to a fine of $100.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In addition, the court may notify the person by mail at the address indicated on the citation that a warrant for the person's arrest may be issued unless, within 15 days from the mailing of the notice, the person:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, by July 1, 1997, the Administration shall:<section prefix="(1)">Install and maintain a video monitoring system on all light rail transit vehicles to enhance security on the light rail transit system; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Take any other actions reasonably considered by the Administrator to be necessary to restrict public access to any unattended transit vehicle within the light rail transit system.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
