<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-26-201</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A police officer may charge a person with a violation of any of the following, if the officer has probable cause to believe that the person has committed or is committing the violation:<section prefix="(1)">The Maryland Vehicle Law, including any regulation adopted under any of its provisions;</section><section prefix="(2)">A traffic law or ordinance of any local authority;</section><section prefix="(3)">Title 9, Subtitle 2 of the Tax - General Article;</section><section prefix="(4)">Title 9, Subtitle 3 of the Tax - General Article;</section><section prefix="(5)">Title 10, Subtitle 4 of the Business Regulation Article;</section><section prefix="(6)">&#xA7; 10-323 of the Business Regulation Article; or</section><section prefix="(7)">&#xA7; 10-323.2 of the Business Regulation Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A police officer who charges a person under this section shall issue a traffic citation, and provide a copy, to the person charged.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A traffic citation issued to a person under this section shall contain:<section prefix="(1)">A notice in boldface type that, if the citation is a payable violation:<section prefix="(i)">The person must comply with one of the following within 30 days after receipt of the citation:<section prefix="1.">Pay the full amount of the preset fine;</section><section prefix="2.">Request a hearing regarding sentencing and disposition in lieu of a trial as provided in &#xA7; 26-204(b)(2) of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="3.">Request a trial date at the date, time, and place established by the District Court by writ or trial notice; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">If the person fails to comply within 30 days after receipt of the citation, the Administration will be notified and may take action to suspend the person's driver's license; and</section><section prefix="2.">Driving on a suspended license is a criminal offense for which the person could be incarcerated; or</section></section></section><section prefix="(2)">If the citation is for a must-appear violation, a notice that:<section prefix="(i)">The citation is a summons to appear as notified by a circuit court or the District Court through a trial notice setting the date, time, and place for the person to appear; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A circuit court or the District Court will issue a writ setting the date, time, and place for the person to appear;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">The name and address of the person;</section><section prefix="(4)">The number of the person's license to drive, if applicable;</section><section prefix="(5)">The State registration number of the vehicle, if applicable;</section><section prefix="(6)">The violation or violations charged;</section><section prefix="(7)">An acknowledgment of receipt of the citation, to be executed by the person as required under &#xA7; 1-605 of the Courts Article;</section><section prefix="(8)">Near the acknowledgment, a clear and conspicuous statement that:<section prefix="(i)">Acknowledgment of the citation by the person does not constitute an admission of guilt; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The failure to acknowledge receipt of the citation may subject the person to arrest; and</section></section><section prefix="(9)">Any other necessary information.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a citation is marked "you have the right to stand trial":<section prefix="(1)">The form of the defendant's copy of the citation shall include in boldface type a description of the following options:<section prefix="(i)">Payment of the fine;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Request a trial; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Request a "guilty with an explanation" hearing regarding sentencing and disposition in lieu of a trial; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The form of the "return to court" copy of the citation shall include in boldface type a check-off box for each of the options described in item (1) of this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A police officer who discovers a vehicle stopped, standing, or parked in violation of &#xA7; 21-1003 or &#xA7; 21-1010 of this article shall:<section prefix="(1)">Deliver a copy of a citation to the driver or, if the vehicle is unattended, attach a copy of a citation to the vehicle in a conspicuous place; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Keep a written or electronic copy of the citation, bearing the police officer's certification under penalty of perjury that the facts stated in the citation are true.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A police officer who discovers a motor vehicle parked in violation of &#xA7; 13-402 of this article shall:<section prefix="(i)">Deliver a copy of a citation to the driver or, if the motor vehicle is unattended, attach a copy of a citation to the motor vehicle in a conspicuous place; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Keep a written or electronic copy of the citation, bearing the law enforcement officer's certification under penalty of perjury that the facts stated in the citation are true.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the absence of the driver, the owner of the motor vehicle is presumed to be the person receiving the copy of a citation or warning.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
