<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-106</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>106</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each application for a driver's license shall be made on the form that the Administration requires.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The application shall state:<section prefix="(1)">The full name, Maryland residence address, race, sex, height, weight, general physical condition, and date of birth of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(2)">Whether the applicant previously has been refused a license to drive and, if so:<section prefix="(i)">By what state or country; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The date of and reason for the refusal;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Whether the applicant previously has been licensed to drive and, if so:<section prefix="(i)">When and by what state or country; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Whether the license ever has been suspended, revoked, or canceled and, if so, the date of and reason for the suspension, revocation, or cancellation;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">Subject to the provisions of subsection (c) of this section, the applicant's Social Security number; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Any other pertinent information that the Administration requires.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An applicant shall provide:<section prefix="(1)">Satisfactory documentary evidence that the applicant has a valid Social Security number by presenting the applicant's Social Security Administration account card or, if the Social Security Administration account card is not available, any of the following documents bearing the applicant's Social Security number:<section prefix="(i)">A current W-2 form;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A current SSA-1099 form;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A current non-SSA-1099 form; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">A current pay stub with the applicant's name and Social Security number on it; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Satisfactory documentary evidence that the applicant is not eligible for a Social Security number.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The applicant shall sign the application and certify that the statements made in it are true.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, an applicant for an original license shall submit with the application a birth certificate or other proof of age and identity that is satisfactory to the Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual party to an absolute divorce may elect to use a prior legal or true name upon filing an affidavit or other proof, satisfactory to the Administration, of:<section prefix="(i)">The prior name; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The absolute divorce.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An applicant who claims a name change by or under the common law of this State or any other state shall submit with the applicant's application the following:<section prefix="(i)">An affidavit of the name by which the applicant is known and transacts business, as demonstrated by a Social Security card or record together with documents from at least 2 of the following categories:<section prefix="1.">Tax records;</section><section prefix="2.">Selective Service card or records;</section><section prefix="3.">Voter registration card or records;</section><section prefix="4.">Passport;</section><section prefix="5.">A form of identification issued by a government unit that contains a photograph of the applicant;</section><section prefix="6.">Baptismal certificate;</section><section prefix="7.">Banking records; and</section><section prefix="8.">Other proof of age and identity that is satisfactory to the Administration;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Any document required under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph reflecting the legal name previously given to, or used by, the applicant prior to assuming the common law name;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any driver's license issued to the applicant in the name previously used by the applicant prior to assuming the common law name; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">A copy of the applicant's birth certificate or other proof of age and identity that is satisfactory to the Administration.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An applicant shall provide satisfactory documentary evidence that the applicant has lawful status.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If an individual previously licensed to drive in another jurisdiction applies for a license, the Administration may request a copy of his driving record from the other jurisdiction.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If another licensing jurisdiction requests a driving record from the Administration, the Administration may send the record to it without charge.</section>
  </text>
</law>
