<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-21-1004</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1004</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, a vehicle that is stopped or parked on a two-way roadway shall be stopped or parked parallel to the right hand curb or edge of the roadway, with its right hand wheels within 12 inches of that curb or edge of the roadway.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as otherwise provided by local ordinance, a vehicle that is stopped or parked on a one-way roadway shall be stopped or parked parallel to the curb or edge of the roadway, in the direction of authorized traffic movement, with:<section prefix="(1)">Its right hand wheels within 12 inches of the right hand curb or edge of the roadway; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Its left hand wheels within 12 inches of the left hand curb or edge of the roadway.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The State Highway Administration or any local authority may permit angle parking on the roadway of any highway in its jurisdiction, if the roadway has been determined to be wide enough to permit angle parking without interfering with the free movement of traffic.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The State Highway Administration or any local authority may place signs that prohibit or restrict the stopping, standing, or parking of vehicles on any highway in its jurisdiction where to stop, stand, or park would:<section prefix="(1)">Endanger those using the highway; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Interfere unduly with the free movement of traffic on the highway.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not stop, stand, or park a vehicle on any private property not owned by the owner or driver of the vehicle unless the person has express or implied permission from the property owner, his tenant, or his agent to stop, stand, or park the vehicle, as the case may be.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Baltimore City or in any county, upon the request of the owner, his agent, or his tenant, a police officer may issue a citation for a violation of the provisions of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">As of October 1, 2010, any sign that designates a parking space or zone for the use of individuals with disabilities shall clearly state the maximum amount of the fine to which a person is subject for parking a vehicle in the parking space or zone in violation of &#xA7; 21-1003(u) of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
