<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-22-405.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>405.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not drive on any highway any motor vehicle, trailer, or semitrailer having any metal tire in contact with the roadway.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, a tire on a vehicle driven on a highway may not have on its periphery any block, stud, flange, cleat, or spike or any other protuberance of any material, other than rubber, that projects beyond the tread of the traction surface of the tire, except that:<section prefix="(1)">It is permissible to use farm machinery with tires having protuberances that will not injure the highway;</section><section prefix="(2)">It is permissible to use tire chains of reasonable proportions on any vehicle when required for safety because of snow, ice, or other conditions tending to cause a vehicle to skid;</section><section prefix="(3)">It is permissible for a vehicle not registered or required to be registered in this State to use tires as described in this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Except in Allegany, Carroll, Frederick, Garrett, and Washington counties, a person may not sell or offer for sale in this State any tire which is not permitted to be used in this State under this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">From November 1 through March 31, owners of vehicles registered in Allegany County, Carroll County, Frederick County, Garrett County, or Washington County are exempt from the prohibition of the use of tires described in subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The State Highway Administration and local authorities in their respective jurisdictions, in their discretion, may issue special permits authorizing the operation on a highway of traction engines or tractors having movable tracks with transverse corrugations on the periphery of the movable tracks or farm tractors or other farm machinery, the operation of which on a highway otherwise would be prohibited under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
