<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-21-10A-05</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to subsection (b) of this section, if a vehicle is towed or otherwise removed from a parking...</catch_line>
  <order_by>05</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to subsection (b) of this section, if a vehicle is towed or otherwise removed from a parking lot, the person in possession of the vehicle:<section prefix="(1)">Shall immediately deliver the vehicle directly to the storage facility stated on the signs posted in accordance with &#xA7; 21-10A-02 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">May not move the towed vehicle from that storage facility to another storage facility for at least 72 hours; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Shall provide the owner of the vehicle or the owner's agent immediate and continuous opportunity, 24 hours per day, 7 days per week, from the time the vehicle was received at the storage facility, to retake possession of the vehicle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Before a vehicle is removed from a parking lot, a tower who possesses the vehicle shall release the vehicle to the owner or an agent of the owner:<section prefix="(1)">If the owner or agent requests that the tower release the vehicle;</section><section prefix="(2)">If the vehicle can be driven under its own power;</section><section prefix="(3)">Whether or not the vehicle has been lifted off the ground; and</section><section prefix="(4)">If the owner or agent pays a drop fee to the tower in an amount not exceeding 50% of the cost of a full tow.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, a storage facility that is in possession of a towed vehicle shall:<section prefix="(i)">Accept payment for outstanding towing, recovery, or storage charges by cash or at least two major, nationally recognized credit cards; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the storage facility accepts only cash, have an operable automatic teller machine available on the premises.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, if a storage facility is unable to process a credit card payment and does not have an operable automatic teller machine on the premises, the storage facility shall accept a personal check as payment for outstanding towing, recovery, and storage charges.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A storage facility may refuse to accept a personal check as payment if it is unable to process a credit card for the payment because use of the credit card has been declined by the credit card company.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A storage facility that is in possession of a towed vehicle shall make the vehicle available to the owner, the owner's agent, the insurer of record, or a secured party, under the supervision of the storage facility, for:<section prefix="(i)">Inspection; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Retrieval from the vehicle of personal property that is not attached to the vehicle.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
