<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-110.2" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-110.2</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "bioptic telescopic lens" means a spectacle mounted telescopic/telescopics telescope placed at the top of a corrective vision lens and designed to increase visual acuity and aid in spotting distant objects at a glance.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notwithstanding any other requirements under this subtitle, an applicant using bioptic telescopic lenses shall be eligible for a noncommercial Class C driver's license under this subtitle if the applicant:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">Demonstrates a visual acuity of at least 20/100 in one or both eyes and a field of 150 degrees horizontal vision with or without corrective lenses; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the applicant has vision in one eye only, demonstrates a field of at least 100 degrees horizontal vision;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Demonstrates a visual acuity of at least 20/70 in one or both eyes with the bioptic telescopic lenses and without the use of field expanders;</section><section prefix="(3)">Submits a report of examination by a licensed ophthalmologist or optometrist for evaluation by the Medical Advisory Board under &#xA7; 16-118 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Meets all the other requirements for licensure under this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An applicant using bioptic telescopic lenses shall be eligible for a learner's instructional permit under &#xA7; 16-103 of this subtitle if the applicant meets the requirements of subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, a license issued in compliance with this section authorizes the licensee to operate a motor vehicle only during the period beginning one-half hour after sunrise and ending one-half hour before sunset.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the applicant is eligible for a license under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Administration shall issue to the applicant a restricted license endorsed "daylight driving only".</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A licensee under this section may operate a motor vehicle without any restriction regarding hours of operation if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">Demonstrates a visual acuity of at least 20/40 in one or both eyes with the bioptic telescopic lenses and without the use of field expanders;</section><section prefix="(2)">Has been licensed under this section for at least one year; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Passes a skills test taken at night.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">This section only applies to an applicant who:<section prefix="(1)">Is granted a license under this section on or before September 30, 1997; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Continues to qualify for a license under this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
