<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-25-209</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>209</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person who owns a vehicle, on whose property is found an abandoned vehicle, or who has lawful, documented possession of a vehicle for which the certificate of title is defective, lost, or destroyed, may apply to a law enforcement agency for the jurisdiction in which the vehicle is located for authority to transfer the vehicle to an automotive dismantler and recycler or scrap processor.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The application shall be made under penalty of perjury and shall include:<section prefix="(1)">The name and address of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(2)">The year, make, model, and vehicle identification number of the vehicle, if ascertainable, and any other identifying features of the vehicle;</section><section prefix="(3)">A concise statement of the facts about the abandonment of the vehicle or the loss, destruction, or defect of the certificate of title of the vehicle; and</section><section prefix="(4)">An affidavit stating that the facts alleged in the application are true and that no material fact has been withheld.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a law enforcement agency finds that the application is executed in proper form and shows either that the vehicle has been abandoned on the property of the applicant or, if the vehicle is not abandoned, that the applicant appears to be the rightful owner, the law enforcement agency may:<section prefix="(i)">If the applicant appears to be the rightful owner, approve the request on verification of the information in the application; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the application is made by a person other than the rightful owner, follow the notification procedures of &#xA7;&#xA7; 25-204 and 25-205 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c-1)">If the applicant submits with the application documentary proof that the notification procedures of &#xA7;&#xA7; 25-204 and 25-205 of this subtitle already have been complied with, the law enforcement agency shall accept the document as proof of compliance and the agency is not required to provide this notification.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an abandoned vehicle is not reclaimed in the time required by this subtitle or notice has already been provided to the owner and any secured party, the law enforcement agency shall give the applicant a certificate of authority to transfer the vehicle to:<section prefix="(i)">Any automotive dismantler and recycler for:<section prefix="1.">Dismantling, destroying, or scrapping; or</section><section prefix="2.">Salvaging as authorized under &#xA7; 13-506 of this article; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Any scrap processor for dismantling, destroying, or scrapping.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The automotive dismantler and recycler or scrap processor shall accept the certificate of authority instead of the certificate of title of the vehicle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The automotive dismantler and recycler may apply for a salvage certificate as provided in &#xA7; 13-506 of this article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
