<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-24-113.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>113.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, and subject to subsections (b) and (c) of this section, the Secretary, by regulation, may determine that a combination of vehicles carrying manifested international freight as the only load of the vehicle in a sealed, seagoing container on a semitrailer is carrying an indivisible load provided that:<section prefix="(1)">A vehicle issued a permit under this section may not exceed 22,400 pounds gross maximum weight for a single axle, 44,000 pounds gross maximum weight for 2 consecutive axles, or 90,000 pounds gross maximum weight; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A vehicle issued a permit under this section may be operated only on:<section prefix="(i)">Those parts of the interstate and State systems of highways that are designated by the Secretary in conjunction with the United States Department of Transportation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any other highway, authorized by the Secretary, that is the shortest practical route between a highway designated pursuant to subparagraph (i) of this paragraph and:<section prefix="1.">A truck terminal;</section><section prefix="2.">A port or other point of origin or destination; or</section><section prefix="3.">For a distance not to exceed one mile, facilities for food, fuel, repairs, or rest.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall adopt regulations, consistent with the provisions of this section, for the issuance of permits for vehicles described under subsection (a) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The regulations adopted under this subsection may set fees and shall establish maximum axle and gross weight limits, routes, and other necessary criteria.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The authority granted under the provisions of this section may not be exercised unless and until the Secretary determines in writing that its exercise:<section prefix="(1)">Is required to provide access to or egress from the Port of Baltimore for international freight;</section><section prefix="(2)">Will not cause extraordinary damage to roads and bridges in the State or require extraordinary expense for the maintenance of those roads and bridges;</section><section prefix="(3)">Will not cause undue adverse environmental impact upon or unduly disrupt residential neighborhoods; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Will not impair highway safety.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
