<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-12-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to the specific powers granted and duties imposed by this title, the Administration has the powers and duties set forth in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Administration may adopt rules and regulations to carry out:<section prefix="(1)">Those provisions of the Maryland Vehicle Law that relate to or are administered and enforced by the Administration; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The provisions of any other law that the Administration is authorized to administer and enforce.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration shall maintain as many offices in this State as the Administrator considers necessary to carry out the powers and duties of the Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each office shall be open on the days and during the hours that the Secretary determines are needed to serve the public.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With the approval of the Secretary, the Administration shall employ the deputies, subordinate officers, clerks, investigators, and other employees necessary to carry out the powers and duties of the Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided by law, and subject to &#xA7; 2-103.4 of this article, each deputy, officer, and employee of the Administration:<section prefix="(i)">Is in the State Personnel Management System; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is entitled to the salary provided in the pay plan established under Title 8, Subtitle 1 of the State Personnel and Pensions Article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Administration may delegate to the Office of Administrative Hearings the power and authority under the Maryland Vehicle Law to conduct hearings under this article and render final decisions in hearings conducted under this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In accordance with &#xA7; 6-313 of the Courts Article and the Maryland Rules, the Administration shall serve as the agent to receive a subpoena, a summons, or other process for a nonresident driver named as a party in an action brought in a court of this State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
