<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-22-410</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>410</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Air-conditioning equipment" means mechanical vapor compression refrigeration equipment used to cool the driver's or passenger compartment of any motor vehicle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Ozone-depleting refrigerant" means a refrigerant used in air-conditioning equipment that contains a substance identified in 42 U.S.C. &#xA7; 7671a(a) or (b).</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Air-conditioning equipment shall be manufactured, installed, and maintained with due regard for the safety of the occupants of the vehicle and the public.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In a motor vehicle of model year 2011, or any model year thereafter, the air-conditioning equipment may contain only a refrigerant that:<section prefix="(1)">Is not an ozone-depleting refrigerant; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Is included in the list published by the United States Environmental Protection Agency as a safe alternative to chlorofluorocarbon-12, pursuant to 42 U.S.C. &#xA7; 7671k(c).</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Administrator, in consultation with the Department of the Environment, may adopt and enforce safety requirements, regulations, and specifications for air-conditioning equipment consistent with the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person may not have for sale, offer for sale, sell, or equip any motor vehicle, of model year 2011 or thereafter, with any air-conditioning equipment unless the air-conditioning equipment complies with the requirements of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
