<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-7-1004</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Administration shall consult with the Department of Aging when considering the eligibility of a ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1004</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Administration shall consult with the Department of Aging when considering the eligibility of a Program applicant for a grant under &#xA7; 7-1003 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">When awarding a grant under &#xA7; 7-1003 of this subtitle, the Administration shall consider:<section prefix="(1)">The ability of the Program applicant to provide door-to-door transportation to low-income to moderate-income seniors;</section><section prefix="(2)">The projected volume of ridership;</section><section prefix="(3)">The Program applicant's marketing and outreach plan to attract riders and drivers;</section><section prefix="(4)">The ability of the Program applicant to sustain door-to-door transportation for low-income to moderate-income seniors beyond the time when grants may be available;</section><section prefix="(5)">The ability of the Program applicant to coordinate its dispatcher system with a local central dispatcher system; and</section><section prefix="(6)">The extent to which the Program applicant encourages:<section prefix="(i)">Shared ridership;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Coordination between public and private sector transportation providers; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Innovations in risk management for drivers and riders.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In consultation with the Department of Aging, the Maryland Insurance Administration, and senior citizen advocacy groups, the Administration shall adopt regulations to implement this subtitle, including regulations governing:<section prefix="(1)">Criminal background and driving record checks of drivers;</section><section prefix="(2)">Driver and vehicle safety;</section><section prefix="(3)">Driver training; and</section><section prefix="(4)">The liability coverage of a Program applicant that provides door-to-door transportation under the Program.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
