<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-408" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-6-408</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An agreement made under &#xA7; 6-407 of this subtitle may provide for the transfer by Baltimore City to the Administration of any officers, including the harbor engineer of Baltimore City, and any employees of Baltimore City as are necessary or convenient for the Administration to perform the duties that it undertakes by the agreement.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each transferred officer and employee covered by and subject to the provisions of the City Service Commission of Baltimore City as a classified employee is entitled, without further examination or restriction, to all the rights and privileges and is subject to all the provisions of the State Personnel and Pensions Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The transfer of an officer or employee may not result in any decrease of the salary or status of the officer or employee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To the extent reasonably possible, each transfer shall be to a position of comparable rank and responsibility.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding any other law to the contrary, each transferred officer and employee is eligible for membership in the State Employees' Retirement System, and all rights of the officer or employee under the employees' retirement system of Baltimore City may be transferred to the State Employees' Retirement System as provided by law.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the Administration and Baltimore City cannot agree by negotiation on the number or type of officers or employees to be transferred under this section, they shall submit the matter to arbitration as provided in &#xA7; 6-402 of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
