<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-752" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-8-752</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to any applicable provisions of this section, a municipal corporation or a county that owns or operates a transit system or in which a transit system operates or a transit operator may enter into an agreement to construct, operate, and maintain bus passenger shelters on a State right-of-way.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An agreement under this section may allow commercial advertising signs to be displayed on bus passenger shelters consistent with applicable State, local, and federal law.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A municipal corporation shall apply to the Administration for a permit to erect bus passenger shelters on State rights-of-way located within the municipal corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A county shall apply to the Administration for a permit to erect bus passenger shelters on State rights-of-way located within the county but not within a municipal corporation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">With the concurrence of the municipal corporation, a county shall apply to the Administration for a permit to erect bus passenger shelters on State rights-of-way that are located within a municipal corporation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A transit operator shall apply to the Administration for a permit to erect bus passenger shelters:<section prefix="(1)">On State rights-of-way located within a municipal corporation, with the concurrence of the municipal corporation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">On State rights-of-way located within an unincorporated area, with the concurrence of the county.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On receipt of an application for a permit to erect a bus passenger shelter, the Administration may issue a permit under &#xA7; 8-646 of this title after determining that:<section prefix="(i)">The location, design, and construction of the bus passenger shelter do not interfere with vehicular or pedestrian safety; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The construction of the bus passenger shelter, including any commercial advertising signs displayed on the bus passenger shelter, conforms with applicable State, local, and federal law.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A permit for a bus passenger shelter shall:<section prefix="(i)">Include a provision requiring continued compliance with the requirements under paragraph (1) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Include a provision that the State is not responsible to any party to an agreement under this section for any costs resulting from enforcement of the permit; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Serve as an agreement with the State as may be required under applicable federal regulation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Administration may not unreasonably withhold approval of a permit under this subsection to a municipal corporation, county, or transit operator that has complied with the provisions of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, the Administration may enter into agreements to construct, operate, and maintain bus passenger shelters at fixed-route bus stops used by the Maryland Transit Administration.</section>
  </text>
</law>
