<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-919" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-919</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">On application, the Administration shall issue a special Class E "dump service registration" to any applicant who certifies that the vehicle for which the application is made is a Class E (truck) vehicle that:<section prefix="(1)">Is designed to haul cargo and to self-unload by gravity or mechanical means; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is to be used to haul feed or other loose materials in bulk.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The maximum gross weight limitation for a vehicle registered under this section is for a vehicle with two axles -- 40,000 pounds.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The maximum gross weight limitation for a vehicle registered under this section after June 1, 1994 is for a vehicle with three axles -- 55,000 pounds.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the maximum gross weight limitation for a vehicle registered under this section after June 1, 1994 is:<section prefix="(i)">In Allegany and Garrett counties for a vehicle with four or more axles in use when loaded -- 70,000 pounds; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">For a vehicle with four axles that is in compliance with regulations adopted by the Department that specify alternative vehicle design configurations based on recommendations of the Dump Truck Technical Task Force -- 70,000 pounds.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to the provisions of subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, three-axle vehicles registered before June 1, 1994 may continue to be operated at the gross vehicle weight limit specified by the applicable law in effect on May 31, 1994 for a period of 20 years beginning:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any vehicle registered under this section before June 1, 1994 may continue to be operated until June 1, 1999 under the applicable provisions of law in effect on May 31, 1994.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A vehicle may continue to be registered under this section, regardless of the vehicle's configuration, and to be operated under the same administrative regulations that were in effect on June 1, 1994, for the applicable time periods specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection, if the vehicle:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subparagraph (i) of this paragraph does not apply to flat bed trucks used to haul concrete blocks.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Administration:<section prefix="(1)">Shall stamp the words "dump service" on each registration card issued for a vehicle registered under this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May issue special registration plates to distinguish registrations made under this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">For each vehicle registered under this section, the annual registration fee is the greater of:<section prefix="(1)">$26.25 for each thousand pounds of gross weight of the vehicle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">$1,050.00.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Except while it is operating on a divided highway with two or more lanes in each direction or while it is unloaded, a vehicle registered under this section may not be operated on any highway at a speed of more than 45 miles an hour.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, if a vehicle registered under this section is hauling loose materials in bulk for a distance of not more than 40 miles:<section prefix="(i)">Subject to the provisions of subsection (i) of this section, the vehicle is limited as to maximum gross weight only by the allowable and paid registration weight; and</section><section prefix="(ii)"/></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A vehicle registered under this section may be operated on a statewide basis without any distance limitations if the vehicle is:<section prefix="(i)">A three-axle vehicle with a maximum gross vehicle weight of 55,000 pounds; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A four-axle vehicle with a maximum gross vehicle weight of 70,000 pounds that is in compliance with the regulations described under subsection (c)(2)(ii) of this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a vehicle registered under this section with a registered maximum gross weight limitation of more than 65,000 pounds that is not in compliance with the regulations described in subsection (c)(2)(ii) of this section is limited to a maximum gross weight of 65,000 pounds when the vehicle is operated on an interstate highway or in a county in the State other than Allegany County or Garrett County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A vehicle used to haul coal, logs, or pulpwood that is registered under this section and operated on Interstate Route 68 in Allegany County or Garrett County is allowed a maximum gross weight limitation of 70,000 pounds, regardless of whether the vehicle is in compliance with the regulations described in subsection (c)(2)(ii) of this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
