<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-103" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-2-103</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary is responsible for the budget of the Office of the Secretary and for the budget of each unit in the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The budget request that the Secretary submits for the Department shall contain, for each modal administration, separate items for:<section prefix="(i)">Capital expenditures; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Operating expenditures.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Whenever the proposed budget of the Governor includes for the Department total capital and operating expenditures that exceed the expenditures proposed in the Consolidated Transportation Program, the Department shall submit to the General Assembly, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, a reconciliation report that specifically sets forth the proposed projects for which the additional expenditures are requested.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except with respect to the Maryland Transportation Authority, the Maryland Port Commission and the Maryland Port Administration, the Secretary:<section prefix="(1)">May adopt rules and regulations for the Department and any of its units to carry out those provisions of this article that are subject to the jurisdiction of the Department; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall review and may approve, disapprove, or revise the rules and regulations of each unit in the Department.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary may create and determine the size of any advisory unit for the Department as he considers appropriate.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Office of the Secretary shall have a seal to authenticate copies of records or papers of the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary is responsible for all planning activities of the Department and for the development and maintenance of a continuing, comprehensive, and integrated transportation planning process.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In accordance with &#xA7; 2-103.1 of this subtitle, the Secretary shall develop and, with the approval of the Governor, shall adopt a State Report on Transportation to guide program development and to foster efficient and economical transportation services throughout the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On or before the 3rd Wednesday of January of each year, the Secretary shall submit the State Report on Transportation to the General Assembly, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Secretary may transfer, assign, and reassign any staff, power, or duty from any unit in the Department to his office or to another unit in the Department. If a transfer, assignment, or reassignment occurs, the appropriation for the respective staff, power, or duty also shall be transferred.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">The powers or duties of the State Roads Commission that are set forth in Article III, &#xA7; 40B of the Maryland Constitution; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The powers or duties that are vested by law in:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Secretary may exercise or perform any power or duty that any unit in the Department may exercise or perform.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">The powers or duties that are set forth in Article III, &#xA7; 40B of the Maryland Constitution; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The powers or duties that do not require by law the approval or action of the Secretary and are vested by law in:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Consistent with the State budget, Division II of the State Finance and Procurement Article, and other applicable provisions of law, the Secretary may contract with any person to provide services, supplies, construction, and maintenance for the Department or for any transportation related purposes.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary may apply for and receive from the federal government or any person any grants-in-aid or gifts for any transportation related purpose.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To the extent permitted by the State budget, the Secretary may make grants-in-aid to:<section prefix="(i)">Any governmental transportation agency in this State, including any county agency, bicounty agency, multijurisdiction agency, or municipal agency; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any other person for any transportation related purpose.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
