<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="22-404.5" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-22-404.5</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "power booster system" means any device installed in a motor vehicle which allows liquid nitrous oxide to combine with gasoline for the purpose of increasing engine power.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, a person may not operate on a highway a motor vehicle equipped with a power booster system.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may operate on a highway a motor vehicle equipped with a power booster if:<section prefix="(1)">The vehicle is enroute to or from a track where the vehicle is used for racing and the power booster system is inoperative; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The container of nitrous oxide has been removed from the vehicle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Every motor vehicle equipped with a power booster system shall be identified with a decal that:<section prefix="(1)">Is a diamond shaped design consisting of the words "Compressed Gas D.O.T. No. 1070" in silver scotchlite letters 1 inch high on a black background with a silver scotchlite border;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is issued by the Office of the Fire Marshal or from a nitrous oxide industry source; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Is attached to the left front and right rear bumper of the vehicle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Office of the Fire Marshal may adopt regulations necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Office of the Fire Marshal or nitrous oxide industry source that issues the vehicle identification decal may charge a fee for the issuance of a vehicle identification decal not to exceed the reasonable cost of preparation and distribution.</section>
  </text>
</law>
