<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-8-610</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this part the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>610</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this part the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Construction phase" means the phase in which a highway project is advanced through detailed engineering, property acquisition, and construction to completion.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This definition does not preclude the Administration from acquiring property during the project planning phase, and the completion of property acquisition does not constitute a commitment to the project's alignment or construction.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Final project planning phase" means that portion of the project planning phase which follows the initial project planning phase. The final project planning phase includes:<section prefix="(1)">Detailed review of alternatives;</section><section prefix="(2)">Selection of final alignment and scope;</section><section prefix="(3)">Preparation of final environmental impact documents;</section><section prefix="(4)">Detailed design and engineering studies;</section><section prefix="(5)">Any formal federal approval of design and location;</section><section prefix="(6)">Full participation of the public; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Full participation of local, State, and federal agencies.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Highway needs inventory" means an identification of needs for highway projects, based on the latest evaluation of highway conditions and transportation needs by the Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Initial project planning phase" means that portion of the project planning phase which includes:<section prefix="(1)">Notification of local, State, and federal officials;</section><section prefix="(2)">Initial interagency review;</section><section prefix="(3)">Initial systems planning;</section><section prefix="(4)">Identification of alternatives, as set forth in &#xA7; 8-102 of this title, for the scope and the location of the project;</section><section prefix="(5)">Estimates of right-of-way requirements, including available detail with respect to specific properties affected, and of cost;</section><section prefix="(6)">Public meetings for discussion of the foregoing; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Reports of consultants, if any have been retained for the analysis of preliminary alternatives.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Local governing body" means:<section prefix="(i)">The county commissioners or county council of a county; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the charter of the county provides for a county executive, the county executive and the county council.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of this part, action by the local governing body of a charter county with a county executive means a majority vote of the county council:<section prefix="(i)">With the approval of the county executive; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the county executive does not grant approval within 10 days of the council action, with subsequent confirmation of the council action by two thirds of the members of the council.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Local legislative delegation" means those members of the State Senate and of the House of Delegates who represent any part of the county involved.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of this part, a "majority" of the local legislative delegation means a majority of those members of the State Senate and a majority of those members of the House of Delegates, voting separately.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In any county which is divided into more than one senatorial district, the vote of approval or disapproval for each Senator shall be in direct proportion to the number of residents living in his senatorial district to the total county population. The population figures for each county and senatorial district shall be taken from the preceding U. S. Census Report. However, if a Senator representing more than one county is voting to approve or disapprove a project in his senatorial district, he shall have the same voting authority as the Senator representing the largest percentage of the population in that county. However, in those counties represented by exactly two senators, if a project is located exclusively in one senatorial district, that Senator shall have the prevailing vote on the approval or disapproval of that project.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Municipality" means the governing body of a municipal corporation as defined in Article 23A, &#xA7; 9 of the Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Project planning phase" means the phase in which engineering and environmental studies and analyses are conducted with full participation of the public, in addition to local, State, and federal agencies, to determine the scope and location of a proposed highway project.</section>
  </text>
</law>
