<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-616.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person may apply to the Administration for a parking placard on a form provided by the Administrat...</catch_line>
  <order_by>616.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may apply to the Administration for a parking placard on a form provided by the Administration if the applicant:<section prefix="(1)">Is a resident of the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">Has a permanent disability as described in &#xA7; 13-616(b)(1) of this subtitle and as certified by a licensed physician, licensed chiropractor, licensed optometrist, or licensed podiatrist, as defined in &#xA7; 13-616(a) of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has a permanent disability as described in &#xA7; 13-616(b)(1)(vi) of this subtitle and as self-certified as provided by &#xA7; 13-616(b)(2)(iv) of this subtitle.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A parking placard for a person with a disability may be issued to an applicant described in subsection (a) of this section only if the applicant submits proof satisfactory to the Administration that the applicant is a person with a disability as described in &#xA7; 13-616(b) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A parent or legal guardian may apply for a special disability parking placard on behalf of a qualified minor.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration may not issue to an applicant:<section prefix="(i)">More than one placard if the applicant requests one set of special registration plates under &#xA7; 13-616 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">More than two placards if the applicant does not request a set of special registration plates under &#xA7; 13-616 of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration may not issue to a person issued special vehicle registration plates under &#xA7; 13-616 of this subtitle a combination of special disability registration plates and placards exceeding two.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A placard issued under this section to an applicant described in subsection (a) of this section expires 4 years from the date of issue.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The placard may be renewed by the placard holder on an application form approved by the Administration.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A parking placard for a person with a disability shall be issued:<section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in item (ii) or item (iii) of this paragraph, in the form of a removable windshield placard capable of being hung from the inside rearview mirror and of a size and design as determined by the Administration;</section><section prefix="(ii)">For a vehicle not equipped with an inside rearview mirror or in which the inside rearview mirror is not visible from the rear of the vehicle, in the form of a windshield placard of a size and design as determined by the Administration; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">For a Class D (motorcycle) vehicle, in the form of a sticker of a size and design as designated by the Administration.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person to whom a parking placard for a person with a disability is issued shall display the placard described in this section:<section prefix="(i)">In a Class A (passenger) vehicle or a Class M (multipurpose) vehicle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">On a Class D (motorcycle) vehicle as required by the Administration;</section><section prefix="(iii)">In a Class E (truck) vehicle with a one ton or less manufacturer's rated capacity and specially equipped for the transportation of or operation by an individual with a disability; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">In a Class H, I, or J vehicle that is specially equipped for the transportation of individuals with disabilities and is used exclusively for the transportation of individuals with disabilities.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, when displayed by the person to whom a removable windshield placard is issued, the removable windshield placard shall be hung from the inside rearview mirror when the vehicle is parked.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not drive a vehicle while a removable windshield placard described under paragraph (1) of this subsection is hanging from the inside rearview mirror.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The removable windshield placard shall be placed inside a vehicle that is not equipped with an inside rearview mirror, in a position from which the removable windshield placard can be viewed from the outside of the vehicle through the lower portion of the windshield on the driver's side of the vehicle.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">When displayed, the person to whom a removable windshield placard is issued under this section or under a similar provision of law of any state or country is accorded the privileges contained in &#xA7; 13-616(f) of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">When using the parking privileges granted under &#xA7; 13-616(f) of this subtitle:<section prefix="(1)">The person shall have in the person's possession identification issued by the Administration as proof that parking privileges are being utilized by a person with a disability as defined in &#xA7; 13-616(b)(1) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The person shall make the identification available upon the request of:<section prefix="(i)">A police officer, while the officer is discharging the official duties of a police officer; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any other person authorized by a political subdivision to enforce this section, while acting within the scope of this authority.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not commit any fraud or make any misrepresentation in certifying a person's disability or applying for or using a parking placard for a person with a disability.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who operates a motor vehicle displaying a parking placard for a person with a disability may not use the privileges granted under this section, unless the person is:<section prefix="(i)">A person with a disability who meets the requirements of &#xA7; 13-616(b)(1) of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Accompanied by a dependent, or an individual who depends on the person for transportation, who meets the requirements of &#xA7; 13-616(b)(1) of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">To determine if the eligibility requirements continue to be met, the Administration may conduct a review of a parking placard for a person with a disability that is issued by the Administration under this section and:<section prefix="(i)">If the Administration finds it necessary to review the severity or permanency of a placard holder's disability, the Administration may request a review and recommendations from the Medical Advisory Board established under &#xA7; 16-118 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the Administration determines that eligibility requirements are not being met, the Administration may revoke the parking placard for a person with a disability.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Any person who violates the provisions of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The Administration shall:<section prefix="(1)">Administer the removable windshield placard program in accordance with the provisions of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">By July 1, 2001, establish an automated system for recording the issuance, renewal, and expiration of placards in a timely manner to ensure that the objectives of the placard program are achieved in an efficient and orderly manner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">In accordance with the provisions of this section, by July 1, 2001, each board for licensed physicians, licensed chiropractors, licensed optometrists, or licensed podiatrists shall be responsible for the development and maintenance of a database system, with which the Administration can interface and verify licensure.</section>
  </text>
</law>
