<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-21-904</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>904</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "visual or audible signal" includes a signal by hand, voice, emergency light or siren.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a police officer gives a visual or audible signal to stop and the police officer is in uniform, prominently displaying the police officer's badge or other insignia of office, a driver of a vehicle may not attempt to elude the police officer by:<section prefix="(1)">Willfully failing to stop the driver's vehicle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Fleeing on foot; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Any other means.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a police officer gives a visual or audible signal to stop and the police officer, whether or not in uniform, is in a vehicle appropriately marked as an official police vehicle, a driver of a vehicle may not attempt to elude the police officer by:<section prefix="(1)">Willfully failing to stop the driver's vehicle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Fleeing on foot; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Any other means.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A driver may not commit a violation of subsection (b)(1) or (c)(1) of this section that results in bodily injury to another person.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A driver may not commit a violation of subsection (b)(1) or (c)(1) of this section that results in death of another person.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "crime of violence" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 14-101 of the Criminal Law Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A driver may not commit a violation of subsection (b)(1) or (c)(1) of this section while the driver is attempting to elude a police officer who is signaling for the driver to stop for the purpose of apprehending the driver for the commission of a crime of violence for which the driver is subsequently convicted.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
