<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-605" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-5-605</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By appropriate action of their respective governing bodies, any two or more political subdivisions may agree to create a joint board and delegate to it the power granted by this subtitle to adopt and enforce airport zoning regulations for any airport located wholly or partly in any one or more of the political subdivisions.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a joint board is created under this section, it may exercise the powers granted by this subtitle to a political subdivision or its legislative body to the extent that these powers have been delegated to it by the political subdivision and subject to the rules, restrictions, guides, and standards established by the governing bodies of the political subdivisions that created it.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each joint board shall consist of:<section prefix="(1)">Two representatives of each political subdivision that creates the joint board, appointed by the chief executive officer of the political subdivision; and</section><section prefix="(2)">One additional member, who shall be the chairman, elected by a majority of the appointed members.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each member of a joint board serves for a term of 4 years and until his successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On written charges and after a public hearing, the respective appointing authority may remove any member of a joint board for cause.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member appointed to fill a vacancy in an unexpired term serves only for the remainder of that term.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each joint board shall adopt rules for the conduct of its business.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Meetings of a joint board shall be held at the call of the chairman or a majority of the joint board. All meetings of the board shall be open to the public.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each joint board shall keep minutes of its proceedings, showing the absence, vote, or failure to vote of each member on each question, and records of its examinations and other official actions. These minutes and records shall be filed immediately in the office of the joint board and shall be a public record.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At a meeting of a joint board, the chairman or, in his absence, the acting chairman may administer oaths and issue subpoenas and orders for the attendance of witnesses and the production of papers, books, and documents.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a person fails to comply with any subpoena or order issued under this subsection, the chairman or acting chairman may invoke the aid of a court of competent jurisdiction. The court may order that person to obey the subpoena or order or to give evidence about the matter in question.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
