<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-401</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>401</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to any vehicle required to be registered under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a vehicle is not registered, a person may not drive the vehicle on a highway in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a vehicle is not registered, the owner of the vehicle may not knowingly allow the vehicle to be driven on a highway in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the required registration fee for a vehicle has not been paid, a person may not drive the vehicle on a highway in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the required registration fee for a vehicle has not been paid, the owner of the vehicle may not knowingly allow the vehicle to be driven on a highway in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If the registration of a vehicle is canceled, a person may not drive the vehicle on a highway in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If the registration of a vehicle is canceled, the owner of the vehicle may not knowingly allow the vehicle to be driven on a highway in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">If the registration of a vehicle is suspended, a person may not drive the vehicle on a highway in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">If the registration of a vehicle is suspended, the owner of the vehicle may not knowingly allow the vehicle to be driven on a highway in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">If the registration of a vehicle is revoked, a person may not drive the vehicle on a highway in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">If the registration of a vehicle is revoked, the owner of the vehicle may not knowingly allow the vehicle to be driven on a highway in this State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
