<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>The application for a certificate of title of a vehicle shall be made by the owner of the vehicle on...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The application for a certificate of title of a vehicle shall be made by the owner of the vehicle on the form that the Administration requires.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, an application for a certificate of title of an off-highway recreational vehicle, a motor scooter, or a moped shall be made by electronic transmission under &#xA7; 13-610 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The owner of a motor scooter or moped shall certify at the time of titling that the motor scooter or moped is covered by the required security described in &#xA7; 17-103 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Administration may not issue a certificate of title to any individual who is not at least 18 years old.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration may issue a certificate of title to an individual under the age of 18 years if the individual submits an application for a certificate of title that is cosigned by:<section prefix="(i)">A parent or guardian of the applicant; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the applicant has no parent or guardian or is married, an adult employer of the applicant or any other responsible adult.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The individual cosigning the application of a minor under this subsection shall certify that the statements made in the application are true to the best of the cosigner's knowledge, information, and belief.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The application shall contain:<section prefix="(1)">The full name and Maryland address of the owner, including:<section prefix="(i)">If the owner is an individual, the owner's Maryland residence and mailing addresses;</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the owner is a business firm, association, or corporation, its federal identification number and:<section prefix="1.">Its business address in this State; or</section><section prefix="2.">The name and address of its resident agent in this State;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">If the owner is a partnership or joint venture, the name of each partner or joint venturer;</section><section prefix="(iv)">If the owner is an unincorporated association, joint stock company, or other group described in &#xA7; 6-406 of the Courts Article, the name and address of a resident agent on whom service may be made in any lawsuit arising out of the ownership, maintenance, or use of the vehicle; and</section><section prefix="(v)">If the owner is a trustee, the address of the trust in this State and the name and address of a person in this State on whom service may be made in any lawsuit arising out of the ownership, maintenance, or use of the vehicle;</section></section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">If the owner is an individual, the owner's date of birth; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the owner is a partnership or joint venture, the date of birth of each partner or joint venturer;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">A description of the vehicle, including:<section prefix="(i)">To the extent that the information exists, its make, model, year, vehicle identification number, type of body, and number of cylinders;</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the vehicle is a two-stage vehicle:<section prefix="1.">The make and year of the first stage; and</section><section prefix="2.">The make, model, and year of the second stage;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">If the vehicle is a motorcycle with an engine manufactured on or after January 1, 1977, the identifying number of the engine; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any other information that the Administration requires;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">A statement of:<section prefix="(i)">The applicant's title to and each security interest in the vehicle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The name and address of each secured party with any security interest in the vehicle and the nature and order of priority of that interest; and</section></section><section prefix="(5)">Any other information that the Administration reasonably requires to determine if the owner is entitled to a certificate of title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The application shall be signed in ink by:<section prefix="(1)">Each owner who is an individual;</section><section prefix="(2)">The individual cosigning the application on behalf of a minor in accordance with subsection (b) of this section;</section><section prefix="(3)">An officer or authorized agent of the owner, if the owner is a business firm, association, or corporation;</section><section prefix="(4)">A partner or joint venturer, if the owner is a partnership or joint venture;</section><section prefix="(5)">An officer or authorized agent, if the owner is an unincorporated association, joint stock company, or other group described in &#xA7; 6-406 of the Courts Article; or</section><section prefix="(6)">A trustee, if the owner is a trust.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The application shall be accompanied by each certificate of title of the vehicle that previously may have been issued by this or any other state and still is outstanding.</section>
  </text>
</law>
