<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-404" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-404</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to a State agency or political subdivision authorized to regulate parking under Title 26, Subtitle 3 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A State agency or political subdivision in this State may act as the agent of the Administration in the registration of vehicles and in the issuance of registration plates and registration cards.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the end of each week, the State agency or political subdivision shall remit to the Administration:<section prefix="(i)">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, all fees collected for the registration of vehicles under this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A complete record of the registrations made during each day.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In addition to the registration fees required by this title, the applicant for registration of a vehicle shall pay a fee of $1 for each registration issued by a State agency or political subdivision acting as an agent of the Administration under subsection (b)(1) of this section. The Administration shall retain a portion of this fee in order to offset its costs. The State agency or political subdivision may collect, for each registration issued, an additional fee not to exceed $1 to offset expenses incurred in the issuance of registrations. The amount of the additional fee shall be determined by the State agency or political subdivision.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Administration shall adopt rules and regulations to govern the issuance of registration plates and validation tabs by a State agency or political subdivision.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
