<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-21-405</section_number>
  <catch_line>On the immediate approach of an emergency vehicle using audible and visual signals that meet the req...</catch_line>
  <order_by>405</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">On the immediate approach of an emergency vehicle using audible and visual signals that meet the requirements of &#xA7; 22-218 of this article or of a police vehicle lawfully using an audible signal, the driver of every other vehicle, unless otherwise directed by a police officer, shall yield the right-of-way.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On the immediate approach of an emergency vehicle using audible and visual signals that meet the requirements of &#xA7; 22-218 of this article or of a police vehicle lawfully using an audible signal, the driver of every other vehicle, unless otherwise directed by a police officer, shall drive immediately to a position parallel to and as close as possible to the edge or curb of the roadway, clear of any intersection.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">On the immediate approach of an emergency vehicle using audible and visual signals that meet the requirements of &#xA7; 22-218 of this article or of a police vehicle lawfully using an audible signal, the driver of every other vehicle, unless otherwise directed by a police officer, shall stop and stay in this position until the emergency vehicle has passed.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A driver, when proceeding in the same direction as an emergency or police vehicle, may not pass an emergency vehicle using audible and visual signals that meet the requirements of &#xA7; 22-218 of this article or a police vehicle lawfully using an audible signal unless:<section prefix="(1)">The emergency vehicle has stopped; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Otherwise directed by a police officer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Unless otherwise directed by a police officer or a traffic control device, when an emergency vehicle using any visual signal that meets the requirements of &#xA7; 22-218 of this article is stopped, standing, or parked on a highway, the driver of a motor vehicle approaching the emergency vehicle from the rear shall:<section prefix="(1)">If practicable and not otherwise prohibited, make a lane change into an available lane not immediately adjacent to the emergency vehicle with due regard for safety and traffic conditions; or</section><section prefix="(2)">If the driver of the motor vehicle is unable to make a lane change in accordance with item (1) of this subsection, slow to a reasonable and prudent speed that is safe for existing weather, road, and vehicular or pedestrian traffic conditions.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">This section does not relieve the driver of an emergency vehicle from the duty to drive with due regard for the safety of all persons.</section>
  </text>
</law>
