<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-937.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>937.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "street rod" means a motor vehicle that:<section prefix="(1)">Is 25 years old or older; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Has been substantially altered from the manufacturer's original design.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, if registered with the Administration under this section, every street rod is a Class N (street rod) vehicle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For each Class N (street rod) vehicle, the annual registration fee is $25.00.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In applying for registration of a street rod under this section, the owner of the street rod shall submit with the application a certification that the vehicle for which the application is made:<section prefix="(1)">Will be maintained for use in exhibitions, club activities, parades, tours, occasional transportation, and similar uses; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Will not be used:<section prefix="(i)">For general daily transportation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Primarily for the transportation of passengers or property on highways.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The registration of a street rod registered before July 1, 1987 as a Class L (historic) vehicle shall remain valid until midnight on the date indicated on the registration card issued by the Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On expiration of a street rod's registration as a Class L (historic) vehicle, a street rod registered with the Administration shall be registered as a Class N (street rod) vehicle as required by this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 13-936.1 of this subtitle, on registration of a vehicle under this section, the Administration shall issue a special street rod vehicle registration plate of the size and design that the Administration determines.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Unless the presence of the equipment was specifically required by a statute of this State as a condition of sale when the vehicle was manufactured, the presence of any specific equipment is not required for the operation of a vehicle registered under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A vehicle registered under this section is exempt from any statute that requires periodic vehicle inspections or that requires the use and inspection of emission controls.</section>
  </text>
</law>
