<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-111" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-12-111</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Administration shall keep a record of each application or other document filed with it and each certificate or other official document that it issues.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to &#xA7; 10-616(p) of the State Government Article, and except as otherwise provided by law, all records of the Administration are public records and open to public inspection during office hours.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection, the Administrator may classify as confidential and not open to public inspection any record or record entry:<section prefix="(i)">That is over 5 years old; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">That relates to any happening that occurred over 5 years earlier.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to &#xA7; 10-616(p) of the State Government Article, a record or record entry of any age shall be open to inspection by authorized representatives of any federal, State, or local governmental agency.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, the Administrator may not open to public inspection any record or record entry that is:<section prefix="(i)">All or part of a licensed driver's public driving record; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Over 3 years old.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Subject to paragraph (6) of this subsection, the Administration may not permit public inspection of a digital photographic image or signature of an individual, or the actual stored data thereof, recorded by the Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Administration may make a digital photographic image or signature of an individual, or the actual stored data thereof, recorded by the Administration available to:<section prefix="(i)">The courts;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Criminal justice agencies;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Driver license authorities;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The individual;</section><section prefix="(v)">The individual's attorney;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Third parties designated by the individual; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">The Child Support Enforcement Administration.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except for records required by law to be kept in their original or other specified form, the Administrator may order any record of the Administration to be kept on microfilm or in other microform, and the original destroyed.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except for records required by law to be kept longer, the Administrator may destroy any record of the Administration that it has kept for 3 years or more and that the Administrator considers obsolete and unnecessary to the work of the Administration.</section>
  </text>
</law>
