<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="21-202" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-21-202</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for special pedestrian signals that carry a legend, where traffic is controlled by traffic control signals that show different colored lights or colored lighted arrows, whether successively one at a time or in combination, only the colors green, red, and yellow may be used.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">These lights apply to drivers and pedestrians as provided in this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Vehicular traffic facing a circular green signal may proceed straight through or, unless a sign at the place prohibits the turn, turn right or left.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Vehicular traffic described under subsection (b) of this section, including any vehicle turning right or left, shall yield the right-of-way to any other vehicle and any pedestrian lawfully within the intersection or an adjacent crosswalk when the signal is shown.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Vehicular traffic facing a green arrow signal, whether shown alone or with another indication, cautiously may enter the intersection, but only to make the movement indicated by the arrow or to make another movement permitted by other indications shown at the same time.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Vehicular traffic described under subsection (d) of this section shall yield the right-of-way to any pedestrian or bicycle lawfully within an adjacent crosswalk and to any other traffic lawfully using the intersection.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Unless otherwise directed by a pedestrian control signal as provided in &#xA7; 21-203 of this subtitle, a pedestrian facing any green signal, unless the green signal is only a turn arrow, may cross the roadway, within any marked or unmarked crosswalk, in the direction of the green signal.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Vehicular traffic facing a steady yellow signal is warned that the related green movement is ending or that a red signal, which will prohibit vehicular traffic from entering the intersection, will be shown immediately after the yellow signal.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless otherwise directed by a pedestrian control signal as provided in &#xA7; 21-203 of this subtitle, a pedestrian facing a steady yellow signal is warned that there is not enough time to cross the roadway before a red signal is shown, and a pedestrian may not then start to cross the roadway.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Vehicular traffic facing a steady circular red signal alone:<section prefix="(i)">Shall stop at the near side of the intersection:</section><section prefix="(ii)">Except as provided in subsections (i), (j), and (k) of this section, shall remain stopped until a signal to proceed is shown.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Vehicular traffic facing a steady red arrow signal:<section prefix="(i)">May not enter the intersection to make the movement indicated by the arrow;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Unless entering the intersection to make a movement permitted by another signal, shall stop at the near side of the intersection:</section><section prefix="(iii)">Except as provided in subsections (i), (j), and (k) of this section, shall remain stopped until a signal permitting the movement is shown.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Unless a sign prohibiting a turn is in place, vehicular traffic facing a steady red signal, after stopping as required by subsection (h) of this section, cautiously may enter the intersection and make:<section prefix="(1)">A right turn; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A left turn from a one-way street onto a one-way street.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">If a sign permitting any other turn is in place, vehicular traffic facing a steady red signal, after stopping as required by subsection (h) of this section, cautiously may enter the intersection and make the turn indicated by the sign.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">In each instance, vehicular traffic described in subsections (i) and (j) of this section shall yield the right-of-way to any pedestrian or bicycle lawfully within an adjacent crosswalk and to any vehicle in the intersection or approaching on another roadway so closely as to constitute an immediate hazard.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">Unless otherwise directed by a pedestrian control signal as provided in &#xA7; 21-203 of this subtitle, pedestrians facing a steady red signal alone may not enter the roadway.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">Except for those provisions of this section that by their very nature cannot apply, this section applies to a traffic control signal placed at a location other than an intersection. Each stop required by the signal shall be made at a sign or marking on the pavement indicating where the stop shall be made or, if there is no sign or marking, at the signal.</section>
  </text>
</law>
