<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-21-509</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>509</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (j) of this section, a pedestrian may not walk along a controlled access highway.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (j) of this section, a pedestrian may not walk on a controlled access highway.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as provided in subsection (j) of this section, a pedestrian may not walk along a ramp leading to or from a controlled access highway.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as provided in subsection (j) of this section, a pedestrian may not walk on a ramp leading to or from a controlled access highway.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except as provided in subsection (j) of this section, a pedestrian may not walk along an access road leading to or from a controlled access highway.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Except as provided in subsection (j) of this section, a pedestrian may not walk on an access road leading to or from a controlled access highway.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Except as provided in subsection (j) of this section, a person may not leave any vehicle that is on a controlled access highway.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Except as provided in subsection (j) of this section, a person may not leave any vehicle that is on a ramp leading to or from a controlled access highway.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subsection (j) of this section, a person may not leave any vehicle that is on an access road leading to or from a controlled access highway.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">This section does not apply to a person if an emergency prevents the movement of a vehicle in which he is riding and the person goes only to the nearest telephone or other source of assistance, nor to a person boarding or leaving a bus within a bus stop approved by the State Highway Administration.</section>
  </text>
</law>
