<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-22-228</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>228</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Administrator may adopt regulations for lighting equipment, special warning devices, markings, and identification to be used by school vehicles.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Regulations adopted under this paragraph shall be consistent with the provisions of the Maryland Vehicle Law.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A school vehicle registered in the State shall be equipped with an 8-light system of alternately flashing lights.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The 8-light safety system of alternately flashing lights shall meet the standards contained in the SAE (Society of Automotive Engineers) Standard J887 (May 1982), and shall consist of 2 amber lights and 2 red lights at the rear of the vehicle, and 2 amber lights and 2 red lights at the front of the vehicle.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A school vehicle may be equipped with a white flashing light installed on the roof of the vehicle.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">School vehicles shall be marked and identified as provided in, and school vehicle lighting equipment and special warning devices shall conform with, the regulations adopted by the Administrator.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, a person may not operate any alternately flashing light on any school vehicle except when the school vehicle is stopping or stopped on a roadway for the purpose of receiving or discharging passengers.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">As to any school vehicle, whenever the vehicle is not being operated on a highway for the transportation of children, students, or teachers for educational purposes or in connection with a school activity:<section prefix="(1)">The alternately flashing lights shall be deactivated; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The words "school bus" at the front and rear of the vehicle shall be covered or otherwise concealed.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, every school vehicle driver shall put in operation alternately flashing amber lights not less than 100 feet before bringing the vehicle to a full stop for the purpose of receiving or discharging passengers, and place into operation the alternately flashing red lights upon stopping.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only to a school vehicle being driven on the same roadway as another school vehicle in the act of loading or unloading passengers.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, every school vehicle driver shall put in operation the alternately flashing lights when approaching from the rear or the front, within 100 feet of another school vehicle in the act of loading or unloading passengers on the roadway.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "loading zone" means an area:<section prefix="(i)">That is:<section prefix="1.">On a highway, but not on the roadway, for use in receiving or discharging passengers residing on the same side of the highway as the loading zone; or</section><section prefix="2.">Not on a highway; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Whose location has been designated and approved by either the superintendent of schools in the local school system in which the loading zone is located, the Department of State Police, or the local police department, in cooperation with the State Highway Administration or local traffic engineering agency, as applicable.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">It is the policy of this State to encourage the establishment and use of loading zones for school vehicles.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Where a loading zone is available, a school vehicle driver, unless otherwise required for safety, may not stop on the roadway for the purpose of receiving or discharging passengers, but shall use the loading zone for this purpose.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Except as provided in subsection (f) of this section, a driver of a school vehicle shall stop on the roadway to:<section prefix="(1)">Receive passengers when transporting them to school; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Discharge passengers when transporting them from school.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
