<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-7-506</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>506</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, until a public hearing is held on the matter, the Administration may not:<section prefix="(i)">Fix or revise any fare or rate charged the general public;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Establish or abandon any bus or rail route listed on a published timetable;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Change a bus or rail route alignment listed on a published timetable, unless the change is needed because of temporary construction or changes in the road network;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Reduce the frequency, number of days, or days of service for a commuter bus or commuter rail route without substituting a comparable level of service, unless the reduction is temporary or a result of:<section prefix="1.">A natural disaster;</section><section prefix="2.">Weather or other emergency conditions;</section><section prefix="3.">Schedule adjustments required by a third party that operates service on the same right-of-way; or</section><section prefix="4.">Other circumstances beyond the control of the Administration; or</section></section><section prefix="(v)">Establish or abandon a rail transit station.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration may only implement a change described in paragraph (1) of this subsection during the time period that begins 6 weeks after the public hearing and ends 6 months after the public hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the Administration gives inadequate or defective notice of a public hearing on a change described in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Administration may not implement the change unless the Administration makes a reasonable effort to correct the inadequacy or defect and a legally sufficient public hearing is held.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For the purposes of this paragraph, notice shall be considered inadequate or defective if:<section prefix="1.">The Administration does not comply with the newspaper publication requirements under subsection (d) of this section;</section><section prefix="2.">The Administration does not comply with the notice requirements for affected jurisdictions prescribed under subsection (d) of this section;</section><section prefix="3.">At least 30% of the Administration's facilities are not posted as required under subsection (d) of this section; or</section><section prefix="4.">The notice contains erroneous information.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A public hearing required under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be at a place and time that is reasonably accessible and convenient to the patrons of the service to be affected.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Administration shall accept written comments for 30 days after a hearing held on a change described in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Administration may add service on a new alignment branching off of an existing route without holding a public hearing, if the addition of the new alignment does not alter the existing route.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The following persons may request the Administration to hold a hearing on any rentals, rates, fares, fees, or other charges of the Administration or any service rendered by the transit facilities owned or controlled by the Administration:<section prefix="(i)">Any person served by or using the transit facilities;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The People's Counsel, as a representative of the general public; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any private carrier operating in the District.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The request for a hearing shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be in writing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">State the matter sought to be heard; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Set forth clearly the grounds for the request.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">As soon as possible after the Administration receives a request for a hearing, a designated employee of the Administration shall confer on the matter with the person requesting the hearing. After the conference, if the Administration considers the matter meritorious and of general significance, it may call a hearing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration shall give at least a 30-day notice before a hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice shall be:<section prefix="(i)">Published once a week for 2 successive weeks in two or more newspapers of daily circulation throughout the District;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Posted in all of the Administration's offices, stations, and terminals and all of the vehicles and rolling stock used in revenue service by the mode of transportation that will be affected by the proposed action described in subsection (a) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Provided to the governing body of each county or municipal corporation affected by a change in transit service or fare or rate described under subsection (a)(1) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Administration may establish a process for providing notice to local governments under paragraph (2)(iii) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The 30-day period begins when the notice first appears in the newspaper.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Before calling a hearing under this section, the Administration shall file at its main office and make available for public inspection:<section prefix="(1)">Its report on the subject matter of the hearing; and</section><section prefix="(2)">If the hearing was requested under subsection (c) of this section, the written request for the hearing and all documents filed in support of it.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
