<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="23-106" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-23-106</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">Any transfer of a used vehicle to any licensed dealer or to any foreign dealer;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any transfer between:<section prefix="(i)">Spouses;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A parent and child; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Co-owners of the vehicle to be transferred when a co-owner's name is being removed from the title;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Any transfer of a used vehicle that is not to be both titled and registered in this State;</section><section prefix="(4)">Any transfer of a used vehicle among any agencies of the State;</section><section prefix="(5)">Any transfer of a used vehicle as described in &#xA7; 13-503.2 of this article;</section><section prefix="(6)">Any transfer of a used vehicle into a written inter vivos trust in which the transferor is the primary beneficiary;</section><section prefix="(7)">Any transfer of a used island vehicle, as defined in &#xA7; 13-935 of this article, registered, or to be registered, as a Class K (farm area/island) vehicle; or</section><section prefix="(8)">Any transfer of an off-highway recreational vehicle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, if any licensed dealer that also is an inspection station transfers any used vehicle, it shall:<section prefix="(i)">Prepare and attach an inspection certificate to a window of the vehicle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Have an inspection certificate prepared and attached to a window of the vehicle by another inspection station.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraphs (4) and (5) of this subsection, if any other person transfers a used vehicle, the person shall obtain an inspection certificate from an inspection station. The inspection certificate shall be issued without charge and attached to a window of the vehicle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a used vehicle is transferred other than by voluntary transfer or is transferred by a political subdivision of the State after that subdivision obtains the vehicle by proceedings pursuant to Title 12 of the Criminal Procedure Article, the transferee shall obtain the inspection certificate from an authorized inspection station. The inspection certificate shall be issued without charge and attached to a window of the vehicle.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In the case of a transfer of any used vehicle registered, or to be registered, as a Class E (truck) exceeding three-fourths ton manufacturer's rated capacity, Class F (tractor), Class G (freight trailer or semitrailer), or Class G (dump service semitrailer) vehicle, the transferor or the transferee of the vehicle may obtain the required inspection certificate.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In the case of a transfer of any used vehicle registered or to be registered, that is sold for dismantling or rebuilding purposes, the transferor or the transferee of the vehicle may obtain the required inspection certificate.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">On applying for a certificate of title of the vehicle, the transferee shall remove the inspection certificate from the vehicle and present it to the Administration.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
