<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-506</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>506</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Administration may suspend, revoke, or refuse to grant or renew certification under the driver education program of any drivers' school or of any classroom or laboratory instructor of a drivers' school, if it finds that the school or instructor has:<section prefix="(1)">Failed to comply with any of the provisions of or any rule or regulation adopted under:<section prefix="(i)">This subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Title 15, Subtitle 7 of this article, as to drivers' schools; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Title 15, Subtitle 8 of this article, as to driving instructors; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Been convicted of a crime of moral turpitude.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Administration refuses to grant or renew a certification under this subtitle, the applicant may request a hearing under Title 12, Subtitle 2 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, the Administration may suspend or revoke a certification under this subtitle only after a hearing under Title 12, Subtitle 2 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the Administration determines that there is a danger of immediate, substantial, and continuing harm to the public if the certification is continued pending a hearing, the Administration shall:<section prefix="(1)">Immediately suspend the certification;</section><section prefix="(2)">Within 7 days of a request for a hearing, grant a hearing as provided in Title 12, Subtitle 2 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(3)">After a hearing, render an immediate decision as to whether the Administration shall continue the suspension or revoke or reinstate the certification.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
