<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-803</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>803</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Commerce" means:<section prefix="(1)">Trade, traffic, and transportation within the jurisdiction of the United States between a place in a state and a place outside of the state, including a place outside the United States; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Trade, traffic, and transportation in the United States which affects any trade, traffic, and transportation within the jurisdiction of the United States between a place in a state and a place outside of the state, including a place outside the United States.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Commercial motor vehicle (CMV)" means a motor vehicle or combination of motor vehicles used to transport passengers or property, if the motor vehicle:<section prefix="(i)">Has a gross combination weight rating of 26,001 or more pounds inclusive of a towed unit with a gross vehicle weight rating of more than 10,000 pounds;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has a gross vehicle weight rating of 26,001 or more pounds;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is designed to transport 16 or more passengers, including the driver; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Is of any size and is used in the transportation of materials found to be hazardous for the purposes of the Hazardous Materials Transportation Act and which requires the motor vehicle to be placarded under hazardous materials regulations (49 C.F.R. Part 172, Subpart F).</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Commercial motor vehicle (CMV)" does not include a vehicle that is:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">Controlled and operated by a farmer;</section><section prefix="2.">Used to transport agricultural products, farm machinery, or farm supplies to or from a farm;</section><section prefix="3.">Not used in the operations of a common or contract motor carrier; and</section><section prefix="4.">Used within 150 miles of the person's farm;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">An emergency vehicle:<section prefix="1.">Equipped with audible and visual signals; and</section><section prefix="2.">Operated by a member of or a person in the employ of a volunteer or paid fire or rescue organization;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">A vehicle owned or operated by the United States Department of Defense if it is controlled and operated by:<section prefix="1.">Any active duty military personnel;</section><section prefix="2.">Any member of the military reserves or National Guard on active duty, including personnel on full-time National Guard duty and personnel on part-time training; or</section><section prefix="3.">Any National Guard military technician; or</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">A motor vehicle designed and constructed primarily to provide temporary living quarters for recreational, camping, or travel use.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Conviction" means a final unvacated adjudication of guilt, or a determination that an individual has violated or failed to comply with the law in a court of original jurisdiction or by an authorized administrative tribunal, an unvacated forfeiture of bail or collateral deposited to secure the person's appearance in court, a plea of guilty or nolo contendere accepted by the court, the payment of a fine or court cost, a probation before judgment finding, or violation of a condition of release without bail, regardless of whether or not the penalty is rebated, suspended, or probated.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Employer" means any individual, including the United States, a state, or a political subdivision of a state, who owns or leases a commercial motor vehicle or assigns drivers to operate such a vehicle. An individual who employs himself as a commercial motor vehicle driver is considered to be both an employer and a driver for the purposes of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Endorsement" means an authorization to an individual's commercial driver's license required to permit the individual to operate certain types of commercial motor vehicles.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Gross combination weight rating (GCWR)" means:<section prefix="(1)">The value specified by the manufacturer as the loaded weight of a combination or articulated vehicle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">In the absence of a value specified by the manufacturer, GCWR shall be determined by adding the gross vehicle weight rating (GVWR) of the power unit and the total weight of the towed unit and its load.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Gross vehicle weight rating (GVWR)" means the value specified by the manufacturer as the loaded weight of a single vehicle.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Hazardous materials" means any material that has been designated as hazardous under 49 U.S.C. &#xA7; 5103 and is required to be placarded under Subpart F of 49 C.F.R. Part 172 or any quantity of a material listed as a select agent or toxin in 42 C.F.R. Part 73.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Serious traffic violation" means:<section prefix="(i)">Excessive speeding, as defined by the United States Secretary of Transportation by regulation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Reckless driving;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A violation of any state or local law relating to operating a motor vehicle, other than a parking violation, arising in connection with an accident or collision resulting in death to any individual;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Driving a commercial motor vehicle without obtaining a commercial driver's license;</section><section prefix="(v)">Driving a commercial motor vehicle without a commercial driver's license in the driver's possession;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Driving a commercial motor vehicle without the proper class of commercial driver's license;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Driving a commercial motor vehicle without the proper endorsements; or</section><section prefix="(viii)">Any other violation of a state or local law which the United States Secretary of Transportation determines by regulation to be serious.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Serious traffic violation does not include vehicle weight and vehicle defect violations.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Tank vehicle" means any commercial motor vehicle that is designed to transport any liquid or gaseous material within a tank that is either permanently or temporarily attached to the vehicle or chassis.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Tank vehicles include cargo tanks and portable tanks.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Tank vehicle does not include portable tanks having a rated capacity under 1,000 gallons.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"United States" means the 50 states and the District of Columbia.</section>
  </text>
</law>
