<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-201" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-6-201</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Maryland Port Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">Establish policies directed toward improving the competitive position of the ports of Maryland within the international port industry;</section><section prefix="(2)">Adopt regulations for the operation of the Administration in a competitive manner within the port industry;</section><section prefix="(3)">Exercise those powers granted to the Commission and to the Maryland Port Administration by this title or by any other provision of law;</section><section prefix="(4)">Unless otherwise directed by the Secretary, serve as the board of directors of any private operating company created under this title; and</section><section prefix="(5)">In carrying out the provisions of this subtitle, seek information and advice from port labor and management groups.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall consist of 7 voting members, 6 of whom shall be appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate and the 7th shall be the Secretary of Transportation who shall be the Chairman of the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary of Business and Economic Development shall serve as a nonvoting ex officio Commission member.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (3) of this subsection, the Governor may not appoint to the Commission:<section prefix="(i)">An officer or employee of the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A representative of any entity whose principal activities are ports-related;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A person employed by any entity whose principal activities are ports-related; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">A member of the General Assembly.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Governor shall take into consideration geographic representation when appointing the 6 members of the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, a member of the Maryland Transportation Authority or any other State board, commission, or authority may be appointed a member of the Maryland Port Commission. Any person so appointed who is compensated by the State is not entitled to any compensation or other emolument, except expenses incurred in connection with attendance at hearings, meetings, field trips, and working sessions, for any services rendered as a Commissioner.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each appointed member serves for a term of 3 years and until a successor is appointed and qualifies. The terms of appointed members shall be staggered as required by the original appointments to the Commission, 2 of which shall be for 3 years, 2 of which shall be for 2 years, and 2 of which shall be for 1 year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member appointed to fill a vacancy in an unexpired term serves only for the remainder of that term or until a replacement is appointed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commission shall meet at a time and place designated by the Chairman of the Commission. The Commission shall meet as often as its duties require, but not less than quarterly. Attendance by 4 voting members shall constitute a quorum.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Except as provided under subsection (d)(3) of this section, members of the Commission appointed by the Governor are entitled to the compensation and expenses provided for in the State budget. Members of the Commission are subject to the provisions of &#xA7; 8-501 of the State Government Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
