<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-8-732</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "centerline" means:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>732</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "centerline" means:<section prefix="(1)">The centerline of the main traveled way of a nondivided highway; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A line equidistant from the edges of the median separating the main traveled ways of a divided highway.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The location of an outdoor sign structure located between highways entering into or intersecting the main traveled way of any federal-aid primary highway shall conform to the minimum spacing criteria specified in this section, to be applied separately to each side of the federal-aid primary highway.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the distance between the centerlines of intersecting highways is less than 1,000 feet, a maximum of three sign structures, whether double-faced, back-to-back, or v-type, may be permitted between the intersecting highways, and the minimum spacing between the structures shall be 100 feet.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the distance between the centerlines of intersecting highways is 1,000 feet or more, the minimum spacing between sign structures, whether double-faced, back-to-back, or v-type, shall be 300 feet.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For purposes of this subsection, the following rules apply.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Alleys, undeveloped rights-of-way, private roads, and driveways may not be regarded as intersecting highways.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Only highways that enter directly into the main traveled way of the federal-aid primary highway may be regarded as intersecting.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Official and "on premise" signs, as defined in Title 23, &#xA7; 131(c) of the United States Code, may not be counted, and measurements may not be made from them for purposes of determining compliance with the spacing requirements.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The minimum distance between signs shall be measured along the nearest edge of the pavement between points directly opposite the signs.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The minimum spacing criteria specified in this section do not apply to sign structures separated by a building or other obstruction so that only one sign structure is visible from any one place on the main traveled way.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
