<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-208" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-208</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, &#xA7;&#xA7; 16-205(d-1) and 16-206(a)(4), (b), and (c) of this subtitle, &#xA7; 16-404(c)(2) and (3) of this title, and &#xA7; 3-8A-23 of the Courts and Judicial Proceedings Article, the Administration may not suspend a license or privilege to drive for a period of more than 1 year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After notice and hearing, the Administration may suspend for an indefinite period the license or privilege of any individual who cannot drive safely because of his physical or mental condition.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This subsection does not apply to or affect the suspension of any license:<section prefix="(i)">For failure to comply with the required security provisions of Title 17 of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">For failure to appear at a hearing as provided in Title 12, Subtitle 2 of this article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">For failure to obey a citation, as provided in Title 26 of this article;</section><section prefix="(iv)">For failure to pay a fine in accordance with the court's directive as provided in Title 27 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(v)">For failure to pay child support, as provided in &#xA7; 16-203 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any individual whose license or privilege to drive has been revoked may apply for reinstatement of the individual's license or privilege as provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If it is the individual's first revocation, the individual may file a reinstatement application at any time after the day the revoked license is surrendered to and received by the Administration or, in the case of an individual who does not have a license issued under this title, after the effective date of the revocation.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Except as provided in paragraph (6) of this subsection, on receipt of the application, the Administration may reinstate the license or privilege 6 months after the revoked license is received by the Administration or, in the case of an individual who does not have a license issued under this title, 6 months after the effective date of revocation.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If it is the individual's second revocation, the individual may file a reinstatement application at any time after 1 year from the day the revoked license is surrendered to and received by the Administration or, in the case of an individual who does not have a license issued under this title, after 1 year from the effective date of revocation.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Except as provided in paragraph (6) of this subsection, on receipt of the application, the Administration may reinstate the license or privilege.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If it is the individual's third revocation, the individual may file a reinstatement application at any time after 18 months from the day the revoked license is surrendered to and received by the Administration or, in the case of an individual who does not have a license issued under this title, after 18 months from the effective date of revocation.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Except as provided in paragraph (6) of this subsection, on receipt of the application, the Administration may reinstate the license or privilege.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If it is the individual's fourth or subsequent revocation, the individual may file a reinstatement application at any time after 2 years from the day the revoked license is surrendered to and received by the Administration or, in the case of an individual who does not have a license issued under this title, after 2 years from the effective date of revocation.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Except as provided in paragraph (6) of this subsection, on receipt of the application, the Administration may reinstate the license or privilege.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Administration may not reinstate a license or privilege to drive under this subsection if the license or privilege has been refused, revoked, suspended, or canceled under any other provision of the Maryland Vehicle Law.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, before issuing a new license, the Administration shall require the applicant to submit to the examinations that it considers appropriate.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
