<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-8-726</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>726</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The General Assembly finds and declares that, except for on premise advertising, outdoor advertising along and adjacent to the federal-aid primary system of highways is a commercial use of these highways that should be regulated to:<section prefix="(1)">Prevent unreasonable distraction of the drivers of motor vehicles;</section><section prefix="(2)">Prevent confusion as to traffic lights, signs, controls, or signals, and prevent interference with the effectiveness of traffic regulations;</section><section prefix="(3)">Promote the prosperity, economic well-being, health, safety, morals, order, convenience, and general welfare of this State;</section><section prefix="(4)">Promote the enjoyment of travel on and protection of the public investment in highways in this State; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Preserve and enhance the natural scenic beauty or esthetic features and values of these highways and their adjacent areas.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">It is a policy of this State that:<section prefix="(i)">The erection and maintenance of outdoor advertising along the rights-of-way of the federal-aid primary system of highways in this State should be limited and regulated in accordance with this part and the rules and regulations adopted by the Administration under it; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">All outdoor advertising that does not meet the requirements of this part and these rules and regulations is not in the public interest.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">By enacting this part, the General Assembly intends to provide a statutory basis for the regulation of outdoor advertising consistent with the public policy for areas adjacent to federal-aid primary highways, as declared by the Congress in the federal Highway Beautification Act of 1965 and the Federal-Aid Highway Amendment of 1974.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This part shall be liberally construed to carry out the legislative policy stated in this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
