<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-104.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">On application, the Administration shall issue a moped operator's permit to an applicant who:<section prefix="(1)">Is 16 years of age or older;</section><section prefix="(2)">Does not possess a valid driver's license issued by this State or any other jurisdiction, but whose license or privilege to drive is not revoked, suspended, refused, or canceled;</section><section prefix="(3)">Provides satisfactory documentary evidence that the applicant has lawful status; and</section><section prefix="(4)"><section prefix="(i)">Provides satisfactory documentary evidence that the applicant has a valid Social Security number by presenting the applicant's Social Security Administration account card or, if the Social Security Administration account card is not available, any of the following documents bearing the applicant's Social Security number:<section prefix="1.">A current W-2 form;</section><section prefix="2.">A current SSA-1099 form;</section><section prefix="3.">A current non-SSA-1099 form; or</section><section prefix="4.">A current pay stub with the applicant's name and Social Security number on it; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Provides satisfactory documentary evidence that the applicant is not eligible for a Social Security number.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An applicant is entitled to receive a moped operator's permit if the applicant:<section prefix="(1)">Passes the examination provided for in &#xA7; 16-110(c)(1) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pays the fee provided for in this section; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Provides the documentary evidence described in subsection (a) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each application for a moped operator's permit shall be on a form and contain the information that the Administration requires and each permit issued shall be of a size, design, and content that the Administration specifies.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A permit is not valid unless the applicant signs the applicant's name on it in the applicant's usual signature.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When issued and signed, a moped operator's permit only authorizes its holder to operate a moped, as defined in &#xA7; 11-134.1 of this article or a motor scooter, as defined in &#xA7; 11-134.5 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, a moped operator's permit expires at the end of a period of not more than 5 years determined in regulations adopted by the Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If an applicant has temporary lawful status, the Administration may not issue a moped operator's permit to the applicant for a period that extends beyond the expiration date of the applicant's authorized stay in the United States or, if there is no expiration date, for a period longer than 1 year.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Nothing contained in this paragraph may be construed to allow the issuance of a moped operator's permit for a period longer than the period described in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Administration shall indicate on the face and in the machine-readable zone of a temporary moped operator's permit issued under this paragraph that the permit is a temporary moped operator's permit.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">It may be renewed on application and payment of the fee required by subsection (f) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For issuance or renewal of a moped operator's permit, an applicant shall pay the Administration a fee established by the Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For issuance of a duplicate moped operator's permit, an applicant shall pay the Administration a fee established by the Administration.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
