<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-211</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>211</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An individual whose license or privilege to drive has been refused under this title may not drive a motor vehicle in this State after the refusal under any license or permit issued by any other jurisdiction or otherwise, until a new license or privilege is obtained under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An individual whose license or privilege to drive has been suspended under this title may not drive a motor vehicle in this State during the suspension under any license or permit issued by any other jurisdiction or otherwise, until a new license or privilege is obtained under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An individual whose license or privilege to drive has been revoked under this title may not drive a motor vehicle in this State after the revocation under any license or permit issued by any other jurisdiction or otherwise, until a new license or privilege is obtained under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An individual whose license or privilege to drive has been refused under this title may not drive a motor vehicle in this State after the refusal under any registration certificate issued by any other jurisdiction or otherwise, until a new license or privilege is obtained under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An individual whose license or privilege to drive has been suspended under this title may not drive a motor vehicle in this State during the suspension under any registration certificate issued by any other jurisdiction or otherwise, until a new license or privilege is obtained under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An individual whose license or privilege to drive has been revoked under this title may not drive a motor vehicle in this State after the revocation under any registration certificate issued by any other jurisdiction or otherwise, until a new license or privilege is obtained under this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
