<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-205" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-10-205</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In accordance with and subject to the principle that, if there is substantial State financial support for the planned rapid rail mass transit system in one metropolitan area of this State, there should be substantial State financial support for the planned rapid rail mass transit system in the other metropolitan area of this State, and subject to the appropriation requirements and budgetary provisions of &#xA7; 3-216(d) of this article, the Department shall provide for grants to the Washington Suburban Transit District in an amount equal to the current expenditures required of the Washington Suburban Transit District in accordance with capital contributions agreements between the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority, the Washington Suburban Transit District, and other participating jurisdictions. The Washington Suburban Transit District shall consult with the Secretary of Transportation prior to the execution of any capital contributions agreement. Expenditures required of the Washington Suburban Transit District for projects and programs not included in the "Adopted Regional System - 1968" revised as of January 1, 1992, are only eligible for State funding in accordance with subsection (f) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the appropriation requirements and budgetary provisions of &#xA7; 3-216(d) of this article and upon receipt of an approval of a grant application in such form and detail as the Secretary shall reasonably require, the Department shall provide for annual grants to the Washington Suburban Transit District for a share of the operating deficits of the regional transit system for which the District is responsible. "Operating deficit" means operating costs less:<section prefix="(i)">The greater of operating revenues or 50 percent of the operating costs; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">All federal operating assistance.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department's share shall equal 100 percent of the operating deficit.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subject to the appropriation requirements and budgetary provision of &#xA7; 3-216(d) of this article, the Department shall provide for grants to the Washington Suburban Transit District in an amount equal to 75 percent of the net debt service assigned to the Washington Suburban Transit District on bonds issued by the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority. In no event shall the amount of net debt service, including the refinancing of any debt, required of the Washington Suburban Transit District exceed the amount presently assigned on a year by year basis to the Washington Suburban Transit District, and payable through the year 2014. Nothing in this article shall preclude the use of bond proceeds for capital improvements and replacements of the "Adopted Regional System - 1968" revised as of January 1, 1992.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In accordance with and subject to the principle that, if there is substantial State financial support for rapid rail and bus transit capital replacement costs in one metropolitan area of this State, there should be substantial State financial support for the costs of similar needs in the other metropolitan area of this State, and in recognition of the fact that timely replacement of capital facilities and equipment is essential to safe and reliable transit service, the Department shall provide grants to fully fund the Washington Suburban Transit District's share of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority's capital equipment replacement programs.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The grants under this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">Shall be made subject to the appropriation and budgetary provisions of &#xA7; 3-216(d) of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall be included in the State budget beginning in fiscal year 2000;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, may be funded with revenues derived from:</section><section prefix="(iv)">Shall be contingent on the receipt of a request by the District to the Department, based on annual capital improvements programs adopted by the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Subject to the appropriation requirements and budgetary provisions of &#xA7; 3-216(d) of this article, the Department shall provide grants from amounts derived from the Transportation Trust Fund to the Washington Suburban Transit District for the purpose of funding Maryland's required share of local funds for the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority to match any federal funds appropriated in any given year authorized under Title VI, &#xA7; 601, P.L. 110-432.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A grant by the Department to the Washington Suburban Transit District in excess of the provisions of subsection (a) of this section may be made only after approval by the Secretary.</section>
  </text>
</law>
