<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-25-102.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>102.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Licensed driver" means an individual who holds a driver's license of any class issued by the State or, if the individual is a nonresident of the State, issued by another state or country.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Licensed driver" does not include an individual who holds a learner's permit or a provisional license issued by the State or, if the individual is a nonresident of the State, the equivalent license issued by another state or country.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Motorized passenger scooter" means a nonpedal vehicle that:<section prefix="1.">Has a cockpit containing a seat for the operator and a passenger;</section><section prefix="2.">Has three wheels, of which one is 10 inches or more in diameter;</section><section prefix="3.">Has a motor:</section><section prefix="4.">Is equipped with an automatic transmission.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Motorized passenger scooter" does not include a vehicle that has been manufactured for off-road use, including a motorcycle and an all-terrain vehicle.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notwithstanding any other provisions of the Maryland Vehicle Law regarding the operation of a vehicle on a highway in the State, in the municipal boundaries of Ocean City, a licensed driver may operate a motorized passenger scooter on:<section prefix="(1)">A local highway; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Subject to subsection (c) of this section, any portion of a State highway designated by the State Highway Administration as a bicycle way.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The State Highway Administration may prohibit the operation of a motorized passenger scooter on a bicycle way under the jurisdiction of the State Highway Administration if it determines that:<section prefix="(1)">An occupant of a motorized passenger scooter is placed at an unacceptable risk of injury on the bicycle way; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The operation of a motorized passenger scooter is a threat to the safety or mobility of others along the bicycle way.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
