<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-12-112</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>112</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Unless the information is classified as confidential under &#xA7; 12-111 of this subtitle or otherwise as provided by law, and subject to &#xA7; 10-616(p) of the State Government Article, the Administration may furnish listings of vehicle registration and other public information in its records to those persons who request them, but only if the Administration approves of the purpose for which the information is requested.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Administration shall charge a fee for any listing furnished under this section. The fee charged may not be less than the cost to this State of preparing that listing. The revenue from the fee shall not be subject to the distribution provisions of Title 8, Subtitle 4 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person furnished any information under this section is prohibited from distributing or otherwise using the information for any purpose other than that for which it was furnished.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following terms have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Personal information" has the meaning indicated in &#xA7; 10-611(f) of the State Government Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Telephone solicitation" has the meaning indicated in &#xA7; 10-611(h) of the State Government Article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration may not disclose personal information for inclusion in listings of information for use in surveys, marketing, or solicitations without written consent from the person in interest.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An individual may allow disclosure of personal information under this section when applying for or renewing a driver's license, certificate of title, registration, or identification card or by notifying the Administrator in writing at any time.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Administration may not disclose personal information under this section for use in telephone solicitations.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">This subsection does not prevent the Administration from furnishing personal information under this section:<section prefix="(i)">To another governmental agency; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">For another purpose permissible under &#xA7; 10-616(p) of the State Government Article.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
