<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-612" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-5-612</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Airport zoning regulations adopted under this subtitle shall provide for a board of appeals with the power:<section prefix="(1)">To hear and decide appeals in all cases in which it is alleged that there is error in any decision of the administrative agency in the enforcement of this subtitle or of any ordinance or other legislation adopted under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">If required by an ordinance or other legislation adopted under this subtitle, to hear and decide special exceptions to the terms of the ordinance or other legislation; and</section><section prefix="(3)">To hear, decide, and, in proper cases, grant specific variances from the zoning regulations adopted under this subtitle, subject to the rules, regulations, restrictions, guides, and standards established under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A zoning board of appeals of the political subdivision may be designated as the board of appeals. In all other cases, subsection (c) of this section applies.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, the board of appeals shall consist of five appointed members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each member of the board of appeals serves for a term of 4 years and until his successor is appointed and qualifies. However, of the original appointees, one is to serve a 1-year term, one is to serve a 2-year term, one is to serve a 3-year term, and two are to serve a 4-year term.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On written charges and after a public hearing, the respective appointing authority may remove any member of the board of appeals for cause.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member appointed to fill a vacancy in an unexpired term serves only for the remainder of that term.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The board of appeals shall adopt rules and regulations in accordance with any ordinance adopted under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Meetings of the board shall be held at the call of the chairman and at any other time that the board determines. All meetings of the board shall be open to the public.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The board shall keep minutes of its proceedings, showing the absence, vote, or failure to vote of each member on each question, and records of its examinations and other official actions. These minutes and records shall be filed immediately in the office of the board and shall be a public record.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At a meeting of the board of appeals, the chairman or, in his absence, the acting chairman may administer oaths and issue subpoenas and orders for the attendance of witnesses and the production of papers, books, and documents.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a person fails to comply with any subpoena or order issued under this subsection, the chairman or acting chairman may invoke the aid of a court of competent jurisdiction. The court may order that person to obey the subpoena or order or to give evidence about the matter in question.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The concurring vote of a majority of the members of the board is sufficient to exercise any of its powers under this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
