<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-8-402</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Gasoline and Motor Vehicle Revenue Account in the Transportation Trust Fund....</catch_line>
  <order_by>402</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Gasoline and Motor Vehicle Revenue Account in the Transportation Trust Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">All revenues collected from the following, after deductions provided by law, shall be credited to the Gasoline and Motor Vehicle Revenue Account:<section prefix="(1)">All of the motor vehicle fuel tax;</section><section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided by law, two-thirds of the vehicle titling tax;</section><section prefix="(3)">Except for revenues collected under Parts III and IV of Title 13, Subtitle 9 of this article, vehicle registration fees;</section><section prefix="(4)">The revenue disbursed to this Account under &#xA7; 2-614 of the Tax - General Article; and</section><section prefix="(5)">80 percent of the funds distributed on short-term vehicle rentals under &#xA7; 2-1302.1 of the Tax - General Article to the Transportation Trust Fund from the sales and use tax.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, for each fiscal year:<section prefix="(i)">90.4% of the revenue credited to the Account may be used as provided in &#xA7; 3-216 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The balance of the Account shall be used to pay the allocations of highway user revenues provided by this subtitle to the counties, municipalities, and Baltimore City.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For fiscal years 2010 through 2013, the Account shall be distributed as follows:<section prefix="(i)">A portion to the General Fund of the State for fiscal years 2010 through 2012 as follows:<section prefix="1.">19.5% for fiscal year 2010;</section><section prefix="2.">23% for fiscal year 2011; and</section><section prefix="3.">11.3% for fiscal year 2012;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">A portion to be used as provided in &#xA7; 3-216 of this article, as follows:<section prefix="1.">70% for fiscal year 2010;</section><section prefix="2.">68.5% for fiscal year 2011;</section><section prefix="3.">Subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, 79.8% for fiscal year 2012; and</section><section prefix="4.">90% for fiscal year 2013; and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">The balance to be used to pay the allocations of highway user revenues provided under this subtitle to the counties, municipalities, and Baltimore City.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For fiscal year 2012, from the amount allocated to the Transportation Trust Fund under paragraph (2)(ii)3 of this subsection, $40,000,000 shall be transferred from the Transportation Trust Fund to the Revenue Stabilization Account established under &#xA7; 7-311 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
