<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-122</section_number>
  <catch_line>Notwithstanding any other provision of this article, the Administration shall, subject to the provis...</catch_line>
  <order_by>122</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this article, the Administration shall, subject to the provisions of this section, issue or renew an identification card, a moped operator's permit, or a license to drive that is not acceptable by federal agencies for official purposes determined by the Secretary of the United States Department of Homeland Security if an applicant:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">Has an unresolved non-match described under &#xA7; 16-121 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="2.">Meets the requirements concerning the non-match contained in regulations adopted by the Administration that are consistent with regulations adopted by the Secretary of the United States Department of Homeland Security; and</section><section prefix="3.">Would be otherwise eligible under this article for the issuance or renewal of an identification card under &#xA7; 12-301 of this article, a moped operator's permit under &#xA7; 16-104.2 of this subtitle, or a license to drive under this title, but for the unresolved non-match; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">Was the holder of an identification card under &#xA7; 12-301 of this article, a moped operator's permit under &#xA7; 16-104.2 of this subtitle, or a license to drive under this subtitle issued or renewed by the Administration before April 19, 2009;</section><section prefix="2.">Does not provide satisfactory documentary evidence that the applicant has lawful status or a valid Social Security number;</section><section prefix="3.">Certifies that the applicant does not have a Social Security number; and</section><section prefix="4.">Would be otherwise eligible for issuance or renewal of an identification card under &#xA7; 12-301 of this article, a moped operator's permit under &#xA7; 16-104.2 of this subtitle, or a license to drive issued under this subtitle, but for the absence of documentary evidence described in item 2 of this item.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration may not issue or renew an identification card, moped operator's permit, or license to drive under paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection on or after July 1, 2015.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An identification card, moped operator's permit, or license to drive issued or renewed under paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection on or after July 1, 2010, shall expire on July 1, 2015.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">This subsection does not apply to any provision of law applicable to the issuance or renewal of a commercial driver's license under this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Administration may require that an application for issuance or renewal of an identification card, a moped operator's permit, or a license to drive under this section be made in person.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not be a holder of an identification card, a moped operator's permit, or a license to drive issued or renewed under this section if the person is the holder of any other identification card, moped operator's permit, or license to drive issued or renewed under this section or any other section of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each identification card, moped operator's permit, and license to drive issued or renewed in accordance with this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">Clearly state on its face and in its  machine-readable zone that it is not acceptable by federal agencies for official purposes;</section><section prefix="(2)">Have a unique design or color indicator that clearly distinguishes it from the design or color of an identification card under &#xA7; 12-301 of this article, a moped operator's permit under &#xA7; 16-115 of this subtitle, or any license to drive under any other section of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Be of the size and design that the Administration requires, tamperproof, to the extent possible, and contain:<section prefix="(i)">The name and address of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The birth date of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The gender of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A description of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(v)">A color photograph of the applicant taken by the procedure that the Administration requires;</section><section prefix="(vi)">The expiration date of the identification card, moped operator's permit, or license to drive;</section><section prefix="(vii)">The signature of the applicant; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">The signature and seal of the issuing agent.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An identification card, a moped operator's permit, or a license to drive issued or renewed under this section shall expire at the end of a period that is equivalent to the expiration period applicable for an identification card under &#xA7; 12-301 of this article, a moped operator's permit under &#xA7; 16-115 of this subtitle, or a license to drive under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Except as otherwise expressly provided by law, an identification card, a moped operator's permit, or a license to drive issued under this section may be used for any purpose as legal identification of the holder to whom the identification card, moped operator's permit, or license to drive is issued.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Administration may establish a fee for the issuance or renewal of an identification card, a moped operator's permit, or a license to drive issued or renewed under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Except as expressly provided in this section, this section does not limit the application of any other provision of this article to an identification card, a moped operator's permit, or a license to drive issued under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
