<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-936.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "vintage registration plate" means a Maryland registration plate that was actually ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>936.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "vintage registration plate" means a Maryland registration plate that was actually issued for display on a motor vehicle in a year not less than 25 years prior to January 1 of each calendar year.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of this subsection, the owner of a motor vehicle registered under &#xA7; 13-936 or &#xA7; 13-937.1 of this subtitle as a Class L (historic) or Class N (street rod) vehicle may display 2 vintage registration plates in lieu of current registration plates on that vehicle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration may authorize the display of 2 vintage registration plates in lieu of current registration plates on a motor vehicle described in paragraph (1) of this subsection if:<section prefix="(i)">The owner of the motor vehicle submits an application on a form prescribed by the Administrator;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The 2 vintage registration plates were issued in the same year as the model year of the motor vehicle; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The owner of the motor vehicle pays a onetime registration fee of $25.50.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the Administration authorizes the display of vintage registration plates under this section:<section prefix="(1)">The vintage registration plates shall remain valid for as long as title to the motor vehicle remains in the person who submitted an application under subsection (b)(2)(i) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A fee in addition to the onetime registration fee prescribed in subsection (b)(2)(iii) of this section is not required for the issuance of the vintage registration plates.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
