<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-12-304</section_number>
  <catch_line>NOT IN EFFECT...</catch_line>
  <order_by>304</order_by>
  <text>NOT IN EFFECT<section prefix="(a)">This section applies only to an adult male applicant under the age of 26 years.</section><section prefix="(b)">Subject to subsection (c) of this section, the Administration shall provide to the Selective Service Administration in an electronic format, for purposes of registration with the Selective Service as required under federal law, the necessary information concerning a male applicant who applies for a driver's license or identification card or the renewal of a driver's license or identification card, including the applicant's:<section prefix="(1)">Full name;</section><section prefix="(2)">Current address;</section><section prefix="(3)">Date of birth;</section><section prefix="(4)">Gender;</section><section prefix="(5)">Date of application; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Social Security number, if available.</section></section><section prefix="(c)"><section prefix="(1)">A male applicant's signature on the application indicates that the applicant has selected one of the options specified in paragraph (2) of this subsection concerning Selective Service registration and the forwarding of information to the Selective Service Administration under this section.</section><section prefix="(2)">In addition to the information required under this subtitle or Title 16 of this article, an application form for a driver's license or identification card or renewal of a driver's license or identification card shall contain a statement that the male applicant:<section prefix="(i)">Has already registered with the Selective Service Administration; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has not registered with the Selective Service Administration and:<section prefix="1.">Consents to forwarding the information in subsection (b) of this section to the Selective Service Administration; or</section><section prefix="2.">Refuses to consent to the forwarding of the information in subsection (b) of this section to the Selective Service Administration.</section></section></section></section><section prefix="(d)">Refusal to consent to the forwarding of the information in subsection (b) of this section to the Selective Service Administration may not be grounds for denial of an application for a driver's license or identification card or renewal of a driver's license or identification card.</section></text>
</law>
