<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-21-704</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>704</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Unless a person has complied with this section, he may not drive or move on or across any railroad grade crossing any power shovel, derrick, roller, crawler-type tractor, or other equipment or structure that has:<section prefix="(1)">A normal operating speed of 10 miles an hour or less; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A vertical body or load clearance, measured above the level surface of a roadway, of less than:<section prefix="(i)">One-half inch for each foot of the distance between any two adjacent axles; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">9 inches.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Before any person drives or moves any equipment described in subsection (a) of this section on or across any railroad grade crossing, the person shall:<section prefix="(1)">Notify an agent of the railroad of his intention; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Afford the railroad reasonable time to provide proper protection at the crossing.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">When the person approaches the crossing, he:<section prefix="(1)">Shall stop within 50 feet but not less than 15 feet from the nearest rail in the crossing;</section><section prefix="(2)">While stopped, shall listen and look in both directions along the track for any approaching or passing railroad train and for any signals indicating the approach or passage of a railroad train; and</section><section prefix="(3)">May not proceed until he can do so safely.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The person may not proceed if a warning is given by an automatic signal, crossing gate, flagman, or otherwise of the immediate approach or passage of a railroad train.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the railroad provides a flagman, the person may proceed over the crossing only at the direction of the flagman.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
