<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-24-107</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>107</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Primary connecting system" means the combination of devices and their attaching structures that are used to connect a towed vehicle to a towing vehicle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Safety chain" means a flexible tension member connected from the front of the towed vehicle to the rear of the towing vehicle for the purpose of retaining the connection between the towed and towing vehicles if the connection provided by the primary connecting system fails.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Tow dolly" means a vehicle having a tongue or towbar attachment designed to tow other vehicles and used to tow:<section prefix="(i)">Another vehicle when the front or rear wheels of the towed vehicle are placed in a cradle-like device that lifts the wheels from the highway; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A trailer or semitrailer when the towing vehicle has a fifth-wheel attachment device.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Towbar" means a strut or column-like device temporarily attached between the rear of a towing vehicle and the front of the towed vehicle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">When towing another vehicle, the driver shall ensure that:<section prefix="(1)">The towed vehicle is securely attached to the towing vehicle by a primary connecting system;</section><section prefix="(2)">The connection used is:<section prefix="(i)">Structurally adequate for the weight drawn; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Mounted properly and securely, without excessive slack, but with enough slack to allow for articulation of the connection;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">The locking device that prevents separation of the towed and towing vehicles is working properly and is locked in place; and</section><section prefix="(4)">One or more safety chains are attached to the towed vehicle and the frame of the towing vehicle and have no more slack than is necessary for proper turning.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Attachment of the safety chains to the pintle hook does not satisfy the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except for the connection between any two vehicles carrying poles, pipes, machinery, or other objects that cannot be readily dismembered, the connection between vehicles may not exceed 15 feet.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A connection made with a fifth-wheel connection device is not required to use safety chains or cables as additional securing devices.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If a vehicle is towed by a rope, chain, or cable, a driver must be in and capable of steering the towed vehicle.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A primary connecting system used in a combination of vehicles shall be designed, constructed, and installed to insure that a towed vehicle does not shift or swerve more than 6 inches to either side of the path of the towing vehicle while the towing vehicle is moving in a straight line on a level, smooth, paved surface.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">While one vehicle is towing another and the connection is a chain, rope, or cable, a white, red, or orange-fluorescent warning flag or cloth at least 18 inches square shall be displayed on the connection.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, or when one tow dolly is used to tow one other vehicle, a vehicle may not be operated in combination with more than one other vehicle.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration may adopt regulations that establish standards for hitching devices and towing procedures for towing and towed vehicles.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, this subsection applies to tractor-trailer combinations, semitrailer combinations, and any other vehicle combinations designed and used for carrying freight or merchandise in furtherance of any commercial enterprise.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
