<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-104.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-104.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A noncommercial Class A driver's license authorizes the licensee to drive combinations of Class F (tractor) and Class G (trailer) vehicles and any vehicle that a noncommercial Class B driver's license authorizes its holder to drive, except:<section prefix="(i)">Commercial motor vehicles; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Motorcycles.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual who is issued a noncommercial Class A driver's license under this subsection may not drive or attempt to drive a motor vehicle on any highway in this State unless a noncommercial Class A driver's license authorizes the individual to drive a vehicle of the class that the individual is driving or attempting to drive.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A noncommercial Class B driver's license authorizes the licensee to drive any single vehicle or combinations of vehicles with a gross vehicle weight rating (GVWR) or gross combination weight rating (GCWR), as defined in &#xA7; 16-803 of this title, of 26,001 pounds and more and any vehicle that a noncommercial Class C driver's license authorizes its holder to drive, except:<section prefix="(i)">Commercial motor vehicles;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Motorcycles; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Combinations of Class F (tractor) and Class G (trailer) vehicles.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual who is issued a noncommercial Class B driver's license under this subsection may not drive or attempt to drive a motor vehicle on any highway in this State unless a noncommercial Class B driver's license authorizes the individual to drive a vehicle of the class that the individual is driving or attempting to drive.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A noncommercial Class C driver's license authorizes the licensee to drive any vehicle or combination of vehicles with a gross vehicle weight rating (GVWR), as defined in &#xA7; 16-803 of this title, of less than 26,001 pounds, except:<section prefix="(i)">Commercial motor vehicles; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Motorcycles.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual who is issued a noncommercial Class C driver's license under this subsection may not drive or attempt to drive a motor vehicle on any highway in this State unless a noncommercial Class C driver's license authorizes the individual to drive a vehicle of the class that the individual is driving or attempting to drive.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A Class M driver's license authorizes the licensee to drive motorcycles.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual who is issued a Class M driver's license under this subsection may not drive or attempt to drive a motor vehicle on any highway in this State unless a Class M driver's license authorizes the individual to drive a vehicle of the class that the individual is driving or attempting to drive.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except when the towing vehicle is a commercial motor vehicle and subject to the provisions of this section, a noncommercial Class A, B, or C license holder may:<section prefix="(1)">Tow any travel trailer as defined in &#xA7; 11-170 of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">Tow any camping trailer as defined in &#xA7; 11-106 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Tow any boat trailer as defined in &#xA7; 11-104.1 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">This section applies to any license issued or renewed on or after January 1, 1990.</section>
  </text>
</law>
