<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-5-415</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "Fire Rescue Service" means the Maryland Aviation Administration Fire Rescue Servic...</catch_line>
  <order_by>415</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Fire Rescue Service" means the Maryland Aviation Administration Fire Rescue Service.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to subsection (c) of this section, the Fire Rescue Service shall charge an ambulance transport fee set in regulations adopted under subsection (d) of this section to an individual if the Fire Rescue Service transports the individual to a hospital from property owned by the Administration or property subject to a mutual aid agreement to which the Administration is a party.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fire Rescue Service may not:<section prefix="(i)">Question an individual about ability to pay the ambulance transport fee at the time that ambulance transportation is requested or provided; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Fail to provide ambulance transportation and emergency medical services because of an individual's actual or perceived inability to pay the ambulance transport fee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration may procure the services of a third party billing company to administer its ambulance transport fee program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Administration shall adopt regulations to:<section prefix="(1)">Set the ambulance transport fee; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Administer the collection of the ambulance transport fee, including regulations governing:<section prefix="(i)">A waiver of the ambulance transport fee in the event of financial hardship;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The acceptance of reduced payments by commercial insurers and other third-party payors, including Medicare and Medicaid; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">A requirement that each individual receiving an ambulance transport provide financial information, including the individual's insurance coverage, and assign insurance benefits to the Administration.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Administration shall deposit the fees collected under this section in the Transportation Trust Fund.</section>
  </text>
</law>
