<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-6-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Administration" means the Maryland Port Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Commission" means the Maryland Port Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Executive Director" means the Executive Director of the Maryland Port Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Port facility" includes any one or more or combination of:<section prefix="(1)">Lands, piers, docks, wharves, warehouses, sheds, transit sheds, elevators, compressors, refrigeration storage plants, buildings, structures, and other facilities, appurtenances, and equipment useful or designed for use in connection with the operation of a port;</section><section prefix="(2)">Every kind of terminal or storage structure or facility useful or designed for use in handling, storing, loading, or unloading freight or passengers at marine terminals;</section><section prefix="(3)">Every kind of transportation facility useful or designed for use in connection with any of these; and</section><section prefix="(4)">An international trade center constituting a facility of commerce and consisting of one or more buildings, structures, improvements, and areas that the Department considers necessary, convenient, or desirable for the centralized accommodation of functions, activities, and services for or incidental to the transportation of persons by water, the exchange, buying, selling, and transportation of commodities and other property in international and national waterborne trade and commerce, the promotion and protection of this trade and commerce, and governmental services related to them and other federal, state, and municipal agencies and services, including foreign trade zones, offices, marketing and exhibition facilities, terminal and transportation facilities, customhouses, custom stores, inspection and appraisal facilities, parking areas, commodity and security exchanges, and, in the case of buildings, structures, improvements, and areas in which such accommodation is afforded, all the buildings, structures, improvements, and areas, although other parts of the buildings, structures, improvements, and areas might not be devoted to purposes of the international trade center other than the production of incidental revenue available for the expenses and financial obligations of the Department in connection with the international trade center and although other parts of the buildings, structures, improvements, and areas might be rented or leased for the use or occupancy of departments, bureaus, units, or agencies of the United States, this State, or any political subdivision of this State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Project" means any port facility acquired, constructed, controlled, or operated by the Administration, including all property acquired for the construction or operation of the port facility.</section>
  </text>
</law>
