<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-8-714</section_number>
  <catch_line>Whether or not the person must be licensed under Part II of this subtitle, a person may not erect or...</catch_line>
  <order_by>714</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Whether or not the person must be licensed under Part II of this subtitle, a person may not erect or maintain any outdoor sign outside the limits of any municipal corporation and within 500 feet of a State highway, unless the person has a permit issued by the Administration for that sign.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A permit is not required under this section to erect or maintain any outdoor sign:<section prefix="(1)">That is used only to advertise the sale or lease of the property on which it is located;</section><section prefix="(2)">That is on or within 100 feet of any building or the entrance to any building in which the business advertised is carried on;</section><section prefix="(3)">That is used only to advertise:<section prefix="(i)">A Maryland historic shrine or institution; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A county or church fair held in this State;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">That advertises a candidate or the support or defeat of any proposition. This sign:<section prefix="(i)">Shall comply with all provisions of the Election Law Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall comply with public safety requirements as set forth in &#xA7; 8-716 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Shall conform to all local restrictions and zoning requirements which are more restrictive than this section; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Shall conform to the restrictions and requirements of Parts IV and V of this subtitle; or</section></section><section prefix="(5)">That is only a temporary outdoor sign that advertises the sale in season of fresh produce on property that adjoins a State highway by a person who has grown the fresh produce and who owns, rents, or has permission to sell on the property. This sign:<section prefix="(i)">Shall comply with public safety requirements as set forth in &#xA7; 8-716 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall conform to all local restrictions and zoning requirements that are more restrictive than this section, including any applicable time limitation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Shall conform to the restrictions and requirements of Parts IV and V of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Shall be removed or covered when produce is no longer for sale.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
