<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-21-1118</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1118</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The driver of a school bus:<section prefix="(1)">Is responsible for its operation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May not drive it into any roadway without first stopping and determining that there is no danger from any other vehicle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The person responsible for any pupils on a school bus is:<section prefix="(1)">The teacher on the bus; or</section><section prefix="(2)">If a teacher is not present, the driver.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person responsible for pupils on a school bus may not permit the number of standing pupils to exceed one pupil for each part of the aisle that is bounded on both sides by forward facing seats.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person responsible for pupils on a school bus may not permit any pupil to stand if the school bus is equipped only with lengthwise or a combination of lengthwise and forward facing seats.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person responsible for pupils on a school bus may not permit any pupil to stand in front of the stanchion and guardrail.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person responsible for pupils on a school bus may not permit any pupil to operate the front door opening mechanism, except in an emergency.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A person responsible for pupils on a school bus may not require any pupil to sit on the floor.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Except for the driver and any fuel station attendant, a person may not occupy a school bus while it is being supplied with fuel.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Either the driver or an adult aide assigned to each school vehicle that is used to transport handicapped children shall be certified as having successfully completed a first aid-safety course approved by the Department of Education.</section>
  </text>
</law>
