<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-22-221</section_number>
  <catch_line>Any motor vehicle may be equipped with not more than two side cowl or fender lamps that:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>221</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Any motor vehicle may be equipped with not more than two side cowl or fender lamps that:<section prefix="(1)">Emit an amber or white light without glare; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Are located at or near the front of the vehicle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Any motor vehicle may be equipped on each side of the vehicle with not more than one running-board courtesy lamp that emits a white or amber light without glare.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any motor vehicle may be equipped with one or more backup lamps, either separately or in combination with other lamps, but any such backup lamp may not be lighted when the motor vehicle is in forward motion.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Any vehicle may be equipped with lamps used for the purpose of warning the drivers of other vehicles of the presence of a vehicular traffic hazard requiring the exercise of unusual care in approaching, overtaking, or passing, and, when so equipped, may display the warning in addition to any other warning signals required by the Maryland Vehicle Law.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The lamps used to display this warning to the front shall be mounted at the same level and as widely spaced laterally as practicable and shall display simultaneously flashing white or amber lights, or any shade of color between white and amber. The lamps used to display this warning to the rear shall be mounted at the same level and as widely spaced laterally as practicable and shall display simultaneously flashing amber or red lights, or any shade of color between amber and red.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">These warning lights shall be visible from a distance of not less than 1,500 feet under normal atmospheric conditions at night.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Every motor vehicle that is registered in this State and that was manufactured or assembled after June 30, 1967, and designated as a 1968 or subsequent year model shall be equipped with these warning lamps by means of which the driver may cause both front and both rear turn signals to flash simultaneously as a vehicular traffic hazard warning.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Any vehicle 80 inches or more in overall width, if not otherwise required by &#xA7; 22-208 of this subtitle, may be equipped with not more than three identification lamps showing to the front, which emit an amber light without glare, and not more than three identification lamps showing to the rear, which emit a red light without glare.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">These lamps shall be mounted as specified in &#xA7; 22-208(c) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">Warning lamps may be used by the operator of any vehicle when the posted speed limit is in excess of 45 miles per hour and the vehicle is traveling at least 20 miles per hour under the posted speed limit, provided that the warning lamps shall be used when required by subsection (k) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The operator of any commercial motor vehicle as defined in &#xA7; 9-201 of the Tax - General Article shall use warning lamps when the posted speed limit is in excess of 45 miles per hour and the vehicle is traveling at least 20 miles per hour under the posted speed limit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection does not apply:<section prefix="(i)">Within any business or residential district;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Whenever a vehicle is slowing or stopping in lawful response to a traffic control device or in response to traffic conditions; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">To any vehicle which is not equipped with warning lamps.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, a motorcycle may be equipped with, and an operator of a motorcycle may use, the following auxiliary lighting:<section prefix="(i)">Blue dot illumination;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Standard bulb running lights; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Light-emitting diode pods and strips added to protect the driver.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Lighting under this subsection shall be:<section prefix="1.">Nonblinking;</section><section prefix="2.">Nonflashing;</section><section prefix="3.">Nonoscillating; and</section><section prefix="4.">Directed toward the engine and the drive train of the motorcycle.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Lighting under this subsection may not:<section prefix="1.">Be attached to the wheels of the motorcycle; or</section><section prefix="2.">Emit a red or blue light.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Blue dot illumination:<section prefix="1.">May be located only on the rear of a motorcycle as part of or adjacent to the rear brake light; and</section><section prefix="2.">May not exceed three-quarters of an inch in diameter.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
