<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-209" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-6-209</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Administration may permit gaming aboard a passenger cruise vessel if:<section prefix="(1)">The vessel has overnight cabin accommodations for at least 300 passengers;</section><section prefix="(2)">The vessel is operated by an authorized cruise ship operator certified under the International Convention for the Safety of Life at Sea (SOLAS); and</section><section prefix="(3)">The owner or operator of the vessel has obtained the required authorization as provided in this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The owner, operator, or any franchise holder of a cruise vessel described in subsection (a) of this section may apply to the Administration for authorization to conduct gaming aboard the vessel.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An application for authorization under this subsection shall include the following information:<section prefix="(i)">The applicant's corporate name, address, and place of incorporation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The name of the applicant's liability insurer;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The gaming rules to be in effect while the vessel is in the waters of the State; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">A schedule of all cruise operations for which authorization is requested, including arrival and departure dates and the identification of the vessel for each cruise.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In addition to the information required under paragraph (2) of this subsection, the applicant shall send a complete copy of the application to the Department of State Police.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An authorization issued by the Administration to a qualified applicant under this section shall remain valid for a period of not more than 1 year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An authorization issued under this section authorizes gaming on the waters of the State only while the vessel:<section prefix="(i)">Is underway;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is east of the Francis Scott Key Bridge; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is operating under an itinerary that either originates or terminates in a foreign port outside the continental United States.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Administration may not issue an authorization under this section for a vessel on an excursion undertaken solely for gaming purposes even though the vessel may leave the territorial waters of the United States during the excursion.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Any legal disputes arising from an authorization issued under this section shall be adjudicated under the applicable State or international maritime law.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A violation of any provision of this section or of any other applicable gaming law of the State:<section prefix="(1)">Shall be investigated jointly by the Administration and the Department of State Police; and</section><section prefix="(2)">In addition to any other penalties provided by law, may result in the withdrawal of an authorization issued under this section after the affected party has been granted an opportunity for a hearing.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Administration may adopt regulations as necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
