<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-8-508</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>508</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Board" means the Governor's Workforce Investment Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Highway or capital transit construction" means actual construction, preliminary engineering, planning and research, or any other work or activity to implement federal laws for the administration of federal aid for highways or capital transit projects.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Workforce investment area" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 11-503(n) of the Labor and Employment Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department shall use the maximum feasible amount of federal funds available to the State under 23 U.S.C. &#xA7; 140(b) to develop, conduct, and administer highway or capital transit construction training and supportive services, including skill improvement programs.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department shall administer the training programs under subsection (b) of this section in collaboration with the Board to ensure that highway or capital transit construction training and supportive services are provided to the greatest extent feasible to individuals in each relevant workforce investment area.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By February 1 of each year, the Department and Board shall submit to the Senate Budget and Taxation Committee, Senate Finance Committee, House Appropriations Committee, and House Committee on Ways and Means, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, a report on the Department's and Board's compliance with subsections (b) and (c) of this section with respect to each of the 2 previous calendar years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The report shall:<section prefix="(i)">Describe the highway or capital transit construction training, supportive services, and skill improvement programs the Department and Board have conducted and administered in each workforce investment area, including a description of:<section prefix="1.">Any entities, institutions, or organizations used by the Department and Board to provide the training and services; and</section><section prefix="2.">The individuals and organizations that have received training and services;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Analyze the results of the training programs in each workforce investment area;</section><section prefix="(iii)">State the amount of federal funds available to the State under 23 U.S.C. &#xA7; 140(b); and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Identify the amount spent in each workforce investment area to conduct and administer the programs.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
