<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-8-630</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>630</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Municipal corporation" has the meaning stated in Article 23A, &#xA7; 9 of the Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Urban highway" means a highway, other than an expressway, that is:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">Constructed with a curb and gutter and an enclosed type storm drainage system;</section><section prefix="2.">Located in an urban area and on which is located a public facility that creates appreciable pedestrian traffic along the highway from adjacent areas;</section><section prefix="3.">Located within urban boundaries as defined by the U.S. Census Bureau; or</section><section prefix="4.">Located within the boundaries of a municipal corporation; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Part of the State highway system.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Sidewalks shall be constructed at the time of construction or reconstruction of an urban highway, or in response to the request of a local government unless:<section prefix="(i)">The Administration determines that the cost or impacts of constructing the sidewalks would be too great in relation to the need for them or their probable use; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The local government indicates that there is no need for sidewalks.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Sidewalks constructed under this section shall be consistent with area master plans and transportation plans adopted by the local planning commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If sidewalks or bicycle pathways are constructed or reconstructed as part of a roadway construction or reconstruction project, the Administration shall fund the sidewalk or bicycle pathway construction or reconstruction as a part of the cost of the roadway project.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraphs (3) and (4) of this subsection, if sidewalks or bicycle pathways are constructed or reconstructed in response to a request from a local government and the adjacent roadway is not being concurrently constructed or reconstructed, the cost to construct or reconstruct the sidewalk or bicycle pathway shall be shared equally between the State and local governments.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If sidewalks or bicycle pathways within a sustainable community as defined in &#xA7; 6-301 of the Housing and Community Development Article are constructed or reconstructed in response to a request from a local government and the adjacent roadway is not being concurrently constructed or reconstructed, the cost to construct or reconstruct the sidewalk or bicycle pathway may be funded entirely by the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph does not apply to a priority funding area that is a sustainable community as defined in &#xA7; 6-301 of the Housing and Community Development Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If sidewalks or bicycle pathways within an area designated as a priority funding area under &#xA7; 5-7B-02 of the State Finance and Procurement Article are constructed or reconstructed in response to a request from a local government and the adjacent roadway is not being concurrently constructed or reconstructed, and if the Administration determines that construction would not occur under this section due to insufficient contribution of funds by the local government, the cost to construct or reconstruct the sidewalk or bicycle pathway shall be shared between the State and local government as follows:<section prefix="1.">75 percent of the cost shall be funded by the State; and</section><section prefix="2.">25 percent of the cost shall be funded by the local government.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If sidewalks or bicycle pathways within an area designated as a priority funding area under &#xA7; 5-7B-02 of the State Finance and Procurement Article are constructed or reconstructed based on a determination by the Administration that a substantial public safety risk or significant impediment to pedestrian access exists and the adjacent roadway is not being concurrently constructed or reconstructed, then:<section prefix="1.">The Administration shall categorize the sidewalk or bicycle pathway construction project as "system preservation" and give corresponding funding priority to the project; and</section><section prefix="2.">The cost to construct or reconstruct the sidewalk or bicycle pathway may be funded entirely by the State.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If sidewalks or bicycle pathways are being constructed or reconstructed in response to a request from a local government and the adjacent roadway is not being concurrently constructed or reconstructed, the local government shall:<section prefix="(i)">Provide public notice and opportunities for community involvement prior to the construction of a sidewalk or bicycle pathway project; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Secure any necessary right-of-way that may be needed beyond the right-of-way already owned by the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, after sidewalks and bicycle pathways are constructed under this section, they shall be maintained and repaired by the political subdivision in which they are located.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subject to approval and the availability of funds, the Administration promptly shall reimburse a political subdivision for the preapproved and documented costs incurred in reconstructing a segment of a sidewalk or bicycle pathway that has deteriorated to the extent that repair is not practical or desirable for public safety.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Administration may not construct any project that will result in the severance or destruction of an existing major route for pedestrian transportation traffic, unless the project provides for construction of a reasonable alternative route or such a route already exists.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Administration shall develop guidelines jointly with local governments to carry out the provisions of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Administration shall maintain and repair all facilities for nighttime illumination that:<section prefix="(1)">Are constructed by the Administration for the safe conduct of vehicular traffic; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Exist adjacent to urban highways.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
