<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-619" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-619</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The owner of a motor vehicle, or a lessee of the vehicle under a lease not intended as security, or a director, officer, employee, or partner of a business entity that owns the vehicle who is a member or, subject to subsection (c)(3) of this section, the surviving spouse of a member, of an organization considered eligible by the Administration may apply to the Administration for the assignment of a special registration number if the vehicle is included in one of the following classes:<section prefix="(1)">A Class A (passenger) vehicle;</section><section prefix="(2)">A Class E (truck) vehicle with a manufacturer's rated capacity of one ton or less; or</section><section prefix="(3)">A Class M (multipurpose) vehicle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "motorcyclist organization" means a motorcyclist organization, institution, association, society, or corporation that:<section prefix="(i)">Is exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 501(c)(7) of the Internal Revenue Code; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is determined by the Administration to be eligible under this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The owner of a Class D (motorcycle) vehicle who is a member of a motorcyclist organization may apply to the Administration for the assignment of a special registration number for the vehicle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Administration may issue and continue a special registration number under this section if:<section prefix="(1)">The owner of the motor vehicle submits, with the original application, proof satisfactory to the Administration that the owner of the vehicle is a member of a nonprofit organization and complies with the regulations adopted by the Administration under subsection (d) of this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">At least 25 owners of vehicles in a class apply to the Administration for the assignment of special registration numbers, and at least 25 special registration numbers are issued initially; and</section><section prefix="(3)">In the case of an owner who is applying as a surviving spouse, the owner submits proof satisfactory to the Administration that at the time of death of the owner's spouse, the deceased spouse was the holder of a special registration number issued under this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Administration shall adopt regulations not inconsistent with the Maryland Vehicle Law to govern the issuance of special registration plates to members of nonprofit organizations under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to the annual registration fee otherwise required under this title, an owner of a vehicle assigned a special registration under this section shall pay a fee determined by the Administration each time new registration plates are issued for the vehicle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The fee:<section prefix="(i)">May not exceed the amount required to enable the Administration to recover its costs under this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall be retained by the Administration for the purpose of recovering its cost under this section; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">May not be credited to the Gasoline and Motor Vehicle Revenue Account for distribution under &#xA7; 8-403 or &#xA7; 8-404 of this article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The additional fee required under subsection (e) of this section is not required for special registration of a vehicle that is exempt under &#xA7; 13-903 of this title, or a vehicle with a special registration plate recognizing:<section prefix="(1)">The Maryland National Guard; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A volunteer fire department, volunteer rescue squad, or volunteer ambulance company in this State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The special registration plates or plate issued under this section may consist of:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)"/></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A special registration number assigned under this section shall be displayed on the registration plates or plate for the vehicle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An organization may, at its option, receive a special registration under either paragraph (1)(i) or paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection, but not under both.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
