<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-818" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-818</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An applicant for a commercial driver's license shall pay the Administration the following fees established by the Administration:<section prefix="(1)">Upon application for a new commercial driver's license or a commercial driver's license of a class other than that which the applicant holds:<section prefix="(i)">The base license fee if a commercial driver's instructional permit is required or an amount established by the Administration if an instructional permit is not required;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A commercial driver's license fee; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The applicable fees listed in subsection (b) of this section;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">For the renewal of any class of commercial driver's license:<section prefix="(i)">A renewal fee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A commercial driver's license fee; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The applicable fees listed in subsection (b) of this section;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">For the conversion of a Maryland Class A, B, C, or D driver's license to a commercial driver's license:<section prefix="(i)">A renewal fee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A commercial driver's license fee; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The applicable fees listed in subsection (b) of this section; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">For issuance of a duplicate or corrected commercial driver's license, a duplicate or corrected driver's license fee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to the fees required by subsection (a) of this section, the applicant shall pay the Administration a fee established by the Administration for a required skills test or for a skills retest.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Fees collected under this section:<section prefix="(1)">Shall be deposited in the Transportation Trust Fund; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Are not subject to the provisions of Title 8, Subtitle 4 of this article on the disposition of highway user revenues.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
