<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-21-1003.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in subsections (c) and (d) of this section, a local authority may not issue a res...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1003.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsections (c) and (d) of this section, a local authority may not issue a residential parking permit to the owner of a vehicle to be valid for a period in excess of 30 days unless the owner provides satisfactory evidence that:<section prefix="(1)">The vehicle for which the parking permit is sought is registered in the State; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The owner of the vehicle has obtained under &#xA7; 13-402.1 of this article:<section prefix="(i)">A nonresident permit; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A complimentary guest card.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a residential parking permit area is established as a result of the construction of a professional sports facility that seats 45,000 or more people, a local authority may not charge a fee for the issuance of a permit to park in that area.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In Baltimore City, the Executive Director of the Baltimore City Parking Authority may issue, on a showing of evidence of ownership and occupancy, a residential parking permit to a person who owns and occupies residential property in the residential parking permit area regardless of whether the person would otherwise qualify for a residential parking permit under subsection (a) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In the City of Annapolis, the Annapolis Parking and Fines Section of the Annapolis Police Department may issue, on a showing of evidence of ownership and occupancy, a residential parking permit to a person who owns and occupies residential property in the residential parking permit area regardless of whether the person would otherwise qualify for a residential parking permit under subsection (a) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
