<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-3-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this title the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Airport facility":<section prefix="(1)">Has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 5-101 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Includes any one or more or combination of air navigation facilities, as defined in &#xA7; 5-101 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Bonds of prior issues" means:<section prefix="(1)">All "State highway construction bonds, second issue" and "State highway construction bonds, third issue" issued and sold under Article 89B of the Code of 1957; and</section><section prefix="(2)">All bonds issued and sold under Article 62B of the Code of 1957, evidencing the "Maryland Port Authority Loan of 1958", "Maryland Port Authority Second Loan of 1961", and "Maryland Port Authority Loan of 1967".</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Cost", as applied to any transportation facility, includes the cost of and all expenses incident to the construction, reconstruction, acquisition, improvement, extension, alteration, modernization, planning, maintenance, and repair of the facility, including the cost and expenses of:<section prefix="(1)">All property acquired in connection with it;</section><section prefix="(2)">Financial, architectural, consulting, engineering, and legal services;</section><section prefix="(3)">Plans, specifications, surveys, estimates, feasibility reports, and direct and indirect labor, material, equipment, and administrative expenses; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Financing the facility, including financing charges and interest before, during, and for 1 year after completion of construction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Debt service" means the amount annually needed to pay the maturing principal of and interest on bonds, notes, and other evidences of obligation and to meet sinking fund requirements for these purposes.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this definition, "highway" and "State highway system" have the meanings stated in &#xA7; 8-101 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Highway facility" includes any one or more or combination of projects involving the rehabilitation and reconstruction of highways in the State highway system to meet present and future needs and the development and construction in new locations of new highways necessitated by traffic demands to become parts of the State highway system, including federally aided highway projects partially funded by this State and all incidental property rights, materials, facilities, and structures.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Outstanding and unpaid" does not include:<section prefix="(1)">Bonds purchased and held in sinking funds by or for the Department; or</section><section prefix="(2)">If the money for their payment or redemption has been provided:<section prefix="(i)">Matured bonds not presented for payment; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Bonds called for redemption but not presented for redemption.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Port facility" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 6-101 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Railroad facility" includes any one or more or combination of:<section prefix="(i)">Switches, spurs, tracks, structures, terminals, yards, real property, and other facilities useful or designed for use in connection with the transportation of persons or goods by rail; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">All other appurtenances, including locomotives, cars, vehicles, and other instrumentalities of shipment or carriage, useful or designed for use in connection with the transportation of persons or goods by rail.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Railroad facility" does not include any transit facility.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Refunding" means the retirement and cancellation of bonds, including bonds of prior issues, after their acquisition by or for the Department, whether before, at, or after maturity, either in exchange for other bonds or by payment, purchase, or redemption with the proceeds of the sale of other bonds.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Transit facility" includes any one or more or combination of tracks, rights-of-way, bridges, tunnels, subways, rolling stock, stations, terminals, ports, parking areas, equipment, fixtures, buildings, structures, other real or personal property, and services incidental to or useful or designed for use in connection with the rendering of transit service by any means, including rail, bus, motor vehicle, or other mode of transportation but does not include any railroad facility.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Transportation facility" includes any one or more or combination of:<section prefix="(1)">Airport facilities;</section><section prefix="(2)">Highway facilities;</section><section prefix="(3)">Port facilities;</section><section prefix="(4)">Railroad facilities; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Transit facilities.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
