<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-6-402</section_number>
  <catch_line>If the Administration and Baltimore City cannot agree on the terms, conditions, and price for any of...</catch_line>
  <order_by>402</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Administration and Baltimore City cannot agree on the terms, conditions, and price for any of the property described in &#xA7; 6-401 of this subtitle, the matter shall be referred to an arbitration board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The arbitration board shall consist of three members appointed as follows:<section prefix="(i)">One by the Administration;</section><section prefix="(ii)">One by the Board of Estimates of Baltimore City; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">One jointly by the two members already appointed.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If, within 15 days after the appointment of the second arbitrator, a third arbitrator has not been appointed, the Governor shall appoint the third arbitrator.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the party seeking arbitration appoints its arbitrator and gives written notice of this appointment to the other party, the other party shall appoint its arbitrator within 30 days after the receipt of the notice. If the other party refuses or neglects to appoint its arbitrator within the 30-day period, the arbitrator appointed by the party seeking arbitration may review the entire matter in controversy as if that individual were an arbitrator appointed by both parties for that purpose.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If only one arbitrator is appointed under subsection (a) of this section, the decision of that arbitrator:<section prefix="(i)">Shall be made within 90 days after the Administration or the Board of Estimates, as the case may be, refuses or neglects to appoint its arbitrator;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall be reported in writing to both parties; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is final and binding on both parties.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If three arbitrators are appointed under subsection (a) of this section, the decision of the majority of them:<section prefix="(i)">Shall be made within 90 days after the first two arbitrators are appointed or within any additional period not exceeding 30 days as may be agreed to by the Administration and the Board of Estimates in writing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall be reported in writing to both parties; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is final and binding on both parties.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The arbitration board or, if only one arbitrator is appointed, the arbitrator may, among other things:<section prefix="(1)">Require that each party to the controversy submit a written statement of its contention to the board and send a copy of the statement to the other party;</section><section prefix="(2)">Make investigations, inspections, and examinations;</section><section prefix="(3)">Take, receive, and keep a permanent record of testimony and other evidence;</section><section prefix="(4)">Hold hearings after notice to the parties in interest; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Adopt rules and regulations for the conduct of the arbitration proceedings.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each party shall pay 50 percent of the arbitration expenses.</section>
  </text>
</law>
