<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-701" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-8-701</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Erect" means, except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, to construct, build, raise, assemble, place, affix, attach, create, paint, draw, or in any other way bring into being or establish.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Erect" does not include any of the activities described in paragraph (1) of this subsection when performed only as an incident to a change of advertising message or the customary maintenance or repair of an outdoor sign or outdoor sign structure.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Main traveled way" means:<section prefix="(i)">That part of a roadway that is used for the movement of vehicles and on which through traffic is carried; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">In the case of a divided highway, that part of each of the separated roadways that is used for the movement of vehicles and on which through traffic is carried in opposite directions.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Main traveled way" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">Shoulders; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Frontage roads, turning roadways, parking areas, or similar facilities.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"On premise outdoor sign" means any outdoor sign that, regardless of content, is designed, intended, or used to advertise or inform the traveling public of:<section prefix="(1)">The sale or lease of the property on which it is located;</section><section prefix="(2)">The sale or lease of a product grown, produced, or manufactured on the property on which it is located; or</section><section prefix="(3)">The name of the owner, agent, assignee, or lessee of the property on which it is located.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Outdoor sign" means any outdoor sign, display, light, structure, figure, painting, drawing, message, plaque, placard, poster, billboard, device, or other thing that is designed, intended, or used to advertise or inform the traveling public.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Visible" means capable of being seen, whether or not legible, without visual aid by a person of normal eyesight.</section>
  </text>
</law>
