<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-602.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-8-602.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The General Assembly finds that the use of best management practices for the storage, application, and disposal of road salt is necessary to reduce the adverse impacts on the water and land resources of the State by preventing:<section prefix="(1)">An increase in chloride concentrations in the soils and waters of the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Harm to soil integrity, soil organisms, and vegetation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The General Assembly intends, by enactment of this section, to reduce to the greatest extent possible the adverse effects of road salt runoff and to safeguard life, limb, property, and public welfare.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">On or before October 1, 2011, the Administration, in consultation with the Department of the Environment, shall develop a road salt management best practices guidance document for use by local jurisdictions and the State to minimize the adverse environmental impacts of road salt runoff in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Administration shall annually update the guidance document required under subsection (c) of this section and shall make the document available to the public on the Administration's website.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In the road salt management best practices guidance document required under this section, the Administration may:<section prefix="(1)">Establish best management practices that protect the environment from the negative impacts of road salt;</section><section prefix="(2)">Identify all activities that may result in the release of road salt into the environment, including road salt storage, the application of road salt on highways, and the disposal of snow that contains road salt;</section><section prefix="(3)">Take into consideration highway safety to the greatest extent possible;</section><section prefix="(4)">Establish standards and procedures for identifying:<section prefix="(i)">Areas that are particularly vulnerable to road salt runoff; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Additional road salt management practices that need to be implemented in these areas;</section></section><section prefix="(5)">Establish goals for achieving a reduction of the environmental impact of road salt released into the environment;</section><section prefix="(6)">Include a training program for all State, local, and contract personnel who perform winter maintenance activities involving the use of road salt;</section><section prefix="(7)">Establish response procedures to address uncontrolled releases of road salt that may adversely impact the environment; and</section><section prefix="(8)">Establish record keeping and annual reporting procedures for the quantity of road salt used, the locations where the road salt is used, and any training conducted.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
