<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-411</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>411</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">On a vehicle for which two registration plates are required, one plate shall be attached on the front and the other on the rear of the vehicle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On a vehicle for which one registration plate is required, the plate shall be attached on the:<section prefix="(1)">Front of the vehicle for a Class F (tractor) vehicle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Rear of the vehicle for every other vehicle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">At all times, each registration plate shall be:<section prefix="(1)">Maintained free from foreign materials, including registration plate covers as defined in &#xA7; 13-411.1 of this subtitle, and in a condition to be clearly legible; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Securely fastened to the vehicle for which it is issued:<section prefix="(i)">In a horizontal position;</section><section prefix="(ii)">In a manner that prevents the plate from swinging; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">In a place and position to be clearly visible.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as otherwise expressly permitted by the Maryland Vehicle Law, as to any vehicle required to be registered under this title, a person may not drive the vehicle on any highway in this State, unless there is attached to the vehicle and displayed on it, as required in this title:<section prefix="(1)">A registration plate or plates issued for the vehicle by the Administration for the current registration period; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Any validation tab issued for the vehicle under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except as otherwise expressly permitted by the Maryland Vehicle Law, as to any vehicle required to be registered under this title, the owner of the vehicle may not permit the vehicle to be driven on any highway in this State, unless there is attached to and displayed on the vehicle, as required in this title:<section prefix="(1)">A registration plate or plates issued by the Administration for the current registration period; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Any validation tab issued for the vehicle under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Except as otherwise expressly permitted by the Maryland Vehicle Law, a vehicle used or driven in this State may not display on either its front or rear any expired registration plate issued by any state.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Except as otherwise expressly permitted by the Maryland Vehicle Law, a person may not display or permit to be displayed on any vehicle used or driven in this State any registration plate issued for another vehicle or to a person other than the owner of the vehicle.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A vehicle registered as a historic or antique vehicle (Class L) in this State or in another state, when used or driven in this State, may display vintage registration plates as an indication of the historic or antique nature of the vehicle. Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the place on the vehicle provided for the display of registration plates may only be used for the display of current registration plates in accordance with subsections (a) through (c) of this section, and any vintage registration plates which are used shall be displayed elsewhere on the vehicle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Administration authorizes the display of vintage registration plates in lieu of current registration plates, as provided in &#xA7; 13-936.1 of this title, the vintage registration plates shall be displayed as required under subsections (a) through (c) of this section. However, the current registration plates shall be kept in the vehicle at all times.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">It is the duty of every police officer to report to the Administration all vehicles operated in violation of this section. The Administration shall verify whether the owner of a reported vehicle has complied with this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
