<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-105" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-15-105</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who is licensed under this title may conduct the licensed activity only from a fixed location, as specified in the application for the license, unless conducting wholesale transactions at auctions or at other licensed dealership locations.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The books of account and records of, except as otherwise specified by law, the licensee shall be kept at that location.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A person, who holds multiple licenses at more than one location and has established a computerized data processing record keeping system at one of his locations, may keep certain records, as designated by the Administrator, of all his licensed activities at the centralized location, provided prior approval of the Administrator has been granted.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A licensee may not remove or relocate the location specified for the licensed activity, unless the licensee has applied for and obtained a supplemental license from the Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A licensee may not open any additional location other than a location specified for the licensed activity, unless the licensee has applied for and obtained a supplemental license from the Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each licensee under this title shall maintain and keep records required by this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The records shall be kept for 3 years after the transaction to which it applies.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">During business hours, the records of the licensee shall be open to inspection by the Administration or any police officer while discharging his official duties.</section>
  </text>
</law>
