<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-501</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, if the owner of a vehicle registered in this State as...</catch_line>
  <order_by>501</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, if the owner of a vehicle registered in this State assigns or otherwise transfers his title or interest in the vehicle, the registration of the vehicle expires, unless the owner gives the transferee written permission to use the existing registration plates.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the owner does not give this permission, the owner shall remove the registration plates from the vehicle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A transferee who has been given written permission to use the existing registration plates may drive and permit the vehicle to be driven with those plates for not more than 10 days from the date of the transfer.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before the 10-day period described under subsection (b) of this section expires, the transferee shall remove the plates from the vehicle and return them promptly to the former owner of the vehicle or to the Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">When the 10-day period expires or, if earlier, when the registration plates are removed, the registration of the vehicle expires.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">After 24 hours of the time the registration of the vehicle expires, neither the transferee nor any other person, other than the person to whom the registration plates originally were issued, may have the registration plates in his possession, whether or not they are in use.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">This section does not prohibit the former owner from transferring the registration plates to another vehicle, as provided in this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
