<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-415" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-415</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If a current registration card or current validation tabs that never have been affixed to registration plates are lost, the owner of the vehicle for which the card or tabs were issued or the legal representative of the owner named in the certificate of title of the vehicle, as shown by the records of the Administration, immediately shall apply for and, after furnishing information satisfactory to the Administration and payment of the required fee, is entitled to obtain a duplicate registration card or replacement validation tabs.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a current registration card or current validation tabs that never have been affixed to registration plates are stolen, the owner of the vehicle for which the card or tabs were issued or the legal representative of the owner named in the certificate of title, as shown by the records of the Administration, immediately shall apply for and, after furnishing information satisfactory to the Administration and payment of the required fee, is entitled to obtain a duplicate registration card or replacement validation tabs.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a current registration card or current validation tabs that never have been affixed to registration plates are damaged to the extent that the registration card or validation tabs are illegible, the owner of the vehicle for which the card or tabs were issued or the legal representative of the owner named in the certificate of title, as shown by the records of the Administration, immediately shall apply for and, after furnishing information satisfactory to the Administration and payment of the required fee, is entitled to obtain a duplicate registration card or replacement validation tabs.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a current registration plate is lost, the owner of the vehicle for which the registration was issued immediately shall place on the vehicle a temporary number plate bearing the vehicle's registration number.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The temporary plate shall be displayed as nearly as possible in the same manner as provided in this subtitle for the registration plate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a current registration plate is stolen, the owner of the vehicle for which the registration was issued immediately shall place on the vehicle a temporary number plate bearing the vehicle's registration number.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The temporary plate shall be displayed as nearly as possible in the same manner as provided in this subtitle for the registration plate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a current registration plate is damaged to the extent that the registration plate is illegible, the owner of the vehicle for which the registration was issued immediately shall place on the vehicle a temporary number plate bearing the vehicle's registration number.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The temporary plate shall be displayed as nearly as possible in the same manner as provided in this subtitle for the registration plate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Within 48 hours after the loss, theft, or damage to the extent of illegibility of any current registration plate or any current validation tab that has been affixed to a registration plate, the owner of the vehicle for which the plate or tab was issued or the legal representative of the owner named in the certificate of title of the vehicle, as shown by the records of the Administration, shall notify the Administration and apply for replacement registration plates, a replacement registration card, and replacement validation tabs. The Administration shall supply the replacements on receiving information satisfactory to it and payment of the required fee.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">On receipt of the replacements, the original registration card and all of the original registration plates and validation tabs issued for that vehicle shall be surrendered to the Administration.</section>
  </text>
</law>
