<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-27-108</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>108</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration shall certify or cause to be certified ignition interlock systems for use in the State and adopt rules and regulations for the certification of the ignition interlock systems.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The regulations adopted under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall include requirements that ignition interlock systems:<section prefix="(i)">Do not impede the safe operation of the vehicle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Minimize opportunities to be bypassed;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Correlate accurately with established measures of blood alcohol levels;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Work accurately and reliably in an unsupervised environment;</section><section prefix="(v)">Require a proper and accurate measure of blood alcohol levels;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Are installed in a tamper proof manner and provide evidence of attempted tampering;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Are difficult to circumvent, and require premeditation to circumvent;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Minimize inconvenience to a sober user;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Are manufactured by a party responsible for installation, user training, service, and maintenance;</section><section prefix="(x)">Operate reliably over the range of motor vehicle environments or motor vehicle manufacturing standards;</section><section prefix="(xi)">Are manufactured by a person who is adequately insured for products liability;</section><section prefix="(xii)">Provide the option for an electronic log of the driver's experience with the system; and</section><section prefix="(xiii)">Are certified by a qualified laboratory approved by the Administration.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Administration shall design and adopt a warning label to be affixed to an ignition interlock system on installation.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The warning label shall state that a person tampering with, circumventing, or otherwise misusing the ignition interlock system is guilty of a misdemeanor, and, on conviction, is subject to a fine or imprisonment or both.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Administration shall publish a list of certified ignition interlock systems.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A manufacturer of an ignition interlock system that seeks to sell or lease the ignition interlock system to persons subject to the provisions of &#xA7; 27-107 of this title in the State shall pay the costs of obtaining the required certification.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not sell or lease or offer to sell or lease an ignition interlock system to a person subject to the provisions of &#xA7; 27-107 of this title in the State unless:<section prefix="(1)">The system has been certified by the Administration; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A warning label approved by the Administration is affixed to the system stating that a person who tampers, circumvents, or otherwise misuses the system is guilty of a misdemeanor, and, on conviction, is subject to a fine or imprisonment or both.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person who sells or leases an ignition interlock system in the State shall:<section prefix="(1)">Monitor the use of the system as required by the court; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Issue a report of the results of the monitoring to the appropriate office of the Division of Parole and Probation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Administration shall adopt regulations establishing minimum standards for the certification of an approved service provider, including:<section prefix="(1)">The minimum qualifications described under &#xA7; 16-404.1 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A requirement that an approved service provider shall maintain service and installation records and provide these records for inspection on the request of the Administration.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
