<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-113</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>113</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If the transferee of a vehicle is a licensed dealer who holds the vehicle for sale, the dealer shall, within 20 days of the date of the transfer to the dealer of the vehicle, obtain the certificate of title of the vehicle, which shall contain an assignment and warranty of title executed by the former owner.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the transferee of a vehicle is a licensed dealer who holds the vehicle for sale, the dealer shall retain the certificate of title in his possession until the further sale or transfer of ownership of the vehicle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">During business hours, the licensed dealer shall allow any representative of the Administration and any police officer full access to all certificates of title of vehicles held by him for sale.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, if a licensed dealer holds a vehicle for sale and transfers the vehicle to another licensed dealer who holds the vehicle for sale, the transferring dealer, without applying for a new certificate of title, shall:<section prefix="(i)">Execute an assignment of title to the transferee dealer in the manner and on the form that the Administration requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Include in the assignment a statement certifying each security interest, lien, or other encumbrance on the vehicle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the certificate of title held by the transferring dealer does not contain an open dealer reassignment section, the transferring dealer shall apply to the Administration for the issuance of a certificate of title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a licensed dealer holds a vehicle for sale and transfers the vehicle to someone other than another licensed dealer who holds the vehicle for sale, the dealer shall:<section prefix="(i)">Execute an assignment and warranty of title to the transferee in the manner and on the form that the Administration requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Comply with the provisions specified in this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the vehicle is a Class A (passenger) vehicle, Class D (motorcycle) vehicle, Class G (trailer) travel trailer or camping trailer, or Class M (multipurpose) vehicle and is to be registered and titled in this State, the transferring dealer shall:<section prefix="(i)">Obtain from the transferee a completed application and collect all taxes and fees required for titling the vehicle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Within 30 days of the date of delivery of the vehicle, send or electronically transmit them, together with every other document or data required by &#xA7;&#xA7; 13-104, 13-104.1, and 13-108.1 of this subtitle, to the Administration.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the vehicle is to be registered and titled in this State, but is not a Class A (passenger) vehicle, Class D (motorcycle) vehicle, Class G (trailer) travel trailer or camping trailer, or Class M (multipurpose) vehicle, the transferring dealer shall, within 30 days of the delivery of the vehicle, either:<section prefix="(i)">Deliver the certificate of title to the transferee; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Send or electronically transmit the transferee's completed application and all taxes and fees required for titling the vehicle, together with every other document or data required by &#xA7;&#xA7; 13-104, 13-104.1, and 13-108.1  of this subtitle, to the Administration.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the vehicle is not to be titled in this State and is to be registered in another state, the transferring dealer shall deliver the certificate of title to the transferee within 30 days of delivery of the vehicle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other provisions to the contrary, an automotive dismantler or recycler licensed under Title 15 of this article may transfer a vehicle that he owns, regardless of the type of ownership document issued for the vehicle, to another licensed automotive dismantler or recycler or to a licensed dealer, without applying for a new certificate of title, as provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The automotive dismantler or recycler shall:<section prefix="(i)">Execute an assignment of title to the transferee automotive dismantler or recycler or dealer in the manner and on the form that the Administration requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Include in the assignment a statement certifying each security interest, lien, or other encumbrances on the vehicle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If an automotive dismantler or recycler licensed under Title 15 of this article owns a vehicle declared as salvage and if a salvage certificate has been issued for the vehicle under &#xA7;&#xA7; 13-506 and 13-507 of this title, the automotive dismantler or recycler may transfer the vehicle to any person, without applying for a new certificate of title, by executing an assignment of ownership on the salvage certificate or on the form that the Administration otherwise requires.</section>
  </text>
</law>
