<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Administration may revoke the license of any person who:<section prefix="(1)">Is convicted under &#xA7; 21-902(a) or (d) of this article of driving or attempting to drive a motor vehicle while under the influence of alcohol, while under the influence of alcohol per se, or while impaired by a controlled dangerous substance; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Within a 3-year period, is convicted under &#xA7; 21-902(b) or (c) of this article of driving or attempting to drive a motor vehicle while impaired by alcohol or while so far impaired by any drug, any combination of drugs, or a combination of one or more drugs and alcohol that the person cannot drive a vehicle safely and who was previously convicted of any combination of two or more violations under:<section prefix="(i)">&#xA7; 21-902(a) of this article of driving or attempting to drive a motor vehicle while under the influence of alcohol or while under the influence of alcohol per se;</section><section prefix="(ii)">&#xA7; 21-902(b) of this article of driving or attempting to drive a motor vehicle while impaired by alcohol;</section><section prefix="(iii)">&#xA7; 21-902(c) of this article of driving or attempting to drive a motor vehicle while so far impaired by any drug, any combination of drugs, or a combination of one or more drugs and alcohol that the person cannot drive a vehicle safely; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">&#xA7; 21-902(d) of this article of driving or attempting to drive a motor vehicle while impaired by a controlled dangerous substance.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Administration:<section prefix="(1)">Shall revoke the license of any person who has been convicted, under Title 2, Subtitle 5 of the Criminal Law Article, of homicide by a motor vehicle while under the influence of alcohol, impaired by alcohol, or impaired by any drug, any combination of drugs, a combination of one or more drugs and alcohol, or a controlled dangerous substance; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May not issue a temporary license to drive for any person whose license has been revoked under item (1) of this subsection during an administrative appeal of the revocation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subject to subsection (d-1) of this section, the Administration may suspend for not more than 60 days the license of any person who is convicted under &#xA7; 21-902(b) or (c) of this article of driving or attempting to drive a motor vehicle while impaired by alcohol or while so far impaired by any drug, any combination of drugs, or a combination of one or more drugs and alcohol that the person cannot drive a vehicle safely.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to subsection (d-1) and subsection (e) of this section, the Administration may suspend for not more than 1 year the license of any person who, within a 5-year period, is convicted of any violation of &#xA7; 21-902 of this article after the person was previously convicted of any violation under &#xA7; 21-902 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If requested by the person, the Administration may issue a restricted license for the period of a suspension to a person who participates in the Ignition Interlock System Program under &#xA7; 16-404.1 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A suspension under this subsection shall be concurrent with any other suspension or revocation imposed by the Administration that arises out of the circumstances of the conviction for the violation of &#xA7; 21-902 of this article described in this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d-1)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding subsections (c) and (d) of this section, for a person who is under the age of 21 years on the date of a violation of &#xA7; 21-902 of this article, and who is subsequently convicted of the violation under &#xA7; 21-902 of this article, the Administration shall suspend the person's license to drive for:<section prefix="(i)">1 year for a first conviction of &#xA7; 21-902 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">2 years for a second or subsequent conviction of &#xA7; 21-902 of this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A suspension imposed under this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be concurrent with any other suspension or revocation imposed by the Administration that arises out of the circumstances of the conviction for a violation of &#xA7; 21-902 of this article described in this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Receive credit for any suspension period imposed under &#xA7; 16-113(f) of this title or &#xA7; 16-205.1 of this subtitle that arises out of the circumstances of the conviction for a violation of &#xA7; 21-902 of this article described in this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to the provisions of this paragraph, a person may request on the record that a hearing on a suspension under this subsection and any other hearing on another suspension or revocation under this section, &#xA7; 16-206(c)(3) or &#xA7; 16-213 of this subtitle, or &#xA7; 16-404 of this title that arises out of the circumstances of the conviction for a violation of &#xA7; 21-902 of this article described in this subsection be consolidated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A person who requests consolidation of hearings under this paragraph shall waive on the record each applicable notice of right to request a hearing required under Title 12, Subtitle 1 or 2 of this article or Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article that applies to the other suspensions or revocations arising out of the same circumstances.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A hearing under this paragraph may not be postponed at the request of the person who requests consolidation of hearings under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph due to a consolidation of the hearings.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Subject to the provisions of this paragraph, the Administration shall consolidate the hearings described in this paragraph unless the administrative law judge finds in writing that good cause exists not to consolidate the hearings.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "motor vehicle" does not include a commercial motor vehicle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to the provisions of this subsection, the Administration shall suspend for 1 year the license of a person who is convicted of:<section prefix="(i)">A violation of &#xA7; 21-902(a) of this article more than once within a 5-year period;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A violation of &#xA7; 21-902(a) of this article within a 5-year period after the person was previously convicted of a violation of &#xA7; 21-902(d) of this article; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A violation of &#xA7; 21-902(d) of this article within a 5-year period after the person was previously convicted of a violation of &#xA7; 21-902(a) of this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On receiving a record of a conviction of a person for a violation described in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Administration shall issue to the person a notice of suspension of the person's license that:<section prefix="(i)">States that the person's license shall be suspended for 1 year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">States that the period of the first 45 days of the 1-year period of suspension is not subject to modification by the Administration;</section><section prefix="(iii)">States a restricted license may be issued for the remainder of the 1-year period of suspension if:<section prefix="1.">The person maintains an ignition interlock system on a motor vehicle owned or operated by the person for the remainder of the 1-year period of suspension;</section><section prefix="2.">The license is restricted to prohibit the person from driving a motor vehicle that is not equipped with an ignition interlock system;</section><section prefix="3.">The license is restricted to permit the person to drive only to and from work, school, an alcohol treatment program, or an ignition interlock system service facility, if the person was convicted of a violation of &#xA7; 21-902(a) of this article more than once within a 5-year period; and</section><section prefix="4.">The license is restricted to permit the person to drive only to and from work, school, an alcohol treatment program, a drug treatment program, or an ignition interlock system service facility, if the person was convicted of:</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">Advises the person of the requirements under paragraph (7) of this subsection for a person who does not participate in the Ignition Interlock System Program in accordance with this paragraph during the 1-year period of suspension;</section><section prefix="(v)">Advises the person of the right to request a hearing on a suspension under this paragraph; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Advises the person of the right, instead of requesting a hearing on a suspension under this paragraph, to be subject to a 1-year period of suspension, with the period of the first 45 days of the suspension not subject to modification by the Administration, and for the remainder of the 1-year period of suspension to be issued a restricted license under this paragraph if the following conditions are met:<section prefix="1.">The person's driver's license is not currently suspended, revoked, canceled, or refused;</section><section prefix="2.">The violation did not arise out of circumstances that involved a death of, or serious physical injury to, another person;</section><section prefix="3.">The person surrenders a valid Maryland driver's license or signs a statement certifying that the driver's license is no longer in the person's possession; and</section><section prefix="4.">The person elects in writing, within the same time limit for requesting a hearing, to meet the ignition interlock system requirements under this paragraph for the remainder of the 1-year period of suspension.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">After notice under paragraph (3) of this subsection, the Administration shall suspend a person's license under this subsection if:<section prefix="(i)">The person does not request a hearing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">After a hearing, the Administration finds that the person was convicted of:<section prefix="1.">More than one violation of &#xA7; 21-902(a) of this article within a 5-year period;</section><section prefix="2.">A violation of &#xA7; 21-902(a) of this article within a 5-year period after the person was previously convicted of a violation of &#xA7; 21-902(d) of this article; or</section><section prefix="3.">A violation of &#xA7; 21-902(d) of this article within a 5-year period after the person was previously convicted of a violation of &#xA7; 21-902(a) of this article; or</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">The person fails to appear for a hearing requested by the person.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Administration may modify a suspension under paragraph (4) of this subsection to:<section prefix="(i)">Impose a suspension of 45 days;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Order the person to maintain, for the remainder of the 1-year period of suspension, an ignition interlock system on a motor vehicle owned or operated by the person; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Impose a restriction on the person's license for the remainder of the 1-year period of suspension that prohibits the person from driving a motor vehicle that is not equipped with an ignition interlock system and permits the person to drive only to and from:<section prefix="1.">Work, school, an alcohol treatment program, or an ignition interlock system service facility, if the person was convicted of a violation of &#xA7; 21-902(a) of this article more than once within a 5-year period;</section><section prefix="2.">Work, school, an alcohol treatment program, a drug treatment program, or an ignition interlock system service facility, if the person was convicted of:</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A person who participates in the Ignition Interlock System Program for at least 3 months under paragraph (5) of this subsection is exempt from the requirements of paragraphs (7) through (11) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The Administration shall, within 90 days of the expiration of the 1-year period of suspension, issue to the person a notice, unless this notice requirement was waived at a hearing described in paragraph (4) of this subsection, that:<section prefix="(i)">States that the person shall maintain for not less than 3 months and not more than 1 year, dating from the expiration of the 1-year period of suspension, an ignition interlock system on each motor vehicle owned by the person;</section><section prefix="(ii)">States that the Administration shall impose a restriction on the person's license that prohibits the person from driving a motor vehicle that is not equipped with an ignition interlock system for a period of not less than 3 months and not more than 1 year, dating from the expiration of the 1-year period of suspension; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Advises the person of the right to request a hearing under this paragraph.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(8)">After notice under paragraph (7) of this subsection, or a waiver of notice, the Administration shall order a person to maintain for not less than 3 months and not more than 1 year, dating from the expiration of the 1-year period of suspension, an ignition interlock system on each motor vehicle owned by the person and impose a license restriction that prohibits the person from driving a motor vehicle that is not equipped with an ignition interlock system if:<section prefix="(i)">The person does not request a hearing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Administration finds at a hearing that the person owns one or more motor vehicles and that no financial hardship, as described in paragraphs (9) and (10) of this subsection, will be created by requiring the person to maintain an ignition interlock system on each motor vehicle owned by the person; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">The person fails to appear for a hearing requested by the person.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(9)">If the Administration finds at a hearing that maintenance of an ignition interlock system on a motor vehicle owned by the person creates a financial hardship on the person, the family of the person, or a co-owner of the motor vehicle, the Administration:<section prefix="(i)">Shall impose a restriction on the license of the person for not less than 3 months and not more than 1 year, dating from the expiration of the 1-year period of suspension, that prohibits the person from driving any motor vehicle that is not equipped with an ignition interlock system; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May not require the person to maintain an ignition interlock system on any motor vehicle to which the financial hardship applies.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(10)">An exemption under paragraph (9)(ii) of this subsection applies only under circumstances that:<section prefix="(i)">Are specific to the person's motor vehicle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Meet criteria contained in regulations that shall be adopted by the Administration.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(11)">If a person requests a hearing and the Administration finds that the person does not own a motor vehicle at the expiration of the 1-year period of suspension, the Administration shall impose a restriction on the license of the person for not less than 3 months and not more than 1 year, dating from the expiration of the 1-year period of suspension, that prohibits the person from driving any motor vehicle that is not equipped with an ignition interlock system.</section>
      <section prefix="(12)">Each notice and hearing under this subsection shall meet the requirements of Title 12, Subtitle 2 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(13)">This subsection does not limit any provision of this article that allows or requires the Administration to:<section prefix="(i)">Revoke or suspend a license of a person; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Prohibit a person from driving a motor vehicle that is not equipped with an ignition interlock system.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(14)">A suspension imposed under this subsection shall be concurrent with any other suspension or revocation imposed by the Administration that arises out of the circumstances of the conviction for a violation of &#xA7; 21-902(a) or (d) of this article described in this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Administration may modify any suspension under this section or any suspension under &#xA7; 16-205.1 of this subtitle and issue a restrictive license to a licensee who participates in the Ignition Interlock System Program established under &#xA7; 16-404.1 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration may not modify a suspension and issue a restrictive license during a mandatory period of suspension described in subsection (e) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">When a suspension imposed under subsection (c), (d), (d-1), or (e) of this section or &#xA7; 16-206(b) of this subtitle expires, the Administration immediately shall return the license or reinstate the privilege of the driver, unless the license or privilege has been refused, revoked, suspended, or canceled under any other provisions of the Maryland Vehicle Law.</section>
  </text>
</law>
