<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Unless excepted by &#xA7; 13-201 of this subtitle, a security interest in a vehicle is not valid against any creditor of the owner or any subsequent transferee or secured party unless the security interest is perfected as provided in this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A security interest is perfected by:<section prefix="(i)">Delivery to the Administration of every existing certificate of title of the vehicle and an application for certificate of title on the form and containing the information about the security interest that the Administration requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Payment of a filing fee established by the Administration, which is in addition to any other fees that apply under the Maryland Vehicle Law.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The security interest is perfected at the time of the delivery and payment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a vehicle already is subject to a security interest when brought into this State, the validity of that security interest in this State is determined by the law (including the conflict of law rules) of the jurisdiction where the vehicle was located when the security interest attached, subject to the provisions of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If, at the time the security interest attached, the parties to the transaction understood that the vehicle would be kept in this State, and if, within 30 days after the security interest attached, the vehicle was brought into this State for purposes other than transportation through this State, the validity of the security interest in this State is determined by the laws of this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If, before the vehicle was brought into this State, the security interest already was perfected under the laws of the jurisdiction where the vehicle was located when the security interest attached, the following rules apply:<section prefix="(i)">If the name of the secured party is shown on an existing certificate of title issued by that jurisdiction, the security interest continues perfected in this State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the name of the secured party is not shown on an existing certificate of title issued by that jurisdiction and if the law of that jurisdiction does not provide for certificates of title disclosing security interests, the security interest continues perfected in this State for 4 months and thereafter if, within the 4-month period, it is perfected in this State, but this security interest also may be perfected in this State after the expiration of the 4-month period, in which case perfection dates from the time of perfection in this State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If, before the vehicle was brought into this State, the security interest was not perfected under the law of the jurisdiction in which the vehicle was located when the security interest attached, it may be perfected in this State, in which case perfection dates from the time of perfection in this State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A secured party under this subtitle may obtain from the Administration a duplicate of the security interest filing as provided in &#xA7; 13-953 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Priority of a security interest in a vehicle perfected as provided under this section is governed by Title 9 of the Commercial Law Article, including &#xA7; 9-317(e).</section>
  </text>
</law>
