<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-18-107</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>107</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person who rents a motor vehicle to a consumer shall:<section prefix="(1)">Compute the daily rental rate based on a 24-hour period, starting at the time the rental begins;</section><section prefix="(2)">Make a notation on the rental agreement of the time the rental begins; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Inform the consumer that:<section prefix="(i)">The daily rental fee is based on a 24-hour period; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The time the rental begins is noted on the rental agreement.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply if:<section prefix="(1)">A person rents a motor vehicle to a consumer; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The rental vehicle is:<section prefix="(i)">A temporary substitute for a vehicle that is out of service because of breakdown, repair, servicing, loss, or destruction; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Covered as a temporary substitute vehicle under the consumer's comprehensive and collision coverage.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Regardless of whether a consumer complies with a requirement by a rental company to notify the rental company in advance of intent to return the vehicle, the rental company may not charge for the use of a rental vehicle after the vehicle has been returned.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a rental agreement requires the consumer to notify the rental company in advance of intent to return the vehicle, the rental company shall make the following written disclosure to the consumer in at least 10 point type:</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition to any remedies otherwise available at law, a violation of this section shall be an unfair or deceptive trade practice under Title 13, Subtitle 3 of the Commercial Law Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
