<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-8-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to &#xA7;&#xA7; 3-307 and 3-308 of this article, and except as provided in subsection (b) of this se...</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to &#xA7;&#xA7; 3-307 and 3-308 of this article, and except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, for each fiscal year, from the total highway user revenues:<section prefix="(1)">An amount equal to 7.7% of total highway user revenues shall be distributed to Baltimore City in monthly installments;</section><section prefix="(2)">An amount shall be distributed to the counties at the times specified in &#xA7; 8-407 of this subtitle, to be allocated as provided in &#xA7; 8-404 of this subtitle, equal to 1.5% of total highway user revenues; and</section><section prefix="(3)">An amount shall be distributed to the municipalities at the times specified in &#xA7; 8-407 of this subtitle, to be allocated as provided in &#xA7; 8-405 of this subtitle, equal to 0.4% of total highway user revenues.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For fiscal year 2010:<section prefix="(i)">The amount distributed to Baltimore City under this subtitle shall equal 8.6% of total highway user revenues;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The amount distributed to the counties under this subtitle shall equal 1.5% of total highway user revenues; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The amount distributed to the municipalities under this subtitle shall equal 0.4% of total highway user revenues.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For fiscal year 2011:<section prefix="(i)">The amount distributed to Baltimore City under this subtitle shall equal 7.9% of total highway user revenues;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The amount distributed to the counties under this subtitle shall equal 0.5% of total highway user revenues; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The amount distributed to the municipalities under this subtitle shall equal 0.1% of total highway user revenues.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For fiscal year 2012:<section prefix="(i)">The amount distributed to Baltimore City under this subtitle shall equal 7.5% of total highway user revenues;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The amount distributed to the counties under this subtitle shall equal 0.8% of total highway user revenues; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The amount distributed to the municipalities under this subtitle shall equal 0.6% of total highway user revenues.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">For fiscal year 2013:<section prefix="(i)">The amount distributed to Baltimore City under this subtitle shall equal 8.1% of total highway user revenues;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The amount distributed to the counties under this subtitle shall equal 1.5% of total highway user revenues; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The amount distributed to the municipalities under this subtitle shall equal 0.4% of total highway user revenues.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
