<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-8-613.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>613.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Roadway" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 11-151 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Shoulder" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 21-101 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Administration shall develop procedures in accordance with subsection (d) of this section to enhance the safety of highway construction, maintenance, utility, and other highway workers during construction or maintenance work on an expressway or controlled access highway with a posted speed limit of 45 miles per hour or more.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A county, municipal corporation, the Administration, or the Maryland Transportation Authority, with respect to highways under its jurisdiction, shall incorporate the procedures developed under subsection (b) of this section into the project planning phase and construction phase of a proposed highway project for an expressway or controlled access highway with a posted speed limit of 45 miles per hour or more.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies to work that is:<section prefix="1.">Performed in a roadway; and</section><section prefix="2.">Expected to last at least two weeks.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The procedures developed under subsection (b) of this section shall ensure that for each highway construction or maintenance project, priority is given to performing the proposed highway construction or maintenance work in the absence of adjacent traffic through full or temporary closure of the highway at the location of the construction or maintenance work, if the closure is determined to be feasible after consideration of the following:<section prefix="1.">Safety of the traveling public;</section><section prefix="2.">Availability and feasibility of detours;</section><section prefix="3.">Access to abutting businesses, residences, and other facilities; and</section><section prefix="4.">Delays that may result from full or temporary closure of the highway.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies to work that is:<section prefix="1.">Performed in a roadway, if a county, municipal corporation, the Administration, or the Maryland Transportation Authority, with respect to highways under its jurisdiction, determines that full or temporary highway closure under paragraph (1) of this subsection is not feasible; or</section><section prefix="2.">Performed on the shoulder and expected to last at least two weeks.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A county, municipal corporation, the Administration, or the Maryland Transportation Authority, with respect to highways under its jurisdiction, shall consider protecting highway construction and maintenance workers by means of:<section prefix="1.">Temporary traffic barriers;</section><section prefix="2.">Movable concrete barriers;</section><section prefix="3.">Movable link-system barriers; or</section><section prefix="4.">Other available barrier systems.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Consideration of the use of barriers under this paragraph shall include consideration of the feasibility of temporarily widening a highway to allow for the installation of the barriers.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">For a highway construction or maintenance project that utilizes barriers under this paragraph, a county, municipal corporation, the Administration, or the Maryland Transportation Authority, with respect to highways under its jurisdiction, may provide for a law enforcement presence at or near the site of the construction or maintenance work in accordance with paragraph (3) of this subsection.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies to work that is:<section prefix="1.">Performed in a roadway or performed on the shoulder; and</section><section prefix="2.">Expected to last at least two weeks.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a county, municipal corporation, the Administration, or the Maryland Transportation Authority, with respect to highways under its jurisdiction, determines that highway closure under paragraph (1) of this subsection and installation of barriers under paragraph (2) of this subsection are not feasible, a county, municipal corporation, the Administration, or the Maryland Transportation Authority, with respect to highways under its jurisdiction, may provide for at least one law enforcement officer to be present at or near the site of the construction or maintenance work when workers are present.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A law enforcement officer present at or near the site of a highway construction or maintenance project under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph may:<section prefix="1.">Be in uniform;</section><section prefix="2.">Be in a marked law enforcement vehicle;</section><section prefix="3.">Display the visual lights or signal devices installed on the law enforcement vehicle; and</section><section prefix="4.">Be located at or near the site of the highway construction or maintenance project in a manner to:</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">A law enforcement officer present at or near the site of a highway construction or maintenance project under subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph may take any authorized action to enforce traffic laws at or near the project.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
