<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="21-902" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-21-902</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not drive or attempt to drive any vehicle while under the influence of alcohol.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not drive or attempt to drive any vehicle while the person is under the influence of alcohol per se.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A person may not violate paragraph (1) or (2) of this subsection while transporting a minor.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not drive or attempt to drive any vehicle while impaired by alcohol.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not violate paragraph (1) of this subsection while transporting a minor.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not drive or attempt to drive any vehicle while he is so far impaired by any drug, any combination of drugs, or a combination of one or more drugs and alcohol that he cannot drive a vehicle safely.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">It is not a defense to any charge of violating this subsection that the person charged is or was entitled under the laws of this State to use the drug, combination of drugs, or combination of one or more drugs and alcohol, unless the person was unaware that the drug or combination would make the person incapable of safely driving a vehicle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A person may not violate paragraph (1) of this subsection while transporting a minor.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not drive or attempt to drive any vehicle while the person is impaired by any controlled dangerous substance, as that term is defined in &#xA7; 5-101 of the Criminal Law Article, if the person is not entitled to use the controlled dangerous substance under the laws of this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not violate paragraph (1) of this subsection while transporting a minor.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">For purposes of the application of subsequent offender penalties under &#xA7; 27-101 of this article, a conviction for a crime committed in another state or federal jurisdiction that, if committed in this State, would constitute a violation of subsection (a), (b), (c), or (d) of this section shall be considered a violation of subsection (a), (b), (c), or (d) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
