<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gtr" order_by="gtr" level="1">Transportation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-16-110</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Administration shall:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>110</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Administration shall:<section prefix="(1)">Establish qualifications for the safe operation of the various classes, types, sizes, or combinations of vehicles; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Examine each applicant to determine the applicant's qualifications for the license class applied for.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, the Administration shall examine each applicant for an original driver's license or for a class of driver's license higher than that which the applicant currently holds.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The examination shall include:<section prefix="(1)">A test of the applicant's:<section prefix="(i)">Vision;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Ability to read and understand highway signs regulating, warning, and directing traffic; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Knowledge of the traffic laws of this State and safe driving practices;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">A demonstration of the applicant's ability to exercise reasonable control in driving a motor vehicle; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Any other additional physical or mental examination that the Administration considers necessary to determine an applicant's fitness to drive a motor vehicle safely.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If an applicant is qualified to take the required examinations for the license applied for, the applicant shall appear in person for examination at any one of the places in this State that the Administration has designated for this purpose.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For a required driver skills examination or driver road examination, each applicant shall provide a motor vehicle of a type appropriate to test the applicant's ability to drive all vehicles that may be driven under the license class applied for.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraphs (3) and (4) of this subsection, when the holder of a learner's instructional permit appears for the driving test, the permit holder shall be accompanied by an individual qualified under &#xA7; 16-105 of this subtitle to accompany the holder of a learner's permit while driving on a highway. That individual shall have his driver's license with him.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The holder of a Class M (motorcycle) learner's instructional permit may:<section prefix="(i)">Transport a motorcycle to the driving test by truck or other vehicle unaccompanied by another individual, if the permit holder is licensed to drive the truck or other vehicle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be accompanied by a person transporting a motorcycle to the test by truck or other vehicle, if that person is licensed to drive the truck or other vehicle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The holder of a learner's instructional permit may be driven to the examination station and to the starting point where the examiner begins the test by any individual authorized to drive the class of vehicle in which the test is being given. That individual shall have a valid driver's license in the individual's possession.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If the applicant does not pass the examination for the license class applied for, the Administration may issue the applicant any license of a lower class for which the applicant qualifies.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Except as provided in subsection (h) of this section, the Administration may waive any driver's license examination provided for under this title if the applicant:<section prefix="(1)">Holds a valid driver's license issued under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is applying for a Class M license and has successfully completed the Administration approved basic motorcycle safety course; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Holds a valid license from:<section prefix="(i)">Another state;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A territory or possession of the United States, the District of Columbia, or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A province or territory of Canada.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Administration may not waive a vision examination required under this section unless the applicant:<section prefix="(1)">Is applying for a corrected driver's license under &#xA7; 16-114.1 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Has passed a vision examination acceptable to the Administration within the last 12 months.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
