<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gtr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-812" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gtr-13-812</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">For collecting and remitting the tax, a licensed dealer who, on behalf of the Administration, collects the excise tax imposed by this part may keep the lesser of $12 per vehicle or 0.6 percent of the gross excise tax the dealer collects.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each dealer who collects any tax or fee required for titling a vehicle shall:<section prefix="(1)">Keep complete and accurate records of each taxable sale, together with a record of the tax collected on the sale;</section><section prefix="(2)">Keep copies of every invoice, bill of sale, and other pertinent documents and records, in the form that the Administration requires; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Preserve these records in original form for at least 3 years, unless the Administration consents in writing to their earlier destruction or, by order, requires that they be kept for a longer period.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each dealer who collects any tax or fee required for titling a vehicle shall, during business hours, allow any representative of the Administration and any police officer full access to records required to be kept under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the Administration finds that the records of a dealer are inadequate or incorrect and that the amount of excise tax collected for the Administration on these sales cannot be determined accurately from the records:<section prefix="(1)">The Administration shall determine the taxable sales of the dealer for the period involved and compute the tax from the best information available; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The determination and computation of the Administration are prima facie correct.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If, under subsection (d) of this section, the Administration determines the sales of vehicles and computes the tax due, it shall:<section prefix="(i)">Levy an assessment against the dealer for the deficiency, interest, and penalties in the manner authorized in &#xA7;&#xA7; 13-401, 13-601, and 13-701 of the Tax - General Article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Notify the dealer of the tax due and of the amount of the deficiency assessment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the dealer fails to pay the tax and assessment within 10 days after receiving the notice from the Administration, the Administration may levy, in addition to the tax and assessment, a penalty equal to 25 percent of the tax due.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If a dealer fails to keep any records of sales of vehicles, the Administration may compute the tax due as provided in &#xA7; 13-407 of the Tax - General Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">All amounts received from any dealer under this section shall be credited:<section prefix="(1)">First, to any penalty and interest accrued under this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Then, to the tax due.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
